<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>344</id>
<name>WANTAGE</name>
<container>BERKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5706076030501</lat>
<lon>-1.42405773616358</lon>
<gazetteerText>WANTAGE, a town, a parish, a sub-district, a district, and a hundred, in Berks. The town stands on the Wilts and Berks canal, near White Horse Vale, 2&#189; miles SSW of Wantage-Road r. station, and 9 SW of Abingdon; is supposed to occupy the site of a Roman station; was the birth-place of King Alfred, and a residence of other Saxon kings; belonged then to the Crown; passed through many noble hands, including Baldwin de Bethune, William de Valence, Hugh Bigod, Fulk Fitzwarren, and the Bourchiers Earls of Bath; numbers among its natives Bishop Butler and the theologian Kimber; is a seat of petty-sessions and county courts; carries on iron and brass founding, and agricultural implement-making; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a banking office, three chief inns, a town hall, a corn exchange, a church, Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, a grammar-school with &#163;39 a year, a national school, an industrial training school for girls, a home for penitent females, alms houses, a workhouse, a weekly corn-market on Wednesday, a weekly general market on Saturday, and five annual fairs. The town hall includes court-rooms and a reading room. The corn exchange was built in 1865. The church ranges from early English to perpendicular; is cruciform, large, and interesting; and has a central tower. The grammar-school was rebuilt after 1849, in result of a millenary commemoration of the birth of King Alfred. Real property of the town, &#163;11,559; of which &#163;200 are in gasworks. Pop., 3,064. Houses, 628. The parish contains also Grove township, and Charlton and West Lockinge hamlets. Acres, 7,530. Pop., 3,925. Houses, 821. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;750.* Patrons, the Dean and Canons of Windsor. The p. curacy of Grove is a separate benefice; and a chapel of ease is at Charlton.-- The sub-district excludes the two hamlets, but includes 4 other parishes, and 3 parts. Pop., 7,304. Houses, 1,599.&#151;The district comprehends also Ilsley and Hendred sub-districts, and comprises 75,700 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;11,390. Pop. in 1851, 17,433; in 1861, 17,308. Houses, 3,717. Marriages in 1863, 121; births, 593,-of which 39 were illegitimate; deaths, 301,-of which 110 were at ages under 5 years, and 8 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,106; births, 5,559; deaths, 3,559. The places of worship, in 1851, were 37 of the Church of England, with 7,457 sittings; 6 of Baptists, with 620 s.; 19 of Wesleyans, with 2,380 s.; 10 of Primitive Methodists, with 772 s.; 1 undefined, with 40 s.; and 1 of Roman Catholics, with 130 s. The schools were 34 public day-schools, with 1,975 scholars; 24 private day-schools, with 622 s.; and 34 Sunday schools, with 2,059 s.-The hundred contains 7 parishes and 3 parts. Acres, 33,317. Pop., 9,537. Houses, 2,081. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wantage</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Wantage</link>
<link>http://www.berksfhs.org.uk/genuki/BRK/Wantage/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634801</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62712</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62719</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62721</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10008566</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10028383</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10031382</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10055064</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10061775</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10113088</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10139089</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10156919</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542935</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581813</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12747408</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3277</id>
   <name>GROVE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3636</id>
   <name>LONGWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3643</id>
   <name>STANFORD IN THE VALE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4517</id>
   <name>EAST CHALLOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4537</id>
   <name>LAMBOURN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4543</id>
   <name>SPEEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5020</id>
   <name>KINTBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6102</id>
   <name>WELFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9932</id>
   <name>BAMPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10015</id>
   <name>BRIZE NORTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
