<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4537</id>
<name>LAMBOURN</name>
<container>BERKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5072758015522</lat>
<lon>-1.53217192035806</lon>
<gazetteerText>LAMBOURN, a small town, a township, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Hungerford district, Berks. The town stands on the river Lambourn, 2&#189; miles from the boundary with Wilts, and 7 N by W of Hungerford r. station; is sometimes called Chipping-Lambourn; dates from an ancient period; contains an ancient market cross, and many neat modern houses; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a post-office&#8225; under Hungerford, a police station, a church, Wesleyan and Primitive Methodist chapels, national schools, almshouses, and charities &#163;46. The church is cruciform and large, variously Norman, early English, and perpendicular; has a massive square embattled tower, surmounted by four octagonal turrets; was extensively repaired in 1861; and contains memorial windows by Williment, a fine marble monument of John D. Estbury, and ornamented brasses of the Estburys and the Garrards. Almshouses for ten poor men are on the N side of the church, and have an endowed income of &#163;223. A weekly market is held on Friday; and fairs are held on 12 May, the Friday after 12 Oct., and 4 Dec.&#151;The township includes the town, and also is sometimes called Chipping-Lambourn. Real property, &#163;5,576. Pop., 1,214. Houses, 284.&#151;The parish contains also the tythings of Upper Lambourn, Blagrave, Hadley, and Eastbury and Bockhampton. Acres, 14,830. Real property, &#163;16,478. Pop., 2,529. Houses, 571. The manor was given by Alfred to his nephew Alfrith; passed to the families of Fitzwarren and De Essex; and, with Lambourn Place, belongs now to H. Hippisley, Esq. A large proportion of the surface consists of chalk downs; many barrows are here; the Ridge way passes along the N; and the remarkable antiquities called the White Horse and the Blowing Stone, are in the vicinity of that way. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Eastbury, in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;204.* Patron, the Bishop of Oxford. A chapel of ease, of recent erection, is at Eastbury; and a free school also is there. The p. curacy of Woodlands is a separate benefice.&#151;The sub-district contains also three other parishes in Berks, and two in Wilts. Acres, 33,964. Pop., 5,654. Houses, 1,270.&#151;The hundred comprises only the parishes of Lambourn and East Garston. Acres, 19,172. Pop., 3,118. Houses, 711. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lambourn</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644993</link>
<link>http://www.berksfhs.org.uk/genuki/BRK/Lambourn/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62709</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62711</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10024602</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>LAMBOURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10064508</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LAMBOURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10156518</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LAMBOURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10188143</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>LAMBOURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543060</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LAMBOURN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3357</id>
   <name>EAST GARSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5006</id>
   <name>FAWLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>23589</id>
<name>LAMBOURN WOODLANDS</name>
<container>BERKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.480670552639</lat>
<lon>-1.54057916430132</lon>
<gazetteerText>WOODLANDS, a chapelry in Lambourn parish, Berks; 5 miles NNW of Hungerford r. station. It was constituted in 1838; and it has a post-office under Hungerford. Pop., 348. Houses, 69. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;220.* Patron, J. Aldridge, Esq. The church was built in 1842. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lambourn_Woodlands</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10045411</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LAMBOURN WOODLANDS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
