<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3808</id>
<name>IMPINGTON</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2423562800371</lat>
<lon>0.121524919533748</lon>
<gazetteerText>IMPINGTON, a village and a parish in Chesterton district, Cambridgeshire. The village stands 1 mile ESE of Histon r. station, and 2 &#189; N of Cambridge; and was once a market town. The parish comprises 1, 200 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 759. Pop. in 1851, 273; in 1861, 335. Houses, 75. The property is much subdivided. A handsome mansion here belonged to the Pepys family; is frequently mentioned in Pepys&apos; diary; and passed, not long ago, to the family of Coffin. A woman of this parish was enveloped in a snow drift in 1799, remained in it nearly eight days and nights, and was taken out alive; and a monument, recording the event, now stands on the spot. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;128. Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Ely. The church consists of nave, aisle, and chancel, with porch and tower; and has a brass of the Burgoynes of 1500. There are a national school, and charities &#163;6. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impington</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Impington/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7298853</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15364</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15360</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15359</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15361</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15362</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15365</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15366</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15363</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10119881</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>IMPINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10159301</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>IMPINGTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1184</id>
   <name>FLENDISH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
