<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1553</id>
<name>BOTTISHAM</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2320628488683</lat>
<lon>0.261618515523855</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOTTISHAM, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Newmarket district, Cambridge. The village stands on an affluent of the river Cam, 3&#189; miles NNE of Fulbourn r. station, and 6&#189; ENE of Cambridge; and it has a post office under Newmarket, and is a seat of petty sessions. The parish includes also the hamlets of Lode and Longmeadow. Acres, 4,700. Real property, &#163;8,830. Pop., 1,508. Houses, 332. The property is much subdivided. Bottisham Hall is the seat of the Jenyns family. Traces exist at Anglesey of an Augustinian priory, founded in the time of Henry I. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;268.* Patron, Trinity College, Cambridge. The church is early English, good, and beautiful. The vicarage of Lode is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Independents and Baptists, and two national schools.-The subdistrict contains two parishes and most of another. Acres, with Newmarket subdistrict, 28,323. Pop., 3,373. Houses, 754. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655123</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bottisham</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Bottisham/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18847</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18848</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18850</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18851</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18853</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18854</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18849</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18852</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10011243</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BOTTISHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10177972</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOTTISHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10562041</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BOTTISHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2987</id>
<name>LODE</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2539683413953</lat>
<lon>0.239702723161092</lon>
<gazetteerText>LODE, a chapelry in Bottisham parish, Cammbridgeshire, 6&#189; miles ENE of Cambridge. Pop., 776. An abbey, called the priory of Anglesey, was founded here by Henry I.; and some remains of it still exist. The chapelry was constituted in 1863. The living is a vicarage..Value, not reported.* There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lode,_Cambridgeshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Lode/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7670885</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10086176</id>
   <status>CP/ExP</status>
   <name>LODE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10118580</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOTTISHAM LODE AND LONG MEADOW</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
