<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>897</id>
<name>CHATTERIS</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4490911261681</lat>
<lon>0.0760407130736977</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHATTERIS, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in the district of North Witchford, Cambridge. The town stands on the west border of the isle of Ely, near the Cambridge and Wisbeach railway, 10&#189; miles NNE of St. Ives; and has a station on the railway, a post office&#8225; under March, a banking office, two chief inns, and a weekly market on Friday. It was known at Domesday as Ceterig or Caterig; and has ever since possessed some local importance; but was not made a market-town till 1834. A Benedictine nunnery was founded at it, in 980, by Alfwen, niece of King Edgar; annexed, in the time of Henry I., to the church of Ely; and given, at the dissolution, to the Clintons. An ancient manor-house now stands on the nunnery&apos;s site. The parish comprises 15, 090 acres. Real property, &#163;37, 460. Pop., 4, 731. Houses, 1, 070. Much of the land is fenny; much has been highly improved; part is common; and 284 acres are devoted to the poor. A hermitage, the burial-place of St. Hunna, was at Hunny farm. British relics were found, in 1757, in a barrow, and many Roman coins have been ploughed up. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;1, 500.* Patron, W. Hawkins, Esq. The church is a handsome structure with a square tower. There are seven chapels for Independents, Baptists, Methodists. and Quakers.&#151;The sub-district contains two parishes and parts of two others. Acres, 33, 093. Pop., 8, 222. Houses, 1, 790. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chatteris</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Chatteris/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653298</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=21900</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10011747</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHATTERIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10047640</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CHATTERIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154339</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>CHATTERIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10166834</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CHATTERIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550944</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHATTERIS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1603</id>
   <name>WELCHES DAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2205</id>
   <name>SUTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3828</id>
   <name>THETFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3833</id>
   <name>WITCHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4623</id>
   <name>MEPAL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4632</id>
   <name>WENTWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5082</id>
   <name>HADDENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5878</id>
   <name>WITCHFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6111</id>
   <name>COVENEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7388</id>
   <name>SOMERSHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
