<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6384</id>
<name>LLANGEITHO</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2365178727389</lat>
<lon>-4.03032884084205</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANGEITHO, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Tregaron district, Cardigan. The village stands on the river Ayron, under the hills, near the Sarn Helen way, 4 miles W of a reach of the Central Wales railway, which was in progress of formation in 1866, and 8&#189; N by E of Lampeter; and has a post office under Carmarthen. The parish contains also the hamlet of Bonteyen. Acres, 2,150. Real property, &#163;1,397. Pop., 453. Houses, 97. The property is much subdivided. Cwrt-Mawr, an old mansion, is now a farm-house. The living is a rec. tory in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;106. Pa. tron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church is dedicated to St. Ceitho; was rebuilt in 1821; was reported in 1859 as then needing repair; and contains a monument to Rowland, once rector of the parish, and founder of the Rowlandites. There are a Calvinistic Methodist chapel, and charities &#163;50. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/Llangeitho/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644035</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10226065</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANGEITHO</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548524</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANGEITHO</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2027</id>
   <name>LLANBADARN ODWYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4344</id>
   <name>GWYNFIL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5630</id>
   <name>BLAENPENNAL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17265</id>
   <name>CARDIGANSHIRE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
