<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11171</id>
<name>LLECHRYD</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0634512803907</lat>
<lon>-4.59989960866117</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLECHRYD, a village and a parish in the district and county of Cardigan. The village stands on the river Teifi, at the boundary with Pembroke, near the Carmarthen and Cardigan railway, 3 miles SE of Cardigan; is a pleasant place, and a resort of anglers; and has a postoffice under Carmarthen, and a bridge over the river, communicating with the charming grounds of Castle Malgwyn. A large weir formerly was here, preventing salmon from ascending the river; and was destroyed, in 1844, by a large body of the Rebecca rioters. The village had once a tin-plate factory.&#151;The parish comprises 943 acres. Real property, with Llangoedmore, &#163;5,050. Pop., 454. Houses, 112. The property is divided among a few. A battle was fought here, in 1087, between Rhys ab Twdwr and the sons of Bleddin ab Cynfyn. The living &amp; is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;109. Patron, alternately T. Lloyd, Esq., andR. Longcroft, Esq. The church was reported in 1859 as bad. A Presbyterian chapel was built here by Wade, one of the officers of Cromwell. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/Llechryd/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llechryd</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643891</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10238870</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LLECHRYD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10388417</id>
   <status>ExP/CP/Ch</status>
   <name>LLECHRYD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6684</id>
   <name>LLECHGYNFARWY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
