<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4450</id>
<name>LLANDYSILIO</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8610030324384</lat>
<lon>-4.7372639922715</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANDISSILIO, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in the district of Narberth; part of the parish in Carmarthenshire, and part in Pembrokeshire. I he village stands on the river Cleddau, at the boundary between the counties, 1&#190; mile N of Narberth-Road r. station, and 4&#188; N of Narberth; and has a post office under Narberth. The parish comprises 4,719 acres in Carmarthenshire, and 1,748 in Pembrokeshire. Real property, &#163;4,985. Pop. of theportion, 630; of the P. portion, 406. Houses, 120 and 95. The property is subdivided. A Druidical circle is at Llwynyebol; and ancient camps are at Portispark and Casgwyn. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Valne, &#163;144. Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church has an ancient inscription, exhumed in 1827; and was reported in 1859 as not good.&#151;The sub-district contains also another parish in Carmarthenshire, and eight other parishes and part of another in Pembrokeshire. Acres, 25,686. Pop., 3,340. Houses, 701. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Llandissilio/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644130</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10060291</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANDYSILIO EAST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10150589</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANDYSILIO WEST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10487444</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>LLANDISSILIO</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10515506</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LLANDISSILIO EAST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10563306</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANDISSILIO</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1961</id>
   <name>GRONDRE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11006</id>
   <name>EGREMONT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
