<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1525</id>
<name>CAEO</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0711588183611</lat>
<lon>-3.93518813108899</lon>
<gazetteerText>CONWIL-CAYO, a parish and a sub-district in Llandovery district, Carmarthen. The parish lies on the Sarn-Helen way, and on a headstream of the river Towy, 7&#189; miles NW of Llandovery town and r. station; and contains the village of Cayo and the hamlets of Cwmcothy, Cwmtwrch Lower, and Maestroyddin. Post town, Llandovery, under Carmarthen. Acres, 41, 785. Real property, &#163;8, 188. Pop., 2, 251. Houses, 442. Mineral springs of several kinds occur, and are in repute. Mines yielding gold were worked here by the Romans Several tumuli are near a place called Remus&apos; Ford; remains of an aqueduct lead to the place of the old mines; remains of the Sarn-Helen way are seen; and Roman bricks, inscriptions, torques, and coins have been found. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Llansawel, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;305.* Patron, the Prince of Wales. The church is ancient, large, and good. There is a Calvinistic Methodist chapel. Conwil-Cayo is sung by the poet Llywarch-Hen. -The sub-district is conterminate with the parish. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/ConwilCaio/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caeo</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301139</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10010342</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CAEO</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10065770</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>CAEO</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10158035</id>
   <status>Cmt</status>
   <name>CAEO</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552692</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CONWIL GAIO</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
