<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5369</id>
<name>LLANARTHNE</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8348154282525</lat>
<lon>-4.13388734614721</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANARTHNEY, a village and a parish in the district and county of Carmarthen. The village stands on the river Towy, adjacent to the Carmarthen and Llandilo railway, 8 miles E of Carmarthen; and has a station on the railway, a post office under Carmarthen, and a fair for horses, cattle, and sheep on 5 June, a fair for pigs on 6 June, and other fairs on the Monday after 12 July and Whit-Monday. The parish contains also the hamlets of Llanllyan, Myhathan, Trefroynan, Trecastell, Trechgwynnon, Miawst, Treclas, and Myddfey; and includes two-thirds of Mynydd-Mawr. Acres, 10,994. Rated property, &#163;6,550. Pop., 2,001. Houses, 424. The property is much subdivided. Dynevor Castle, in the vicinity, was a stronghold of the early princes of Wales; underwent repeated demolition and reconstruction; is now an ivy-clad ruin, consisting chiefly of a square tower, a round tower, and some battlemented walls, overhanging a precipice; and gave place to the modern mansion of Dynevor Park, or Newton, the seat of Lord Dynevor. Dryslwyn Castle was one of the Edwardian fortalices, erected by one of the princes of the house of Dynevor; and is now represented by extensive earth-works and ivy-clad walls, on the top of a high hill. Middleton Hall is the seat of E. Abadan, Esq. A monument to Nelson, in the form of a triangular tower, is on the other side of the Towy from Dryslwyn Castle, and was erected by Sir William Paxton. Grongar Hill, in the vicinity, and approached through Dynevor Park, commands a very fine view, is crowned by vestiges of an ancient camp, was sung by the poet Dyer, and was the place where he wrote his verses. Coal and limestone are worked; and there is a mineral spring, of similar quality to the water of Tunbridge-Wells. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Carmarthen. Valne, &#163;340. Patron, the Bishop of St. Davids. The church is ancient but good, and has an ancient stone cross. There are two Calvinistic Methodist chapels. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Llanarthney/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644186</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10192626</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANARTHNE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2600</id>
   <name>LLANFYNYDD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4958</id>
   <name>LLANDDAROG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6380</id>
   <name>LLANGATHEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10976</id>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL CILFARGEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
