<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5393</id>
<name>LLANEGWAD</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9058624387208</lat>
<lon>-4.1593400419283</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANEGWAD, a parish in Llandilo-fawr district, Carmarthen; on the river Towy, at the influx of the Cothi, near the Llanarthney station of the Carmarthen and Llandilo railway, 8 miles W by S of Llandilo-fawr. It contains the hamlets of Egwad, Hernin, LLlechfraith, Llechgron, Llethergele, Miros, Monachty, and Ystrad; and its Post town is Llandilo, under Carmarthen. Acres, 12,330. Real property, &#163;5,342. Pop., 1,920. Houses, 421. The property is subdivided. Much land was, not long ago, reclaimed and enclosed. Copper ore is found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;259. Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church is dedicated to St. Egwad, and is good. There are a Calvinistic Methodist chapel, and charities &#163;100. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Llanegwad/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/3345193</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10193175</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANEGWAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2600</id>
<name>LLANFYNYDD</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9384328538228</lat>
<lon>-4.08740262440948</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANFYNYDD, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Llandilo-fawr district, Carmarthen. The village stands on an affluent of the river Towy, 6 miles NW of Llandilo-fawr r. station; and has fairs on 5 July, 13 Aug., and 11 Nov. The parish contains also the hamlets of Brisken, Cathilas, Clynynnos, Crachyty, Eskercam, Eskerevan, Cilangwr, Eskergarn, Gothylon, Pan tarfion, Cornoyron, Penrhos, and Cwmban; and its posttown is Dryslwyn, under Carmarthen. Acres, 10,744. Real property, &#163;4,017. Pop. in 1851,1,376; in 1861, 1,230. Houses, 253. The decrease of pop. arose from the migration of agricultural labourers to mining and manufacturing localities. The property is subdivided. There are remains of an ancient camp. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;.150. Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church is dedicated to St. Egwad, and was restored in 1861. There are an endowed school with &#163;37 a year, and other charities &#163;23.&#151;The sub-district contains also two other parishes. Acres, 11,790. Pop., 1,410. Houses, 289. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llanfynydd</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644052</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Llanfynydd/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10067250</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANFYNYDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552758</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANFYNYDD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
