<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4646</id>
<name>GERRANS</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1846473954865</lat>
<lon>-4.98265062338871</lon>
<gazetteerText>GERRANS, a village and a parish in Truro district, Cornwall. The village stands on the W side of a bay of its own name, and near the head of St. Mawe&apos;s harbour., 7 miles SW by S of Tregony, and 7&#189; SSE of Truro r. station; is alleged to have been founded by Gerennius, a king of Cornwall, in the latter part of the 6th century; and has a post office under Grampound. The parish contains also the hamlet of Porthskatho. Acres, 2, 870; of which 215 are water. Real property, &#163;3, 752. Pop., 935. Houses, 215. The manor belonged formerly to the bishops of Exeter. An ancient earthwork, called Dungerein, situated N of the church, and communicating with the shore by a subterranean passage, is regarded as a vestige of a fort or palace of a King Gerennius. The rocks include slate. Gerrans bay has a semicircular outline, and measures about 2&#189; miles across the chord. A fine specimen of a raised beach, consisting of pebbles cemented into conglomerate by oxide of iron, is on its E shore. The living of Gerrans is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Valne, &#163;258.* Patron, the Bishop of Exeter. The church stands on an eminence, with a fine view, and contains a monument to the Hobbe family. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, and charities &#163;9. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gerrans</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648714</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Gerrans/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10159994</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GERRANS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160467</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST GERRANS WITH ST ANTHONY IN ROSELAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10198872</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST GERRANS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
