<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4654</id>
<name>ST JOHN</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.3482777125635</lat>
<lon>-4.23897641180028</lon>
<gazetteerText>JOHN (ST.), a village and a parish in St. Germans district, Cornwall. The village stands at the head of a branch of the Hamoaze, called St. John&apos;s lake, opposite Devonport town and r. station, and 5&#189; miles SE by E of St. Germans. The parish extends to the English Channel; and comprises 698 acres of land, and 125 of water. Post town, Devonport. Real property, &#163;1, 094. Pop. in 1851, 155; in 1861, 213. Houses, 38. The increase of pop. arose from the temporary presence of labourers at the erection of forts. The manor formerly belonged to the Champernowns, and belongs now to Deeble Boger, Esq. Tregenhawke belonged to the Trevilles, and others; and passed to Lord Graves. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;179. * Patron, W. H. Pole Carew, Esq. The church measures 56 feet by 18: and was restored in 1866. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StJohn/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10122259</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160479</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>26446</id>
<name>ST JOHNS</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1005120040273</lat>
<lon>-5.28234297336166</lon>
<gazetteerText>JOHN&apos;S (ST.), a village c of a mile W of Helston, in Cornwall. It had an hospital of the Knights of St. John; and it has furnished some architectural relics. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
</results>
