<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1637</id>
<name>ST BLAZEY</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.354064237121</lat>
<lon>-4.73007022304017</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLAZEY (St.), a small town and a parish in St. Austell district, Cornwall. The town stands under an amphitheatre of wooded heights, 1 mile NNW of Par r. station, and 4 ENE of St. Austell. It took its name from Blaise, Bishop of Sebaste, in Armenia, who is said to have landed at Par in the third century, and to have suffered martyrdom in 316. It has a post office&#8225; under Par station, and an inn; and is a centre of traffic for the neighbouring mines; and fairs are held at it on 2 Feb. and 4 July. The parish includes also Par-harbour. Acres, 1,797. Real property, &#163;28,514; of which &#163;21,505 are in mines, and &#163;1,063 in canal. Pop., 4,224. Houses, 876. The property is divided among a few. Granite and slate are quarried; tin and iron ores are worked; and there is a large iron foundry. Much scenery within the parish and in the neighbourhood is picturesque and romantic. Prideaux, the seat of Sir Colman Rashleigh, Bart., an ancient edifice, with granite stairs, is on a height above the town; and Prideaux Warren, the remains of an ancient earth-work, is on an adjacent height. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;120.* Patron,-Carlyon, Esq. The church has an effigies of St. Blaise; and is good. There are Wesleyan Methodist, Primitive Methodist, and United Free Methodist chapels. The vicarage of Biscovey or Par is a separate benefice. R. Allen, who brought polite stone into use, was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Blazey</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StBlazey/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10014244</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ST BALZEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10067881</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST BALZEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3865</id>
   <name>LUXULYAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
