<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5545</id>
<name>CONSTANTINE</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1188418951001</lat>
<lon>-5.17257754692516</lon>
<gazetteerText>CONSTANTINE, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Falmouth district, Cornwall. The village stands on a branch of the Helford river, near the coast, 5 miles SW of Falmouth town and r. station; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a post office under Falmouth, and fairs on 12 April, 21 June, and 27 Sept. The parish com. prises 7, 909 acres of land and 270 of water. Real property, &#163;8, 517; of which &#163;445 are in fisheries, and &#163;199 in quarries. Pop., 2, 014. Houses, 413. The property is divided among a few. Fine-grained granite is quarried; copper and tin mines are worked; and oyster-fishing is carried on. The Tolm&#234;n, Meantol, or Holed Stone, an egg-shaped block of granite, 33 feet long and 18 feet broad, supposed by some antiquaries to be Druidical, is here on a barren hill 690 feet high. The parish is a resort of sportsmen. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;450.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Exeter. The church contains monuments of the Gerveyses; and is good. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitve Methodists. -The sub-district contains three parishes. Acres, 13, 006. Pop., 3, 199. Houses, 645. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constantine,_Cornwall</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652434</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Constantine/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10048424</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CONSTANTINE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10198823</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CONSTANTINE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542571</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CONSTANTINE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17296</id>
   <name>KERRIER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
