<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>973</id>
<name>CALLINGTON</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.5005091880181</lat>
<lon>-4.31159915454789</lon>
<gazetteerText>CALLINGTON, formerly Kellington, a small town, a parish, and a subdistrict in Liskeard district, Cornwall. The town stands on a gentle acclivity, near the river Lynner, 6 miles N of St. Germans r. station, and 11 S of Launceston. It consists chiefly of one broad street, irregularly built; is a seat of petty sessions, and a polling-place; and has a head post office,&#8225; (designated Callington, Cornwall,) two banking offices, a hotel, a church, two dissenting chapels, a literary institution, and a free school. The church was built, on the site of a previous one, in 1460; is perpendicular English; was restored in 1859; and contains a very curious old Norman font, and an elaborate monument to Lord Willoughby de Broke. A fine gabled sculptured cross is in the churchyard. Many of the inhabitants are miners. A weekly market is held on Wednesday; and fairs on the second Thursday of March and Nov., and on the first Thursday of May and after 19 Sept. The town was made a borough in the time of Elizabeth; and sent two members to parliament, till disfranchised by the act of 1832.&#151;The parish comprises 2,492 acres. Real property, &#163;6,962; of which &#163;700 are in mines. Pop., 2,202. Houses, 347. The manor belonged to successively the Champernounes, the Ferrers, the Dennises, the Brokes, and others. Kit-Hill, about 2 miles N of the town, consists of granite, is 1,067 feet high; and commands an extensive view. Stream tin and copper ore are worked. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Southill, in the diocese of Exeter.-The subdistrict contains six parishes. Acres, 28,984. Pop., 8,899. Houses, 1,595. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Callington</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653981</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Callington/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10084258</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>CALLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186468</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CALLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10192160</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CALLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542601</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CALLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758182</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>CALLINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
