<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5686</id>
<name>LANDRAKE</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.4212154867102</lat>
<lon>-4.28921768237265</lon>
<gazetteerText>LANDRAKE, a village and a parish in St. Germans district, Cornwall. The village stands on the river Lynher, 3&#189; miles NE of St. Germans r. station; and has a post-office under St. Germans, and fairs on the first Wednesday of Feb., St. Peter&apos;s day, 29 June, and the first Wednesday of Sept. The parish is a united one, and bears the name of Landrake-with-St. Erney. Acres, 3,745,&#151;of which 205 are water. Real property, &#163;5,106. Pop. of Landrake proper, 714; of St. Erney, 79. Houses, 164 and 13. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to the Earl of Mount Edgecumbe. The living is a double vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;300. * Patron, the Earl of Mount Edgecumbe. The church is ancient but good; has a lofty turretted tower; and contains a monument to the Courtney family. There is a chapel of ease at St. Erney, an ancient building with low square tower. There are also chapels for Wesleyan and Primitive Methodists, an endowed school with &#163;80 a-year, and five alms-houses for women. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Landrake/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644962</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StErney/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Landrake</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10121504</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LANDRAKE WITH ST ERNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10203545</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LANDRAKE WITH ST ERNEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
