<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3390</id>
<name>ROCHE</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.4107891965807</lat>
<lon>-4.83271196143677</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROCHE, a village and a parish in St. Austell district, Cornwall. The village stands 2 miles N N W of Hens-barrow Beacon, and 5 N N W of St. Austell r. station; was known, at Domesday, as Treroache; and has a post-office under St. Austell; and fairs on 24 May, 18 July, and 10 Oct. The parish comprises 6, 440 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 143; of which &#163;1, 189 are in quarries, and &#163;60 in mines. Pop., 1,882. Houses, 379. The property is divided among a few. The manor was ancientlyheld by the De Rapes. Roche Rocks, &#189; a mile S of the village, rise to an altitude of 680 feet above sea-level; consist of quartz and friable schorl; terminate in greatmasses, piled confusedly together; and enclose, on thesummit, remains of an ancient hermitage chapel, in decorated English architecture. St. Roche&apos;s well is in thevicinity of the Rocks; and is superstitiously visited, by some of the peasantry, as &quot;a wishing well.&quot; Hensbarrow Beacon is on the S boundary, and rises to an altitude of 1,034 feet. Stream tin and porcelain clay are worked; and the latter is sent, by way of Liverpool, to Staffordshire. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;413.* Patrons, the Trustees of the late J. Thornton, Esq., and J. Rashleigh, Esq. The church was re-built in 1822. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Bible Christians, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roche,_Cornwall</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Roche/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639270</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10049039</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROCHE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10100756</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ROCHE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
