<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>733</id>
<name>CAMBORNE</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.2131115709721</lat>
<lon>-5.30999866965347</lon>
<gazetteerText>CAMBORNE, a town, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Redruth district, Cornwall. The town stands adjacent to the West Cornwall railway, in the centre of a rich mining tract, 14&#188; miles WSW of Truro. It is a thriving place, a scene of considerable traffic, and a seat of petty sessions; and has a head post office,&#8225; a r. station with telegraph, a banking office, a hotel, a market house of 1866, a church, four dissenting chapels, and charities &#163;70. The church is perpendicular English, in granite, large, but very low; was restored in 1862; contains a carved wooden pulpit, a new granite font, and monuments of the family of Pendarves; and has, on the outside, an ancient inscribed stone, placed in its present position by the late Lord de Dunstanville, and believed to have been originally an altar cover. A weekly market is held on Saturday; and fairs on 7 March, Whit-Tuesday, 29 June, and 11 Nov. Pop., 7,208. Houses, 1,415.&#151;The parish includes also the villages of Tucking-mill, Penponds, Berippa, Trewithan, and others. Acres, 6,744. Real property, &#163;39,102; of which &#163;26,315 are in mines. Pop., 14,056. Houses, 2,737. Pendarves, about a mile S of the town, the seat of the late E. W. W. Pendarves, Esq., is a modern granite edifice; contains some good pictures and a rich mineral cabinet; and stands in a fine park, formed entirely out of a moor. Tehidy, the seat of J. F. Basset, Esq., has a good collection of pictures, and stands in a park of upwards of 700 acres. Carnbrea, a rocky eminence 740 feet high, is regarded by Borlase as having been the chief seat of the Druids in the west of England; and Carwinnen, a wild moorish hill confronting Pendarves, has at its foot a cromlech, called the Pendarves Quoit. Extensive mines are worked, and employ most of the inhabitants. Dolcoath mine, about 3 miles W of Carnbrea, has been sunk to the depth of 1,080 feet, and extends under ground fully a mile. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;600.* Patron, J. F. Basset, Esq. The vicarages of Tucking-mill, Penponds, and Treslothan are separate charges. A modern chapel, in the Norman style, is at Tucking-mill; and a handsome one, built in 1842, is on an eminence in Pendarves park. An ancient chapel stood on the latter&apos;s site; another stood at Trewin, adjacent to a medicinal well; and four or five more stood in other places. The subdistrict is conterminate with the parish. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Camborne</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Camborne/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653945</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10002163</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CAMBORNE REDRUTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10013057</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CAMBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10105924</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>CAMBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135898</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CAMBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10207770</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CAMBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10220026</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>CAMBORNE REDRUTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542534</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CAMBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12737300</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>CORNWALL NORTH WESTERN OR CAMBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12737324</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>CORNWALL CAMBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12829024</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CAMBORNE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>54</id>
   <name>HELSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>734</id>
   <name>HAYLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2210</id>
   <name>CROWAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2224</id>
   <name>ST ERTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3838</id>
   <name>BREAGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3851</id>
   <name>GERMOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3855</id>
   <name>GWITHIAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5688</id>
   <name>WENDRON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5881</id>
   <name>SITHNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6036</id>
   <name>GWINEAR</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
