<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2209</id>
<name>CREED</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.3001675260413</lat>
<lon>-4.87807608657664</lon>
<gazetteerText>CREED, a parish in St. Austell district, Cornwall; on the river Fal, near Grampound Road r. station, 6&#189; miles SW by W of St. Austell. It contains the greater part of Grampound township, which has a head post office. Acres, 2, 809. Real property, with the rest of Grampound, &#163;4, 005. Pop., 743. Houses, 153. The property is subdivided. There a . e traces of ancient camps. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;351.* Patron,H. T. Hawkins, Esq. The church is not good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creed,_Cornwall</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Creed/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652029</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10048461</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CREED</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5100</id>
<name>GRAMPOUND</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.2995206096262</lat>
<lon>-4.9020024356186</lon>
<gazetteerText>GRAMPOUND, a decayed ancient town, a township, and a sub-district in Cornwall. The town stands on the river Fal, 1&#189; mile SSE of Grampound Road r. station, and 2&#189; NNE of Tregony; is supposed to have been the Voliba of Ptolemy; took the name of Grampound, originally Grandpont, signifying &quot;great bridge, &quot; from a bridge built at it over the Fal; acquired the right of a market from John of Eltham, Earl of Cornwall, brother of Edward III.; was made a borough, after the Earl&apos;s death, by Edward III.; sent two members to parliament from the time of Edward VI. till 1824, when it was disfranchised for corrupt practices; had, for one of its parliamentary representatives, in 1620, John Hampden; consists now chiefly of one street on a declivity, with decayed and mean appearance; and has a granite cross, a town-hall, and a head post office, &#8225; designated Grampound, Cornwall, an Independent chapel, a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and fairs on 18 Jan., the Tuesday after 25 March, 1 June, and the Tuesday after 29 Sept. Six ancient camps are in its neighbourhood, on the Fal; one of them, 1 mile S, on Golden farm; another, &#189; mile NE, on the road to St. Austell; another, 1 mile W, on the road to Truro; another, 1 mile N, close to the Fal; another, a little further N, called Resugga Castle; and another, 1 mile W of Resugga, on Barrow Down. -The township includes the town, and is partly in Probus parish, but chiefly in Creed. Real property, &#163;939. Pop., 573. Houses, 115. Pop. of the Creed portion, 477. Houses, 96. -The sub-district contains also the parishes of St. Stephen-in-Brannel, St. Mewan, and the rest of Creed. Acres, 14, 443. Pop., 5, 111. Houses, 972. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grampound</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648227</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10024511</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>GRAMPOUND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10104762</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GRAMPOUND WITH CREED</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10179294</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>GRAMPOUND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542807</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>GRAMPOUND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758595</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>GRAMPOUND</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
