<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1623</id>
<name>GORRAN</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.248957906787</lat>
<lon>-4.81525035966307</lon>
<gazetteerText>GORRAN, two villages and a parish in St. Austell district, Cornwall. The villages stand 2 miles N of Dodman point, 2 S of Mevagissey, and 6&#189; S of St. Austell r. station; and have a post office under St. Austell. One of them is on the coast, at the entrance of Mevagissey bay; bears the name of Gorran Haven, or Port-east; is a coast-guard station; has a very old pier, said to have been constructed by some of the Bodrugan family; is supposed to have been anciently a place of some consequence; and has still some trade in importing coals and in pilchard fishing. The parish includes also the hamlets of Treninick, Trevear, Menegwins, and Trevarrick. Acres, 4, 725. Real property, &#163;5, 519. Pop. in 1851, 1, 188; in 1861, 1, 054. Houses, 234. The decrease of pop. was caused partly by the closing of a large mine, partly by the failure of the fisheries. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged to the Bodrugans; had a magnificent mansion, called Bodrugan Castle, long ago destroyed; and passed to Lord Mount-Edgecumbe. Sir Henry Bodrugan was attainted for treason, at the accession of Henry VII.; and, being in danger of capture, he fled to a vessel by a tremendous leap over a cliff, at a spot which is still called Bodrugan&apos;s Leap. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;258.* Patron, the Bishop of Exeter. The church stands on an eminence; has a pinnacled tower of 1606; and was reported, in 1859, as not good. Chapels anciently stood at Gorran Haven, Bodrugan, and Galowres. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Gorran/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10013586</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GORRAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10048679</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GORRAN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
