<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3837</id>
<name>BOCONNOC</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.4114095128437</lat>
<lon>-4.59595766604422</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOCONNOC, a parish in Liskeard district, Cornwall; on affluents of the river Lerrin, 3 miles SW of Doublebois r. station, and 4 NE of Lostwithiel. Post Town, Lostwithiel. Acres, 2,003. Real property, &#163;1,606. Pop., 323. Houses, 57. The manor belonged to the Courtenays, the Carmenowes, and the Mohuns; was purchased by Governor Pitt, the grandfather of the great Earl of Chatham; and is now the property of Lady Grenville. The old mansion on it was the headquarters of Prince Maurice, and for a short time the residence of Charles I.,-who narrowly escaped being shot by an assassin on the grounds. The present mansion was built by Governor Pitt, and improved by Lord Camelford; was the birthplace of the Earl of Chatham; is now the residence of the Hon. G. M. Fortescue; and contains a bust of Lord Chatham, some fine paintings by Kneller, Lely, and Reynolds, and two ebony chairs, made out of Queen Elizabeth&apos;s cradle. The grounds are the finest in Cornwall; and contain an obelisk, 123 feet high, to the memory of Sir Richard Lyttleton. Lead mines were formerly worked, but were not productive. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Broadoak, in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;378.* Patron, Lady Grenville. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Boconnoc/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7294417</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10012946</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOCONNOC</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10120512</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BOCONNOC</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
