<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3414</id>
<name>STRATTON</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.8242588003402</lat>
<lon>-4.52112842850366</lon>
<gazetteerText>STRATTON, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, a district, and a hundred, in Cornwall. The town stands among hills, near the Bude canaland the Bude railway, 2 miles E of the coast, and 16 NNW of Launceston; occupies the site of the Roman Musidunum; was known, at Domesday, as Stratone; belonged then to the Earl of Mortaigne; adjoins Stamford Hill, where a battle was fought, in 1643, between the royalists and the parliamentarians; is a seat of petty-sessions, and a polling place; and has a post-office,&#8225; designated Stratton, Cornwall, a banking office, a good inn, an ancient church, a Wesleyan chapel, an endowed school with &#163;18 a year, a workhouse, charities &#163;171, a weekly market on Tuesday, and fairs on 19 May, 8 Nov., and 11 Dec.&#151;The parish includes Bude chapelry, extends to the coast, and comprises 2,617 acres of land and 220 of water. Real property, &#163;5,449. Pop., 1,755. Houses, 375. Binhamy or Bimomy castle belonged to the Blanchminsters; passed to the Arundells and the Cartarets; and is now represented by a quadrangular moat in a farm-orchard-The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;201.* Patron, the Prince of Wales. The p. curacy of Bude is a separate benefice.&#151;The sub-district contains 4 parishes. Acres, 13,683. Pop., 3,392. Houses, 704.&#151;The district includes also Kilkhampton and Week-St. Mary sub-districts, and comprises 54,406 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;3,451. Pop. in 1851, 8,580; in 1861, 8,028. Houses, 1,645. Marriages in 1863, 60; births, 254,-of which 16 were illegitimate; deaths, 179,-of which 43 were at ages under 5 years, and 6 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 589; births, 2,449; deaths, 1,624. The places of worship, in 1851, were 12 of the Church of England, with 4,446 sittings; 13 of Wesleyans, with 1,312 s.; 11 of Bible Christians, with 1,041 s.; and 6 of the Wesleyan Association, with 1,006 s. The schools were 11 public day-schools, with 659 scholars; 17 private day-schools, with 257 s.; and 31 Sunday schools, with 1,345 s.-The hundred is mainly identical with the district. Acres, 53,491. Pop. in 1851, 8,210; in 1861, 7,787. Houses, 1,576. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Stratton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Stratton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stratton,_Cornwall</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636681</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10055659</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10101645</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10122405</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135930</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10140882</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10201421</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542674</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580833</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3874</id>
   <name>POUGHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>1001</id>
<name>BUDE</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.8288304063499</lat>
<lon>-4.5434546478644</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUDE, or Budehaven, a village and a chapelry in Stratton parish, Cornwall. The village stands on a small bay of Bristol Channel, at the mouth of the Bude canal, 1&#189; mile W of Stratton. It has a post office,&#8225; of the name of Bude, North Devon, and a hotel; is frented as a bathing place; and carries on a great trade in the deportation of shell sand as manure. A fair is held at it on 22 Sept. The tract around it includes drifted sand hills, a grand coast, brilliant view points, and the house of Mr. Gurney, the inventor of the Bude light. The chapelry includes the village; and was constituted in 1836. Pop., 766. Houses, 163. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;120.* Patron, Sir T. D. Acland, Bart. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654380</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10082869</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BUDE STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10120585</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BUDE HAVEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10193928</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BUDE STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>738</id>
   <name>HOLSWORTHY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1773</id>
   <name>CLOVELLY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2219</id>
   <name>MORWENSTOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2603</id>
   <name>LAUNCELLS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2765</id>
   <name>WOOLFARDISWORTHY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3414</id>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3858</id>
   <name>KILKHAMPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3866</id>
   <name>MARHAMCHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4851</id>
   <name>HARTLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5825</id>
   <name>BRADWORTHY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
