<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1645</id>
<name>TINTAGEL</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.6517253454688</lat>
<lon>-4.73362883448827</lon>
<gazetteerText>TINTAGEL, a parish in Camelford district, Cornwall; on the coast, 5 miles NW of Camelford, and 17 N of Bodmin-Road r. station. It contains the villages of Bossiney, Tregatta, and Trevena; the last of which has a post-office under Camelford. Acres, 4,350; of which 70 are water. Real property, &#163;4,013; of which &#163;156 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 1,084; in 1861, 900. Houses, 204. The manor belongs to the Duchy of Cornwall. T. Castle stood on a cliff about 300 feet high; is alleged to have been the birthplace and the residence of King Arthur; was known, at Domesday, as Dunchine, signifying &quot;Chain Castle;&quot; became, soon after the Norman conquest, a residence of the Earls of Cornwall; gave entertainment, in 1245, to David, Prince of Wales; passed afterwards to the Crown; was used occasionally as a prison till the time of Elizabeth; went then into neglect on account of the great cost which had been incurred in keeping it in repair; and is now represented by dark and sombre ruins. Legends respecting King Arthur abound in connexion with the castle; and some of them are graphically embodied in the poetry of Warton. Slate rocks around the castle&apos;s site, have been weathered into curious and grotesque forms, variously columnar and cavernous; and some of the excavated ones are whimsically called &quot;King Arthur&apos;s cups and saucers&quot; The quarrying of slate was largely carried on, but has greatly diminished. Rock crystals, moonstone, and other interesting minerals, have been plentifully found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;268.* Patrons, the Dean and Canons of Windsor. The church is very old; includes remains of Saxon architecture, and considerable portions of Norman; belonged once to Fontevrault abbey in Normandy; was given, by Edward IV., to the Dean and Canons of Windsor; and was recently restored. There are three dissenting chapels and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tintagel</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Tintagel/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/8299848</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10014475</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TINTAGEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10179828</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TINTAGEL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
