<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2900</id>
<name>CALSTOCK</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.5137059276755</lat>
<lon>-4.23704996390697</lon>
<gazetteerText>CALSTOCK, a village and a parish in Liskeard district, Cornwall. The village stands on the river Tamar, near the Tavistock canal, 5&#189; miles WNW of Horrabridge r. station, and 6 SW of Tavistock; is a sub-port to Plymouth; and has a post office&#8225; under Tavistock, and an inn. The parish comprises 6,133 acres. Real property, &#163;14,233; of which &#163;4,173 are in mines, &#163;30 in quarries, and &#163;50 in fisheries. Pop., 7,090. Houses, 1,377. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the duchy of Cornwall; Calstock House is an old mansion, the seat of the Earl of Mount-Edgcumbe; and Harewood House is the seat of Sir W. Trelawny, Bart. Porphyritic elvan, called Roborough stone, is quarried; granite abounds; and tin, copper, manganese, and lead ores have been mined. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;510.* Patron, the Prince of Wales. The church is a granite structure, with a lofty pinnacled tower; and contains the vault of the Edgcumbes, and monuments to Pearse Edgcumbe and the Countess of Sandwich There is a Baptist chapel. Blackburn, Archbishop of York, was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calstock</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Calstock/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653971</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10013033</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CALSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10082699</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CALSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10153414</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>CALSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10537563</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CALSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>973</id>
   <name>CALLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2223</id>
   <name>ST DOMINICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2601</id>
   <name>SOUTH HILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2610</id>
   <name>ST MELLION</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4326</id>
   <name>SYDENHAM DAMEREL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5113</id>
   <name>STOKE CLIMSLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5703</id>
   <name>BERE FERRERS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
