<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1644</id>
<name>SANCREED</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1156613282624</lat>
<lon>-5.61507306409422</lon>
<gazetteerText>SANCREED, or Sancreet, a village and a parish in Penzance district, Cornwall. The village stands on highground, under a wild upland called Sancreed Beacon, 4 miles S W by W of Penzance r. station. The parish contains also the village of Brahane; and its post town is Penzance. Acres, 4, 471. Real property, &#163;4, 717. Pop.in 1851, 1, 394; in 1861, 1, 233. Houses, 237. The decrease of pop. was caused by suspension of the works ofseveral tin mines. The property is much subdivided. Remains of an ancient castle, called Caerbran, are near Brahane; an ancient monument, consisting of two concentric walls, the outer one 55 feet in diameter, is at Bodinnar; and Druidical stones are at Drift. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;450.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Exeter. The church is good, and contains several monuments. A very fineold cross is in the churchyard; two smaller crosses are at the gate and on the outside; and a well, formerly held insuperstitions repute, is adjacent. Two ancient chapelswere in different parts, and have left some traces. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Bible Christians, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Sancreed/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sancreed</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638613</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10014440</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SANCREED</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10122399</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SANCREED</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
