<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3105</id>
<name>ANTONY</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.3713183001478</lat>
<lon>-4.24083244890681</lon>
<gazetteerText>ANTONY, a parish and a subdistrict, in the district of St. Germans, Cornwall. The parish is called also Anthony-in-East and St. Jacob Anthony; lies on Lynher creek and the Hamoaze, 4 miles S of Saltash r. station, and 4 SE of St. Germans; and has a post office, of the name of Antony, under Devonport. Acres, 3,222 of land, and 1,260 of water. Real property, &#163;14,508. Pop., 3,887. Houses, 562. The manor of East Antony be longed formerly to the Dawneys, and belongs now to the Carews. Antony House, on that manor, is a large square edifice of Pentnan stone, built in 1721 by Gibbs. and contains an interesting collection of old pictures. West Antony village, or St. Jacob, is a pleasant place; and, owing to its proximity to Devonport and Plymouth, is a favourite residence of officers connected with the dock yards and the navy at these towns. Antony Passage, at East Antony, has a ferry to Trematon. Beggars Island, below the passage, was named after Bamfyeld Moore Carew, commonly called King of the Beggars. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;262* Patron, W. H. P. Carew. The church was built in 1420, but has a tower of the previous century; and it contains monuments of Lady Marjory Arundel, Richard Carew, who wrote the &quot;Survey of Cornwall,&quot; and Captain Graves, R. N., who figured in the time of George II. The curacy of Merrifield is united with the vicarage; and the p. curacy of Torpoint is a separate incumbency. There is a Wesleyan chapel. The workhouse of St. Germans is in this parish. Charities, &#163;12. The subdistrict of Antony comprises four parishes. Acres, 9,740. Pop., 7,878. Houses, 1,336. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657258</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antony,_Cornwall</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10080794</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ANTONY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10090647</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ANTONY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542832</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ANTONY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
