<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2218</id>
<name>LINKINHORNE</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.5376206249092</lat>
<lon>-4.41092212134441</lon>
<gazetteerText>LINKINHORNE, a parish in Liskeard district, Cornwall; between the rivers Inny and Lynher, 4 miles NW by N of Callington, and 8 S by W of Launceston r. station. Post town, Callington, Cornwall. Acres, 7,894. Real property, &#163;12,734; of which &#163;5,637 are in mines, and &#163;100 in quarries. Pop. in 1851,2,005; in 1861,2,551. Houses, 464. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of mining operations. The property is munch subdivided. The manor belonged formerly to Launceston priory, and belongs now to the duchy of Cornwall. The surface includes Carraton Downs, 1,208 feet high, where Charles I. was joined, in 1644, by Prince Manrice; includes also Sharp Tor, Cheesewring, the Hurlers, and other vantage-grounds commanding fine views. Tin and copper are mined. A cattle fair is held at Rilla Mill on 3 Dec. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Valne, &#163;312.* Patron, the Rev.T. Kempe. The church is ancient but good; was rebuilt by the Trecarells of Trefey; has a lofty tower; and contains seVeral monuments. There are Wesleyan chapels, an endowed school with &#163;21 a year, and charities &#163;8. Daniel Gum, whose mathematical acquirements and singular mode of living procured him the appellation of the &quot;Mountain Philosopher, &apos;&apos;resided here amongst the rocks, one of which he had excavated for his own residence. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Linkinhorne/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644448</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10013860</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LINKINHORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10048825</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LINKINHORNE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
