<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>811</id>
<name>HARRINGTON</name>
<container>CUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.5967579499468</lat>
<lon>-3.56083938466437</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARRINGTON, a small seaport town, a parish, and a sub-district in Whitehaven district, Cumberland. The town stands on Bellaport harbour, and on the Whitehaven Junction railway, 2&#190; miles S of Workington; is of modern origin, and a sub-port to Whitehaven; carries on a considerable trade, chiefly as a focus of export for extensive neighbouring mines; has a ship-building yard and a ropery, and formerly had chemical works; and has a station on the railway, and a post-office&#8225; under Carlisle. The harbour has a pier and a fixed light; the latter 44 feet high, visible at the distance of 11 miles, and put up in 1797. The parish comprises 2,338 acres of land, and 452 of water. Real property, &#163;5,497; of which &#163;86 are in ironworks. Pop. in 1851,2,169; in 1861,1,788. Houses, 426. The decrease of pop. was occasioned by the discontinuance of the chemical works, and by diminution of coal-working. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Carlisle. Value, &#163;250.* Patron, E. S. Curwen, Esq. The church is a neat edifice, with a tower; and there are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists.&#151;The sub-district contains five parishes, three townships of another parish, and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 51,089. Pop., 6. 765. Houses, 1,384. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CUL/Harrington/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647434</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10029296</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HARRINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10118840</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HARRINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10144050</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HARRINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10201767</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARRINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544531</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HARRINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12832965</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HARRINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
