<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4131</id>
<name>NORTON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3318813451799</lat>
<lon>-1.4624271869902</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in the district of Ecclesall-Bierlow and county of Derby. The village stands 11/3 mile S E of the river Sheaf, at the boundary with Yorkshire, 2&#189; N of Dronfield, and 4 S by E of Sheffield r. station; is a pleasant place; has a post-office under Sheffield and a good inn; and is a seat ofpetty sessions, and the monthly meeting-place of a local farmers&apos; club. The parish contains also the villages of Norton-Lees, Greenhill, Backmoor, Maugerhay, Hems-worth, and Woodseats. Acres, 4, 330. Real property, &#163;9, 341; of which &#163;20 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 1,856; in 1861, 2, 318. Houses, 479. The increase of pop. arose chiefly from the operations of Freehold Land and Building Societies. The property is much sub-divided. The manor, with Norton Hall, belongs to Cammell, Esq. Norton House, the Oaks, Grange House, and Mearsbrook House, are chief residences. The manufacture of scythes, sickles, saw-files, and nails is carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, H. Wilson, Esq. The church is large and handsome; has a tower; and contains a tablet to Sir Francis Chantrey, and several other monuments. There are three Wesleyan chapels, an endowed school with &#163;65 a year, a national school, and considerable charities. Sir Francis Chantrey, Bishop Geoffry Blythe, and Bishop John Blythe were natives.&#151;The sub-district contains also the extra-parochial tract of Beauchief-Abbey. Acres, 5, 110. Pop., 440. Houses, 503. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Norton/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10003076</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>NORTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10072372</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10131479</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NORTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10457488</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>NORTON WITHIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10555553</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NORTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>649</id>
   <name>DRONFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2697</id>
   <name>DORE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2999</id>
   <name>HOLMESFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4150</id>
   <name>TOTLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4152</id>
   <name>UNSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4802</id>
   <name>COAL ASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5088</id>
   <name>BEAUCHIEF</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>24505</id>
<name>NORTON WOODSEATS</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3424522376934</lat>
<lon>-1.46974272811686</lon>
<gazetteerText>Norton Woodseats, eccl. dist., Norton par., Derbyshire, near N. border of co., 4 miles S. of Sheffield, pop. 2456. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10021947</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTON WOODSEATS ST CHAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10165234</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTON WOODSEATS</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>26408</id>
<name>NORTON LEES</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3505414352805</lat>
<lon>-1.46964249287705</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTON-LEES, a village in Norton parish, Derby; near the boundary with Yorkshire, 5 miles S S E of Sheffield. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norton_Lees</link>
</links>
</place>
</results>
