<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2945</id>
<name>ECKINGTON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3155413752997</lat>
<lon>-1.37899483431246</lon>
<gazetteerText>ECKINGTON, a township, a parish, and a sub-district in Chesterfield district, Derby. The township lies on the river Rother, adjacent to the Midland railway and the Chesterfield canal, 6 miles NNE of Chesterfield; and has a station on the railway, and a post office&#8225; under Chesterfield. The parish contains also the townships of Troway, Renishaw, Ridgeway, and Mosborough. Acres, 6, 610. Real property, &#163;20, 601; of which &#163;4, 631 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 4, 958; in 1861, 6, 064. Houses, 1, 189. The property is much subdivided. The working of coal has recently been much extended; and the manufacture of pottery and hardware is largely carried on. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Valne, &#163;774.* Patron, the Crown. The church is good. The vicarage of Ridgeway is a separate benefice. There are four Methodist chapels, a R. Catholic church and college, an endowed free school, and some charities.&#151;The sub-district includes also Killamarsh parish and Staveley township. Acres, 14, 938. Pop., 13, 948. Houses, 2, 620. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Eckington/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eckington,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650264</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018432</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ECKINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10083590</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ECKINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544828</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ECKINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835279</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ECKINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
