<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4834</id>
<name>MORTON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1370505067791</lat>
<lon>-1.41147388739235</lon>
<gazetteerText>MORTON, a township and a parish in Chesterfield district, Derby. The township lies &#189; a mile WNW of Doehill r. station, 1 SE of Stretton r. station, and 2&#190; N of Alfreton. Real property, &#163;1,397. Pop. in 1851, 257; in 1861,594. Houses, 100. The increase of pop. arose from the temporary presence of labourers on railway works. The parish contains also the township of Brackenfield; and its Post town is Alfreton. Acres, 2,800. Real property, &#163;4,895; of which &#163;15 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851,656; in 1861,911. Houses, 177. The property is divided among a few. Ogston Hall is the seat of G. Turbutt, Esq. Upwards of 1,000 acres were recently leased by a company for the working of coal and other minerals. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Valne, &#163;460.* Patron, alternately St. John&apos;s College, Cambridge, and G. Turbutt, Esq. The church, excepting the tower, was rebuilt in 1850; is in the decorated English style; consists of nave, N aisle, and chancel, with pinnacled tower; and contains monument&apos;s to the Turbutts. The p. cnracy of Brackenfield is a separate benefice. A Primitive Methodist chapel and a national school are in Brackenfield; and a recently erected school is in Morton. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morton,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Morton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642165</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10070650</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MORTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10165155</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MORTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
