<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2357</id>
<name>DUFFIELD</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0084987321544</lat>
<lon>-1.49765741492048</lon>
<gazetteerText>DUFFIELD, a village, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Belper district, Derbyshire. The village stands on the river Derwent, adjacent to the North Midland railway, 4&#188; miles N of Derby; was known, at Domesday, as Dunelle; and has a station on the railway, a post office&#8225; under Derby, and fairs on the Thursday after 1 Jan. and 1 March. The township includes the village; extends into the country; and carries on cotton spinning, lace-making, stocking-making, glove-making, and mining. Real property, &#163;11, 872. Pop., 2, 639. Houses, 571. The parish contains also the townships of Hazlewood, Turnditch, Windley, and Shottle and Postern, and the chapelries of Holbrook and Belper. Acres, 17, 390. Real property, &#163;43, 292; of which &#163;145 are in quarries. Pop., 16, 776. Houses, 3, 518. The property is much subdivided. Duffield Hall, Duffield House, and Duffield Bank are chief residences. A castle was built, about 1096, by Henry de Ferrars, on a spot now called Castle-orchard, at the north-west end of the village; and demolished, in 1325 by Henry II. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;185.* Patron, the Bishop of Lichfield. The church is good. The chapelries of Belper, Bridge-Hill, Hazlewood, Heage, Holbrook, Milford, and Turnditch are separate benefices. There are several dissenting chapels, a free school with &#163;124 from endowment, and other charities with &#163;253. -The sub-district contains four townships of Duffield parish, parts of another parish, and five entire parishes. Acres, 23, 975. Pop., 6, 466. Houses, 1, 349. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duffield</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Duffield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650836</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10051800</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>DUFFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127373</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DUFFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544658</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DUFFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10572642</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DUFFIELD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>132</id>
   <name>BELPER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1821</id>
   <name>RAVENSDALE PARK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2387</id>
   <name>TURNDITCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2700</id>
   <name>LITTLE EATON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3427</id>
   <name>HAZLEWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4071</id>
   <name>KEDLESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4072</id>
   <name>KILBURN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4134</id>
   <name>QUARNDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4139</id>
   <name>SHOTTLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5253</id>
   <name>WESTON UNDERWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
