<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13697</id>
<name>MAIDEN NEWTON</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.7678085189183</lat>
<lon>-2.56189573718622</lon>
<gazetteerText>MAIDEN-NEWTON, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Dorchester district, Dorset. The village stands on the river Frome, and on the Dorchester and Yeovilrailway, at the junction of the branch to Bridport, 7&#190; miles NW of Dorchester; was once a markettown; and has a station with telegraph on the railway, a post office&#8225; under Dorchester, and fairs on 9 March and 4 May. The parish contains also the hamlets of Cruxton and Notton. Acres, 2,853. Real property, &#163;3,912. Pop., 84e. Houses, 167. The property is mostly in one estate. Iron-founding and brewing are carried on. Some Roman tesselated pavement was found on the S border, near the end of last century. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Salisbury. Valne, &#163;600.* Patrons, the Earl of Ilchester and the Countess of Egremont. The church is Norman; consists of nave, S aisle, and transept, with a central embattled tower; and is in good condition. There are an Independent chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;5.&#151;The sub-district contains also seventeen other parishes. Acres, 35,234. Pop., 5,603. Houses, (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/MaidenNewton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maiden_Newton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643185</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10454013</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MAIDEN NEWTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10454025</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MAIDEN NEWTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10454037</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MAIDEN NEWTON WITH FROME VAUCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10538695</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MAIDEN NEWTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13637</id>
   <name>FROME VAUCHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14044</id>
   <name>WYNFORD EAGLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17247</id>
   <name>WEST DORSET</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
