<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>692</id>
<name>SWANAGE</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.6117919130519</lat>
<lon>-1.96729350398777</lon>
<gazetteerText>SWANAGE, or Swanwich, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Wareham district, Dorset. The village stands on S. bay, 9 miles SE of Wareham r. station; was known, at Domesday, as Swanawic or Sonwic; is a sub-port to Poole, and a pleasant watering-place; consists chiefly of one street, nearly a mile long; commands a fine view of the Hants coast and the Isle of Wight; enjoys very fine environs, with many interesting natural features; and has a post-office&#8225; under Wareham, a banking office, two chief inns, an ancient cruciform church restored in 1860, two dissenting chapels, and a coastguard station. S. bay is proximately semi-circular, on a chord of 1&#190; mile; has a depth of from 5 to 8 fathoms; and affords good shelter in westerly winds. The parish includes Herston and Ulwell hamlets; and comprises 2,953 acres of land, and 240 of water. Real property, &#163;4,819. Pop., 2,004. Houses, 445. The property is subdivided. Building stone is quarried. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;555.* Patron, J. H. Calcraft, Esq.&#151;The sub-district contains four parishes. Acres, 15,872. Pop., 3,682. Houses, 798. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/Swanage/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swanage</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636445</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10062366</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SWANAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135151</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SWANAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10460451</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SWANAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10460463</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWANAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10538464</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWANAGE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13610</id>
   <name>CHURCH KNOWLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13619</id>
   <name>CORFE CASTLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13664</id>
   <name>EAST HOLME</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13677</id>
   <name>KIMMERIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13684</id>
   <name>LANGTON MATRAVERS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13692</id>
   <name>EAST LULWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13895</id>
   <name>STEEPLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13944</id>
   <name>STUDLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13993</id>
   <name>TYNEHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14037</id>
   <name>WORTH MATRAVERS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
