<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20279</id>
<name>FORDINGTON</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.7127775493404</lat>
<lon>-2.42637566782626</lon>
<gazetteerText>FORDINGTON, a suburban village, a parish, and a liberty, in Dorset. The village is suburban to Dorchester; stands on Icknield street and the river Frome, adjacent to branches of the Southwestern railway; partakes in the trade and interests of Dorchester; and was itself, at one time, a market-town. The parish is in Dorchester district, and partly within Dorchester borough; and contains Dorchester workhouse. Post town, Dorchester. Acres, 2, 749. Real property, &#163;9, 200. Pop., 3, 258. Houses, 538. Pop. of the part within Dorchester borough, 3, 172. Houses, 533. - The manor was held, in the time of Edward III., by the queen dowager, Isabella; passed to the Black Prince, as Duke of Cornwall; and, with nearly all the land, belongs now to the Prince of Wales. Fordington Field here comprises 1, 657 acres; continues to be unenclosed; and affords pasturage, on its stubbles, to large flocks of sheep. A Roman camp, and a well preserved amphitheatre, are in the parish; and a road in it has, from time immemorial, been called Icen-lane; and seems to have got that name from its connexion with Icknield street or the Via Iceniana. A raised causeway, 1, 980 feet long., in improvement of a bad road into the village, was formed, in 1747, by Mrs. Pitt, of Kingston House, at a cost of &#163;1, 500; and, at the same time a three-arched bridge was constructed over a branch of the Frome. A Roman bath, some coins, and a great number of skeletons were found at the forming of the causeway. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;325.* Patron, the Prebendary of Fordington. The church is noticed in our article on Dorchester. The The vicarage of West Fordington is a separate benefice. -The liberty is partly in Dorchester division, and partly in Cerne division. Acres, 3, 041. Pop., 405. Houses, 53. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/Fordington/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10194179</id>
   <status>Liberty</status>
   <name>FORDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10452351</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FORDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10452363</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FORDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10452375</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST FORDINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25799</id>
<name>WEST FORDINGTON</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.7163169083105</lat>
<lon>-2.441990847882</lon>
<gazetteerText>FORDINGTON (West), a chapelry in Fordington parish, Dorchester district, Dorset; in the western vicinity of Dorchester town and r. station. Post town, Dorchester. The chapelry was constituted in 1847. Pop., 1, 059. Houses, 113. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, not reported. Patron, the Vicar of Fordington. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
</results>
