<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13594</id>
<name>CERNE ABBAS</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.8040530339016</lat>
<lon>-2.47962037801344</lon>
<gazetteerText>CERNE-ABBAS, a small town and a parish in Dorchester district, Dorset. The town stands on the river Cerne, 4&#190; miles ESE of Evershot r. station, and 7&#189; N by W of Dorchester. It includes four or five streets; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a post office,&#8225; of the name of Cerne, under Dorchester, three inns, and a workhouse, a church, two dissenting chapels, and some remains of a Benedictine Abbey. The church is perpendicular English; and has a tower. The Abbey was founded, in 987, by Aylmer, Earl of Cornwall; plundered, in 1015, by Canute; and occupied, in 1471, by Queen Margaret, on her way to Tewkesbury. St. Augustine is said by some to have founded it; Edwald, the brother of St. Edmund the martyr, is said by others to have founded it, and to have been buried in it; and Cardinal Morton, born at Bere-Regis, was one of its monks. The remains of it are a gatehouse, bearing escutcheons, a long buttressed barn, still used as a granary, and some traces of the gardens and park. An ancient earthwork, unknown to record, is north of the churchyard. A lofty eminence, called Trendle-hill or the Giant&apos;s hill, rises adjacent to the town; has the figure of a man, 180 feet high, cut on its chalky surface; and is crowned by an ancient camp. Markets are held on Wednesdays; fairs are held on Midlent Monday, 28 April, and 2 Oct.; and some trade is carried on in inalting, brewing, and leather-dressing.&#151;The parish comprises 3,063 acres. Real property, with Upper Cerne, &#163;6,389. Pop., 1,185. Houses, 254. The property is not much divided; and the manor belongs to Lord Rivers. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;81.* Patron, Lord Rivers. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cerne_Abbas</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653423</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Cerne</link>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/CerneAbbas/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10451279</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CERNE ABBAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10451280</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CERNE ABBAS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13550</id>
   <name>BUCKLAND NEWTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13576</id>
   <name>CATTISTOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13621</id>
   <name>CORSCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13628</id>
   <name>EVERSHOT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13697</id>
   <name>MAIDEN NEWTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13793</id>
   <name>PIDDLETRENTHIDE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13807</id>
   <name>POWERSTOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13949</id>
   <name>SYDLING ST NICHOLAS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13985</id>
   <name>TOLLER PORCORUM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14045</id>
   <name>YETMINSTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
