<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13690</id>
<name>LODERS</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.7421344713699</lat>
<lon>-2.71383199100731</lon>
<gazetteerText>LODERS, a village and a parish in Bridport district, Dorset. The village stands adjacent to the Bridport railway, on a small affluent of the river Brit, 2 miles NE of Bridport; and has a post office under Bridport. The parish comprises 2,241 acres. Real property, with UpLoders, Mattravers, and Askerswell, &#163;7,127. Rated property of L. alone, &#163;4,498. Pop. in 1851,986; in 1861, 1,053. Houses, 218. The property is divided among a few. Loders Court is the seat of Sir M. H. Nepean, Bart. A priory, subordinate to Montsburgh abbey in Normandy, was founded here in the time of Henry II.; and was given, by Henry V., to Sion abbey. Building stone is quarried. A large flax and hemp mill is at West End. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;315.* Patron, alternately the Lord Chancellor and Sir M. H. Nepean, Bart. The church has a low massive W tower, and is good. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;12. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loders</link>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/Uploders/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/Loders/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643780</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10056032</id>
   <status>Liberty</status>
   <name>LODERS AND BOTHENHAMPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10453847</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LODERS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10453859</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LODERS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
