<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14000</id>
<name>WHITECHURCH CANONICORUM</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.7605801386886</lat>
<lon>-2.87392461918999</lon>
<gazetteerText>WHITCHURCH-CANONICORUM, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Dorset. The village stands 5 miles WNW of Bridport r. station; took its name from an alien monastery called Album Monasterium, a cell to St. Wandragisil abbey in Normandy; was once a market-town; and has a post-office under Bridport. The parish includes four hamlets, and comprises 6,113 acres. Rated property, &#163;4,765. Pop., 1,533. Houses, 336. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage, united with Chideock and with Stanton-St. Gabriel, in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;739.* Patron, the Bishop of S. The church is good; a chapel of ease is at Marshwood; and part of the parish is in Monckton-Wyld chapelry. There are Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, national schools, and charities &#163;22.&#151;The sub-district contains six parishes, and is in Bridport district. Acres, 15,259. Pop., 4,095. Houses, 902.- The hundred contains nine parishes and a part, and is in Bridport division. Acres, 20,734. Pop. in 1851, 5,686. Houses, 1,181. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitchurch_Canonicorum</link>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/WhitchurchCanonicorum/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634123</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10044133</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH CANONICORUM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10133774</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WHITECHURCH CANONICORUM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10461807</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH CANONICORUM WITH STANTON ST GABRIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10461819</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WHITECHURCH CANONICORUM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10538520</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH CANONICORUM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
