<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8397</id>
<name>NORTHOP</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2143433368876</lat>
<lon>-3.12043595395551</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTHOP, or North-Hope, a village, a township, and a parish, in Holywell district, Flint. The village stands near Wats dyke, under the Halkin mountains, 3&#189; miles S of Flint r. station; is a pretty place; is called Llaneurgain by the Welsh; and has a post-office designated Northop, Flintshire, and fairs on 14 March, 7 July, and 12 Oct. The township includes the village, and extends into the country. Real property, &#163;4, 382; of which &#163;50 are in mines. Pop., 753. Houses, 178. The parish contains also the townships of Caerfallwch, Golftyn, Wepre, Kelsterton, Soughton, Leadbrook-Major, and Leadbrook-Minor, and extends to the estuary of the Dee. Acres, 12, 366; of which 3, 515 are water. Real property, &#163;22, 718; of which &#163;6, 896 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 3, 567; in 1861, 3, 657. Houses, 798. The property is subdivided. Highfield Hall is the seat of J. Huntley, Esq.; and Soughton Hall, of J. S. Bankes, Esq. There are lead mines, collieries, potteries, and tile-works; and a railway connects the chief of them with the sea-port village of Connah&apos;s-Quay. The lead mines are supposed to have been worked by the Romans; and they now belong to the Grosvenor family. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;500.* Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church is later English, handsomely restored in the interior; has a tower of 5 stages, 98 feet high, commanding a fine view; and contains some carving of the 11th century, and stone effigies of Edwyn, a Welsh prince of the 11th century, Ithel Vyshan ap Bleddyn, a knight of the 14th century, and Lleuci Llwyd, a lady famous for beauty in the 15thcentury. The p. curacy of Connah&apos;s-Quay is a separate benefice. There are two Methodist chapels, an endowed grammar school with &#163;35 a year, an endowed national school with &#163;40, and charities about &#163;90. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/FLN/Northop/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Northop</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641289</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10288289</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>NORTHOP</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
