<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1146</id>
<name>OYSTERMOUTH</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.5738197510503</lat>
<lon>-4.00482533882971</lon>
<gazetteerText>OYSTERMOUTH, a parish in Swansea district, Glamorgan; in the Gower peninsula, on the W side of Swansea bay, 5 miles S S W of Swansea r. station. It contains the villages of Newton, Norton, and Mumbles, the last of which has a post-office under Swansea; and it is a sea-bathing resort. Acres, 5, 194; of which 1, 220 are water-Real property, &#163;7, 774; of which &#163;80 are in quarries. Pop.in 1851, 1, 938; in 1861, 2, 460. Houses, 519. Oyster-mouth Castle stands on an eminence overlooking the bay; surmounts a huge limestone cliff; was founded in the 11thcentury, probably by Henry de Bellamonte; has beenpartly restored by the Duke of Beanfort; is enteredthrough a gateway, formerly flanked by two towers; hasan irregular outline, approximating that of an isoscelestriangle; and includes, at the N E angle, a heavily-buttressed square tower of three stages, the upper story of which is a chapel of early decorated English date. Limestone is quarried and calcined; an oyster fishery iscarried on; and a tram railway goes to Swansea. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;85. Patron, Col. Perrot. The church is ancient; was nearly rebuilt in 1860, in the early decorated English style, at a cost of &#163;2, 100; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with tower and vestry. There are an Independent chapel, and charities &#163;6. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oystermouth</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Oystermouth/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640705</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10288666</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>OYSTERMOUTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412936</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>OYSTERMOUTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12827921</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>OYSTERMOUTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2017</id>
   <name>ILSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2215</id>
   <name>Y COCYD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3648</id>
   <name>BISHOPSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8395</id>
   <name>NICHOLASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8409</id>
   <name>OXWICH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8453</id>
   <name>PEN MAEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8461</id>
   <name>PENNARD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10755</id>
   <name>BRYNAU</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
