<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11070</id>
<name>PAINSWICK</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7843736460492</lat>
<lon>-2.18763971257783</lon>
<gazetteerText>PAINWICK, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Stroud district, Gloucester. The town stands on the declivity of Spoonbed hill, adjacent to a smallaffluent of the river Stroud, 3&#189; miles N N E of Stroud r.station, and 6 S S E of Gloucester; is regularly built of apeculiar white local stone; and has a post-office&#8225; under Stroud. A weekly market is held on Thursday; a market, chiefly for sheep, on the Tuesday after All Saintsday; and fairs, on Whit-Tuesday and 19 Sept. The parish comprises the tythings of Edge, Sheepscombe, Spoonbed, and Stroud-End. Acres, 5, 815. Real property, &#163;20, 997; of which &#163;72 are in quarries, and &#163;3, 575in the Thames and Severn canal. Pop. in 1851, 3, 464; in 1861, 3, 229. Houses, 763. The manor bore the name of Wiche at Domesday; belonged then to Rogerde Lacy; and passed to Pain Fitz-John, the Kingstons, and the Jerninghams. Court House was the scene of a court by Charles I., and is now unoccupied. Painswick House is the residence of W. H. Hyett, Esq.; Brown&apos;s Hill, of S. S. Dickinson, Esq.; Tocknells, ofCodrington, Esq.; Steinbridge House, of R. L. Townsend, Esq.; and the Grove, of W. Capel, Esq. Spoonbed hill commandsa very extensive view of the valley of the Severn; wasoccupied by the troops of Charles I., after the siege of Gloucester; and is crowned by a well-preserved double-entrenched Roman camp, where Roman coins and weaponshave been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;449.* Patron, the Rev. A. J. Biddell. The church is ancient; shows features of both pointed and columnar architecture; has a tower and spire 174 feet high; and contains monuments of the Jerninghams. The church yard is remarkably neat, and has 116 yew-trees. A cemetery was formed, in 1863, on Spoonbed hill; comprises about 4 acres; and has twomortuary chapels, in the decorated English style, with a tower and spire between them. The p. curacies of Sheepscombe and Slad are separate benefices. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Quakers, Primitive Methodists, and Roman Catholics, a nunnery, an endowed school with &#163;64 a year, three national schools, and charities &#163;66. The Independent chapel was rebuilt in 1865, and is in the pointed style of the 13th century. The Roman Catholic chapel stands at Beeches-Green, near Stroud; and is large and handsome.&#151;The sub-district contains also three other parishes. Acres, 10, 325. Pop., 4, 334. Houses, 992. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640678</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Painswick/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19044</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19046</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19048</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19047</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19041</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19043</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19049</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19042</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19045</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10199323</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>PAINSWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10386070</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PAINSWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10386081</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PAINSWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552837</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PAINSWICK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10820</id>
   <name>HARESCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11090</id>
   <name>PITCHCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17432</id>
   <name>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
