<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10544</id>
<name>BISHOPS CLEEVE</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9462786296751</lat>
<lon>-2.06100022089087</lon>
<gazetteerText>BISHOPS-CLEEVE, a township in Winchcombe district, and a parish in Winchcombe and Tewkesbury districts, Gloucester. The township lies 1&#190; mile E of Cleeve r. station, and 3 N by E of Cheltenham; and has a post office under Cheltenham. Real property, &#163;3,950. Pop., 703. Houses, 184.&#151;The parish includes also the hamlets of Gotheringtone, Woodmancote, Stoke-Orchard, and Southam and Brockhampton. Acres, 8,150. Real property, &#163;15,107. Pop., 1,970. Houses, 486. The property is much subdivided. The Cleeve hills, along the E, have a crescent-shaped ancient British camp, and the race-ground of the Cheltenham races; and exhibit brilliant scenery of cliff and wood. There are mineral springs. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol Value, &#163;2,000.* Patron, the Rev. W. L. Townsend. The church exhibits features from early Norman downward; is cruciform and large; and has a central tower, of modern construction. The parsonage was at one time the residence of the Bishops of Worcester. There are Independent and Baptist chapels and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655570</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/BishopsCleeve/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bishops_Cleeve</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10024249</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>CLEEVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10367943</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BISHOPS CLEEVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10367955</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BISHOPS CLEEVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553039</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CLEEVE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10805</id>
   <name>GOTHERINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11299</id>
   <name>SOUTHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11348</id>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11475</id>
   <name>WOODMANCOTE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11477</id>
   <name>WOOLSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
