<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11315</id>
<name>LEONARD STANLEY</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7263247731384</lat>
<lon>-2.30579443530264</lon>
<gazetteerText>LEONARD-STANLEY, or STANLEY-ST. LEONARDS, a village and a parish in Stroud district, Gloucester. The village stands 1 mile E by S of Frocester r. station, 1&#189; S by E of Stonehouse r. station, and 3&#189; SW by W of Stroud; was once a market-town; was nearly all destroyed by fire in 1686; and has a post office under Stonehouse, and a fair on 20 July. The parish contains also the hamlet of Downton, and includes the detached tract of Lorridge. Acres, 1,070. Real property, &#163;4,188; of which &#163;655 are in railways. Pop., 864. Houses, 193. The manor belonged at Domesday to Richard de Berkeley; and belongs now to Mrs. P. Jones. Townsend House is the residence of - Minchin, Esq.; and the Priory is occupied by John Townsend, Esq. A Benedictine priory, a cell to Gloucester abbey, was founded here, in 1146, by one of the Berkeleys; was given, at the dissolution, to the Kingstons; and has left some fragmentary remains. Sandford&apos;s knoll commands an extensive and beautiful view. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;220.* Patron, Mrs. P. Jones. The church is Norman and cruciform; is said to have belonged to the priory; has a low massive tower, of interesting character; and contains monuments of the Sandfords, and of the last prior Croose. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;30. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/LeonardStanley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7300611</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15877</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15879</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15881</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15882</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15884</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15880</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15878</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15883</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10391775</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LEONARD STANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10391854</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEONARD STANLEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10718</id>
   <name>FROCESTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
