<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10652</id>
<name>FAIRFORD</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7129547790836</lat>
<lon>-1.77641117635328</lon>
<gazetteerText>FAIRFORD, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district in Cirencester district, Gloucester. The town stands on the river Colne, at the foot of the Cotswolds, near the boundary with Wilts and Berks, 4&#188; miles WNW of Lech-lade, and 8&#189; E by S of Cirencester r. station; is neatly and regularly built; has a post office&#8225; under Swindon, a chief inn, cloth mills, two bridges, a church, three dissenting chapels, a lunatic asylum, a reading room and library, a charity for apprentices with &#163;69, other charities with &#163;254, and fairs on 14 May and 12 Nov.; and is a seat of petty sessions. The church was built in 1423, and following years, by the family of Tame; is a fine specimen of perpendicular English; has large windows of painted glass, inferior only to those of King&apos;s College chapel, Cambridge; and contains a table-tomb of John Tame, and brasses of other Tames. An Independent chapel, in the Gothic style, was built in 1863. The lunatic asylum was formerly a public institution, but has been converted into a private establishment. The parish comprises 3, 879 acres. Real property, &#163;8, 262; of which &#163;60 are in gas-works. Pop., 1, 654. Houses, 361. The property is not much divided. The manor belonged to Earl Bithric; was held by the Crown at Domesday; passed to the Clares, the Beauchamps, the Nevilles, the Tames, and others; and came to the Barkers. The ancient manor-house stood near the church, but was demolished by Andrew. Barker, Esq.; and the present one stands a few furlongs farther north, was built with the materials of the old, and is a spacions edifice. Roman coins and urns were found in the cuttings for its foundations; and several barrows occur on the neighbouring lands. Fairford gives the title of Viscount to the Marquis of Downshire. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;432. Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Gloucester.&#151;The sub-district contains twelve parishes, -one of them in Wilts. Acres, 26, 198. Pop., 6, 148. Houses, 1, 338. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Fairford/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fairford,_Gloucestershire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649741</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10000920</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>FAIRFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10372010</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FAIRFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10372045</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FAIRFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553143</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FAIRFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10573373</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FAIRFORD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10632</id>
   <name>EASTLEACH MARTIN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10933</id>
   <name>KEMPSFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10943</id>
   <name>LECHLADE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11306</id>
   <name>SOUTHROP</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11970</id>
   <name>MARSTON MEYSEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
