<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11055</id>
<name>OLVESTON</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5789566678633</lat>
<lon>-2.58208521819772</lon>
<gazetteerText>OLVESTON, a village, a tything, and a parish, in Thornbury district, Gloucester. The village stands 2&#190; miles E S E of the Severn, 2&#190; N N E of piling r. station, and 3&#188; S W of Thornbury; and has a post-office under Bristol. The tything includes the village, and bears the name of Olveston and Cote. Real property, &#163;6, 848. Pop. in 1851, 789. Houses, 156. The parish contains also the tything of Upper Tockington, and comprises 4, 787 acres. Real property, &#163;12, 795. Pop. in 1861, 1, 699. Houses, 337. The property is subdivided. The manor of Olveston belonged anciently to the Dennis family; and belongs now to R.Lippincott, Esq. The manor of Tockington belongs to the Rev. J. R. Charlton. Olveston-Green, Freezewood, Fern Park, New Leaze House, Oakleaze, Harts, Ridgeway, Lower Hazel, Woodhouse, and Tockington House are chief residences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;799.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Bristol. The church is partly early English; was repaired and considerably enlarged in 1840; consists of nave, transepts, aisles, and chancel, with Sporch and pinnacled tower; and contains an old brass of Sir W. Dennis. There are chapels for Quakers, Wesleyans, and United Free Methodists, a mixed national school, an infant school, and charities &#163;12. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Olveston/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640969</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10385740</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>OLVESTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10385805</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLVESTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
