<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10588</id>
<name>DEERHURST</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9521081317061</lat>
<lon>-2.18873035992771</lon>
<gazetteerText>DEERHURST, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred in Gloucester. The village stands on the river Severn, at the boundary with Worcester, 2 miles SW of Tewkesbury town and r. station; was formerly called Deorhurst and Deortyrst; and gives the title of Viscount to the Earl of Coventry. The parish includes also the hamlets of Deerhurst-Walton and Apperley-with-Whitefield: and its post town is Tewkesbury. Acres, 2, 930. Real property, &#163;7, 781. Pop., 930. Houses, 207. The property is divided among a few. A priory was founded here, in 715, by Duke Dodo; rebuilt, in 980, after being destroyed by the Danes; was given in 1056 to St. Denis abbey, and afterwards to Tewkesbury abbey; and passed, at the dissolution, to the Throckmortous. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Apperley, in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;102. Patron, the Bishop of Gloucester and Bristol. The church was rebuilt in 1490; has Norman traces; comprises a nave and aisles, with a square tower; was renovated in 1862, at a cost of about &#163;2, 500; and contains two brasses, one of them a fine canopied brass of Chief-Baron Cassey. There is a Wesleyan chapel.&#151;The sub-district is in Tewkesbury district; and contains nine parishes, and parts of two others. Acres, 18, 152. Pop., 4, 229. Houses, 948.-The hundred consists of detached pieces; contains nine parishes and parts of three others; and is cut into two divisions, lower and upper. Acres, 11, 909 and 7, 970. Pop. of the whole, 4, 994. Houses, 1, 092. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Deerhurst/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651412</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10063413</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>DEERHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10369563</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>DEERHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10369629</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DEERHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12823587</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DEERHURST</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9754</id>
   <name>CHACELEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
