<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5599</id>
<name>WATTON AT STONE</name>
<container>HERTFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8551789803282</lat>
<lon>-0.111945492920026</lon>
<gazetteerText>WATTON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in the district and county of Hertford. The village stands on the river Beane, 4&#188; miles N by W of Hertford r. station; and has a post-office&#8225; under Hertford, a malting establishment, and a large water mill. The parish includes Wemstead hamlet, and comprises 3,499 acres. Real property, &#163;5,364. Pop. in 1851, 976; in 1861, 864. Houses, 178. The manor belonged, in the time of Henry I., to Peter de Valoines; and passed to the Baliols, the D&apos;Aubenis, the Peletots, the Botelers, the Rumbolds, and the Smiths. Woodhall Park is the seat of A. Smith, Esq. Roman coins have been found. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;700.* Patron, A. Smith, Esq. The church has been restored at a cost of about &#163;6,000. A lecture-room is at Wemstead; and there are national schools, and charities &#163;40.&#151;The sub-district contains 7 parishes. Acres, 16,133. Pop., 4,138. Houses, 831. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.pjoiner.demon.co.uk/genuki/HRT/Watton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watton-at-Stone</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634660</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43596</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10149253</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WATTON AT STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10200507</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WATTON AT STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549000</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WATTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
