<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>707</id>
<name>RICKMANSWORTH</name>
<container>HERTFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.635192054696</lat>
<lon>-0.46316850757579</lon>
<gazetteerText>RICKMANSWORTH, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Watford district, Herts. The town standsat the confluence of the rivers Chess and Colne, on the Grand Junction canal, and at the terminus of the Watford and Rickmansworth railway, 3&#190; miles W by S of Watford; was originally called Richmeresweorth; haspleasant environs; attracts many anglers, for sake ofsport in the neighbouring waters; is irregularly laid out; was once a market-town; and has a head post-office, &#8225;designated Rickmansworth, Herts, a railway station, a banking office, a good inn, a timbered market house onpillars, a church, Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, an endowed school with &#163;24 a year, alms-houses with &#163;10, other charities &#163;32, an extensive brewery, a silk mill, four paper mills, cattle fairs on 20 July and 24 Nov., and a fair on the Saturday before the third Monday of Sept. The church is large and good, with ancient embattled tower; has a fine painted window, 300 years old, brought from a church at Rouen; and contains a brass of 1585, and monuments of the Duke of Monmouth, the Fother-leys, the Coltes, and the Earles. The Wesleyan chapel was rebuilt in 1866, at a cost of about &#163;2, 500; is in the early English style; and has an octagonal tower and spire75 feet high. The parish contains also Mill-End, Croxley-Green, West Hyde, Batchworth, and Chorley-Wood. Acres, 9, 937. Real property, &#163;26, 550; of which &#163;150 are in gas-works. Pop., 4, 873. Houses, 1,004. The property is much divided. The chief manor belonged to the Saxonkings; was given by Offa to St. Albans abbey; went, at the dissolution, to Bishop Ridley; was given, by Mary, to Bishop Bonner; reverted, in the time of Elizabeth, to the Crown; and passed to the Fotherleys and the Whitfields. Moor Park was formerly the residence of Cardinal Wolsey and the Duke of Monmouth; and is now the seat of Lord Ebury. Rickmansworth Park is the seat of J. Arden, Esq. There are several other goodresidences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;510.* Patron, the Bishop of Rochester. The p. curacies of West Hyde and Chorley-Wood are separate benefices. Baptist chapels are at Mill-End and Chorley-Wood.&#151;The sub-district contains also Sarratt parish, and comprises 11, 487 acres. Pop., 5, 609. Houses, 1, 146. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rickmansworth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639381</link>
<link>http://www.pjoiner.demon.co.uk/genuki/HRT/Rickmansworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43298</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10103101</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RICKMANSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135436</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>RICKMANSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10148704</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>RICKMANSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10171167</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>RICKMANSWORTH URBAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10200994</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>RICKMANSWORTH RURAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548962</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RICKMANSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10579090</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RICKMANSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12831559</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RICKMANSWORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
