<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>32</id>
<name>BUSHEY</name>
<container>HERTFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6476001939782</lat>
<lon>-0.356216090758678</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUSHEY, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Watford district, Herts. The village stands &#190; of a mile E of the North Western railway, near the river Colne, 1&#189; mile SE of Watford; has a station on the railway and a post office under Watford; and was once a markettown. The parish includes also Bushey-Heath, which likewise has a post office under Watford, and is 3 miles from that town. Acres, 3,188. Real property, &#163;15,586. Pop. 3,159. Houses, 680. The property is much subdivided. The manor was given by William the Conqueror to Geoffrey de Mandeville; and passed afterwards to the Crown. Bushey-Manor-House, Bushey-Grove, and Bushey-Grange are chief residences. The high grounds of Bushey-Heath command an extensive and beautiful view. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of St. Peter, in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;765.* Patron, Exeter College, Oxford. The parish church is tolerable; and St. Peter&apos;s church is modern and very good. There are three dissenting chapels and three public schools. The subdistrict contains two parishes. Pop., 4,928. Houses, 1,032. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bushey</link>
<link>http://www.pjoiner.demon.co.uk/genuki/HRT/Bushey/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654179</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43267</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001687</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BUSHEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10100719</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BUSHEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10103060</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BUSHEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10212996</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BUSHEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548949</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BUSHEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5612</id>
   <name>OXHEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>5612</id>
<name>OXHEY</name>
<container>HERTFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6448220174653</lat>
<lon>-0.378325537081718</lon>
<gazetteerText>OXHEY, a hamlet and a chapelry in Watford parish, Herts. The hamlet lies on the Northwestern railway, at the boundary with Middlesex, 2&#189; miles S by E of Watford. Pop., 733. Houses, 153. The chapelry has nodefined limits, but may be regarded as coextensive with the hamlet; and its post town is Watford. The living is a donative in the diocese of Rochester. Value, notreported. Patron, T. H. S. Estcourt, Esq. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oxhey</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10090118</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OXHEY ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10148649</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OXHEY ST MATTHEW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10200933</id>
   <status>Hmlt/CP</status>
   <name>OXHEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23812</id>
<name>BUSHEY HEATH</name>
<container>HERTFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6307349217092</lat>
<lon>-0.33538214061025</lon>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654177</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10170849</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BUSHEY HEATH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
