<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6315</id>
<name>PENSHURST</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1634240210439</lat>
<lon>0.177662348351096</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENSHURST, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Sevenoaks district, Kent. The village stands at the confluence of the rivers Eden and Medway, 1&#189; mile S of the Southeastern railway, and 4&#189; S W of Tunbridge; was anciently called Penchester; is a pretty place; and has a station with telegraph on the railway, a post-office&#8225; under Tunbridge, and a fair on 26 June. The parish contains also the hamlet of FordcombeGreen. Acres, 4, 526. Real property, &#163;9, 176. Pop., 1, 698. Houses, 325. The manor belonged, at the Norman conquest, to the Penchesters; passed to the Poultneys, the Louvaines, the St. Cleres, the Bohuns, Humphrey Duke of Gloucester, and the Fanes; was given, by Edward VI., to Sir W. Sidney; and, with Penshurst Castle, belongs now to Lord de L&apos; Isle. The castle was mainly rebuilt in 1570-85; figures in some graphic lines by Ben Jonson; is aquadrangular structure, in florid Tudor architecture, with a spacious court. includes a portion, called the King&apos;s Tower, restored in 1862; contains a grand hall, datingfrom 1349, in which James I. was entertained; contains also an apartment, called Queen Elizabeth&apos;s room, withfurniture said to have been presented by Elizabeth herself; contains likewise a splendid collection of paintings and old armour; was the birthplace of Sir Philip Sidney, of &quot; Sidney&apos;s sister, Pembroke&apos;s mother, &quot; of Algernon Sidney, and of Dorothy Sidney, Waller&apos;s &quot; Sacharissa; &quot;and stands in beautiful grounds, formerly of vast extent, and still containing beautiful gardens, Sidney&apos;s oak, Sacharissa&apos;s walk, and Sancup well. South Park is the seat of Viscount Hardinge; Red Leaf, of A. Glendinning, Esq.; and Culver Hill, of J. Nasmyth, Esq. There are a large cricket ball and bat manufactory, and a largepaper-mill. The living is a rectory, united with the chapelry of Fordcombe, in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;756.* Patron, Lord de L&apos; Isle. The churchadjoins P. Castle; was recently restored; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with pinnacled tower; and contains an effigies of a Penchester, and brasses and monuments of the Sidneys. Fordcombe chapel was built in 1847, as a memorial to the Gen. Viscount Hardinge; and is in the early English style. There are a Baptist chapel, a national school, a parochial school, and alms-houses.&#151;The sub-district contains also five other parishes. Acres, 28,025. Pop., 7, 288. Houses, 1, 361. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Penshurst</link>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/PENS_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Penshurst</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640409</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10139510</id>
   <status>PLU</status>
   <name>PENSHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10223878</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>PENSHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10223880</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PENSHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10537010</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PENSHURST</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
