<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5944</id>
<name>BRABOURNE</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1348439857915</lat>
<lon>0.985839852880795</lon>
<gazetteerText>BRABOURNE, two villages, a parish, and a subdistrict in East Ashford district, Kent. The villages are East Brabourne and Brabourne-Lees. East Brabourne stands 3 miles NNE of Smeath r. station, and 6 E of Ashford; has a post office under Ashford; and was once a market-town. Brabourne-Lees is a mile to the west; and also has a post office under Ashford.&#151;The parish comprises 3,499 acres. Real property, &#163;4,697. Pop., 743. Houses, 165. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to Aymer de Valence; and passed to the Scotts and the Honeywoods. Much of the land is cold wet clay. Large barracks stood near BrabourneLees, but have been removed. The living is a vicarage, united with the rectory of Monks-Horton, in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;320. Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church is early English; contains monuments of the Scotts; and is in good condition. A yew stood in the churchyard in Evelyn&apos;s time, 59 feet in girth. There are two Baptist chapels, and charities &#163;8.-The subdistrict contains seven parishes. Acres, 11,035. Pop., 4,032. Houses, 794. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655021</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brabourne</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10039344</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BRABOURNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10212182</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BRABOURNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10537095</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BRABOURNE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3517</id>
   <name>BIRCHOLT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4483</id>
   <name>HASTINGLEIGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
