<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6425</id>
<name>STROOD</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.3969650959409</lat>
<lon>0.491792867801118</lon>
<gazetteerText>STROOD, a town, a parish, and a sub-district, in North Aylesford district, Kent. The town stands on the river Medway, at the junction of the North Kent and the London, Chatham, and Dover railways, opposite Rochester; forms practically one town with Rochester and Chatham; and has a post-office&#8225; under Rochester, a r. station with telegraph, a church rebuilt in 1812, Independent and Wesleyan chapels, a national school, and the North Aylesford workhouse. The parish consists of S.-Intra and Media, within Rochester borough, and S.-Extra without the borough. Acres, 1,622; of which 130 are water. Real property, &#163;15,501; of which &#163;400 are in quarries, &#163;2,650 in railways, and &#163;100 in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 3,067; in 1861, 4,057. Houses, 704. The manor was given, by Henry II., to the Knights Templars. A preceptory of the Knights, and an hospital of the time of Richard I., were here; and have left some remains-Brick-making is largely carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;290.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of R.&#151;The sub-district contains six parishes. Acres, 20,045. Pop., 9,521. Houses, 1,763. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strood</link>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/STRO_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636619</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10074137</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>STROOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154110</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>STROOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10187539</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>STROOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227057</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>STROOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227069</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STROOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227070</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>STROOD EXTRA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227082</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>STROOD INTRA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227094</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STROOD ST FRANCIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227100</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STROOD ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10536730</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STROOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580870</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STROOD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4479</id>
   <name>FRINDSBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
