<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3055</id>
<name>HAWKHURST</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.0514759668769</lat>
<lon>0.500153249403365</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAWKHURST, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Cranbrook district, Kent; but part of the parish and the sub-district also in Sussex. The village stands near the river Rother, 3&#189; miles NE of Etchingham r. station, and 4 SSW of Cranbrook; occupies a rising ground, with fine views over the Weald; was once a market town, and was noted, in last century, as a resort of smugglers; is now a charming place; and has a post office&#8225; under Staplehurst, a banking office, a hotel, a reading room, and a fair on 10 Aug. The parish comprises 6, 494 acres. Real property, &quot;.11, 040. Pop., 2, 715. Houses, 529. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged to Battle abbey. Lillesden, Collingwood House, and Fowler&apos;s Park are handsome seats; Elfords is an ancient Tudor mansion; and Risden House, Oakfield Lodge and others are pleasant residences. There is a private lunatic asylum. There were formerly iron furnaces, belonging to William Penn, the courtier Quaker. The part of the parish within Sussex comprises 2, 060 acres; had no houses at the census of 1861; and was separated from the rest of the parish by an alteration in the course of the river Rother, caused by the erection of a bridge. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of All Saints, in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;350. * Patron, Christ Church, Oxford. The parochial church is decorated and perpendicular English; consists of lofty nave, aisles, chancel, and side chapels, with square embattled tower; and was restored in 1860 and previous years, at a cost of nearly &#163;3, 000. All Saints church stands at Highgate; was erected in 1861;. is in the French Gothic style; and consists of nave, chancel, and aisles, with a spire. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, an endowed school, almshouses with &#163;180, and other charities with &#163;41. Dr. Lardner, author of &quot; the Credibility of the Gospel History, , &apos; was a native.&#151;The sub-district contains also two other parishes. Acres, 20, 561. Pop., 6, 724. Houses, 1, 321. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hawkhurst</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647291</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10088550</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HAWKHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10152161</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAWKHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10536923</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAWKHURST</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8348</id>
   <name>ETCHINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
