<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6332</id>
<name>ROLVENDEN</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.045166180672</lat>
<lon>0.63186587917178</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROLVENDEN, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Kent. The village stands on an eminence3 miles S W of Tenterden, and 10 S of Headcorn r. station; and has a post-office&#8225; under Staplehurst, a good inn, and a literary institution. The parish comprises 5, 622 acres. Real property, &#163;9, 379. Pop., 1, 483. Houses, 306. The property is subdivided. The manor, with Hole House, belongs to F. Morrison, Esq. Kingsgate House, Maytham Hall, and Rawlinson are chief residences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;200.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Rochester. The church is early and later English; and consists of nave, aisles, transepts, and chancel, withvestry and lofty tower. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Unitarians, a national school, and charities &#163;158.&#151;The sub-district contains five parishes, and is in Tenterden district. Acres, 20, 517. Pop., 4, 331. Houses, 865. The hundred contains only Rolvenden and Benenden parishes, and is in the lathe of Scray. Acres, 12, 130. Pop., 3, 145. Houses, 615. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rolvenden</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639201</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10094252</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>ROLVENDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224585</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ROLVENDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224597</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROLVENDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10561863</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ROLVENDEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
