<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5915</id>
<name>HALLING</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.3541218652406</lat>
<lon>0.430721893515028</lon>
<gazetteerText>HALLING, two hamlets and a parish in North Aylesford district, Kent. The hamlets are Lower H. and Upper H. L. H. lies on the river Medway, and on the Strood and Maidstone railway, between Cuxton and Snodland stations, 4&#188; miles SW by S of Rochester; and has a post office under Rochester. U. H. is &#189; a mile to the WNW. The parish comprises 1,847 acres of land, and 70 of water. Real property, &#163;, 776. Pop. in 185, 550; in 186, 760. Houses, 133. The property is divided among a few. The manor took its name from being the &quot;mark&quot; or settlement of the Saxon Hallangas; and it was very early a possession of the bishops of Rochester. A palace of the bishops stood on it, by the side of the Medway; was the death place, in 1184, of Richard, Archbishop of Canterbury, who succeeded Becket; was repaired and extended, in 1322, by Bishop Hamo; was abandoned before the Reformation; and is now represented by only scanty fragments. Lime burning, and the manufacture of Portland and Roman cement, are extensively carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;214.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Rochester. The church is early English; consists of nave and chancel, with large square tower; and has a. brass of 1587. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/HALL_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halling,_Kent</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647616</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10060722</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HALLING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10211177</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HALLING</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
