<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5392</id>
<name>CHARING</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.210592797934</lat>
<lon>0.782727288966779</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHARING, a village and a parish in West Ashford district, Kent. The village stands on the ancient road called the Pilgrims&apos; way, near the source of the Len, 5 miles N by E of Pluckley r. station, and 5&#189; NW of Ashford. It is an ancient place, known at Domesday as Cheringes; and it has a post office&#8225; under Ashford, an inn, and fair s on 29 April, and 29 Oct. The parish comprises 4,551 acres. Real property, &#163;7,610. Pop., 1,285. Houses, 265. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged early to the see of Canterbury; was held some time but the Saxon kings; reverted to the Archbishops; was given up by Cranmer to Henry VIII.; and passed to the Whelers of Otterden. A palace of the Archbishops stood here; was rebuilt in the 14th century; and gave entertainment to Henry VII. and Henry VIII. The edifice was in the early decorated style, and badly executed; and considerable ruins of it still exist. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;475.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of St. Paul&apos;s. The church was chiefly rebuilt after a destruction of it by fire in 1590, but retains portions in early English and perpendicular; and it contains monuments of the Brents, the Sayers, the Honeywoods, and Mrs. Ludwell. A school, founded by Mrs. Ludwell, who died in 1765, has &#163;88 a year from endowment, and two exhibitions at Oriel college. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charing</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653342</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10040012</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHARING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10193151</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CHARING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10571315</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHARING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10572952</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EAST CHARING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582283</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEST CHARING</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6308</id>
   <name>OTTERDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6406</id>
   <name>STALISFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>23332</id>
<name>CHARING HEATH</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.2088975556542</lat>
<lon>0.760535310664393</lon>
<unit>
   <id>10080824</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHARING HEATH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
