<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2025</id>
<name>APPLEDORE</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.0378978912727</lat>
<lon>0.787648616513074</lon>
<gazetteerText>APPLEDORE, a village and a parish in Tenterden district, Kent. The village stands on the Military canal, on a branch of the river Rother, on the W border of Romney marsh, 1&#189; mile W of a station of its own name on the Ashford and Hastings railway, and 6 ESE of Ten terden. It has a post office&#8225; under Staplehurst; and it formerly had a weekly market, and still has a fair on the 4th Monday in June. It once was a seaport, on the quondam estuary of the Rother; and it was assailed by the Danes in the time of King Alfred, and by the French in 1380. The parish comprises 3,001 acres. Real property, &#163;6,184. Pop. 640. Houses, 132. The property is divided among a few. Much of the land is rich meadowy pasture. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury; and includes the curacy of Ebony. Value, &#163;200.* Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church has a singular projection from the N side of the nave, and is a strange mixture of Norman, early English, and decorated; but has been greatly altered, and is in good condition. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Appledore,_Kent</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296473</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10038900</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>APPLEDORE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10211050</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>APPLEDORE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4477</id>
   <name>FAIRFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6399</id>
   <name>SNARGATE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
