<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6401</id>
<name>SNODLAND</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.3361816834239</lat>
<lon>0.427744892755623</lon>
<gazetteerText>SNODLAND, a village and a parish in Malling district, Kent. The village stands on the river Medway and the North Kent railway, 5&#189; miles SSW of Rochester; and has a r. station with telegraph, and a post-office&#8225; under Rochester. The parish contains also the hamlets of Paddlesworth, Holborough, and Rookery. Acres, 2,072. Real property, &#163;3,887. Pop. in 1851, 625; in 1861, 1,078. Houses, 198. The increase of pop. arose from employment in a paper-manufactory, and in lime-works. Holborough Court is the seat of W. Lee, Esq. A hill above H. was anciently fortified, has remains of a Roman barrow, and commands an extensive view. The Living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;297.* Patron, the Bishop of R. The church contains portions from early English to perpendicular; includes Roman bricks and tiles in its walls; and has twelve stained-glass windows. There are an Independent chapel, a literary institution, a national school, an endowed school with &#163;19 a year, and charities &#163;40. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Snodland</link>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/SNOD_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637571</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10226478</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SNODLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10226508</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SNODLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10226521</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SNODLAND WITH PADDLESWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12829474</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SNODLAND</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5915</id>
   <name>HALLING</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
