<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2074</id>
<name>HEADCORN</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1691124101808</lat>
<lon>0.625733820855623</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEADCORN, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Hollingbourn district, Kent. The village stands on the river Beult, and on the Southeastern railway, 11 miles W by N of Ashford; consists chiefly of one wide straggling street; and has a post office&#8225; under Staplehurst, a railway station with telegraph, a hotel, a commodious town hall built in 1867, a weekly market on Wednesday, and a fair on 12 June. The parish comprises 5, 011 acres. Real property, &#163;6, 503. Pop., 1, 339. Houses, 291. The property is much subdivided. Some hops are grown; and bricks and tiles are made. An Augustinian priory was founded at Mottenden, in 1224, by Sir Robert de Rokesby; and was given, at the dissolution, to Lord Cromwell, -and, after his attainder, to Sir Anthony Aucher. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;294. * Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church is decorated and later English; consists of nave, aisle, and chancel, with a tower; and was restored in 1855. The churchyard has a very old oak, 40 feet in girth. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Unitarians, a national school, and charities &#163;25.&#151;The sub-district contains eight parishes. Acres, 18, 849. Pop., 5, 286. Houses, 1, 117. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Headcorn</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647240</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10040840</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HEADCORN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10172391</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEADCORN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10537150</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEADCORN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
