<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6268</id>
<name>LYMINGE</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1377750055557</lat>
<lon>1.07751044488208</lon>
<gazetteerText>LYMINGE, a village and a parish in Elham district, Kent. The village stands 1&#190; mile E of Stane-street, 3&#189; NE of Westenhanger r. station, and 3&#190; N of Hythe; has a post office under Hythe; and will have a station on the Elham Valley railway, which was begun to be forwarded in 1867. The parish comprises 4,459 acres. Real property, &#163;4,078. Pop., 938. Houses, 156. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to a nunnery founded here in 633, by Ethelburga, daughter of King Ethelbert; passed to the Archbishops of Canterbury; was surrendered by Archbishop Cranmer to the Crown; went through varions possessors to Lord Loughborough; and belongs now to Stephen Kelcey, Esq. The nunnery was destroyed by the Danes, and early disappeared. A spring, called St. Eadburg&apos;s well, is near the church, and emits a headstream of the Little Stour river. Upwards of 1,000 acres are under wood; and part of the land is hilly, with a light poor Soil: but the rest is very fertile. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Paddlesworth, in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;920.* Patron, the Rev. R.Jenkins. The church belonged to the nunnery; was built out of the materials of a Roman structure, some remains of which still exist; is mentioned in charter&apos;s of Wihtred and Cuthred, of the years 697 and 804; was the burial-place of Ethelburga: comprises nave, N aisle, and chancel, with a remarkable flying-buttress; and was recently repaired. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;38. The Elham workhouse also is here; and, at the census of 1861, had 215 inmates. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lyminge</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643313</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10222357</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LYMINGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10222369</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LYMINGE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
