<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6351</id>
<name>LAMBERHURST</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1103525333272</lat>
<lon>0.374121079168048</lon>
<gazetteerText>LAMBERHURST, a village and a parish in the district of Ticehurst, and counties of Kent and Sussex. The village stands on an affluent of the river Medway, 4&#188; miles E of Frant r. station and 6&#189; ESE of Tunbridge Wells; is a large place; and has a post-office under Hurst Green, a good inn, and fairs on 6 April and 21 May.&#151; The parish includes Scotney manor, and comprises 3,590 acres in Kent, and 1,700 in Sussex. Real property, &#163;8,008. Pop. of the K. portion in 1851,560; in 1861,554. Houses, 115. Pop. of the S. portion in 1851, 1,174; in 1861, 1,051. Houses, 207. The property is much subdivided. Court Lodge stands on an eminence, within a park; commands pleasant views of the surrounding country; and is the seat of W. C. Morland, Esq. Scotney Castle was the seat of Archbishop Chicheley, in the early part of the 15th century; went to his collateral descendants, the Darrells; was rebuilt by Inigo Jones; and has given place to a modern mansion, the seat of Edward Hussey, Esq. Extensive iron-smelting furnaces were formerly in the parish; and they furnished the massive iron balustrades around St. Paul&apos;s in London. Brewing and brick-making are now carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;401. * Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Rochester. The church is old but good, and has a conspicuous steeple. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, a national school, and charities &#163;39. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/LAMB_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lamberhurst</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645005</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10225115</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LAMBERHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10225188</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LAMBERHURST</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
