<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3324</id>
<name>DYMCHURCH</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.0290046162913</lat>
<lon>0.996904548337109</lon>
<gazetteerText>DYMCHURCH, a parish in Romney-Marsh district, Kent; on the coast, 4 miles NE of New Romney, and 5&#188; SSW of Westenhanger and Hythe r. station. It has a post office&#8225; under Folkestone. Acres, 1, 534; of which 420 are water. Real property, &#163;3, 163. Pop., 718. Houses, 142. The property is much subdivided. The surface is all on the level of Romney-Marsh; and, together with the rest of that low tract, is protected from sea-inundation only by means of Dymchurch wall. This is an embankment about 3 miles long, about 20 feet high, and from 15 to 30 feet wide, with three sluice-gates for drainage; and is kept in repair by a local rate, under management of a local body. During some recent alterations on the embankment, relics of the Medi&#230;val and the Saxon times were obtained; and below these, great quantities of Roman pottery; and under these, bones of the whale and the mammoth. The living is a rectory united in 1868 with Eastbridge, Blackmanstone, and Orgarswick, in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;363.* Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church is old. There are Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, and charities &#163;111. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dymchurch</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650589</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10060643</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DYMCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10098348</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>DYMCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6303</id>
   <name>ORGARSWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
