<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6511</id>
<name>CHARLTON</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.481795749332</lat>
<lon>0.0408920378078598</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHARLTON-NEXT-WOOLWICH, a village and a parish in Lewisham district, Kent. The village lies among the low hills between Blackheath and Woolwich, adjacent to the North Kent railway, near the river Thames, 8 miles E by S of London Bridge; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under London S. E., both of the name of Charlton. It formerly was a market town; and it still has a famous fair on 18 Oct., known as Horn Fair. The parish comprises 1,251 acres of land and 91 of water. Real property, &#163;36,162. Pop., 8,472. Houses, 1,117. The manor was given by William Rufus to Bermondsey Abbey; went, at the dissolution, to the Newtons; passed to the Langhornes, the Ducies, and the Maryons; and belongs now to Sir T. M. Wilson, Bart. Charlton House was built, about 1612, by Sir Adam Newton; forms a fine specimen of the architecture of its age; contains a good portrait of Henry, Prince of Wales, to whom Sir Adam Newton acted as tutor; was the death place, in 1679, of Lord Doune; and is now the seat of Sir T. M. Wilson. The grounds connected with it have some very old cypresses; the &quot;Hanging Wood,&quot; adjoining it, affords a charming walk; and some sand pits in the vicinity present great attractions to geologists. A farmhouse in the parish, called Cherry Garden, is said to have been erected by Inigo Jones for his own residence. Several handsome villas have recently been built. The living is a rectory in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;350.* Patron, Sir T. M. Wilson, Bart. The church is a plain brick edifice of 1640. The rectories of St. Thomas and St. Paul, and the chapelries of Blackheath Park and St. GermansBlackheath, are separate charges. Value of St. Thomas, &#163;400;* of St. Paul, &#163;286. Patron of both, Sir J M. Wilson, Bart. St. Thomas&apos; church stands at New Charlton; is a handsome structure; and was built in 1850, at a cost of &#163;5,000. St. Paul&apos;s church was built in 1867; is in the second pointed style, cruciform, and highly ornate; and has a SW tower and spire. There are a Wesleyan chapel, the cottages on Woolwich Common, Morden college for decayed merchants, national schools, Langhorne&apos;s school and alms-houses, and other charities &#163;80. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlton,_London</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10040073</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLD CHARLTON ST LUKE WITH ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10080848</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHARLTON ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10150929</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHARLTON NEXT WOOLWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10150930</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEW CHARLTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10213071</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CHARLTON NEXT WOOLWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10233896</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>CHARLTON AND KIDBROOKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10539420</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHARLTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>20706</id>
<name>CHARLTON NEAR DOVER</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1345353573878</lat>
<lon>1.30371614824554</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHARLTON-NEAR-DOVER, a parish in Dover district, Kent; on the river Dour and the Southeastern railway, contiguous to the north side of Dover, and mostly within Dover borough. It has a post office,&#8225; of the name of Charlton, under Dover. Acres, 381. Rated property, &#163;7,254. Pop., 4,093. Houses, 761. The property is much subdivided. The surface is hilly and picturesque; and there are paper, oil, and corn mills. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;93.* Patron, the Rev. J. Monins. The church was rebuilt in 1820. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/CHAR_plc.htm</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10040036</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHARLTON BY DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10040048</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHARLTON BY DOVER ST PETER AND ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10080836</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHARLTON BY DOVER ST BARTHOLOMEW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10150899</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CHARLTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10172226</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DOVER CHARLTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
