<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4431</id>
<name>BOXLEY</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.3048292848334</lat>
<lon>0.545448469061154</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOXLEY, a village and a parish in Hollingbourn district, Kent. The village stands at the foot of a barren range of chalk hills, 2 miles NE by N of Maidstone; has a post office under Maidstone; and was once a market-town. The parish includes part of Penenden Heath; and comprises 5,745 acres. Real property, &#163;11,677. Pop., 1,470. Houses, 289. The property is much subdivided. The manor was given by Richard I. to Boxley Abbey; passed, at the dissolution, to Sir Thomas Wyatt; and belongs now to the Earl of Romney. The Abbey was founded, in 1146, by William d&apos;Ypres, Earl of Kent; stood 1&#189; mile WSW of the village; was Cistertian, mitred, and well endowed; had an image of St. Rumbald and an automaton crucifix, which attracted crowds of pilgrims, and were publicly burnt at the Reformation; and is now all effaced except the foundations. Boxley Abbey Mansion, adjacent, is the seat of Major M. G. Best; Boxley House is the seat of Mrs. Mercer; and Boxley Park is the seat of E. Lushington, Esq. A deep thick vein of fuller&apos;s earth occurs at Grove; and was worked so early as 1630. Fulling-mills stood on the neighbouring rivulets; and have been succeeded by papermills. A Roman urn and several other Roman relics have been found in the neighbourhood of Grove. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;834.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Rochester. The church is decorated English; and contains the remains of the poet Sandys, and tombs of the Wyatts and others. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655040</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boxley</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10080447</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOXLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10150103</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BOXLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
