<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6292</id>
<name>NEWENDEN</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.0210440834357</lat>
<lon>0.620766057269683</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWENDEN, a village and a parish in Tenterden district, Kent. The village stands on the river Rother at the boundary with Sussex, 5&#189; miles S W by S of Tenterden, and 10 N W by W of Rye r. station; was once a considerable shipping place; and has a post-office under Staplehurst, a three-arched bridge over the Rother, and a fair on 21 June. The parish is a liberty, and comprises 1,044 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 230. Pop. in 1851, 172; in 1861, 137. Houses, 23. The property is sub-divided. A Carmelite priory stood at Losenham, about&#189; a mile E of the village; contests with a friary at Ayles-ford the claim of having been the earliest Carmelite establishment in England; is thought by Camden to have been founded on the site of the Roman Anderida; and has left no remains. A spot called Castle-Toll, at some distance from Losenham, exhibits traces of large and deep entrenchments, enclosing a lofty mound; has furnished many Roman relics; and used also to be regarded, by some antiquaries, as the site of Anderida. That ancient city, however, is now identified, by the best antiquaries, with Pevensey. The living of Newenden is a rectory in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;240. Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church is ancient; bears marks of being only a portion of originally a much larger structure; and contains a good decorated screen, and a very curious square carved font, either Saxon or early Norman. There is an endowed school with &#163;25 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newenden</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641652</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10223258</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NEWENDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10223260</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWENDEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
