<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>863</id>
<name>UPHOLLAND</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5398730238574</lat>
<lon>-2.7427572172771</lon>
<gazetteerText>UPHOLLAND, a village, a township, a chapelry, and a sub-district, in Wigan parish and district, Lancashire. The village stands 1 mile NNW of Orrell r. station and 4 W of Wigan; and has a post-office under Wigan, and a cattle and horse fair on Easter Monday. The township contains also three hamlets, and comprises 4,452 acres. Real property, &#163;16,912; of which &#163;5,500 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 3,359; in 1861, 3,463. Houses, 685. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to Lord Skelmersdale. Holland Grove is the seat of G. Bolderstone, Esq. A Benedictine priory was founded here, in 1319, by Sir R. de Holland; and has left some remains. Stone and slate are quarried, and fire bricks are made.&#151;The chapelry is more extensive than the township. Pop., 6,091. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;300.* Patron. the Rector of Wigan. The church was the chapel of the priory. A school at Pimbo-Lane is used as a chapel of ease. There are two Methodist chapels, an endowed grammar-school, two national schools, and charities &#163;110.&#151;The sub-district contains 4 townships. Acres, 9,220. Pop., 6,982. Houses, 1,360. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Upholland/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Upholland</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635156</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41385</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10153785</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>UPHOLLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10167310</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>UPHOLLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10381885</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>UPHOLLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10381939</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>UPHOLLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10565972</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>UPHOLLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12830312</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>UPHOLLAND</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>405</id>
   <name>SKELMERSDALE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>794</id>
   <name>BILLINGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10073</id>
   <name>DALTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
