<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11014</id>
<name>WARTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>54.1440714541937</lat>
<lon>-2.81564002193555</lon>
<gazetteerText>WARTON, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Lancaster district, Lancashire. The township lies near Morecambe bay, the Kendal canal, and Carnforth r. station, 6&#189; miles N by E of Lancaster; and includes Lindeth hamlet. Acres, 2,924. Real property, &#163;3,754. Pop., 581. Houses, 131.&#151;The parish contains also Carnforth township, which has a post-office under Lancaster; contains likewise 5 other townships; and comprises 11,141 acres. Pop., 2,161. Houses, 443. The property is much subdivided. Hyning Hall, Hazlemount, Linden Hall, Prospect House, Leighton Hall, and Morecambe Lodge are chief residences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;300.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Worcester. The church was repaired in 1850, and has seven memorial windows. The p. curacies of Silverdale and Yealand-Conyers are separate benefices. Two school-houses, at Carnforth and Priest-Hutton, are used as chapels of ease There are chapels for Quakers and Roman Catholics.&#151;The sub-district includes also three townships of Bolton-le-Sands, and comprises 17,932 acres. Pop., 3,562. Houses, 732. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/WartonC/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634726</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53289</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53286</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53291</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53292</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53290</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53287</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53288</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53293</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10207022</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384394</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384424</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384436</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384461</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>WARTON WITH LINDETH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545912</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WARTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>11013</id>
<name>WARTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.7434480495038</lat>
<lon>-2.90430960679843</lon>
<gazetteerText>WARTON, a township and a chapelry in Kirkham parish, Lancashire. The township lies on the river Ribble&apos;s estuary, 3 miles SW of Kirkham r. station; contains a scattered village of its own name; and has a postal wall-box, under Preston. Acres, 3,939; of which 2,405 are water. Real property, &#163;2,960. Pop., 446. Houses, 91. The chapelry includes also Freckleton township, and comprises 6,598 acres. Pop., 1,325. Houses, 279. The property is much subdivided. Cotton spinning and the manufacture of sacking, sail-cloth, and cordage, are carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;350.* Patron, Christchurch, Oxford. There are two churches, both good. There are also two Methodist chapels and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warton,_Fylde</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/WartonK/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634727</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53211</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10384448</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>WARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384450</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WARTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
