<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1005</id>
<name>FARNWORTH</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5487512687234</lat>
<lon>-2.40847773952148</lon>
<gazetteerText>FARNWORTH, a town, a township, a chapelry, and a sub-district in Deane parish and Bolton district, Lancashire. The town stands near the Bolton and Manchester railway, 3 miles SE of Bolton; has a post office&#8225; under Bolton, and a railway station with telegraph, jointly with Halshaw-Moor, on the railway; publishes a weekly newspaper; is a seat of cotton manufacture, and of the iron trade; is also the place where the late Mr. T. B. Crompton, for some time, carried on one of the largest paper-works in the kingdom; and is regarded, in statistics, as co-extensive with township. Acres of the township, 1, 450. Real property, &#163;26, 684; of which &#163;3, 249 are in mines, &#163;40 in quarries, and &#163;839 in gas-works. Pop. in 1851, 6, 389; in 1861, 8, 720. Houses, 1, 720. The property is much subdivided. The increase of pop. arose from the erection of cotton mills and the establishment of foundries. A public park for Bolton is situated at Farnworth; was presented by T. Barnes, Esq., M. P. for Bolton; was inagurated, in 1864, by Mr. Gladstone; and is estimated to be worth nearly &#163;13, 000.&#151;The chapelry includes also the township of Kersley; and was constituted in 1828. Pop., 13, 723. Houses, 2, 714. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;300.* Patrons, Hulme&apos;s Trustees. The church is modern, in the pointed style, and cost &#163;8, 000. A tract, with a pop. of 4, 000, was formed, in 1866, into the separate charge of New Bury. There are two Church schools, used as chapels of ease; an Independent chapel, built in 1863, at a cost of &#163;2, 500; a Wesleyan chapel, built in 1862, at a cost of &#163;4, 000; P. Methodist, Swedenborgian, and Roman Catholic chapels; and a national school.&#151;The sub-district is conterminate with the chapelry. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/FarnworthW/</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/FarnworthD/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649650</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=52995</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10085676</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10193977</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351560</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351571</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351595</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351601</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH AND KEARSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351613</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH ST PETER BRADFORD STREET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545160</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10573403</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12735479</id>
   <status>CCon/BCon</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741182</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>LANCASHIRE FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12829814</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25726</id>
<name>FARNWORTH</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3818751376712</lat>
<lon>-2.72620874910251</lon>
<gazetteerText>FARNWORTH, a village, a chapelry, and a sub-district, in Prescot parish and district, Lancashire. The village stands near the St. Helen&apos;s and Runcorn Gap railway, 2&#190; miles N by E of Runcorn Gap, and 4&#190; SE of Prescot; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Warrington. The chapelry is partly in Warrington district; and was constituted in 1859. Pop. of the Warrington d. part, 1, 539; of the whole, 6, 447. Houses in the W. d. part, 283; in the whole, 1, 191. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Vicar of Prescot. The church is ancient, and was recently restored. Another church, at Widnes Dock, was built in 1858, and designed with a view to enlargement. There is a free gammar-school. William Smith, the founder of Brasenose college, Oxford, and bishop of Lincoln, was born in this chapelry, at Peel House.&#151;The sub-district comprises the townships of Widnes, Cronton, Ditton, and Bold. Acres, 10, 861. Pop., 8, 879. Houses, 1, 599. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Farnworth,_Cheshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649651</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10351583</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545407</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WIDNES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10573415</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12796742</id>
   <status>Ch</status>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
