<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>21269</id>
<name>HOLCOMBE</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6470242625488</lat>
<lon>-2.3283088067674</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOLCOMBE, a village, a chapelry, and a sub-district in Bury district, Lancashire. The village stands near the river Irwell and the Bury and Haslingden railway, 1&#188; mile SW of Ramsbottom r. station, and 4&#189; N by W of Bury. The chapelry is in Tottington-Lower-End township, Bury parish; and was recently made ecclesiastically parochial. Post town, Ramsbottom, under Manchester. Pop., 2, 511. A tower or column, to the memory of Sir Robert Peel, stands on Holcombe hill. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;175.* Patron, the Rector of Bury. The church is in the early decorated English style; and consists of nave, N transept, and chancel, with tower and fine spire. -The sub-district consists mainly of part of Tottington-Lower-End township, but includes a pendicle of Walmersley-cum-Shuttleworth township. Pop., 6, 645. Houses, 1, 276. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646774</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10355801</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HOLCOMBE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>774</id>
<name>RAMSBOTTOM</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6531858824613</lat>
<lon>-2.30896356050469</lon>
<gazetteerText>RAMSBOTTOM, a small town and a chapelry in Bury parish, Lancashire. The town stands on the river Irwell and on the East Lancashire railway, 4 miles N of Bury; was the place where the first Sir Robert Peelestablished calico-printing; carries on cotton spinning, calico-printing, machine-making, rope-making, and iron and brass founding; is governed by a local board, under the act of 1858; and has a post-office&#8225; under Manchester, a railway-station with telegraph, a commodious inn, a police station, a church, four dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a public school, an athen&#230;um, a public library, and an Odd Fellows&apos; hall. The church was built in 1850, at a cost of &#163;3, 400; was enlarged shortly before 1868; is in the early English style; and has amemorial window to the late Lord Palmerston, and a tower and spire. The Presbyterian chapel was built in 1834; is a handsome edifice, in the pointed style; and has a lofty pinnacled tower. The chapelry was constituted in 1844. Pop. in 1861, 4, 134. Houses, 798. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;170. Patron, alternately the Crown and the Bishop. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramsbottom</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Ramsbottom/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639668</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10136647</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>RAMSBOTTOM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10138632</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>RAMSBOTTOM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376865</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RAMSBOTTOM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376877</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>RAMSBOTTOM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376889</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RAMSBOTTOM ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544956</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RAMSBOTTOM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12830816</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RAMSBOTTOM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10941</id>
   <name>WALMERSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
