<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>641</id>
<name>RADCLIFFE</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5678179008715</lat>
<lon>-2.33406731726245</lon>
<gazetteerText>RADCLIFFE, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Bury district, Lancashire. The town stands on the river Irwell, near the influx of the Roach, and on the Manchester and Bury railway, adjacent to the Bolton and Bury canal, 2&#189; miles S S W of Bury; took its name from a red cliff on the opposite side of the Irwell; consists of two parts, called Radcliffe and Radcliffe-Bridge, about &#189; a mile asunder; carries on bleaching, paper-making, cotton-spinning, calico-printing, gingham, fustian, nankeen, and check-weaving, machine-making, iron-founding, and small-ware manufacture; has several collieries; and has a post-office&#8225; under Manchester, a railway station of Radcliffe-Bridge, with telegraph, agood inn, a police station, a market house built in 1851at a cost of &#163;1, 500, a bridge over the Irwell, two churches, three dissenting chapels, four national schools, an agricultural show on 28 Sept., races about the middle of Aug., a fair on 29 Sept., and charities &#163;9. The parish church is ancient, of various dates; has a low massive tower; and includes a chapel restored in 1845, and a N transept added in 1846. St. Thomas&apos; church, at Radcliffe-Bridge, was built in 1819, at a cost of &#163;5,000; was rebuilt in 1865, at a cost of &#163;7, 274; is in the perpendicular English style; and contains 1, 200 sittings. The parish contains also part of Starling village, and comprises 2, 466 acres. Real property, &#163;35, 800; of which &#163;8, 940 are in mines, and &#163;1, 439 in gas-works. Pop. in 1851, 6, 293; in 1861, 8, 838. Houses, 1, 726. The manor belongs to the Earl of Wilton. R. Tower, now a ruin, was formerly a great manorial mansion. The living is a rectory, and that of St. Thomas is a p. curacy, in the diocese of Manchester. Value of the former, &#163;500; * of the latter, &#163;300.* Patron of both, the Earl of Wilton. The sub-district excludes two small portions of the parish, but includes portions of three other parishes. Pop., 8, 972. Houses, 1, 754. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Radcliffe/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radcliffe</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6691227</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53000</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10029090</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>RADCLIFFE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109164</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>RADCLIFFE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376622</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RADCLIFFE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376634</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RADCLIFFE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376646</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RADCLIFFE ST ANDREW BLACK LANE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376658</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RADCLIFFE ST THOMAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544932</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RADCLIFFE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578887</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RADCLIFFE AND PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739503</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>SOUTH EAST LANCASHIRE RADCLIFFE CUM FARNWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739588</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>BURY AND RADCLIFFE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12830117</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RADCLIFFE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>816</id>
   <name>LITTLE LEVER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9818</id>
   <name>AINSWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10050</id>
   <name>CLIFTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10744</id>
   <name>OUTWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
