<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>661</id>
<name>HEATON NORRIS</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4190200568522</lat>
<lon>-2.1715513958804</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEATON-NORRIS, a town, a township, two chapelries, and a sub-district, in the parish of Manchester, the district of Stockport, and the county of Lancaster. The town is suburban to Stockport; stands on the verge of Lancashire, on the river Mersey, on the Northwestern railway, and on the Stockport and Altrincham Junction railway, at the terminus of the Ashton, Manchester, and Oldham canal, 5&#190; miles SSE of Manchester; and has two railway stations, several good hotels, two churches, five dissenting chapels, two national schools, and numerous respectable residences. Six bridges, and a foot one, connect it with Stockport. A viaduct, 1, 780 feet long, 108 feet high, with twenty-two arches, erected at a cost of &#163;75, 000, takes the Northwestern railway across the Mersey. An extensive luggage dep&#244;t is connected with the Northwestern r. station. Christ Church was built in 1846; is a handsome edifice, in the pointed style; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with an elegant spire. The Wycliffe Independent chapel is an ornamental Gothic structure. The town shares generally in the trade of Stockport; and has large cotton factories, iron foundries, machine works, rope walks, and saw mills -The township includes also the village of Heaton-Mersey, and is partly within Stockport borough. Acres, 2, 108. Real property, &#163;52, 750. Pop. in 1851, 15, 697; in 1861, 16, 333. Houses, 3, 379. Pop. of the part within Stockport borough, 13, 838. Houses, 2, 922.- The two chapelries are Christchurch and St. Thomas; both were constituted in 1854; and the latter lies round Heaton-Chapel r. station. Post town of both, Stockport. Pop. in 1861, of Christchurch, 9, 625; of St. Thomas, 6, 179. Houses, 1, 970 and 1, 336. The livings are rectories in the diocese of Manchester. Value of Christchurch, &#163;30;* of St. Thomas, &#163;116. * Patron of the former, the Bishop of Manchester; of the latter, the Dean and Chapter of Manchester. An ancient chapelry of Heaton-Norris comprehends also what are now the chapelries of Reddish.&#151;The sub-district contains also the township of Reddish. Acres, 3, 649. Pop., 17, 696. Houses, 3, 659. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/HeatonNorris/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heaton_Norris</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647212</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41434</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10109498</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HEATON NORRIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10111134</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HEATON NORRIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10354948</id>
   <status>CP/Tn/Ch</status>
   <name>HEATON NORRIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10355060</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEATON NORRIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10355072</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEATON NORRIS ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10355096</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEATON NORRIS CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542224</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEATON NORRIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12780692</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEATON NORRIS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
