<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10964</id>
<name>KIBWORTH BEAUCHAMP</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5294344103305</lat>
<lon>-0.995792872686224</lon>
<gazetteerText>KIBWORTH-BEAUCHAMP, a village, a township, and a parish in Market-Harborough district, Leicester. The village stands near Kibworth r. station, and near the Union canal, 6 miles NW by N of Market-Harborough; and was once a market town. The township includes the village, and extends beyond it. Real property, &#163;3, 581. Pop. in 1851, 733; in 1861, 868. Houses, 199. The parish contains also the townships of Kibworth-Harcourt and Smeeton-Westerby; the former of which has a post office&#8225; under Leicester. Acres, 3, 220. Real property, &#163;10, 582. Pop. in 1851, 1, 752; in 1861, 1,867. Houses, 408. The manor of K. B. belongs to Sir Henry Halford, Bart.; that of K. H., to Merton College, Oxford; and that of Smeeton, to Henry H. H. Hungerford, Esq. A moated camp, 54 feet high and 366 feet in circuit, and a large barrow, are in K. H. Framework-knitting is carried on. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborongh. Value, &#163;850.* Patron, Merton College, Oxford. The church stands on a height; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with porches and an embattled tower; contains sedilia and a piscina; and was improved, at a cost of fully &#163;1, 150, in 1862. The tower of the previous church had a lofty spire; and while under repair in 1826, fell suddenly to the ground. The p. curacy of Smeeton-Westerby is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Free Methodists in K. B.; a chapel for Independents in K. H.; and a Baptist chapel in Smeeton. A free grammar school was founded by some person or persons unknown; was rebuilt in 1725; and has &#163;285 a year from endowment. A lectureship in the parish church, for Thursday evenings, was founded in 1836, by the Rev. J. Goodman, then head master of the school. There are also a national school, and charities &#163;12. Dr. John Aiken was a native; and Dr. Doddridge was minister of the Independent chapel here before going to Northampton. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LEI/Kibworth.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kibworth_Beauchamp</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296329</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22057</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10382555</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>KIBWORTH BEAUCHAMP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10382567</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KIBWORTH BEAUCHAMP</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10852</id>
   <name>GUMLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10983</id>
   <name>TUR LANGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10984</id>
   <name>WEST LANGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11263</id>
   <name>SHANGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11284</id>
   <name>SMEETON WESTERBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
