<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11827</id>
<name>BUTTERWICK</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.992284213385</lat>
<lon>0.0779066496360836</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUTTERWICK, a parish in Boston district, Lincoln; on the coast, near Boston Deeps, 4&#188; miles E of Boston r. station. It includes an allotment in the East Fen; and has a post office under Boston. Acres, 4,420; of which 3,050 are water. Real property, &#163;4,660. Pop., 605. Houses, 120. A large pond, which medical men declared to be highly pestiferous, was recently filled up and planted with vegetables. The living is a vicarage annexed to the vicarage of Frieston, in the diocese of Lincoln. The church has an early English octagonal font, and a rood turret. There are a Wesleyan chapel, an endowed school with &#163;289 a year, and charities &#163;160. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Butterwick/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Butterwick,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654148</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10405361</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BUTTERWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10405373</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BUTTERWICK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11562</id>
   <name>BENINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>11828</id>
<name>EAST BUTTERWICK</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5456662301395</lat>
<lon>-0.724473962956442</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUTTERWICK (East), a township in Bottesford and Messingham parishes, Lincoln; on the river Trent, 3&#189; miles S by E of Keadby. Real property, &#163;2,397-Pop., 420. There are three dissenting chapels. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650490</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10405385</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>EAST BUTTERWICK</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>11830</id>
<name>WEST BUTTERWICK</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5331136188023</lat>
<lon>-0.753606846733753</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUTTERWICK (West), with Kelfield, a townshipchapelry in Owston parish, Lincoln; on the river Trent, 3&#189; miles S of Keadby r. station. It has a post office, of the name of West Butterwick, under Bawtry. Real property, &#163;4,995. Pop., 907. Houses, 203. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Vicar of Owston. The church was built in 1841. There are three dissenting chapels and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/WestButterwick/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634479</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10405403</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>WEST BUTTERWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10405452</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST BUTTERWICK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
