<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14089</id>
<name>NORTH WITHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7762356811107</lat>
<lon>-0.600767379009317</lon>
<gazetteerText>WITHAM (North), a parish, with a village, in Grantham district, Lincoln; on the river Witham; 4&#188; miles WSW of Corby r. station, and 9 S of Grantham. Post town, Colsterworth, under Grantham. Acres, 2,373. Real property, &#163;5,103. Pop., 278. Houses, 62. The manor belongs to the Earl of Dysart. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;520.* Patron, Viscount Downe. The church is good, and has a spire. Charities, &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/NorthWitham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Witham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641219</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463828</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NORTH WITHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463830</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTH WITHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>14090</id>
<name>SOUTH WITHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7654342381813</lat>
<lon>-0.636055078444737</lon>
<gazetteerText>WITHAM (South), a parish, with a village, in Grantham district, Lincoln; on the river Witham, 5&#189; miles SW of Corby r. station, and 10&#190; S of Grantham. Post town, Colsterworth, under Grantham. Acres, 3,230. Real property, &#163;2,762. Pop., 531. Houses, 119. The manor belongs to the Earl of Dysart. A preceptory of Knights-Templars was founded here in 1164. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;225.* Patron, the Earl of Dysart. The church was originally cruciform, but consists now of only nave and transept, and was recently in bad condition. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, and charities &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/SouthWitham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Witham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637278</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463841</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SOUTH WITHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463853</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH WITHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1991</id>
   <name>STRETTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5339</id>
   <name>THISTLETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12479</id>
   <name>GUNBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14089</id>
   <name>NORTH WITHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>14091</id>
<name>WITHAM ON THE HILL</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7404016048214</lat>
<lon>-0.43425487423522</lon>
<gazetteerText>WITHAM-ON-THE-HILL, a township and a parish in Bourn district, Lincoln. The township lies 2 miles ESE of Little Bytham r. station, and 4 SW of Bourn; and has a post-office under Bourn. Acres, 2,150. Real property, &#163;3,045. Pop., 236. Houses, 44. The parish includes Manthorpe, Toft, and Lound hamlets, and comprises 4,210 acres. Pop., 548. Houses, 115. The manor, with W. Hall, belongs to the Johnsons. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;107.* Patrons, the Representatives of the late Gen. Johnson. The church is good, and has a tower and spire. There are a Wesleyan chapel, an endowed school with &#163;24 a year, and charities &#163;232. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/WithamleHill/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301613</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463865</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WITHAM ON THE HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463877</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WITHAM ON THE HILL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11898</id>
   <name>CARLBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12982</id>
   <name>MANTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13976</id>
   <name>TOFT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>22763</id>
<name>SOUTH OF THE WITHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.012019617577</lat>
<lon>-0.100828177985675</lon>
<gazetteerText>Witham, South of the, par., Lincolnshire, pop. 2. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10452624</id>
   <status>ExP/CP</status>
   <name>SOUTH OF THE WITHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
