<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12696</id>
<name>KILLINGHOLME</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6311517295654</lat>
<lon>-0.2494511210058</lon>
<gazetteerText>KILLINGHOLME, a parish, consisting of the two townships of North K. and South K., in Glanford-Brigg district, Lincoln. North K. lies 2 miles NE of Ulceby r. station, 2 W of the Humber, and 9&#189; NW of Great Grimsby; and contains a small straggling village of its own name. Real property, &#163;2, 682. Pop., 181. Houses, 34. South K. lies 1 mile S of North K.; extends to the Humber; contains Ulceby r. station, a small village of its own name, and the hamlet of Ryehill; and has a post office, of the name of Killingholme, under Ulceby, and a small haven on the shore. Real property, &#163;3, 691. Pop., 555. Houses, 117. Acres of the parish, 7, 225; of which 1, 935 are water. The property is subdivided. Brick and tileworks are in South K.; and three lighthouses are on the coast there, two of them erected in 1836, and one in 1852. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Habrough, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;350. Patron, the Earl of Yarborough. The church stands in North K.; and is a neat edifice, with a small tower. Chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, and a subscription school, are in South K. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Killingholme</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Killingholme</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Killingholme/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7290737</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296124</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10427411</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>KILLINGHOLME</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427423</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KILLINGHOLME</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427435</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>NORTH KILLINGHOLME</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427447</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>SOUTH KILLINGHOLME</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
