<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13395</id>
<name>NORTH OWERSBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4403696891062</lat>
<lon>-0.410683152364808</lon>
<gazetteerText>OWERSBY, a village and a parish in Caistor district, Lincoln. The village stands 2&#189; miles E of the river Ancholme, 3 W N W of Usselby r. station, and 4&#190; N W by N of Market-Rasen; and has a post-office under Market-Rasen. The parish is cut into two sections, N and S; and is sometimes regarded as two parishes. Acres of N. O., 4, 718. Real property, &#163;4, 935. Pop. in 1851, 351; in 1861, 421. Houses, 76. The increase of pop. arose from the erection of cottages for local labourers, who previously resided in adjacent parishes. Acres of S. O., 810. Real property, &#163;2,020. Pop. in 1851, 97; in 1861, 76. Houses, 18. The manor belongs to W. Angerstein, Esq. Much improvement was recently effected by taking down old buildings, and replacing them with superior new ones. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Kirkby-Osgodby, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;291.* Patron, W. Anger-stein, Esq. The church is a neat modern edifice, with a tower. There are a Wesleyan chapel, built in 1856; an endowed school, founded in 1705; and a small charity. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/SouthOwersby/</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/NorthOwersby/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641285</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10446170</id>
   <status>CP/CP/AP</status>
   <name>OWERSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446259</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OWERSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446260</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>NORTH OWERSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446296</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>SOUTH OWERSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446326</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OWERSBY WITH KIRKBY AND OSGODBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
