<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14064</id>
<name>WELL</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2417160033735</lat>
<lon>0.160289544165261</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELL, a parish in Spilsby district, Lincoln; 1&#189; mile SSW of Alford r. station. Post town, Alford. Acres, 2,110. Real property, &#163;2,454. Pop., 99. Houses, 17. W. Hall is the residence of T. Cartwright, Esq. There are three ancient British barrows; and about 600 Roman coins, in two urns, were found in 1725. The living is a rectory, united with Claxby, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, the Right Hon. R. A.N. Hamilton. The church is modern, in the form of a Grecian temple. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Well/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Well,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7300399</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463350</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463361</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>14054</id>
<name>WELLINGORE</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0930818428712</lat>
<lon>-0.535139587070415</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELLINGORE, a parish, with a village, in Sleaford district, Lincoln; 1&#189; mile from Navenby r. station, and 9&#189; NW of Sleaford. It has a post-office under Grantham. Acres, 2,400. Real property, &#163;5,807. Pop., 943. Houses, 200. The manor belongs to the Executors of H. Nevile, Esq. W. Hall is a residence of theirs, but nearly unoccupied; and Hill House, of G. Woolhouse, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;206.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of L. The church is good, and has a tower and spire. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Wellingore/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wellingore</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634576</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463154</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WELLINGORE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463166</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELLINGORE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>26162</id>
<name>WELL</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3119745816469</lat>
<lon>-0.707695037860208</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELL, a wapentake in the parts of Lindsey, Lincolnshire; containing 8 parishes and a part. Acres, 18,698. Pop., 3,727. Houses, 826. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10140122</id>
   <status>Wap</status>
   <name>WELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25664</id>
<name>WELLOW</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5602124123814</lat>
<lon>-0.0839053381838742</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELLOW, or Welhove, a hamlet in Great Grimsby parish, Lincoln; near Grimsby. An Augustinian canonry was founded here in the time of Henry I.; and was given, at the dissolution, to Sir T. Henneage. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wellow_Abbey</link>
</links>
</place>
<place>
<id>14052</id>
<name>WELBOURN</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0741858785506</lat>
<lon>-0.559719472344843</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELBOURN, a parish, with a village, in Sleaford district, Lincoln; 7 miles N of Ancaster r. station, and 9 NW of Sleaford. It has a post-office under Grantham. Acres, 3,270. Real property, &#163;5,241. Pop., 664. Houses, 123. The manor belongs to the Countess of Ripon. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;498.* Patron, the Countess of Ripon. The church is early English, with later English clerestory windows, and with a chancel rebuilt in 1854; and has a richly crocketted spire, supported by flying buttresses. There is a Wesleyan chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Welbourn/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welbourn</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634596</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463105</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WELBOURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463117</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELBOURN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
