<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12768</id>
<name>KIRTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9563466433856</lat>
<lon>-0.0899726317211027</lon>
<gazetteerText>KIRTON, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a wapentake in the parts of Holland, Lincoln. The village stands near the Peterborough and Boston railway, 4 miles SSW of Boston; is a large place; was once a market town; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Boston.&#151;The parish contains also Kirton-Fen, and the township of Brothertoft. Acres, 5, 820. Real property, &#163;22, 177. Pop., 2, 255. Houses, 484. The property is much subdivided. Kirton House is the seat of S. Smeeton, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;304. * Patrons, the Mercers&apos; Company, London. The church was founded, in 1311, by Alexander de Blois; was a superb cruciform structnre, in decorated English; became much dilapidated toward the end of last century; was shorn of its transepts, and its Lady chapel in 1809; was, at the same time, partially rebuilt on a smaller scale; has a fine early English W arch, and a later English clerestory of twelve three light windows on each side; and contains an octagonal font of 1405. The donative of Brotherstoft is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Independents and Methodists, a free grammar school, alms houses, and some other charities. The grammar school was originally a free school, founded and endowed in 1624 by Sir Thomas Middlecott; and was recently remodelled and rebuilt.&#151;The sub-district includes only 4, 920 acres of the parish, but contains two other parishes, parts of three more, and an extra-parochial tract; and is in the district of Boston. Acres, 31, 412. Pop., 5, 028. Houses, 1, 085.-The wapen take comprises sixteen parishes and part of another. Acres, 74, 892. Pop. in 1851, 16, 770: in 1861, 18, 938. Houses, 4, 075. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kirton,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645181</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10177959</id>
   <status>Wap</status>
   <name>KIRTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429377</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>KIRTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429420</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KIRTON IN HOLLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547672</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KIRTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11399</id>
   <name>AMBER HILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11567</id>
   <name>BICKER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11768</id>
   <name>BROTHERTOFT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12045</id>
   <name>DONINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12279</id>
   <name>FRAMPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12492</id>
   <name>GREAT HALE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12782</id>
   <name>LANGRIVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13863</id>
   <name>SUTTERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13904</id>
   <name>SWINESHEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>12771</id>
<name>KIRTON IN LINDSEY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4747079686584</lat>
<lon>-0.592929301218602</lon>
<gazetteerText>KIRTON-IN-LINDSEY, a small town and a parish in Glanford-Brigg district, Lincoln. The town stands on a commanding eminence, adjacent to the Manchester and Lincolnshire railway, near Ermine street, 10 miles NE by E of Gainsborough; is an ancient place; and has a head post office, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, a banking office, three chief inns, a court house, a county house of correction, a church, three dissenting chapels, a grammar school, an infant school, and charities &#163;122. The court house is a detached brick building, on KirtonGreen, and is used for manorial courts. The house of correction is a stone structure, of centre and wings; has capacity for 100 male and 22 female prisoners; and includes an apartment which is used both as a meetingplace of quarter sessions, and as a prison chapel. The church is early English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and was thoroughly restored, and partly rebuilt, in 1861. The grammar school was founded, in the time of Elizabeth, by Lady Wray; has two fellowships and six scholarships, which have long been unclaimed; and is now conducted on the national system. A corn market is held on Friday; cattle markets are held on five alternate Saturdays after Good Friday, and on five after the first week of October; and large cattle fairs are held on 18 July and 11 December- The parish comprises 4, 210 acres. Real property, &#163;10, 490; of which &#163;90 are in gas works. Pop., 2, 058. Houses, 460. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to Robert de Mortaigne; passed to Piers Gavestone and the Black Prince; went then to the Duchy of Lancaster; was sold to the late J. J. Angerstein, Esq.; and belongs now to J. W. Pashley, Esq. A tunnel of the railway, 1, 300 yards long, goes through a hill called the Cliff. There are corn mills, a ropery, a brick and tile yard, lime kilns, and an iron ore mine. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;300 **-Patron, the Bishop of Lincoln. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/KirtoninLindsey/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kirton_in_Lindsey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645180</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10429470</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>KIRTON IN LINDSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429481</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KIRTON IN LINDSEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11421</id>
   <name>ATTERBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11937</id>
   <name>CLEATHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11962</id>
   <name>CORRINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12347</id>
   <name>GRAYINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13375</id>
   <name>NORTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13376</id>
   <name>BISHOP NORTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13429</id>
   <name>PILHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13584</id>
   <name>SNITTERBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13646</id>
   <name>SOUTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14081</id>
   <name>WILLOUGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
