<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12307</id>
<name>GEDNEY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8335638121171</lat>
<lon>0.138739391339661</lon>
<gazetteerText>GEDNEY, a village and a parish in Holbeach district, Lincoln. The village stands adjacent to the Spalding and Sutton-Bridge railway, 3&#188; miles E by S of Holbeach; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Wisbeach. The parish contains also the hamlet of Gedney-Hill. Acres, 25, 257; of which 12, 880 are water. Real property, &#163;24, 836. Pop., 2, 459. Houses, 497. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged. anciently to Crowland abbey. Remains of Roman en-trenchments exist; and Roman coins have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;667.* Patron, the Crown. The church was built by the abbots of Crowland; is chiefly perpendicular English; has a tower 86 feet high; measures 160 feet in length, exclusive of the tower; contains an ancient copper lock, with Saxon inscription; and is in a fair condition. The p. curacies of Drove-End and Gedney-Hill are separate benefices. There are chapels for Quakers, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and charities &#163;79. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Gedney/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gedney,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296464</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10417466</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GEDNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10417478</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GEDNEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12308</id>
<name>GEDNEY HILL</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6920668152607</lat>
<lon>-0.0122297537606585</lon>
<gazetteerText>GEDNEY-HILL, a hamlet-chapelry and a sub-district in Holbeach district, Lincoln. The chapelry is in Gedney parish; was constituted a separate charge in last century; lies contiguous to Cambridgeshire, 6&#190; miles E of Crowland, and 9 E by S of Peakirk and Crowland r. station; and has a post office under Wisbeach. Real property, &#163;4, 511. Pop., 466. Houses, 99. The property is much subdivided. Much of the surface is fen. A moated fort of the Romans was here; a Roman road went hence to Spalding; and Roman coins have been found. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;120.* Patron, the Rev. Thomas Clark. The church is old, and was recently in disrepair. There are a Baptist chapel, and charities &#163;353. The sub-district excludes most of Gedney parish; but includes parts of four other parishes. Pop., 2, 994. Houses, 605. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gedney_Hill</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648735</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/GedneyHill/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10417480</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GEDNEY HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10417697</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GEDNEY HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547878</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>GEDNEY HILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
