<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14066</id>
<name>WELTON LE MARSH</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.197345925544</lat>
<lon>0.202639645883968</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELTON-IN-THE-MARSH, a parish, with a village and a hamlet, in Spilsby district, Lincoln; on the East Lincoln railway, 1&#190; mile N of Burgh r. station, and 6 ENE of Spilsby. Post town, Spilsby. Acres, 2,600. Real property, &#163;3,416. Pop., 468. Houses, 91. The manor belongs to Lord Willoughby d&apos;Eresby. Hanby House and Boothby Hall are chief residences. The living is a p. curacy, united with Gunby rectory, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;140. Patrons,L. Massingberd, Esq., and others. The church is a modern brick building. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, and a poors&apos; allotment of nearly 5 acres. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/WeltonleMarsh/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299123</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463385</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WELTON LE MARSH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463397</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELTON LE MARSH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463403</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELTON LE MARSH WITH GUMBY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11860</id>
   <name>CANDLESBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11928</id>
   <name>CLAXBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13555</id>
   <name>SCREMBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>14065</id>
<name>WELTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3106982859076</lat>
<lon>-0.486689464431265</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELTON, a parish, with W. village and Ryland hamlet, in the district and county of Lincoln; 3&#190; miles NW by W of Langworth r. station, and 6 NNE of Lincoln. It has a post-office under Lincoln. Acres, 3,690. Real property, &#163;6,743. Pop., 692. Houses, 150. Portions of land, in lien of former manorial rights, belong to five prebends in Lincoln cathedral. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;450. Patron, the Bishop of L. The church is good; and there are three Methodist chapels, Church schools, and several charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Welton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welton,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634558</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10086541</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WELTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463373</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WELTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>14067</id>
<name>WELTON LE WOLD</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3663414941082</lat>
<lon>-0.0854081865004973</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELTON-LE-WOLD, a parish, with a village, in Louth district, Lincoln; 4 miles W of Louth r. station. Post town, Louth. Acres, 2,520. Real property, &#163;4,065. Pop., 335. Houses, 68. The manor belongs to the Rev. W. Smyth. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;600.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church was enlarged in 1838, and restored in 1850. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/WeltonleWold/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634555</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463415</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WELTON LE WOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463427</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELTON LE WOLD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
