<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14079</id>
<name>WILLOUGHBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2166595675459</lat>
<lon>0.229190408304844</lon>
<gazetteerText>WILLOUGHBY, a village and a parish in Spilsby district, Lincoln. The village stands near the East Lincoln railway, 3 miles SSE of Alford; is supposed to occupy the site of a Roman station; gives, with Eresby, the title of Baron to Lord Willoughby D&apos;Eresby; was the birthplace of Capt. John Smith, of American notoriety; and has a post-office under Spilsby, and a r. station. The parish includes seven hamlets, and comprises 4,280 acres. Real property, &#163;7,733. Pop., 785. Houses, 150. The manor belongs to Lord Willoughby D&apos;Eresby; and the Manor House is the residence of W. Hurdman, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;1,200.* Patron, Lord Willoughby D&apos;Eresby. The church was interiorly restored in 1856. There are a Wesleyan chapel, an endowed school with &#163;25 a year, and charities &#163;16. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Willoughby/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Willoughby,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633892</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463634</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WILLOUGHBY AND SLOOTHBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463660</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WILLOUGHBY WITH SLOOTHBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>14080</id>
<name>SCOTT WILLOUGHBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.928094772635</lat>
<lon>-0.431557109851112</lon>
<gazetteerText>WILLOUGHBY-SCOT, a parish in Sleaford district, Lincoln; 5&#188; miles S by W of Sleaford r. station. Post town, Falkingham Acres, 556. Real property, &#163;993. Pop., 19. Houses, 3. The manor belongs to Earl Brownlow. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;125.* Patron, Earl Brownlow. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/ScottWilloughby/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463646</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SCOTT WILLOUGHBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463658</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SCOTT WILLOUGHBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>14083</id>
<name>SILK WILLOUGHBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9699743194992</lat>
<lon>-0.429576001588801</lon>
<gazetteerText>WILLOUGHBY-SILK, a parish in Sleaford district, Lincoln: 1&#190; mile SSW of Sleaford r. station. Post town, Sleaford. Acres, 2,505. Real property, &#163;3,326. Pop., 237. Houses, 50. The manor belongs to the Earl of Dysart. Bricks and tiles are made. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;650.* Patron, the Earl of Dysart. The church is old but good. There is a parochial school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/SilkWilloughby/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637839</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463713</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SILK WILLOUGHBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463725</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SILK WILLOUGHBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
