<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2742</id>
<name>SOUTH MIMMS</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.6858003471858</lat>
<lon>-0.20450096151357</lon>
<gazetteerText>MIMMS (SOUTH), a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Barnet district, Middlesex. The village stands near the boundary with Herts, 1&#190; mile W of PottersBar r. station, and 3&#189; N by W of Barnet; was anciently called Mymes and Mymmys; and has a post office under Barnet, London N, a police station, a good inn, and a weekly Wednesday market, dating from the time of Henry II., long defunct, and revived in 1851. The parish contains also the village of Potters-Bar, and part of the town of Barnet. Acres, 5,153. Real property, &#163;17,096. Pop. in 1851,2,825; in 1861,3,238. Houses, 650. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the Lenknors; passed to the Scropes and the Windsors; and belongs now to the Marquis of Salisbury. Wrotham Park is the seat of the Earl of Strafford; Dyrham Park, of Capt. J. Trotter; Bridgefoot, of S. O. Percival, Esq.; Norfolk Lodge, of B. F. Smith, Esq.; and Dancers House, of W. R. Price, Esq. The surface is diversified, and the scenery is beautiful. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;310. * Patron, W. P. Hammond, Esq. The church was built in 1130; has a W tower, overgrown with ivy; was recently in disrepair; and contains a piscina and two old brasses. The p. curacies of Potters-Bar and Barnet-Christchurch are separate benefices. There are a Roman Catholic cha pel, two national schools, a British school, an orphan home, a female mission training home, three suites of alms houses, and other charities &#163;18.&#151;The sub-district contains also three parishes electorally in Herts. Acres, 14,186. Pop., 5,381. Houses, 1,104. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/SouthMimms/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Mimms</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26977</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637375</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26981</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26974</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26975</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26976</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26980</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26970</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26971</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26972</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26978</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26982</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26973</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26979</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10052890</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>SOUTH MIMMS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10052920</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH MYMMS CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10071677</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH MYMMS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10072682</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SOUTH MIMMS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10214543</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH MYMMS KING CHARLES THE MARTYR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10217477</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SOUTH MIMMS URBAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10220920</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>SOUTH MIMMS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543733</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOUTH MIMMS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
