<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1341</id>
<name>HILLINGDON</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.5379689475686</lat>
<lon>-0.457023378392501</lon>
<gazetteerText>HILLINGDON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Uxbridge district, Middlesex. The village stands near the Uxbridge railway, the Grand Junction canal, the river Colne, and the boundary with Bucks, 1 mile SE of Uxbridge; was known, at Domesday, as Hillendone; and has a post office under Uxbridge, and a policestation.&#151;The parish contains also the town and township of Uxbridge, the villages of Yiewsley and Colham, and the hamlets of Gould-Green, Peel-Hatch, ColhamGreen, Long Atter, and Hockley Hole; and a detached part of it is encompassed by Ickenham parish. Acres, 4, 720. Real property, &#163;32, 230; of which &#163;200 are in the canal, and &#163;250 in gas works. Pop. in 1851, 9, 588; in 1861, 10, 758. Houses, 2, 052. Pop., exclusive of Uxbridge, in 1851, 6, 352; in 1861, 7, 522. Houses, 1, 424. The increase of pop. arose partly from the erection of barracks. The Uxbridge workhouse is in ColhamGreen; and, at the census of 1861, had 211 inmates. Moorcroft lunatic asylum is in Gould-Green; and, at the census, had 61 inmates. The manor belonged to Roger de Montgomery; passed to the Salisburys, the Lacies, the Stranges, and the Stanleys; and belongs now to the De Burghs. The old manor house has been demolished. An old rectory-house, now extinct, was used by the Bishops of Worcester, who had the rectorial titles. Hillingdon Park, or Little London, belonged to Count de Salis. Cedar House was the seat of Reynardson, the naturalist; and took its name from a cedar tree which, in 1779, measured from 12&#189; to nearly 16 feet in the girth of its stem, and from 89 to 96 feet in the diameter of its head. Other chief residences are Hillingdon House, H. Court, H. Place, H. Grove, Little H. and Dawley Court. Charles I. halted here, in 1646, on his way to the Scottish army. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;489.* Patron, the Bishop of London. The church is later English, in good condition; stands on a commanding eminence at the village; figures conspicuously over many miles; and contains a few brasses and two fine monuments. A chapel of ease, built in 1859, is in Yiewsley. A section of the parish, with a pop. of about 2, 500, was constituted a separate charge in 1865, a vicarage, with income of &#163;230, * in the patronage of the Bishop of London. The church for it bears the name of St. Andrew&apos;s; was built, in 1865, at a cost of &#163;7, 700; is of yellow brick, with red brick in patterns; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with tower and lofty shingle spire. The p. curacies of Uxbridge and Uxbridge-Moor also are separate benefices. There are national and British schools, and charities &#163;878.&#151;The sub-district includes also Cowley and West Drayton parishes, but excludes Uxbridge township. Acres, 5, 870. Pop., 8, 844. Houses, 1, 681. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Hillingdon/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hillingdon</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646895</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22410</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22417</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22414</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22416</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22411</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22412</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22413</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22409</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22415</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10002436</id>
   <status>LB</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10020943</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10052993</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10083928</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10091299</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON EAST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10099316</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HILLINGDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10164746</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON WEST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10212704</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543897</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HILLINGDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575138</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HILLINGDON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>380</id>
<name>UXBRIDGE</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.5463416979736</lat>
<lon>-0.478375766280329</lon>
<gazetteerText>Uxbridge, market town and township, Hillingdon par., Middlesex, on W. border of co. and on river Colne, 16 miles NW. of London by rail - township, 99 ac., pop. 3346; town (containing also part of Hillingdon township and part of Cowley par.), 496 ac., pop. 7669; P.O., T.O., 2 Banks, 2 newspapers. Market-days, Thursday and Saturday. Uxbridge is supposed to have been founded by Alfred, and was the scene of negotiations between Charles I. and the Parliament in 1645. It is well built, and contains an ancient church and a spacious corn exchange. Iron-founding, brick-making, and brewing are carried on, and there is an extensive traffic in corn and flour. Uxbridge gives the title of earl to the Marquis of Anglesey. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Uxbridge</link>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Uxbridge/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uxbridge</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7645989</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635042</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10061544</id>
   <status>MB/UD</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10074794</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10075403</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10107672</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10129205</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154145</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10183418</id>
   <status>CP/Hmlt/Ch</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10208397</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543885</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581588</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740177</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740189</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12742009</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>MIDDLESEX UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12756525</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835188</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>UXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>892</id>
<name>HAYES</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.5158574512708</lat>
<lon>-0.417411079874687</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAYES, or HEESE, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Uxbridge district, Middlesex. The village stands near the Grand Junction canal and the Great Western railway, 3&#189; miles SE of Uxbridge; and has a station on the railway, and a post-office&#8225; under Uxbridge. The parish contains also the precinct of Norwood, and the hamlets of Yeading, Botwell, and Woodend Green. Acres, 5,670. Real property, exclusive of Norwood, &#163;15,193,&#151;of which &#163;2,591 are in railways; inclusive of Norwood, &#163;30,927. Pop., exc. of N., in 1851, 2,076; in 1861, 2,650 ;&#151;inc. of N., in 1851, 4,769; in 1861, 7,134. Houses, exc. of N., 489; inc. of N., 907. The increase of pop. arose partly from the erection of cottages for brick-makers, and partly from the establishment of the Marylebone parochial schools at Southall. The manor belonged, from 830, to the archbishops of Canterbury; had a manor-house, which was often a residence of the archbishops; passed to the Norths, the Jenyns, and others; and is now the Rectory House. Hayes Park, a fine mansion in a well-wooded park, is a lunatic asylum for the middle and upper classes. The living is a rectory in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;700.* Patron, the Rev. W. Randall. The church is early English, with portions of Norman; and contains sedilia, a curious font, and some brasses and monuments. The chapelries of Norwood and Southall are separate benefices. There are chapels for Independents and Baptists, a national school, and charities &#163;378. Bishop Wright and the Greek scholar, P. Young, were rectors.&#151;The sub-district contains also two other parishes. Acres, 14,123. Pop., 9,157. Houses, 1,321. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Hayes/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hayes,_Hillingdon</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647261</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22392</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22394</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22395</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22396</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22398</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22399</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22391</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22393</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22397</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10020890</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAYES ST ANSELM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10130281</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAYES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10166755</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HAYES AND HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10183947</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HAYES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543873</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAYES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12738924</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON HAYES AND HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12753111</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>HAYES AND HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12757530</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>HAYES AND HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833740</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAYES</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>275</id>
   <name>YIEWSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>841</id>
   <name>SOUTHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1341</id>
   <name>HILLINGDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1802</id>
   <name>HARLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2730</id>
   <name>WEST DRAYTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4830</id>
   <name>COWLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5232</id>
   <name>CRANFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5657</id>
   <name>NORWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>5657</id>
<name>NORWOOD</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.4972285628944</lat>
<lon>-0.370508888936643</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORWOOD, a village, a precinct, and a chapelry in Hayes parish, Middlesex. The village stands adjacent to the Grand Junction canal, 1&#189; mile S S E of Southall r.station, and 3 W N W of Brentford; and is a large place. The precinct contains also the hamlets of Norwood-Green, Southall, and Southall-Green, and part of the hamlet of North Hyde; includes the Hanwell, the Southall Park, and Dr. Horsburgh&apos;s lunatic asylums; and has a head post-office, &#8225; of Southall, and a receiving post-office, of the name of Norwood-Green, under Southall. Real property, &#163;15, 734. Pop. in 1851, 2, 693; in 1861, 4, 484. Houses, 418. The manor belongs to Mills, Esq.; Osterley Park, to the Earl of Jersey. Norwood House is the seat of W. Rush, Esq.; Norwood Lodge, of W. Unwin, Esq. The inmates in the lunatic asylums, at the census of 1861, were 1, 517 in the Hanwell, 39 in the Southall Park, and 18 in Dr. Horsburgh&apos;s. The chapelry of Norwood comprises all the precinct except the minor part, which forms the chapelry of Southall. Pop. in 1861, 4,010. The living is a rectory in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, the Rev. H. Worsley. The church is of the 15th century; was well restored in 1864; and has an interesting oakroof, and a curious wooden belfry. There are a freeschool and four alms-houses. The Marylebone parochial schools also are here; and, at the census of 1861, had397 inmates. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/NorwoodPrecinct/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norwood,_Ealing</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6690875</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22401</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22402</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22406</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22405</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22403</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22404</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22407</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22408</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22400</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10003751</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>NORWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10020748</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10202279</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>NORWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12753330</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON RUISLIP NORTHWOOD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
