<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2950</id>
<name>HANWORTH</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.4345641516852</lat>
<lon>-0.391445148513239</lon>
<gazetteerText>HANWORTH, a village and a parish in Staines district, Middlesex. The village stands 2 miles NNW of Hampton r. station, and 5 W by N of Kingston-on-Thames; and has a post office under Hounslow, London W., and a picturesque inn. The parish comprises 1, 390 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 826. Pop., 763. Houses, 169. The property is not much divided. The manor belonged to Ulf, the Saxon; came to the Crown; was the pleasureseat of Queen Catherine Parr; is noted for Queen Elizabeth having lived in it in her youth, and for her having visited it after she ascended the throne; passed to the Killigrews, the Cottingtons, and others; and belongs now to A. Perkins, Esq. An ancient castellated mansion which stood on it was burnt in 1797. Hanworth Park is a principal residence. The living is a rectory in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;451. * Patron, the Rev. O. J. Cresswell. The church was enlarged and mainly rebuilt in 1865. There are a national school, and charities &#163;32. The dramatist Killigrew and the first Lord Berkeley of Stratton, were natives. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Hanworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanworth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647514</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22214</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10071975</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANWORTH ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10083965</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HANWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10089517</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANWORTH ST RICHARD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10210161</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANWORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
