<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4829</id>
<name>NORTHOLT</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.5475459600499</lat>
<lon>-0.367269160979892</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTHOLT, or Northall, a village and a parish in Uxbridge district., Middlesex. The village stands near the Paddington canal, 3 miles N N W of Hanwell r. station, and 4&#190; E of Uxbridge; was known, at Domesday, as Northala; and has a post-office, of the name of Northolt, under Southall. The parish contains also the hamlets of West-End and Wood-End. Acres, 2, 193. Real property, &#163;4, 988; of which &#163;25 are in the canal. Pop. in 1851, 614; in 1861, 658. Houses, 123. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged to the Mandevilles; and passed, through the Botelers and others, to Earl Jersey. A plain in the N W, comprising several square miles, contains only two or three houses, and was the scene of several skirmishes, both in thewars of the Roses and in the civil wars of Charles I. Bricks are made. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;682.* Patron, Brasenose College, Oxford. The church is partly of the 14th century, partly somewhat later; and contains memorials of the Rowdellfamily, Bishop Lisle, who was vicar, and the philosopher Dr. Demainbray. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Northolt/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Northolt</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641290</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22430</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22427</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22431</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22433</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22426</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22428</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22429</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22432</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10097186</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTHOLT PARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10164679</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>NORTHOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10184654</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTHOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10567853</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NORTHOLT</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
