<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1043</id>
<name>HESTON</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.4873407926909</lat>
<lon>-0.370861457714695</lon>
<gazetteerText>HESTON, a village and a parish in Brentford district, Middlesex. The village stands near the Grand Junction canal, 1&#189; mile S of Southall r. station, and 1&#189; N by W of Hounslow; is irregularly built, yet contains good houses and villas; and has a post office under Hounslow, London W, and a fair on 1 May. The parish contains also the hamlets of Sutton, Lampton, Cranford, Scrattage, and Spring Grove, and parts of the hamlet of North Hyde and the town of Hounslow. Acres, 3, 720. Real property, &#163;25, 355; of which &#163;30 are in the canal. Pop. in 1851, 5, 202; in 1861, 7, 096. Houses, 1, 265. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the Crown; was given, by Queen Elizabeth, to Sir T. Gresham; passed to Sir W. Waller and to Child the banker; and belongs now to Earl Jersey. Osterley House was built by Sir T. Gresham; and is a handsome square, redbrick edifice. The land is famous for its wheat; and this, in Queen Elizabeth&apos;s time, was reserved for the Royal table. There are market gardens and extensive brick fields. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;654.* Patron, the Bishop of London. The church is early English; was rebuilt in 1865; and contains a brass of 1650, a tomb of Sir J. Banks, and an octagonal font. The vicarages of Hounslow and SpringGrove are separate benefices. There are a Roman Catholic chapel and orphanage, a large national school, and charities &#163;157. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Heston/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heston</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647027</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22277</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22271</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22276</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22282</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22286</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22278</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22284</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22270</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22273</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22274</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22275</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22279</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22280</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22281</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22283</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22285</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22272</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10020918</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HESTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10074782</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HESTON AND ISLEWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10130323</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HESTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10183959</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HESTON AND ISLEWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10213526</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>HESTON AND ISLEWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12736836</id>
   <status>PBCon/BCon</status>
   <name>HESTON AND ISLEWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12834111</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HESTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>493</id>
<name>FELTHAM</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.443788862032</lat>
<lon>-0.408390821318741</lon>
<gazetteerText>FELTHAM, a village and a parish in Staines district, Middlesex. The village stands on the Richmond Extension railway, near the Longford river, 4&#188; miles E by N of Staines; has a station on the railway with telegraph, and a post office&#8225; under Hounslow, London W; and is a pleasant rural place, environed by many ornate dwellings. The parish comprises 2, 620 acres. Real property, &#163;6, 615. Pop. in 1851, 1, 109; in 1861, 1,837. Houses, 306. The increase of pop. arose partly from the facilities of railway communication with London, and partly from the establishment of industrial and Welsh schools. The manor belonged, at Domesday, to Earl Mortaigne; passed to the Cottingtons, the Beauclercs, and others; was held, in 1537, by Henry VIII.; went to the Veres; and belongs now to Messrs. Barnett and Birch. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;302.* Patron, W. J. Jemmett, Esq. The church occupies the site of an ancient one; was built in 1802, and enlarged in 1856; and has a tower and spire. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans. Charities, &#163;90. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Feltham/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feltham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649571</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22203</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10072153</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FELTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10086991</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>FELTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10165039</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FELTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12737920</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>HOUNSLOW FELTHAM AND HESTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739084</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>FELTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12745760</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>FELTHAM AND HESTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2950</id>
   <name>HANWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
