<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1802</id>
<name>HARLINGTON</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.4917803115111</lat>
<lon>-0.432651682741949</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARLINGTON, a village and a parish in Staines district, Middlesex. The village stands near the Grand Junction Canal. and the Great Western railway, 2&#188; miles SE of West Drayton r. station, and 3&#189; NW by W of Hounslow; was known at Domesday as Herdintone; has a post-office under Hounslow, London W, and a police station; and gave the title of Earl, as Earl Arlington, to Secretary Bennett, who was born here in 1618, and who figured as one of the Cabal after the restoration of Charles II. A fair is held on Whit-Tuesday. The parish comprises 1,414 acres. Real property, &#163;8,641; of which &#163;36 are in the canal, and &#163;1,376 in the railway. Pop. in 1851,872; in 1861,1,159. Houses, 234. The increase of pop. arose from the erection of cottages for brick-makers. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the Lovells; passed to the Bennetts, to Lord Bolingbroke, and to the Berkeleys; and belongs now to Lord Fitzhardinge and Count de Salis. Dawley House was the seat of the Bennetts and of Lord Bolingbroke; and a wing of it still remains. Market-gardening is largely carried on. Hardington Lodge, the seat of the late W. Brown, Esq., stands amid charming grounds. The living is a rectory in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;478.* Patron, the Rev. E. Davison. The church is ancient but good; has a fine Norman door; and contains two brasses of the 16th century, and monuments of the Lovells and the Bennetts. The churchyard contains a yew, of much celebrity, measuring 20 feet in girth of trunk. There are a Baptist chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;70. Bishop Kyte, and Trapp the translator of Virgil, were rectors. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Harlington/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harlington,_London</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7522532</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22367</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22364</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22368</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22370</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22360</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22361</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22362</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22365</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22366</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22363</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22369</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10020840</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10130244</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>892</id>
<name>HAYES</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.5158574512708</lat>
<lon>-0.417411079874687</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAYES, or HEESE, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Uxbridge district, Middlesex. The village stands near the Grand Junction canal and the Great Western railway, 3&#189; miles SE of Uxbridge; and has a station on the railway, and a post-office&#8225; under Uxbridge. The parish contains also the precinct of Norwood, and the hamlets of Yeading, Botwell, and Woodend Green. Acres, 5,670. Real property, exclusive of Norwood, &#163;15,193,&#151;of which &#163;2,591 are in railways; inclusive of Norwood, &#163;30,927. Pop., exc. of N., in 1851, 2,076; in 1861, 2,650 ;&#151;inc. of N., in 1851, 4,769; in 1861, 7,134. Houses, exc. of N., 489; inc. of N., 907. The increase of pop. arose partly from the erection of cottages for brick-makers, and partly from the establishment of the Marylebone parochial schools at Southall. The manor belonged, from 830, to the archbishops of Canterbury; had a manor-house, which was often a residence of the archbishops; passed to the Norths, the Jenyns, and others; and is now the Rectory House. Hayes Park, a fine mansion in a well-wooded park, is a lunatic asylum for the middle and upper classes. The living is a rectory in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;700.* Patron, the Rev. W. Randall. The church is early English, with portions of Norman; and contains sedilia, a curious font, and some brasses and monuments. The chapelries of Norwood and Southall are separate benefices. There are chapels for Independents and Baptists, a national school, and charities &#163;378. Bishop Wright and the Greek scholar, P. Young, were rectors.&#151;The sub-district contains also two other parishes. Acres, 14,123. Pop., 9,157. Houses, 1,321. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Hayes/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hayes,_Hillingdon</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647261</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22392</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22394</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22395</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22396</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22398</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22399</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22391</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22393</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22397</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10020890</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAYES ST ANSELM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10130281</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAYES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10166755</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HAYES AND HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10183947</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HAYES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543873</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAYES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12738924</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>HILLINGDON HAYES AND HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12753111</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>HAYES AND HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12757530</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>HAYES AND HARLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833740</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAYES</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>275</id>
   <name>YIEWSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>841</id>
   <name>SOUTHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1341</id>
   <name>HILLINGDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1802</id>
   <name>HARLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2730</id>
   <name>WEST DRAYTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4830</id>
   <name>COWLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5232</id>
   <name>CRANFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5657</id>
   <name>NORWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
