<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1799</id>
<name>MONKEN HADLEY</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.6637839039402</lat>
<lon>-0.198234065313301</lon>
<gazetteerText>HADLEY, or MONKEN HADLEY, a village and a parish in Barnet district, Middlesex. The village stands on high ground, near Enfield chase, the Great Northern railway, and the boundary with Herts, 1 mile NNE of Barnet; is a pretty rural place; and has a post office under Barnet, London N. The parish includes also part of the High street of Barnet. Acres, 2, 530. Real property, &#163;5, 194; of which &#163;100 are in gas works. Pop. 1, 053. Houses, 200. The manor was given, by Geoffrey de Mandeville, to Walden abbey; and, by Henry VIII., to Lord Audley. Hadley House is a chief residence. The high land around the village once formed a part of Enfield chase. The battle between the Yorkists and the Lancastrians in 1471, was fought partly within the parish; and is commemorated by an obelisk, erected in 1740. The living is a donative in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;199.* Patron, the Rev. F.Cass. The church is ancient and cruciform; has a western square tower, built of flint with stone coins, and bearing the date 1494; was thoroughly restored in 1848; and contains several interesting monuments. Au iron beacon is on the top of the tower; supposed to have been used for a signal light to moving monks or armies; and was last illuminated on the occasion of the Prince of Wales&apos; marriage. There are a Weslcyan chapel, national and infant schools, two suites of alms houses with &#163;120, and other charities with &#163;12. Staunford, the lawyer, and Atkyns, the historian of Gloucestershire, were natives. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Hadley/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monken_Hadley</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26969</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26968</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26966</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26964</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26967</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26963</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=26965</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10020530</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MONKEN HADLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10148078</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HADLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10206900</id>
   <status>EExP</status>
   <name>MONKEN HADLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
