<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1798</id>
<name>STANWELL</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.4570538889545</lat>
<lon>-0.488216787147546</lon>
<gazetteerText>STANWELL, a village and a parish in Staines district, Middlesex. The village stands 2&#188; miles NE of Staines r. station, and has a post-office under Staines. The parish contains also Staines workhouse, Poyle hamlet, and part of Colnbrook. Acres, 3,963. Real property, &#163;11,012. Pop., 1,714. Houses, 314. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged, from the Norman conquest till 1541, to the Windsors; went then, by an exchange, to the Crown; was the death-place of the Princess Mary, daughter of James I.; passed to the Knyvets and the Falklands; and, with S. Place, belongs now to Sir J. Gibbons, Bart. There are paper mills, and two large flour mills. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is later English and good. There are an Independent chapel, an endowed school with &#163;40 a year, a national school for girls, and charities &#163;220. Judge Nares was a native; and Ryves, the author of &quot;Mercurins Rusticus,&apos;&apos; was vicar. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Stanwell/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanwell</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637035</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22244</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22238</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22239</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22241</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22242</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22245</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22246</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22240</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22243</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22247</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10020232</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>STANWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10071409</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STANWELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
