<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1148</id>
<name>MALLWYD</name>
<container>MERIONETHSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7102901209791</lat>
<lon>-3.71516150513242</lon>
<gazetteerText>MALLWYD, a village and a parish in the district of Dolgelly; the village and most of the parish in Merioneth, the rest of the parish in Montgomery. The village stands on the river Dyfi, and near the Mowddwy rail way which was in course of formation in 1867, amid highly picturesque environs, 2 miles SSE of Dinas-Moeddwy: has a good inn; is a favourite resort of anglers; and has been termed the paradise of artists. Evans describes it as &quot;placed between the salient angles of three abrupt mountains, which form a grand natural amphitheatre, Camlan rising with rude majesty immediately opposite, and the conical Aran lifting up its head, with its different cwms, and reflected with varying tint and shade in the waters of the Dyfi.&quot; The Merioneth section of the parish contains also the townships of Camlan, Cerist, Dinas, Dugoed, Gartheing, and Maesyglasey; and the Montgomery section consists of the township of Caereinion-fechan. Posttown, Dinas-Mowddwy, under Cemmaes, Montgomery. Acres of the Merioneth section, 14,556. Real property &#163;3,699. Pop. in 1851,1,085; in 1861,938. Houses, 207. Acres of the Montgomery section, 1,894. Real property, &#163;707. Pop. in 1851,116; in 1861,111. Houses, 22. The property is much subdivided. A remarkably picturesque waterfall is on the Dyfi at Pont-Vallwyd, a short distance from the village. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;340.* Patron, the Bishop of Bangor. The church is substantial; and the churchyard contain. some venerable yews, one of which has a girth of 23 feets There are a Calvinistic Methodist chapel, and charities &#163;12. Dr. Davies, the author of a dictionary, was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mallwyd</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MER/Mallwyd/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643147</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10241364</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MALLWYD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10413035</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MALLWYD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
