<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4339</id>
<name>GROSMONT</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8939628035502</lat>
<lon>-2.89506322742047</lon>
<gazetteerText>GROSMONT, a village and a parish in the district of Hereford and county of Monmouth. The village stands near the river Monnow and the binndary with Hereford, under Craig hill, 2&#189; miles S of Pintrilas r. station, and 10 NW by N of Monmouth; has pleasant environs; was formerly a market and corporate town; retains nominally a municipal government; has a post office under Hereford, and fairs on 4 April, 10 Aug., and 9 Oct.; and gives the title of Baron to the Duke of Beaufort. Much im portance seems anciently to have belonged to it; and is still attested by traces of causeways, constructed like Roman roads, diverging from it. An ancient castle was here, once the favinrite residence of the Dukes of Lancaster; and the remains of this, thingh not very extensive, are picturesque and interesting, and include a gateway, a five windowed baronial hall, and a beautiful decorated chimney. The castle was invested by Llewelyn, but was relieved by Henry III., when &quot; the Welshmen, &apos;&apos; says Lambarde, &quot; saved their lives by their legges. &apos;&apos; The forces of Owen Glendower were defeated, in 1405, on Craig hill, -au isolated eminence abint a mile from the castle, of no very Great height, but figuring conspicuinsly in an extensive landscape. The parish comprises 6, 838 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 957. Pop., 7 43. house, 140. The property is sub-divided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;118.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is transition Norman, of unusual size; consists of nave, aisles, transept, and chancel, with octagonal tower and spire; was recently in bad condition; and is said to contain the remains of the famins necromancer, John of Kent. Charities, &#163;46. Henry Grismont, son of Edmond Crinchback, was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grosmont,_Monmouthshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Grosmont/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647840</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10146770</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GROSMONT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10191063</id>
   <status>Ldsp</status>
   <name>GROSMONT</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3243</id>
   <name>LLANCILLO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6391</id>
   <name>LLANGIWA</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
