<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10919</id>
<name>LLANVIHANGEL PONT Y MOILE</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7061883942438</lat>
<lon>-3.00596119934047</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANVIHANGEL-PONT-Y-MOILE, a parish in Pontypool district, Monmouth; on the Brecon canal, adjacent to the Abergavenny and Pontypool railway, 1 mile E of Pontypool. Post town, Pontypool. Acres, 1,651. Real property, &#163;1,598. Pop. in 1851,205; in 1861,300. Houses, 53. The property is divided among a few. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;87. Patron,H. Leigh, Esq. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10193631</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL PONT Y MOEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10380996</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANVIHANGEL PONT Y MOILE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2490</id>
<name>LLANVIHANGEL NEAR ROGGIETT</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5868045146953</lat>
<lon>-2.79250940308088</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANVIHANGEL-NEAR-ROGGIETT, a parish in Chepstow district, Monmouth; on the South Wales railway, 1&#190; mile ENE of Magor r. station, and 6&#189; SW by W of Chepstow. Post town, Chepstow. Acres, 557. Rated property, &#163;755. Pop., 36. Houses, 7. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Roggiett, in the diocese of Llandaff. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/LlanvihangelNearRoggiett/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643922</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10060588</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANVIHANGEL NEAR ROGGIETT</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>10800</id>
<name>LLANFIHANGEL CRUCORNAU</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8820064065957</lat>
<lon>-2.97029636201912</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANVIHANGEL-CRUCORNEY, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Abergavenny district, Monmouth. The village stands on the river Monnow, adjacent to the Abergavenny and Hereford railway, near the boundary with Hereford, and under Skirrid-fawr mountain, 1 mile NNE of Llanfihangel r. station, and 4&#189; NNE of Abergavenny; and has a post office under Abergavenny.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlet o Penbiddle, and comprises 3,264 acres. Real property, &#163;3,579; of which &#163;215 are on the railway. Pop., 479. Houses, 103. The property is much subdivided. Llanvihangel Court belonged to the Arnolds; passed, in the time of Queen Anne, to the Harleys; belongs now to the Hon. W. Rodney; is an ancient edifice; and has a remarkably grand avenue of firs. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;281. Patron, the Prince of Wales. The church is good. Charities, &#163;4.&#151;The sub-district contains also six other parishes. Acres, 20,510. Pop., 1,860. Houses, 402. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/LlanvihangelCrucorney/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643924</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10165179</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL CRUCORNAU</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377780</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL CRUCORNAU</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549322</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANVIHANGEL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4119</id>
   <name>WALTERSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6212</id>
   <name>BWLCH TRE WYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10793</id>
   <name>LLANGATWG LINGOED</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10804</id>
   <name>OLDCASTLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14565</id>
   <name>CWMYOY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>10801</id>
<name>LLANFIHANGEL Y GOFION</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7821445050684</lat>
<lon>-2.94519107996893</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANVIHANGEL-NIGH-USK, a parish in Abergavenny district, Monmouth; on the river Usk, 2&#189; miles NNE of Nantyderry r. station, and 4&#189; miles SE of Aber gavenny. Post town, Usk, under Newport, Monmouth Acres, 385. Real property, &#163;721. Pop., 112. Houses, 24. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;123. Patrons, Sir S. Fludyer, Bart. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/LlanvihangelNighUsk/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10377810</id>
   <status>AP/Ch/CP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL Y GOFION</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1382</id>
<name>LLANFIHANGEL LLANTARNAM</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6395809268925</lat>
<lon>-3.0292518554506</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANVIHANGEL-LLANTARNAM, a parish in Newport district, Monmouth; on the river A fon-Llwyd, an affluent of the Usk, adjacent to the Eastern Valleys railway, 3&#189; miles N of Newport. It has a station, of the name of Llantarnam, on the railway; and its Post town is Caerleon, under Newport, Monmouth. Acres, 4,092. Real property, &#163;6,1 00; of which &#163;1,000 are in ironworks, and &#163;13 on the railway. Pop. in 1851,1,228; in 1861, 1,301. Houses, 263. The property is much subdivided. A Cistertian abbey stood here; and was given, at the dissolution, to the Morgans. Llantarnam House was built from the materials of the abbey; is a Tudor edifice; belonged, for a time, to the Morgans; and is now the seat of E. Blewitt, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;108. Patron, E. Blewitt, Esq. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/LlanvihangelLlantarnam/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10000403</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL LLANTARNAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1141</id>
   <name>LLANTARNAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>10812</id>
<name>LLANVIHANGEL TOR Y MYNYDD</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7106254789939</lat>
<lon>-2.77704449720539</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANVIHANGEL-TOR-Y-MYNYDD, a parish in Chepstow district, Monmouth; 3&#189; miles ESE of Llandenny r. station and 5&#190; E by N of Usk. Post town, Chepstow. Acres, 1,031. Real property, &#163;1,056. Pop., 197. Houses, 45. The property is subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;89. Patron, the Archdeacon of Llandaff. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10151855</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL TORYMYNYDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10378035</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANVIHANGEL TOR Y MYNYDD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>6806</id>
<name>MICHAELSTON Y VEDW</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5533056842106</lat>
<lon>-3.09397583635001</lon>
<gazetteerText>MICHAELSTONE-Y-VEDW, a hamlet and a parish in the district of Newport; the hamlet in Monmouth, the parish partly also in Glamorgan. The hamlet lies on the river Rumney, at the boundary with Glamorgan, 2&#189; miles NW of Marshfield r. station, and 5 SW of Newport. Acres, 1,134. Real property, &#163;1,110. Pop., 203. Houses, 43. The parish contains also the hamlet of Llanvedw, which is its Glamor.gan portion. Acres of that hamlet, 2,299. Real property, &#163;1,962. Pop., 309. Houses, 62. Post town, Newport, Monmouth. The property is divided between two. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;500. * Patron, Col.K. K. Tynte. The church is good. There are an endowed school with &#163;64 a year, and charities &#163;11. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/MichaelstoneYFedw/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10243877</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MICHAELSTON Y VEDW</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>10893</id>
<name>PEN Y CLAWDD</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7670104972457</lat>
<lon>-2.80054400363789</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENYCLAWDD, a parish in the district and county of Monmouth; 1&#189; mile S W of Dingestow r. station, and 4&#190; S W of Monmouth. Post-town, Raglan, under New-port, Monmouth. Acres, 614. Real property, &#163;385. Pop., 53. Houses, 11. The property is subdivided. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the p. curacy of Llangoven, in the diocese of Llandaff. The church is ancient but good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/PenYClawdd/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640384</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10289531</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PEN CLAWDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10380066</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PEN Y CLAWDD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>8231</id>
<name>MITCHELL TROY</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7861670572391</lat>
<lon>-2.73083057080934</lon>
<gazetteerText>MITCHEL-TROY, or ST. MICHAEL-TROY, a village and a parish in the district and county of Monmouth. The village stands on the river Trothy, adjacent to the Monmouth and Pontypool railway, 2 miles SW by S of Monmouth; takes the latter part of its name, by corruption, from the Trothy; and has a post office, called Mitchell-Troy, under Monmouth. The parish comprises 2,000 acres. Real property, 2,858. Pop., 385. Houses, 85. The property is much subdivided. Troy House belongs to the Duke of Beaufort; stands by the side of the Trothy, under the shelter of a hill; has a huge roof; is said to have been built by Inigo Jones; contains some family portraits of the Herberts, the Somersets, and others, including one of Lord Herbert of Cherbury when a boy; contains also a good specimen of Tudor ceiling, a panelling of the time of James I., an old oak chimney-piece curiously carved with Scripture subjects, and a suite of armour said to have been worn by Henry V. at Agincourt, but apparently of more recent date. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Cumcarvan, in the diocese of Llandaff. Valne, &#163;398.* Patron, the Duke of Beaufort. The church is ancient, with a tower; and was reported in 1859 as bad. The churchyard contains an ancient cross. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/MitchelTroy/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642410</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10282457</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MITCHELL TROY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10515634</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>MITCHELL TROY UNITED</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9504</id>
   <name>WONASTOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>10875</id>
<name>LLANVIHANGEL YSTERN LLEWERN</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8289100182075</lat>
<lon>-2.83255645497806</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANVIHANGEL-YSTERN-LLEWERN, a parish in the district and county of Monmouth; on the river Trothy, 3&#190; miles N by W of Raglan Footpath r. station, and 5 WNW of Monmouth. Post town, Monmouth. Acres, 1,864. Real property, &#163;1,810. Pop., 183. Houses, 29. The property is divided among a few. Much of the land is meadow and orchard. A barn of Grace Dieu Cistertian abbey was here. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;211.* Patron, the Earl of Abergavenny. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10040887</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL YSTUM LLYWERN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10379477</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANVIHANGEL YSTERN LLEWERN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
