<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8928</id>
<name>CHOLLERTON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.0807098272033</lat>
<lon>-2.11628374226838</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHOLLERTON, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Hexham district, Northumberland. The township lies on the North Tyne river and the Border Counties railway, adjacent to the Roman wall, 6&#188; miles NNW of Hexham; has a station on the railway; and includes the villages of Whiteside-Law and Little Swinburn. Acres, 2, 817. Pop., 151. Houses, 26. The parish contains also the township of Barrasford, which has a post office under Hexham; and the townships of Colwell and Swinburn, and Gunnerton and Chipchase. Acres, 12, 950. Real property, &#163;23, 657. Pop., 1, 156. Houses, 232. The property is subdivided. Swinburn and Chipchase are modern seats on the site of ancient castles. A victory was obtained in the south, at the Roman wall, in 635, by King Oswald over Ceadwallon. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;361.* Patron, the Rev.Bird. The church is good. The vicarage of Birtley is a separate benefice. -The sub-district contains three parishes, part of another, a parochial chapelry, and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 46, 230. Pop., 5, 365. Houses, 1, 013. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chollerton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Chollerton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653097</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10306450</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CHOLLERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10306462</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHOLLERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551766</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHOLLERTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
