<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>626</id>
<name>NEWBURN</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.9919308780678</lat>
<lon>-1.72784302003372</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWBURN, a village, a township, and a parish, in Castle Ward district, Northumberland. The village stands on the river Tyne, near the Roman wall, 1 mile N E of Ryton r. station, and 5&#188; W N W of Newcastle; was styled a borough in the time of King John; containsextensive steel-works; and has a post-office under Blaydon-on-Tyne. The township comprises 635 acres ofland and 155 of water. Pop. in 1851, 938; in 1861, 1,008. Houses, 198. The parish contains also the townships of Newburn-Hall, Sugley, Throckley, Wall-bottle, East Denton, West Denton, Newbiggin, East and West Whorlton, Butterlaw, Black-Callerton, South Dissington, North Dissington, and Dalton. Acres, 11, 566. Real property, &#163;26, 586; of which &#163;645 are in mines, and &#163;4,000 in iron-works. Pop. in 1851, 4, 307; in 1861, 4, 619. Houses, 923. The property is not muchdivided. The manor belongs to the Duke of Northumberland. Copsi, in 1072, when quarrelling with Osulph about the earldom of Northumberland, fled from him to Newburn, took refuge in the church, and was murderedby him when attempting to escape. The Scottish army, in 1 640, planted their cannon on the Newburn side of the Tyne; crossed the river, under cover of its fire, to Stellahaugh; and there defeated the royal army under Lord Conway. Coal is largely worked; and several coal-staiths, iron-works, glass-works, chemical-works, brick and tile manufactories, and a paper mill are on the banks of the river. George Stephenson, when a raw lad, drovethe &quot;gin&quot; at Black-Callerton colliery; and he was married to his first wife in Newburn church. Salmon preserves, belonging to the Duke of Northumberland, are at Newburn and Lemington Point. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelries of Holy Trinity and St. Saviour, in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;230.* Patron, the Bishop of Durham. The church is ancient and cruciform, with a tower; was restored, partly rebuilt, and considerably enlarged in 1827; and contains monuments of the Delavals. There are a chapel of ease, a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;24. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Newburn/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newburn</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641690</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10004561</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>NEWBURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10024729</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>NEWBURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10108949</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>NEWBURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10324063</id>
   <status>CP/Tn/AP</status>
   <name>NEWBURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10324087</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWBURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10324099</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>NEWBURN HALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551985</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NEWBURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833490</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NEWBURN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4285</id>
   <name>STELLA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8878</id>
   <name>HIGH CALLERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8957</id>
   <name>EAST DENTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9075</id>
   <name>WEST DENTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9403</id>
   <name>KENTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9691</id>
   <name>SUGLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9711</id>
   <name>THROCKLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9745</id>
   <name>WALLBOTTLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9789</id>
   <name>WHORLTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9800</id>
   <name>WOOLSINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
