<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>982</id>
<name>WALLSEND</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.9991765143636</lat>
<lon>-1.52335412528076</lon>
<gazetteerText>WALLSEND, a township and a parish in Tynemouth district, Northumberland. The township lies on the river Tyne and on the Newcastle and Tynemonth railway, at the E end of the Roman wall, 3&#189; miles ENE of Newcastle; took its name from its position at the end of the wall; contained the Roman Segedunum, where Roman pottery, inscriptions, coins, an altar to Jupiter, and other Roman relics have been found; became noted, in last century, for coal-workings of prime quality, which yielded an average profit of &#163;20,000 annually for twenty years, but became unprofitable and were abandoned in 1853; contains a village of its own name; and has a post-office under Newcastle-upon-Tyne, a r. station, a church of 1809, U. Presbyterian and Methodist chapels, a free school, two blast furnaces, forge-works, lead and copper smelting-works, and two chemical manufactories. Pop. in 1851, 2,161; in 1861, 2,371. Houses, 501. The parish includes two other townships; forms a sub-district; and comprises 2,579 acres of land and 208 of water. Real property, &#163;17,335; of which &#163;600 are in ironworks. Pop. in 1851, 5,721; in 1861, 6,715. Houses, 1,079. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;300.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of D. The p. curacies of Willington and Howdon-Pans are separate benefices. The painter Martin was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wallsend</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Wallsend/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634864</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10004585</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WALLSEND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186626</id>
   <status>MB/UD</status>
   <name>WALLSEND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329620</id>
   <status>Ch/CP/AP</status>
   <name>WALLSEND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329670</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WALLSEND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329681</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WALLSEND ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329693</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WALLSEND ST LUKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551924</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WALLSEND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740360</id>
   <status>PBCon/BCon</status>
   <name>WALLSEND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12832631</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WALLSEND</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
