<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9761</id>
<name>WARKWORTH</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.3256447719168</lat>
<lon>-1.62185399751094</lon>
<gazetteerText>WARKWORTH, a village, a township, and a sub-district, in Alnwick district, and a parish partly also in Morpeth district, Northumberland. The village stands on the river Coquet, 1&#188; mile from the river&apos;s month, 1&#188; mile E of the Northeastern railway, and 7 SE by S of Alnwick; is a borough by prescription, governed by a portreeve; gives the title of Baron to the Duke of Northumberland; comprises three streets; and has a post-office under Acklington, a r. station, an inn, an old three-arched bridge, an old market-cross, an ancient castle, a church, a U. Presbyterian chapel, a bar-harbour, with a fixed pier light, a small weekly market on Saturday, and a fair on the Thursday after 23 Nov. The castle was built in the 12th century, by a Fitz-Richard, but then left unfinished; underwent, in course of time, many changes of form and proprietorship; was greatly enlarged in 1400-7 and in 1435-40, by the Percys; sustained a siege, in 1405, by Henry IV.; figures in Shakespear&apos;s drama of Henry IV.; belongs now to the Duke of Northumberland; was partly restored in 1846, and promised for a time to compete with Alnwick castle for complete restoration as the ducal residence; occupies a triangular area of 5 acres; and presents an imposing appearance of lofty walls, towers, turrets, and great keep, but is mainly ruinous. The church is partly Norman, was recently restored, and has a tower and spire. A Benedictine priory, a cell to Durham, stood near the church, and was founded in 1256 by Bishop Barnham. An ancient hermitage, &quot;deep hewn within a craggy cliff,&quot; is on the river&apos;s banks about a mile above the castle; appears to be of the time of Edward II.; measures 18 feet by 7, exclusive of a sacristy 13 feet by 5; and is celebrated in Bishop Percy&apos;s well-known ballad of the &quot;Hermit of Warkworth.&quot;-The township comprises 1,078 acres of land, and 2,560 of water. Pop. in 1851, 834; in 1861, 730. Houses, 114.&#151;The sub-district contains 14 townships of W. parish, and 13 of other parishes. Acres, 31,864. Pop. in 1851, 7,413; in 1861, 7,631. Houses, 1,493.-The parish, besides its 14 townships of W. sub-district, contains 4 townships in Morpeth district; and comprises 19,365 acres. Real property, &#163;21,539; of which &#163;18 are in quarries, &#163;2,610 in mines, &#163;240 in fisheries, and &#163;10 in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 4,439; in 1861, 5,087. Houses, 960. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;528.* Patron, the Bishop of Carlisle. The p. curacies of Acklington and Chevington are separate benefices. Independent and Roman Catholic chapels are in Amble; and a Methodist chapel is at Radcliffe colliery. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warkworth,_Northumberland</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Warkworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634762</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10133737</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WARKWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329930</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WARKWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329954</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WARKWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551791</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WARKWORTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9181</id>
   <name>GLOSTER HILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9509</id>
   <name>MORWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9742</id>
   <name>WALKMILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>9757</id>
<name>WARK</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.0899895079052</lat>
<lon>-2.3337012737344</lon>
<gazetteerText>WARK, a village, a township, and a parish, in Bellingham district, Northumberland. The village stands on the North Tyne river, near the Border Counties railway, 4&#188; miles SSE of Bellingham; and has a post-office under Hexham, and a r. station. The township comprises 3,160 acres. Pop., 546. Houses, 132.&#151;The parish includes three other townships, and comprises 22,986 acres. Real property, &#163;7,891. Pop., 899. Houses, 197. The property is much subdivided. A seat of the Ratcliffes was at Mote Hill. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;340.* Patron, Greenwich Hospital. The church was built in 1818. There are an English Presbyterian chapel, a Wesleyan chapel, a free school, and a charity of &#163;200 a year partly expended on the school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wark_on_Tyne</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wark_on_Tweed</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Wark/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7291478</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10329826</id>
   <status>AP/CP/Ch</status>
   <name>WARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329840</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WARK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8927</id>
   <name>CHIRDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9676</id>
   <name>SMALESMOUTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9706</id>
   <name>THORNEYBURN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17240</id>
   <name>TYNEDALE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>21339</id>
<name>WARK</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.6406357100658</lat>
<lon>-2.28122427618524</lon>
<gazetteerText>WARK, or Werk, a hamlet, with a r. station, in Carham parish, Northumberland; on the river Tweed, and on the Tweedmouth and Kelso railway, 2&#189; miles W by S of Cornhill. The manor belonged to the De Roses, passed to the Greys, and belongs now to the Earl of Tankerville. W. Castle sustained eleven sieges by the Scots; was seven times taken; is alleged to have originated the noble order of the Garter, at a ball given by Edward III.; and is now represented by only ramparts and outworks. The ballad of the &quot;Hermit of Warkworth&quot; says- All pale, extended on their shields, And weltering in his gore, Lord Percy&apos;s knights their bleeding friend To Wark&apos;s fair castle bore. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634766</link>
</links>
</place>
<place>
<id>22593</id>
<name>WARKSBURN</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.0852827331437</lat>
<lon>-2.26948051013428</lon>
<gazetteerText>WARKSBURN, a township in Wark parish, Northumberland; 2 miles NNW of Wark village. Acres, 9,925. Pop., 199. Houses, 37. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634764</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10329929</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>WARKSBURN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
