<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9167</id>
<name>FORD</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.6325769967706</lat>
<lon>-2.10486884091472</lon>
<gazetteerText>FORD, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Glendale district, Northumberland. The village stands on the river Till, 6&#188; miles ESE of Cornhill r. station, and 7&#189; NNW of Wooler; was once a market-town; consists of neat modern cottages, in one irregular street; commands a fine view along the valley of the Till; and has a post office under Coldstream. The parish contains also the villages of Etal and Ford-Forge. Acres, 11, 464. Real property, &#163;18, 270; of which &#163;500 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 2, 322; in 1861, 2, 072. Houses, 407. The decrease of pop. was occasioned by the closing of a colliery, and the reducing of an extensive spade and shovel factory. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged anciently to the Fords; passed to the Herons, the Blakes, and the Delavals; and belongs now to the Marquis of Waterford. Ford Castle stands on the west side of the village; was built in 1287, by Sir William Heron, rebuilt in 1764, by Lord Delaval, and restored in 1863, by the Marchioness of Waterford; retains two towers of the original edifice; was a place of strength and a scene of conflict, in the Border warfare; and was taken by James IV. of Scotland before the battle of Flodden. Coal, slate, limestone, and freestone are found. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;1, 380.* Patron, the Marquis of Waterford. The church is ancient; was restored in 1852; and contains the tomb of Lord Frederick Fitzclarence, who died in 1854. The p. curacy of Etal is a separate charge. There are three dissenting chapels, and a national school. -The sub-district contains also three other parishes and part of a fourth. Acres, 59, 774. Pop., 6, 833. Houses, 1, 321. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ford,_Northumberland</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649236</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Ford/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10315888</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10315920</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FORD WITH ETAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551869</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FORD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2396</id>
   <name>FELKINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4207</id>
   <name>GRINDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5187</id>
   <name>DUDDO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9319</id>
   <name>HOWTEL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9407</id>
   <name>KILHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9576</id>
   <name>NORHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9600</id>
   <name>PASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9729</id>
   <name>TWIZELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>26657</id>
<name>FORD FORGE</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.6382256653295</lat>
<lon>-2.09214678579404</lon>
<gazetteerText>FORD-FORGE, a village in Ford parish, Northumberland; on the river Till, about 1&#189; mile from Ford village. It has a factory of spades and shovels. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ford_Forge</link>
</links>
</place>
</results>
