<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>21089</id>
<name>ST JOHN LEE</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.9857781804157</lat>
<lon>-2.10471214198253</lon>
<gazetteerText>JOHN-LEE (ST.), a parish in Hexham district, Northumberland; on the river Tyne, the Border Counties railway, and the Roman wall, immediately N of Hexham. It adjoins Hexham bridge, in the neighbourhood of Hexham r. station; it contains Acomb township, with a village 1&#188; mile NNW of that bridge, and with a postoffice under Hexham; and it contains also the townships of Portgate, Sandhoe, Anick, Anick-Grange, Fallowfield, Cocklaw, Bingfield, Hallington, and Wall, the last of which has a station on the Border Counties railway. Acres, 15, 090. Real property, &#163;19, 264; of which &#163;1, 099 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 2, 073; in 1861, 2, 254. Houses, 401. The increase of pop. was chiefly in Acomb township, and arose from the extension of lead mines, and the opening of a new colliery. The property is not much divided. The manor belongs to W. B. Beaumont, Esq. Lee Hall belonged to the Jarins and the Coatesworths, and passed to the Charltons. Hermitage is the seat of Mrs. Allgood. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Durham. Valne, &#163;280. Patron, W. B. Beaumont, Esq. The church is in Acomb township stands on the wooded brow of an extensive tableau, overlooking the Tyne valley; has a fine spire, figuring conspicuously in the beautiful landscape around Hexham; is ancient, and very good; and occupies the site of an oratory of St. John of Beverley, which used to be visited annually by the monks of Hexham in solemn procession. There are chapels of ease at Wall and Bingfield, a Wesleyan chapel at Acomb, and an endowed school with &#163;12 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10322157</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LEE ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10322194</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST JOHN LEE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
