<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1715</id>
<name>CARLETON ST PETER</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5688119886621</lat>
<lon>1.46098022254465</lon>
<gazetteerText>CARLETON-ST. PETER, a parish in Loddon district, Norfolk; near the river Yare; 3 miles NNW of Loddon, and 3&#189; SW by S of Buckenham r. station. Post Town, Loddon, under Norwich. Acres, 772. Real property, &#163;1,159. Pop., 79. Houses, 18. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Ashby, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;294. Patrons, Sir W. B. Proctor and SirH. Rich, Barts. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/c/carleton_st_peter/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015868</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CARLETON ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10502238</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CARLETON ST PETER</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2315</id>
<name>CARLETON FOREHOE</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6111962365124</lat>
<lon>1.08960494271312</lon>
<gazetteerText>CARLETON-FOREHOE, a parish in Forehoe district, Norfolk; on the river Yare, 2 miles NE of Kimberley r. station, and 3&#189; N by W of Wymondham. Post Town, Wymondham. Acres, 772. Real property, &#163;1,732. Pop., 124. Houses, 25. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, Lord Wodehouse. The church is later English, with a square tower; and was repaired in 1839. Charities, &#163;26. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/c/carleton_forehoe/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050406</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CARLETON FOREHOE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10502202</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CARLETON FOREHOE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4753</id>
<name>CARLETON RODE</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4888381088611</lat>
<lon>1.10300583462708</lon>
<gazetteerText>CARLTON-RODE, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; 2 miles NE of New Buckenham, and 4 ESE of Attleborough r. station. Post Town, New Buckenham, under Attleborough. Acres, 2,631. Real property, &#163;5,823. Pop., 905. Houses, 203. The property is much subdivided. an ancient rood or cross gave rise to the suffix Rode. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;850.* Patron, Sir R. J. Buxton, Bart. The church is good; and there are a Baptist chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;68. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carleton_Rode</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/c/carleton_rode/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299501</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10161952</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CARLETON RODE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10512580</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CARLETON RODE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
