<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1678</id>
<name>MOULTON ST MICHAEL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4640627502707</lat>
<lon>1.1948050240719</lon>
<gazetteerText>MOULTON (GREAT), or MOULTON-ST. MICHAEL, a village and a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk. The village stands adjacent to the Great Eastern railway, midway between Tivetshall and Forncett r. stations, and 7 miles NW of Harleston; and has a post office, of the name of Moulton, under Long Stratton. The parish contains also the hamlet of Little Moulton, and comprises 1,347 acres. Real property, &#163;3,485; of which &#163;600 are on the railway. Pop., 442. Houses, 103. The manor belongs to T. and E. Betts, Esqs. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;440. * Patron, W. L. W. Chute, Esq. The church has a round tower, surmounted by an octagonal lantern. There are a national school and charities &#163;21. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/moulton_st_michael/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7295702</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015297</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MOULTON ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10077230</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GREAT MOULTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143263</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GREAT MOULTON WITH LITTLE MOULTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1677</id>
<name>MOULTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6057155168465</lat>
<lon>1.55065397787551</lon>
<gazetteerText>MOULTON, a parish in Blofield district, Norfolk; 2 miles N NE of Cantley r. station, and 8 W of Yarmouth. Post town, Acle, under Norwich. Acres, 1,018. Real property, &#163;2,650. Pop., 259. Houses, 50. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Lady Catherine Melville. Moulton Hall is a farmhouse. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;177.* Patron, LadyMelville. The church is ancient but good, and has a round tower. Charities &#163;24. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/moulton_st_mary/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moulton_St_Mary</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015285</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MOULTON ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10189354</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MOULTON ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10514060</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MOULTON ST MARY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>20987</id>
<name>LITTLE MOULTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4535633191181</lat>
<lon>1.19551517610421</lon>
<gazetteerText>MOULTON (LITTLE), a hamlet in Great Moulton parish, Norfolk; near Great Moulton village. It was formerly a parish; and the living is still a separate rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;30. Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church was taken down in 1579. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10123409</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LITTLE MOULTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10175112</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LITTLE MOULTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
