<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2801</id>
<name>MELTON CONSTABLE</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8459593337383</lat>
<lon>1.03008141255947</lon>
<gazetteerText>MELTON-CONSTABLE, a parish in Erpingham district, Norfolk; 5&#189; miles SW by S of Holt, and 6 NE of Ryburgh r. station. It includes the hamlet or quondam parish of Burgh-Parva; and its Post town is Briston, under Thetford. Acres, 2,710. Real property, &#163;2,429. Pop., 118. Houses, 19. The property belongs to Lord Hastings. The manor was given, by William the Conqueror, to the Bishop of Thetford; was held, under the Bishop, by Roger de Lyons; continued to be held by his descendants, who assumed the name of Mealton, with sometimes the affix of.De Constable, in allusion to their office under the Bishop; and passed, several centuries ago, to the Astleys. Melton Hall is the seat of Lord Hastings; was built in 1680, by Sir J. Astley; is a handsome square edifice of brick and stone, with four fronts, and with an elegant interior; includes an ornate domestic chapel; and stands in a fine park, about 4 miles in circuit, containing a tower which commands a charming view of the surrounding country to the sea. A small house of industry stands within the parish; serves, under. Gilbert&apos;s act, for Melton-Constable and Brinton; and, at the census of 1861, had 9 inmates. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Burgh-Parva, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;219. Patron, Lord Hastings. The church consists of nave and chancel, with a central tower. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melton_Constable</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/melton_constable/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642764</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10078994</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MELTON CONSTABLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506669</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MELTON CONSTABLE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1673</id>
   <name>WOOD NORTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2276</id>
   <name>STIBBARD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2622</id>
   <name>SWANTON NOVERS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3977</id>
   <name>BARNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4722</id>
   <name>GUIST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4750</id>
   <name>BRININGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5586</id>
   <name>HINDOLVESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5644</id>
   <name>GUNTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5780</id>
   <name>FULMODESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6166</id>
   <name>THURSFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
