<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2655</id>
<name>BURNHAM MARKET</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9359759555123</lat>
<lon>0.693315100441038</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURNHAM-WESTGATE, a village and a parish in Docking district, Norfolk. The village stands adjacent to the rivulet Burn, and on the Heacham and wells railway, 8&#189; miles NW of Fakenham. It has a post office,&#8225; of the name of Burnham, under Lynn, and a railway station; was formerly a market town; and still has fairs on Easter Tuesday and 1 and 2 Aug. The parish comprises 3,047 acres. Real property, &#163;6,219. Pop., 1,094. Houses, 255. The property is divided among a few. Holkham Park is a seat of the Earl of Leicester. There are two iron-foundries, and an agricultural implement manufactory. The living is a rectory, united with half of the rectories of Burnham-Norton and Burnham-Ulph, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;768.* Patron, Christ&apos;s College, Cambridge. The church is a neat building of flint and freestone, with a square tower. There are an Independent chapel, a Primitive Methodist chapel, large national schools, and charities &#163;28. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burnham_Market</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/burnham_market/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654271</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10068782</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BURNHAM WESTGATE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10078544</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>BURNHAM ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10205566</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BURNHAM MARKET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10513601</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURNHAM WESTGATE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541050</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570761</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570773</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURNHAM AND WALSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
