<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5549</id>
<name>MIDDLETON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7156830578866</lat>
<lon>0.46172564035799</lon>
<gazetteerText>MIDDLETON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Freebridge-Llyn district, Norfolk. The village stands 1&#188; mile S of the East Anglian railway, 1&#190; N of the river Nar, and 3&#189; SE of Kings-Lynn; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Lynn. The parish comprises 3,029 acres. Real property, &#163;5,872; of which &#163;80 are in quarries. Pop., 894. Houses, 190. The property is divided among a few. Middleton manor, with Middleton Tower and much of the land, belongs to L. W. Jarvis, Esq. The Tower was built, in the time of Henry VI., by the Lords Scales; was recently restored and enlarged; and has an old brick turreted gate way, 54 feet by 27. Middleton Hall is the seat of Major E. Hutton; and Valleyfield is the seat of S. A. Gurney, Esq. Blackborough manor, with the largest estate in the parish, belongs to the see of Norwich, and is now vested in the Ecclesiastical Commissioners. Blackborough priory, in the vale of the Nar, was founded, in the time of Henry II., for Benedictine nuns. Middleton Stop drain runs to the Wash at Lynn. A lofty circular mound, surrounded by a deep fosse, is near the church. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;315.* Patron, W. Durst, Esq. The church is ancient but good; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a fuel allotment.&#151;The sub-district contains also five other parishes. Acres, 10,848. Pop., 2,239. Houses, (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/middleton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Middleton,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642596</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10198902</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MIDDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506761</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MIDDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10565637</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MIDDLETON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2260</id>
   <name>WORMEGAY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3028</id>
   <name>EAST WINCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3938</id>
   <name>PENTNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5889</id>
   <name>WEST BILNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
