<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>830</id>
<name>EAST DEREHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6818160780145</lat>
<lon>0.95890608842228</lon>
<gazetteerText>DEREHAM (East), a town, a parish, and a sub-district in Mitford district, Norfolk. The town stands on a rivulet between two branches of the Wensum, and on the East Anglian railway, 17 miles by road, but 21&#189; by railway, WNW of Norwich. It was a seat of the East Anglian kings; and it suffered severely from fire in 1581 and 1679, and from plague in 1646. A nunnery was founded at it, about 750, by Withburga, daughter of King Anna; destroyed by the Danes; and refounded as an abbey. The present parish church was the church of the abbey; is a large cruciform structure, with a central tower; has Norman parts, and various forms of columns; includes three chapels, and a singular porch; and contains an organ of 1667, mentioned by Dr. Burney in his &quot;History of Music, &quot; a large, rich figured font of 1468, a curiously worked ancient chest, brought from the ruins of Buckenham Castle, a monument to the poet Cowper, who died in the town and was buried here, and tablets to Cowper&apos;s friends, Mrs. Unwin and Miss Perowne. A Norman arch, over St. Withburga&apos;s well, and a large tower, of the time of Henry VII., called the New Clocker, are in the churchyard. The town is sometimes called Market-Dereham; and it publishes a weekly newspaper, and is a seat of petty sessions and a polling-place. It is one of the handsomest towns in Norfolk; and has undergone much recent improvement. The assembly room, in the market-place, was built about 1755. The corn exchange was built in 1856; and cost &#163;2, 400, exclusive of the site. There are a post office&#8225; under Thetford, a railway station with telegraph, three banking offices, two chief inns, six dissenting chapels, a mechanics&apos; institute, an endowed school, a British school, town estates for the poor, &#163;242, and other charities &#163;205. Markets are held on Fridays; and fairs on the Thursdays before 6 July and 29 Sept. Manufactures of agricultural machines, malt, malt liquors, and sacking are carried on. Pop., 3, 070. Houses, 702.&#151;The parish includes also the hamlet of Dillington. Acres, 5, 222. Real property, &#163;22, 832, -of which &#163;200 are in gas-works. Pop., 4, 368. Houses, 998. The property is much subdivided. Quebec Hall is the seat of the Warners. Gardens and orchards are numerous and prolific. The living is a vicarge, united with the p. curacy of Hoo, in the diocese of Norwich; and there is a sinecure rectory. Value of the living, &#163;478; of the sinecure, &#163;704. Patrons, not reported. Bishop Bonner was vicar.&#151;The sub-district contains seven parishes. Acres, 18, 172. Pop., 7, 531. Houses, 1, 629. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Dereham</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/d/dereham_east/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650470</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10153074</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>EAST DEREHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173978</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>EAST DEREHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10180442</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EAST DEREHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10503085</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EAST DEREHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541165</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EAST DEREHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740049</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>NORFOLK MID</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835784</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EAST DEREHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1737</id>
   <name>BEESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2236</id>
   <name>LITCHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2309</id>
   <name>BINTREE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2921</id>
   <name>NORTH ELMHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3159</id>
   <name>MILEHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3291</id>
   <name>SWANTON MORLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3957</id>
   <name>FOULSHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4744</id>
   <name>BEETLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5748</id>
   <name>LYNG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6239</id>
   <name>GRESSENHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
