<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5121</id>
<name>ICKBURGH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5337613569074</lat>
<lon>0.681020130644257</lon>
<gazetteerText>IGBOROUGH, or ICKBOROUGH, a parish in Swaffham district, Norfolk; on the river Wissey and on Icknieldstreet, 1&#189; mile NE of Mundford, and 6 NNE of Brandon r. station. Post town, Mundford, under Brandon. Acres, 1, 599. Real property, &#163;934. Pop., 192. Houses, 39. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Lord Ashburton and W. A. T. Amhnrst, Esq. A Roman milestone, pavement, and urns have been found. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Langford, in the diocese of Norwich. The church is early English; and consists of nave and chancel, with a tower. There are a national school, and charities &#163;9. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/i/ickburgh/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646307</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10179981</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ICKBURGH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2648</id>
<name>LYNFORD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4889836257451</lat>
<lon>0.69123005271681</lon>
<gazetteerText>LYNFORD, a parish in Thetford district, Norfolk; on the river Wissey, 4&#190; miles NNE of Brandon r. station, and 7&#189; NW by N of Thetford. Post town, Brandon. Acres, 1,500. Real property, &#163;670. Pop., 95. Houses, 23. The property, with Lynford Hall, belongs to Mrs. Stephens. The Hall is a splendid mansion, in the Tudor style. The living is a discharged vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. The church was destroyed some centuries ago. Roman urns were found in 1720. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/l/lynford/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299283</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10068654</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LYNFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10210744</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LYNFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506414</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LYNFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
