<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2272</id>
<name>SHIPDHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6288533717803</lat>
<lon>0.904431954168947</lon>
<gazetteerText>SHIPDHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Mitford district, Norfolk. The village stands 3&#190; miles SW by W of Yaxham r. station, and 4&#189; SW by S of East Dereham; was once a market town; and has a post-office&#8225; under Thetford, and a stock fair on 30 June. The parish comprises 4,560 acres. Real property, &#163;18,028. Pop., 1,644. Houses, 382. The property is much sub-divided. The manor belongs to W. Birch, Esq. Hill House is the seat of H. B. Cannell, Esq. A hall was built here, by a bishop of Ely, in the time of Henry III.; and a hermitage of Thomas &#224; Becket was here about 1490. The living is a rectory in the dioceses of Norwich. Value, &#163;1,240.* Patron, the Rev. G.Bailey. The church was extensively altered in 1845. There are three dissenting chapels, an endowed school with &#163;70 a year, fuel allotments &#163;125, and other charities &#163;118.&#151;The sub-district contains seven parishes. Acres, 11,349. Pop., 2,777. Houses, 632. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/s/shipdham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637962</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10049921</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SHIPDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10508850</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHIPDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541130</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHIPDHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1712</id>
   <name>WEST BRADENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3069</id>
   <name>WHINBURGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3199</id>
   <name>NECTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3948</id>
   <name>CRANWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4733</id>
   <name>LETTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4748</id>
   <name>EAST BRADENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5461</id>
   <name>WESTFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5885</id>
   <name>SCARNING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6087</id>
   <name>HOLME HALE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
