<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3501</id>
<name>THORPE NEXT NORWICH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6345140244828</lat>
<lon>1.34914074666299</lon>
<gazetteerText>THORPE-NEXT-NORWICH, or T.-St. Andrew, a parish in Norwich and Blofield districts, Norfolk; on the river Yare, and on the Norwich and Yarmouth railway, 2 miles E of Norwich. A picturesque village is on the Yare, and a recent railway bridge spans the river. Thorpe-Hamlet is the part within Norwich district, and has a post-office under Norwich. Acres of the parish, 2,525. Real property, &#163;14,414; of which &#163;800 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 3,000; in 1861, 3,841. Houses, 752. The increase of pop. arose from the erection of houses suburban to Norwich. The manor was given by Henry I. to the Bishops of Norwich; had a palace of the Bishops; was exchanged away to Henry VIII.; and belongs now to W. Birkbeck, Esq. The Norfolk lunatic asylum, erected in 1814, is 1 mile SE of the village. A section of the parish, under the name of T.-St. Matthew, was made a separate charge in 1852. The head living is a rectory, and that of St. Matthew is a p. curacy in the diocese of Norwich. Value of the former, &#163;600;* of the latter, &#163;99.* Patron of the former, W. Birkbeck, Esq.; of the latter, the Rector. A new church was built in 1866. There are an Independent chapel, an endowed school with &#163;45 a year, a free school, and charities &#163;77. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10097885</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>THORPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10104830</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>THORPE ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1682</id>
   <name>PORINGLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1683</id>
   <name>RACKHEATH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1714</id>
   <name>BRUNDALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2234</id>
   <name>BLOFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3512</id>
   <name>SALHOUSE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4692</id>
   <name>WOODBASTWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4717</id>
   <name>STOKE HOLY CROSS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4751</id>
   <name>BROOKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5459</id>
   <name>TROWSE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5958</id>
   <name>SPROWSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>5580</id>
<name>THORPE ABBOTS</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.3705555386146</lat>
<lon>1.21698623759297</lon>
<gazetteerText>THORPE-ABBOTS, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; 3&#190; miles E of Diss r. station. Post town, Scole. Acres, 1,122. Real property, &#163;1,819. Pop., 256. Houses, 55. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;305.* Patron, J. P. Reade, Esq. The church is good. Charities, &#163;9. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/t/thorpe_abbotts/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thorpe_Abbots</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10200143</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>THORPE ABBOTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10509932</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>THORPE ABBOTTS</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>21110</id>
<name>THORPE PARVA</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.3678173391942</lat>
<lon>1.17315414565082</lon>
<gazetteerText>THORPE-PARVA, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; 1&#190; mile E of Diss r. station. Post town, Scole. Acres, 349. Real property, &#163;487. Pop., 21. Houses, 4. The manor belongs to G. H. Wilson, Esq. The living is a rectory, annexed to Billingford. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/t/thorpe_parva/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015169</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>THORPE PARVA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10509970</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>THORPE PARVA</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3923</id>
<name>THORPE NEXT HADDISCOE</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5271687160549</lat>
<lon>1.59411520546962</lon>
<gazetteerText>THORPE-NEXT-HADDISCOE, a parish in Loddon district, Norfolk; 1&#188; mile W of St. Olaves Junction r. station, and 5 E of Loddon. Post town, Loddon, under Norwich. Acres, 824. Real property, &#163;1,517. Pop., 84. Houses, 19. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;175.* Patron, alternately the Lord Chancellor and Lord Calthorpe. The church&apos;s chancel was rebuilt in 1838. Charities, &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/t/thorpe_next_haddiscoe/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10123264</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>THORPE NEXT HADDISCOE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10509968</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>THORPE NEXT HADDISCOE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2624</id>
<name>THORPE MARKET</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.86983249311</lat>
<lon>1.32517555007384</lon>
<gazetteerText>THORPE-MARKET, a parish, with a village, in Erpingham district, Norfolk; 4&#189; miles NNW of North Walsham r. station. Post town, Aylsham, under Norwich. Acres, 1,309. Real property, &#163;1,282. Pop., 215. Houses, 47. Much of the land belongs to Lord Suffield. The village was once a considerable market-town. The living is a vicarage, annexed to Antingham. The church was rebuilt in the present century. Charities, &#163;13. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/t/thorpe_market/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6951043</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10068289</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>THORPE MARKET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10509956</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>THORPE MARKET</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23795</id>
<name>THORPE HAMLET</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6301734248417</lat>
<lon>1.31481356951255</lon>
<gazetteerText>Thorpe, township and eccl. dist. (Thorpe St Matthew), Thorpe St Andrew par., Norfolk, in bor. of Norwich, 730 ac., pop. 2864; P.O., called Thorpe Hamlet. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thorpe_Hamlet</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6615542</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10214993</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>THORPE ST MATTHEW</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1709</id>
<name>ASHWELLTHORPE</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5309285968354</lat>
<lon>1.16685619336098</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHWELL-THORPE, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; on an affluent of the river Yare, 3 miles SE of Wymondham r. station. Post Town, Wymondham. Acres, 979. Real property, &#163;2,191. Pop., 409. Houses, 88. The manor belonged anciently to the family of Thorpe; passed to that of Bourchier; and was held, in the time of Henry VII., by Sir John Bourchier, the translator of Froissart, and ancestor of the present Lord Berners. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Wreningham, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;648.* Patron, Lord Berners. The church contains some old monuments. Charities, 1&#189; acre of fuel allotment. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656909</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashwellthorpe_and_Fundenhall</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/a/ashwellthorpe/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015790</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ASHWELLTHORPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10513431</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ASHWELLTHORPE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
