<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3943</id>
<name>RUNHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6288804497326</lat>
<lon>1.6677955465802</lon>
<gazetteerText>RUNHAM, a village and a parish in Flegg district, Norfolk. The village stands near the river Bure, at the Runham-Swim ferry, 4&#189; miles W N W of Yarmouth r.station; and was once a market-town. The parish includes a detached portion, called New Runham or Vauxhall, immediately adjoining Yarmouth, and on which fish-offices, manure-works, and the terminus of the Norwich and Yarmouth railway are situated; and it was re-turned in the census of 1851 as including also the extra-parochial tract of Nowhere. Post-town, Filby, under Norwich. Acres, with Nowhere, 1, 715. Real property, &#163;4, 413. Pop., exclusive of Nowhere, 396. Houses, 84. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;207.* Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is old, and was recently restored. There are a national school and a poors&apos;allotment of 27 acres. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/r/runham_vauxhall/</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/r/runham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mautby</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638958</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10016204</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>RUNHAM VAUXHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10123598</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>RUNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10508289</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RUNHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4735</id>
   <name>MAUTBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
