<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>567</id>
<name>DISS</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.3766777035169</lat>
<lon>1.1105919241752</lon>
<gazetteerText>DISS, a town, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Norfolk. The town stands on the river Waveney, at the boundary with Suffolk, &#189; a mile W of the Eastern Union railway, and 19&#189; SSW of Norwich. It chiefly occupies an acclivity, encompassed by a large sheet of water; presents an airy and prosperous appearance; and has a head post office, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, two banking offices, two chief inns, a corn exchange, a parish church, six dissenting chapels, and charities &#163;187. The corn exchange was built in 1854; and is handsome and commodious. The church is early English, good and beautiful. A cemetery, with two chapels, was formed in 1869. Markets are held on Fridays; fairs on the 3d Friday of Sept., and 8 Nov.; and there are manufactures of brushes, cocoa-matting, and malt liquors. Ralph De Diceto, dean of St. Paul&apos;s in the time of Henry II., Friar Walter, confessor to the Duke of Lancaster, and John Skelton, poet laureate to Henry VIII., were natives. Pop., 3, 164. Houses, 669. -The parish comprises 3, 627 acres. Real property, &#163;14, 134; of which &#163;235 are in canals. Pop., 3, 710. Houses, 785. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged anciently to the Crown; and was given by Edward I. to the Fitzwalters. Diss Common has a post office under Diss; and Diss-Heywood has a chapel-school, built in 1865. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;715.* Patron, the Rev.R. Manning.&#151;The sub-district contains 12 parishes; and is in Depwade district. Acres, 17, 412. Pop., 7, 567. Houses, 1, 624. The hundred contains 16 parishes. Acres, 25, 000. Pop., 9, 851. Houses, 2, 129. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/d/diss/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diss</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651214</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10094150</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>DISS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10099560</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>DISS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10101773</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>DISS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10107702</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>DISS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541025</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DISS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12738237</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>NORFOLK SOUTHERN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2247</id>
   <name>DICKLEBURGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2618</id>
   <name>REDENHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2647</id>
   <name>KENNINGHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2653</id>
   <name>BANHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3111</id>
   <name>PULHAM ST MARY MAGDALENE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3196</id>
   <name>PULHAM ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3254</id>
   <name>SCOLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4723</id>
   <name>EAST HARLING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7210</id>
   <name>FRESSINGFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8126</id>
   <name>WORTHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
