<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2918</id>
<name>GREAT PLUMSTEAD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6415785421098</lat>
<lon>1.38887587705906</lon>
<gazetteerText>PLUMSTEAD (Great), a village and a parish in Blofield district, Norfolk. The village stands 2 miles N W of Brundall r. station, and 4&#189; E by N of Norwich; and has a post-office under Norwich. The parish comprises 1, 403 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 903. Pop., 342. Houses, 72. The property is divided among a few. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;70. Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Norwich. The church is plain, and partly of brick. Charities, &#163;22. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/p/plumstead/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648036</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10083096</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GREAT PLUMSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10099936</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD GREAT AND LITTLE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4701</id>
<name>LITTLE PLUMSTEAD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6537315237896</lat>
<lon>1.40748892859844</lon>
<gazetteerText>PLUMSTEAD (Little), a parish, with a village, in Blofield district, Norfolk; 2 miles N N W of Brundall r.station, and 5 E by N of Norwich. Post-town, Norwich. Acres, 1, 395. Real property, &#163;3, 377. Pop., 319. Houses, 72. The property is divided among three. P. Hall is the seat ofJecks, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value and Patron, notreported. The church is neat and good; has a round tower, and a fine E window; and contains several monuments. There are a national school and a fuel allotment &#163;48. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/p/plumstead_little/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644269</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10161289</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LITTLE PLUMSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507686</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LITTLE PLUMSTEAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2631</id>
<name>PLUMSTEAD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8684068512232</lat>
<lon>1.1609174475756</lon>
<gazetteerText>PLUMSTEAD, a parish in Erpingham district, Norfolk; 4&#188; miles S E of Holt, and 12&#189; N E of Elmham r.station. Post-town, Hanworth, under Norwich. Acres, 1, 272. Real property, &#163;1, 245. Pop., 178. Houses, 48. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to J. T. Mott, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;182. Patron, the Duchy of Lancaster. The church is plain but good, and has a tower (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plumstead,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640200</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10068423</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3964</id>
<name>HOLT</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9036996628871</lat>
<lon>1.09387134996255</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOLT, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Norfolk. The town stands on an eminence, 3&#189; miles from the coast, and 10 E by N of Walsingham r. station; commands a charming view over the surrounding fertile country; suffered great damage, by fire, in 1708; is now well built, and presents a pleasant appearance; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a postoffice &#8225; under Thetford, a banking office, two good inns, a sessions house, a police station, a corn exchange, a church, three dissenting chapels, a free grammar school, a national school, a British and infant school, a literary institute, and charities &#163;357. The church is decorated and later English; has a square tower, formerly surmounted by a lofty spire, which served as a sea mark; and contains several monuments. The grammar school was founded, in 1654, by Sir Thomas Gresham; was rebuilt, in a handsome and commodious manner, in 1860; has an endowed income of &#163;348, and an excellent library; holds a scholarship in Sidney-Sussex college, Cambridge, and another scholarship at either university; and had as a master, for upwards of 30 years, John Holmes, author of a Greek grammar. A weekly market is held on Friday; and fairs are held on 25 April and 25 Nov. Sir Thomas Gresham, Sir Richard Gresham, Thomas Girdlestone, the physician, and William Withers, the writer on forest trees, were natives.&#151;The parish comprises 2, 991 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 670; of which &#163;13 are in gas works. Pop., 1, 635. Houses, 372. The manor belonged to the family of De Vaux; and is now divided into four. A common around the town was enclosed in 1810. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;563.* Patron, St. John&apos;s College, Cambridge.&#151;The sub-district contains also sixteen other parishes, and is in Erpingham district. Acres, 28, 221. Pop., 6, 787. Houses, 1, 593. - The hundred contains thirty-one parishes. Acres, 43, 908. Pop. in 1851, 10, 764; in 1861, 9, 942. Houses, 2, 351. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/holt/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holt,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646701</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10044297</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10123823</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505343</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507674</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD BY HOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575254</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2924</id>
   <name>LETHERINGSETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
