<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>236</id>
<name>HIGHAM FERRERS</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3069115672579</lat>
<lon>-0.577957555221902</lon>
<gazetteerText>HIGHAM-FERRERS, a small town, a parish, a subdistrict, and a hundred in Northamptonshire. The town stands on a rocky height, near the river Nen and the Northampton and Peterborough railway, 3 miles from the boundary with Beds, and 15&#189; ENE of Northampton. It was known, at Domesday, as Higham; and it took its after name from the Earls Ferrers, who were its lords. Its site has yielded relics which show it to have been probably occupied by the Romans; and is within 3 miles of the Roman station of Chester. A castle was built at it, either by Thomas, Earl of Lancaster, or by the Ferrers; but nothing of this remains except part of the earthwork. The town has a plain appearance, is about a mile long, and contains some houses of the 15th century. An ancient cross is in the market place; and the shaft of another is in the churchyard. The church is early English; has been thoroughly restored, and partially rebuilt, at a cost of &#163;6, 000; measures 119 feet by 69; comprises a sort of double nave, a choir, and several chapels, with a tower and hexagonal spire 180 feet high; and contains a screen, some carved seats, a double piscina, some armour of John of Gaunt, and many brasses. An old Baptist chapel, noted for preachings by John Bunyan, is now a stable. There are a Wesleyan chapel, an endowed grammar school, and charities &#163;30. An ancient hospital, called the hospital of St. James, is extinct. A college was built, in the time of Henry V., by Archbishop Chichele, a native of the town; and was suppressed at the dissolution of monasteries. A bede house also was built by the archbishop; still stands on the S side of the churchyard; and is now used as a Sunday school. The town hall is a small edifice of 1808. Markets used to be held thrice a week, but have ceased; fairs are still held on the Thursday before 5 Feb., 7 March, the Thursday before 12 May, 28 June, the Thursday before 5 Aug., 11 Oct., and 6 Dec.; and shoe making and lace making are carried on. The town has a headpost office, &#8225; a railway station, and a good inn. It is a borough by prescription; and it sent a member to parliament, from the time of Queen Mary, till disfranchised by t] act of 183222.&#151;The parish comprises 2, 260 acres. Real property, &#163;4, 775, of which &#163;20 are in gas works. Pop., 1, 152. Houses, 246. The manor belongs to the Hon. G. W. Fitzwilliam. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Chelveston, in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Hon. G. W. Fitzwilliam.&#151;The sub-district contains also four other parishes and an extra-parochial tract in Northamptonshire, and three parishes in Beds; and is in the district of Wellingborough. Acres, 18, 356. Pop., 7, 100. Houses, 1, 564.-The hundred contains fourteen parishes and part of another. Acres, 29, 660. Pop. in 1851, 10, 090; in 1861, 11, 508. Houses, 2, 506. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Higham_Ferrers</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646985</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66303</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66300</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66301</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10027172</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10063486</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10075294</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10107167</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10276706</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10276743</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10554081</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574985</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HIGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575000</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575011</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS I</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575023</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS II</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575035</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS III</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758662</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>HIGHAM FERRERS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
