<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>532</id>
<name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3141400287167</lat>
<lon>-0.68453399977779</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELLINGBOROUGH, a town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Northamptonshire. The town stands on a declivity near the river Nen, and near the intersection of the Midland railway and the Northampton and Peterborough railway, 10 miles NE by E of Northampton; takes its name from chalybeate springs, which were used by Charles I., and are still of great note; was extensively destroyed by fire in 1738; is a seat of petty sessions and county courts, and a polling place; publishes a weekly newspaper; carries on a considerable trade in corn, shoe-making, boot-making, and the smelting of iron ore; comprises four principal streets, diverging from a central market-square; presents a modern and pleasant appearance, recently much improved; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a r. station with telegraph, two banking-offices, two chief inns, a police station, a recently-formed promenade, a corn exchange of 1861, built at a cost of &#163;3,500, an ancient church restored in 1861, and surmounted by a lofty spire, another church of 1867, built at a cost of &#163;4,500, two Independent chapels, four other dissenting chapels, a public cemetery, a literary institute, with an extensive library, an endowed grammar-school with &#163;87 a year, another endowed school with &#163;55, national and British schools, a workhouse built at a cost of &#163;5,000, a town-estate &#163;800, some general charities, a weekly market on Wednesday, and three annual fairs. Pop. in 1861, 6,067. Houses, 1,279. The parish comprises 4,490 acres. Real property, &#163;19,828; of which &#163;200 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 5,297; in 1861, 6,382. Houses, 1,312. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of the shoe manufacture, and from the erection of a smelting furnace. Hatton Hall is the chief residence. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, Q. Vivian, Esq.&#151;The sub-district contains nine parishes. Acres, 17,865. Pop., 10,885. Houses, 2,306.&#151;The district includes also Earls-Barton and Higham-Ferrers subdistricts, and comprises 55,505 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;11,742. Pop. in 1851, 21,367; in 1861, 24,224. Houses, 5,199. Marriages in 1863, 174; births, 970,-of which 38 were illegitimate; deaths, 583,-of which 264 were at ages under 5 years, and 12 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,969; births, 8,298; deaths, 5,070. The places of worship, in 1851, were 27 of the Church of England, with 8,486 sittings; 8 of Independents, with 2,655 s.; 12 of Baptists, with 2,374 s.; 2 of Quakers, with 500 s.: 15 of Wesleyans, with 2,904 s.; 2 of Primitive Methodists, with 110 s.; 1 undefined, with 150 s.; and 2 of Latter Day Saints, with 50 s. The schools were 24 public day-schools, with 1,513 scholars; 28 private day-schools, with 530 s.; 43 Sunday schools, with 4,151 s.: and 3 evening schools for adults, with 41 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wellingborough</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Wellingborough</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634578</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66335</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10000476</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10063140</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10075300</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10084817</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10100999</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10104543</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10284120</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10284144</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10284156</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10284170</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10284193</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH ST BARNABAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10284200</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH ST MARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10284211</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10554093</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581977</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740580</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12750729</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE AND SOKE OF PETERBOROUGH WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12752581</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE EASTERN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12831766</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WELLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>945</id>
   <name>FINEDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7526</id>
   <name>CASTLE ASHBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7564</id>
   <name>EARLS BARTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7894</id>
   <name>GREAT DODDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7957</id>
   <name>GRENDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7980</id>
   <name>LITTLE HARROWDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8037</id>
   <name>ISHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8201</id>
   <name>SYWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8351</id>
   <name>WILBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8354</id>
   <name>WOLLASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
