<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1204</id>
<name>KINGSTHORPE</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2613497475869</lat>
<lon>-0.892826221521467</lon>
<gazetteerText>KINGSTHORPE, a village and a parish in the district and county of Northampton. The village stands near the Northampton and Leicester railway, and a branch of the river Nen, 2 miles N by W of Northampton; is a considerable place; was formerly governed by a bailiff; and has a post office under Northampton. The parish comprises 1,800 acres. Real property, &#163;7, 684; of which &#163;60 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 1, 586; in 1861, 1, 906. Houses, 434. The increase of pop. was caused by the extension of the shoe trade. The manor belonged anciently to the Crown. An hospital was founded here, in 1200, by Peter de Northampton; and was given by Queen Mary to the master of the Savoy. Kingsthorpe Hall is the seat of the Misses Boddington. A buildingstone of excellent quality is quarried. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;700.* Patron, St. Katherine&apos;s Hospital, London. The church is partly Norman, partly later English. There are a Baptist chapel, a national school, and charities about &#163;70. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.kellner.eclipse.co.uk/genuki/NTH/Kingsthorpe</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kingsthorpe</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645441</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66321</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10041478</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>KINGSTHORPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10111316</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>KINGSTHORPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10277486</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>KINGSTHORPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10277516</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KINGSTHORPE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1310</id>
   <name>FAR COTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7605</id>
   <name>BOUGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7638</id>
   <name>LONG BUCKBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7694</id>
   <name>DALLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8087</id>
   <name>MOULTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8248</id>
   <name>TOWCESTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8255</id>
   <name>UPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8275</id>
   <name>WEEDON BEC</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8343</id>
   <name>WESTON FAVELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8362</id>
   <name>WOOTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
