<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8012</id>
<name>NETHER HEYFORD</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2200249901125</lat>
<lon>-1.04187256153459</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEYFORD (Nether), or Lower Heyford, a village and a parish in the district and county of Northampton. The village stands near Watling street, the river Nen, and the Grand Junction canal, 2&#188; miles SE of Weedon r. station, and 6 WSW of Northampton; and has a postoffice, of the name of Heyford, under Weedon. The parish comprises 1, 690 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 936; of which &#163;500 are in ironworks. Pop. in 1851, 624; in 1861, 807. Houses, 166. The increase of pop. was occasioned by the erection of ironworks. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to Mrs. Ann Crawley. A Roman pavement, indicating the site of a Roman villa, was discovered here in 1699. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, Rev. T. W. Crawley. The church consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and contains the tomb of Judge Morgan, who pronounced sentence on Lady Jane Grey, and a brass of 1497. There are chapels for Baptists and Primitive Methodists, an endowed school with &#163;105 a year, and other charities with &#163;40. Stanbridge, the scholar, and Preston, the distinguished puritan, were natives. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6692751</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10276597</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEYFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10276603</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NETHER HEYFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>8014</id>
<name>UPPER HEYFORD</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.232588640981</lat>
<lon>-1.02172789493794</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEYFORD (Upper), a parish in the district and county of Northampton; 2&#188; miles E of Weedon r. station, and 5&#189; W of Northampton. Post town, Heyford, under Weedon. Acres, 726. Real property, &#163;1, 827. Pop., 116. Houses, 28. The manor belongs to Sir Charles Knightley, Bart. There is no church; and the inhabitants attend that of Nether Heyford. Charities, &#163;20. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7290985</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10276639</id>
   <status>CP/PA</status>
   <name>UPPER HEYFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
