<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8090</id>
<name>NASEBY</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3975241707969</lat>
<lon>-0.991823926180788</lon>
<gazetteerText>NASEBY, a village and a parish in Brixworth district, Northampton. The village stands on a high tract, at or near the sources of the rivers Avon, Welland, and Nen, 4 miles W S W of Kelmarsh r. station, and 7 S W by S of Market-Harborough; was once a market-town; and has a post-office under Rugby. An ancient market-cross, a plain stone column, stood adjacent to the church-yard, but was removed to the E entrance of the village; and a new stone cross now stands on the old site. The parish comprises 3, 690 acres. Real property, &#163;4, 545. Pop., 811. Houses, 161. The property belongs chiefly to Viscount Clifden, who owns the manor, and to G. A. Ashby, Esq., whose seat is the Woolleys. The scene of the famous battle of Naseby, in 1645, when Cromwelldefeated Charles I. and Prince Rupert, lies on the N side of the village; has a square stone obelisk, erected in 1823, in commemoration of the battle; and commands aview over an expanse of country, with nearly 40 churches. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;85.* Patron, G. A. Ashby, Esq. The church is ancient; comprises nave, aisles, and chancel; was thoroughly restored in 1860; has a tower and handsomespire, rebuilt in 1860; and contains, in the tower, a memorial window to the late Rev. J. Jones. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.kellner.eclipse.co.uk/genuki/NTH/Naseby</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naseby</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641874</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10278508</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NASEBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278521</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NASEBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
