<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8077</id>
<name>MARSTON TRUSSEL</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4577335636665</lat>
<lon>-0.98831470751156</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARSTON-TRUSSELL, a village and a parish in the district of Market-Harborough and county of Northampton. The village stands adjacent to the boundary with Leicester, 1&#190; mile E of Theddingworth r. station, and 3 W by S of Market-Harborough. The parish, in some sense, includes also Thorpe-Lubenham, which otherwise is an extra-parochial tract. Post town, Marlket-Harborough. Acres, with T. L., 1,640. Real property, exclusive of T. L., &#163;2,432; inc. of T. L., &#163;3,376. Pop., exc. of T. L., 219. Houses, 48. Pop., inc. of T. L., 244. Houses, 50. The manor-farm, with Marston-Trussell Hall, belongs to B. E. Bennett, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Valne, &#163;500.* Patron, the Rev. W. Law. The church is of the 14th centnry; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with embattled tower. There are a parochial school, and charities &#163;6. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marston_Trussell</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301948</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10278235</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MARSTON TRUSSEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278247</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON TRUSSEL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>8074</id>
<name>MARSTON ST LAWRENCE</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.082734813596</lat>
<lon>-1.21193183759632</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARSTON-ST., a village and a parish in Brackley district, Northampton. The village stands 1&#189; mile NNE of Farthinghoe r. station, and 5&#188; NW of Brackley; and has a postal wall-box under Banbury. The parish contains also the hamlet of Westrop, and comprises 1,230 acres. Real property, &#163;4,071. Pop., 535. Houses, 122. The property is divided among a few. The manor, with Marston House, belongs to J. A. Blencowe, Esq. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Warkworth, in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;420.* Patron, J. J. Blencowe, Esq. The church is ancient, of varions dates; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with embattled tower; and contains sedilia, a carved oak altar-piece, a piscina, and several monuments of the Blencowes. There is a free school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10278181</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MARSTON ST LAWRENCE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278223</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON ST LAWRENCE WITH WARKWORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
