<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8081</id>
<name>MIDDLETON CHENEY</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0700689586671</lat>
<lon>-1.26718681514921</lon>
<gazetteerText>MIDDLETON-CHENEY, a village and a parish in the district of Banbury and county of NorthamptonThe village stands 2 miles E of the river Cherwell at the boundary with Oxfordshire, and 2&#190; E by N of Banbury r. station; is divided into two parts, called Lower and Upper; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a post office under Banbury, and a recently erected police court and station. The parish comprises 1,780 acres, and is some times called M. Chenduit Real property, &#163;6,380. Pop in 1851,1,330; in 1861,1,250. Houses, 301. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to Miss Horton. A battle was fought here, in 1643, between the royalists under the Earl of Northampton, and the parliamentarians. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;423.* Patron, Brasenose College, Oxford. The church is decorated English; comprises nave, aisles, and chancel, with lofty pinnacled tower and graceful spire; has a porch of fine decorated stone work, with lofty ogee roof; was restored in 1865, at a cost of about &#163;3,000; and contains a well-preserved cinquefoil-headed piscina. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists; national schools, built in 1856; nine alms houses, built and endowed by Miss Horton in 1863-7; and some other charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Middleton_Cheney</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296726</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10206248</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>MIDDLETON CHENEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278326</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MIDDLETON CHENEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278338</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MIDDLETON CHENEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7692</id>
   <name>CULWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8074</id>
   <name>MARSTON ST LAWRENCE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8205</id>
   <name>THENFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8217</id>
   <name>THORPE MANDEVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
