<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8127</id>
<name>POTTERSPURY</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0828664289351</lat>
<lon>-0.895436337190899</lon>
<gazetteerText>POTTERSPURY, a village, a parish, and a district, in Northampton. The village stands near Watling-street, 1 mile W of the Grand Junction canal, 1&#189; W of the river Tove at the boundary with Bucks, 2&#189; N N W of Stony-Stratford, and 3&#190; N W by W of Wolverton r. station; and has a post-office under Stony-Stratford. The parish contains also the hamlet of Yardley-Gobion, and comprises 2, 820 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 621. Pop., 1, 710. Houses, 372. The property is divided among a few. The manor, with Wakefield Lodge and much of the land, belongs to the Duke of Grafton. W. Lodgestands in the centre of a woodland, which was formerly Whittlewood forest; and it has a lawn of 500 acres. Onwhich are the kennels of a pack of foxhounds. Yardley House is the seat of Mrs. Franklin. The living is a vicarage in the .diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;116.* Patron, Earl Bathurst. The church was restored in 1848, at a cost of about &#163;3,000; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with massive W tower. A cemetery, with a small chapel, is at the S E end of the village. Achapel of ease is in Yardley-Gobion, and was built in 1864. An Independent chapel and a parochial schoolare at Potterspury; and an Independent chapel and the district workhouse are at Yardley-Gobion. The work-house was built in 1837, and has accommodation for 200inmates. The district contains also the parishes of Paulerspury, Wicken, Passenham, Cosgrove, Furtho, Grafton-Regis, Alderton, Ashton, and Hartwell, and twolodges of Salcey-Forest, in Northampton, and the parishes of Wolverton, Calverton, and Stony-Stratford in Bucks. Acres, 22, 401. Poor-rates in 1863, &#163;5, 853. Pop. in 1851, 10, 663; in 1861, 11, 632. Houses, 2, 301. Marriages in 1863, 77; births, 479, of which 24 wereillegitimate; deaths, 215, of which 88 were at ages under 5 years, and 11 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 819; births, 3, 540; deaths, 2, 228. The places of worship, in 1851, were 14 of the Church of England, with 3, 587 sittings; 6 of Independents, with1, 740 s.; 4 of Baptists, with 760 s.; 5 of Wesleyans, with 490 s.; and 1 of Primitive Methodists, with 150 s. The schools were 8 public day schools, with 675 scholars; 10 private day schools, with 285 s.; and 15 Sunday schools, with 1, 405 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.kellner.eclipse.co.uk/genuki/NTH/Potterspury</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Potterspury</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Potterspury</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639969</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22789</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10043610</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>POTTERSPURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10108895</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>POTTERSPURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10139545</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>POTTERSPURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10277668</id>
   <status>PA</status>
   <name>LANDS COMMON TO POTTERSPURY AND YARDLEY GOBION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279951</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>POTTERSPURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279963</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>POTTERSPURY WITH YARDLEY GOBION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279999</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>POTTERSPURY WITH FURTHO AND YARDLEY GOBION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10554019</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>POTTERSPURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12797977</id>
   <status>ExP</status>
   <name>POTTERSPURY LODGE FARM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
