<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8117</id>
<name>PATTISHALL</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1814431517855</lat>
<lon>-1.0087131984589</lon>
<gazetteerText>PATTISHALL, or Pateshull, a village and a parish in Towcester district, Northampton. The village stands near Watling-street, 3&#188; miles W by N of Blisworth r.station, and 4&#188; N N W of Towcester; and has a post-office, of the name of Pattishall, under Towcester. The parish contains also the hamlets of Ascote, Dalscote, Eastcote, and Catchems-End, and parts of Fosters-Booth and Foxley. Acres, 2, 460. Real property, &#163;6,008. Pop. in 1851, 775; in 1861, 885. Houses, 199. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to the Earl of Pomfret. Pattishall House is the seat of T. Drayson, Esq. The living is a vicarage in two parts, called P.-Upper and P.-Lower, in the diocese of Peterborough. Value of P.-Upper, &#163;136; of P.-Lower, not reported. Patron, of theformer, the Lord Chancellor; of the latter, the Rev. T.Welch. The church is Norman and good; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower. There are two Baptist chapels, a primitive Methodist chapel, an endowed school with &#163;24 a year, and charities &#163;172. Chief-Justices Simon and Martin de Pateshull, Bishop Hugh de Pateshull, and Dean Steward, were natives. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattishall</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640565</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10279630</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PATTISHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279641</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PATTISHALL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8015</id>
   <name>COLD HIGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8243</id>
   <name>TIFFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
