<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8118</id>
<name>PAULERSPURY</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1111574929698</lat>
<lon>-0.952350608599871</lon>
<gazetteerText>PAULERSPURY, a village and a parish in Potterspury district, Northampton. The village stands near Watling-street, 1&#189; mile N of the boundary with Bucks, 2&#190; S S E of Towcester, and 5&#188; S W of Roade r. station; and has a post-office under Towcester. The parish contains also the hamlet of Heathencote, and comprises 2, 961acres. Real property, &#163;5, 602. Pop., 1, 233. Houses, 281. The manor belongs to G. Shedden, Esq. Paulerspury House is the residence of Mrs. E. Ashby. Romancoins have been found. Pillow lace is made. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Petersborough. Value, &#163;864. Patron, New College, Oxford. The church is early and decorated English, with later English tower; was partly rebuilt in 1844, and partly restored in 1855; comprises nave, aisles, N chapel, and chancel; and contains a piscina, very fine sedilia, and an altar-tomb of the 14th century. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, a handsome Church of England school, erected in 1861, and endowed with &#163;41 a year, an Independent school, and charities &#163;33. Professor Bernardwas a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640562</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22788</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10279653</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>PAULERSPURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279665</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PAULERSPURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7482</id>
   <name>ALDERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7906</id>
   <name>EASTON NESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8154</id>
   <name>SHUTLANGER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8178</id>
   <name>STOKE BRUERNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
