<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>543</id>
<name>RAUNDS</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3428808362065</lat>
<lon>-0.527564641888658</lon>
<gazetteerText>RAUNDS, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Thrapstone district, Northampton. The village stands1&#190; mile E of the Northampton and Peterborough railway, and 3&#190; S of Thrapstone; carries on extensive shoe-making; and has a station on the Midland railway, a post-office&#8225;under Thrapstone, and a temperance hall. The parish comprises 3, 680 acres. Real property, &#163;7,074. Pop. in 1851, 1,870: in 1861, 2, 337. Houses, 511. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of shoe-manufacture. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to the Duchy of Lancaster and Sir J. Langham, Bart. There is a petrifying spring. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;250.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is early English; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with tower and spire. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, an endowed school with &#163;18 a year, and charities &#163;44. Grimbald, who built Trinity College chapel in Cambridge, was anative.&#151;The sub-district contains also 11 other parishes, 6 of them electorally in Hunts. Acres, 23, 801. Pop., 6, 606. Houses, 1, 440. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raunds</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639600</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66310</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10103344</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>RAUNDS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280175</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RAUNDS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280199</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RAUNDS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553957</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RAUNDS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7473</id>
   <name>GREAT ADDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7478</id>
   <name>LITTLE ADDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7887</id>
   <name>DENFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8039</id>
   <name>ISLIP</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8063</id>
   <name>LOWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8140</id>
   <name>RINGSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8174</id>
   <name>STANWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8357</id>
   <name>WOODFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
