<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8142</id>
<name>ROCKINGHAM</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5127778849493</lat>
<lon>-0.721236740821638</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROCKINGHAM, a village and a parish in the district of Uppingham and county of Northampton. The village stands on the declivity of a hill, adjacent to the river Welland, at the boundary with Rutlandshire, 1 mile S of the Stamford and Rugby railway, and 9 N of Kettering; was known to the Saxons as Rockingaham; servedas a centre to Rockingham Foresta forest measuring 30 miles by 8; had, on the top of the hill, a castle erectedby William the Conqueror, for defence of extensive iron-works then in the forest; was afterwards a market-town; gave the titles of Baron and Marquis to the family of Watson; and now has a post-office&#8225; under Leicester, and a railway station. The castle was the meeting-place of agreat council in 1094; was occupied, for some time, by Edward III. and his court; was garrisoned for Charles I.by Sir L. Watson, afterwards created Lord Rockingham; and is now represented by only two massive bastions, whichflanked its gateway. The modern seat of the Watsonfamily now occupies the castle&apos;s site, and bears its name. The parish comprises 890 acres. Real property, &#163;1, 688. Pop., 211. Houses, 48. The manor belongs to G. L. Watson, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;216.* Patron, G. L. Watson, Esq. The church is old and partly ivy-clad. There are a national school, and charities &#163;17. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.kellner.eclipse.co.uk/genuki/NTH/Rockingham</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rockingham,_Northamptonshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639247</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10148236</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROCKINGHAM WITH CALDECOTE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10172767</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>ROCKINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280291</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ROCKINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280310</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROCKINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280321</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROCKINGHAM WITH CALDECOTE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
