<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7935</id>
<name>FOTHERINGHAY</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5306948827051</lat>
<lon>-0.430684019922854</lon>
<gazetteerText>FOTHERINGHAY, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Oundle district, Northampton. The village stands on the river Nen, near the boundary with Huntingdon, and near the Northampton and Peterborough railway, 3&#189; miles NNE of Oundle; was once a market-town; and has now a post office under Oundle, and a fair on the third Monday after 5 July. The parish comprises 2, 110 acres. Real property, &#163;4, 185. Pop., 246. Houses, 48. The property is all Lord Overstone&apos;s. A castle here was built, in the time of William the Conqueror, by Simon St. Liz, second Earl of Northampton; was rebuilt by Edmund, Duke of York, son of Edward III.; had a keep in the shape of a fetterlock; was the place of Edward IV. &apos;s meeting with his queen, on his return from quelling the insurrection in the north; was the place also of that king&apos;s receiving homage from Alexander, king of Scotland; was the birthplace of Richard III.; was settled by Henry VIII. on his first queen, Catherine; was the prison, the place of trial, and the execution-place of Mary Queen of Scots; and was dismantled about 1628. A nunnery stood near the church in ancient times; was made collegiate by Edward of York, in 1412; and was given, by Edward VI., to Northumberland. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;200.* Patron, Lord Overstone. The church is decorated English, of the time of Henry V.; was the burial-place of Shakspeare&apos;s Edward of York who died at Agincourt, and of Richard Duke of York who was slain at the battle of Wakefield; contains a fine font, a finely carved pulpit, and some monuments erected by Queen Elizabeth to the Plantagenets; and is in good condition. A grammar-school, founded by Queen Elizabeth, has &#163;20: and other charities have &#163;75. -The sub-district contains twelve parishes and four extra-parochial places. Acres, 26, 110. Pop., 6, 251. Houses, 1, 353. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.kellner.eclipse.co.uk/genuki/NTH/Fotheringhay</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fotheringhay</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649154</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10274606</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FOTHERINGHAY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10274655</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FOTHERINGHAY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10563392</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FOTHERINGHAY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
