<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7460</id>
<name>HOLME PIERREPONT</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9368105940598</lat>
<lon>-1.08029066464796</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOLME-PIERREPONT, a parish in Bingham district, Notts; on the river Trent, 1&#189; mile SW of Ratcliffe r. station, and 4&#189; E by S of Nottingham. It contains the hamlets of Holme-Lane and Adbolton, and parts of the hamlet of Lamcote and the township of Bassingfield, the last of which has a post office under Nottingham. Acres, 2, 120. Real property, &#163;4, 011. Pop. in 1851, 179; in 1861, 150. Houses, 28. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged formerly to the Pierreponts, Dukes of Kingston; and belongs now to Earl Manvers. Holme-Pierrepont Hall, a large Gothic mansion, is the seat of Earl Manvers. The living is a rectory, united with the chapelry of Adbolton, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;747.* Patron, Earl Manvers. The church is ancient; was recently restored; comprises nave, chancel, and aisle, with tower and lofty spire; and includes a magnificent mortuary chapel, containing numerous monuments of the Pierreponts and the Manverses. There are three small charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/HolmePierrePont/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holme_Pierrepont</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646721</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10262290</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HOLME PIERREPONT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10262320</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HOLME PIERREPONT WITH ADBOLTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7411</id>
   <name>GAMSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>7459</id>
<name>HOLME</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1199000218311</lat>
<lon>-0.78974530936535</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOLME, a parish in Southwell district, Notts; on the river Trent, adjacent to the Great Northern railway, 3&#189; miles N of Newark. Post town, Newark. Acres, 1, 330. Real property, &#163;1, 912. Pop., 121. Houses, 26. The manor belongs to the Duke of Newcastle. Holme Hall was, in the middle of the 17th century, the residence of Lord Bellasis; and has, ever since then, been inhabited by the Wells family. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Langford, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;172.* Patron, Trinity College, Cambridge. The church is ancient; consists of nave, chancel, and S aisle, with a tower; contains several very ancient monuments, one to Lord Bellasis, and some to the Bartons; and has, over its porch, &quot;Nan Scott&apos;s Chamber, &quot; to which a woman of that name fled from the great plague. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Holme/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holme,_Nottinghamshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646730</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10262240</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>HOLME</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10262288</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HOLME</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
