<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>21078</id>
<name>SNEINTON</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9511516989232</lat>
<lon>-1.1262136264734</lon>
<gazetteerText>SNENTON, or Sneinton, a parish, which is also a sub-district, in Radford district, Notts; suburban to the SE side of Nottingham; and consisting of S.-Elements, Old S., New S., and the Hermitage. It took its name from the same source as Nottingham; is thought by some writers to have been the cradle or original of that town; was given, by King John, to W. de Briwere; passed to the Pierre-ponts; had no greater seat of population, in the early years of the present century, than a few straggling houses; rose thence to the condition of a great suburb, with well built streets; shares now in the general interests of Nottingham; carries on lace-making, hose-making, the manufacture of chemicals, and the making of Roman cement, plaster, and bricks; and has a post-office, of the name of S. -Elements, under Nottingham. Acres, 720. Real property, &#163;27,277. Pop. in 1851, 8,440; in 1861, 11,048. Houses, 278. The manor belongs to Earl Manvers. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;227.* Patron, Earl Manvers. The church was rebuilt in 1840; is in the early English style, cruciform, and 120 feet long; and has a tower 90 feet high. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and the Notts lunatic asylum. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sneinton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637585</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Sneinton/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10266300</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NOTTINGHAM ST CYPRIAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270108</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>SNEINTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270110</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SNEINTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270121</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SNEINTON ST ALBAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270133</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SNEINTON ST CHRISTOPHER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270145</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SNEINTON ST CHRISTOPHER WITH ST PHILIP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270157</id>
   <status>EExP</status>
   <name>SNEINTON ST MATTHIAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270170</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SNEINTON ST STEPHEN WITH ST ALBAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10562740</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SNENTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
