<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11168</id>
<name>ST DOGMAELS</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0780460359941</lat>
<lon>-4.68123385433742</lon>
<gazetteerText>DOGMELLS (St.), or Llandydoch, a suburb and a parish in the district of Cardigan, and county of Pembroke. The suburb lies on the river Teifi, separated only by that river from the town of Cardigan; is called Bridgend, but includes a village of the name of St. Dogmells; and has a post office, &#8225; of that name, under Cardigan. The parish contains also the hamlets of Cippin, Panty-groes, and Abbey, and the workhouse of Cardigan. Acres, 6, 220; of which 235 are water. Real property, &#163;5, 642. Pop., 2, 438. Houses, 641. The Welsh princes had a seat here; and Rhys ap Tewdwr defeated here the sons of Codifor ab Collwyw. A large and splendid abbey was founded at what is now called Abbeybarn, by Martin de Tours; and some remains of the church, and of the eastern attached buildings, together with two curious antiquities in the grounds, still exist. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarages of Llantyd and Monington, in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;143. Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is a neat early English structure, adjacent to the remains of the abbey; and contains a monument of Bradshaw, who got the abbey at the dissolution. There is a dissenting chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/StDogmaels/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Dogmaels</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638814</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10302122</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST DOGMAELS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10386100</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>ST DOGMELLS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10388284</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST DOGMELLS MUNICIPAL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4095</id>
   <name>Y FERWIG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6639</id>
   <name>LLANTWYD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8236</id>
   <name>MONINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8261</id>
   <name>MOYLGROVE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11260</id>
   <name>CARDIGAN ISLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
