<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1407</id>
<name>ABATY CWM HIR</name>
<container>RADNORSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.354725447597</lat>
<lon>-3.40794659909101</lon>
<gazetteerText>ABBEY-CWM-HIR, a parochial chapelry in Rhayader district, Radnor; 6 miles NNW of the Central Wales railway below Penybont, and 6&#189; ENE of Rhayader. Post Town, Penybont. Acres, 10,965. Pop. 537. Houses, 96. The name signifies the Abbey of the Long Vale. The surface lies along the Clywedog, a tributary of the Ithon; and is a charming, fertile bottom, environed and overhung by picturesque wooded hills. A Cistertian Abbey was founded here, in 1143, by Cadwathelan ap Madoc; and destroyed, in 1401, by Owen Glendower. The property belonged, in the 17th century, to Sir Wm. Fowler, concerning whom it was said,- There is neither a park nor a deer To be seen in all Radnorshire, Nor a man with five hundred a year Save Fowler of Abbey-Cwm-Hir. The Abbey church was 255 feet long and 73 feet wide but only a few fragments of it remain. The mansion of F. Philips, Esq., partly built with the stones of the church in 1816, stands adjacent. A Roman road goes up the vale past the Abbey, toward the valley of the Marteg. The living of Abbey-Cwm-Hir is a vicarage in the diocese of St David&apos;s. Value, &#163;61. Patron, G. H. Philips, Esq. The church was rebuilt in 1867, and is in the Continental first pointed style. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/RAD/AbbeyCwm-hir/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7293929</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10006521</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ABATY CWM HIR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17298</id>
   <name>POWYS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
