<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3727</id>
<name>OLD RADNOR</name>
<container>RADNORSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2245791513568</lat>
<lon>-3.09957899694214</lon>
<gazetteerText>RADNOR. (Old), a village, a township, and a parish, in Presteigne district, Radnorshire. The village stands on a rocky height, 2&#190; miles E S E of New Radnor and 3&#190; W N W of Kington r. station. The township contains also the hamlet of Burlingjobb, and bears the name of O. R. and B. Real property, &#163;1, 960. Pop., 350. Houses, 79. The parish contains also the townships of Lower Harpton, electorally in Hereford, part of Upper Harpton, and all Ednol, all Walton and Womaston, all Evenjobb, Newcastle, Barland, and Burfa, and all Kinnerton, Salford, and Badland; and is partly within New Radnor borough. Post-town, Kington. Acres, exclusive of Lower Harpton, 10,069. Real property, inc. of therest of Upper Harpton, &#163;11, 536. Pop. of the parish1, 349. Houses, 292. Pop. of the part in N. R. borough, 1, 264. Houses, 277. The property is divided amongvery few. Harpton Court is the seat of the Lewis family. The hills of Old Radnor, Stanner, Hanter, and Worzelconsist of rocks similar to the hypersthene of Coruisk in Skye, and possess much interest for geologists. Charles I., when fleeing from Cromwell, in 1645, supped with a yeoman at Stones. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Kinnerton, in the diocese of Hereford. Value, &#163;195.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Worcester. The church stands on a hill; is ancient, large, and good; has a tower; and contains an ancientfont, a carved oak screen, and monuments of the Lewises. The p. curacy of Evenjobb is a separate benefice. There are an Independent chapel, an endowed school with &#163;40a year, and charities &#163;19. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HEF/OldRadnor/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640999</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/RAD/OldRadnor/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Radnor</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10117458</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Tn</status>
   <name>BURLINGJOBB AND OLD RADNOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10130864</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLD RADNOR WITH KINNERTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24434</id>
<name>EVANCOYD</name>
<container>RADNORSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2616138453972</lat>
<lon>-3.08144477358175</lon>
<gazetteerText>EVANCOYD, a chapelry in Old Radnor parish; near Kington. It was constituted in 1866. Pop., 365. The living is a p. curacy. Value, &#163;150. Patrons, Trustees. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7297056</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10182785</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVANCOYD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
