<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3144</id>
<name>UPPINGHAM</name>
<container>RUTLAND</container>
<lat>52.5861376757231</lat>
<lon>-0.725269804610961</lon>
<gazetteerText>UPPINGHAM, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Rutland. The town stands 3 miles SSW of Manton r. station, and 6 S of Oakham; is a seat of county courts; consists chiefly of one long street; and has a head post-office,&#8225; two banking offices, a hotel, an ancient church restored in 1861, and surmounted by a lofty spire, four dissenting chapels, a new cemetery formed at a cost of more than &#163;6,000, a famous grammar-school, a national school, a workhouse, charities &#163;53, a weekly market on Wednesday, and fairs on 7 March and 7 July. The grammar-school was founded in the time of Elizabeth; was rebuilt in 1863, at a cost of &#163;40,000; has a chapel in the decorated English style, built in 1865, at a cost of nearly &#163;6,000; includes accommodation for from 250 to 300 boarders; holds two scholarships of &#163;70 a year each, and three exhibitions at the universities; had Archbishop Manners Sutton, Bishops Ferne and Bramston, and Lord Chancellor Manners for pupils; and has, in connexion with it, an hospital-charity for decayed tradesmen, widows, and others. Pop. of the town, in 1861, 2,176. Houses, 392.&#151;The parish comprises 1,210 acres. Real property, &#163;.9,201; of which &#163;140 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 2,068; in 1861, 2,186. Houses, 397. The manor belonged to the Montforts; passed to the Beauchamps, the Cecils, the Greys, and others; and belongs now to the Earl of Gainsborough. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;661.* Patron, the Bishop of P. Jeremy Taylor was rector.&#151;The sub-district contains 12 parishes. Acres, 19,007. Pop., 5,356. Houses, 1,080.&#151;The district includes also Barrowden and Great Easton sub-districts, and comprises 52,698 acres. Poor rates, in 1863, &#163;6,179. Pop. in 1851, 12,719; in 1861, 12,367. Houses, 2,626. Marriages in 1863, 73; births, 371,-of which 35 were illegitimate; deaths,. 259, -of which 100 were at ages under 5 years, and 7 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 756; births, 3,920; deaths 2,206. The places of worship, in 1851, were 31 of the Church of England, with 6,817 sittings; 4 of Independents, with 818 s.; 9 of Baptists, with 1,161 s.; 1 of Quakers, with 60 s.; 8 of Wesleyans, with 895 s; 2 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 186 s.; 2 undefined, with 380 s.: and 1 of Latter Day Saints, with 30 s. The schools were 18 public day-schools, with 1,170 scholars; 39 private day-schools, with 554 s.; and 37 Sunday schools, with 1,971 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uppingham</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Uppingham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635101</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10004627</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>UPPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10037918</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>UPPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10055696</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>UPPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10074447</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>UPPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10092085</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>UPPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541499</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>UPPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581552</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>UPPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1990</id>
   <name>PRESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3313</id>
   <name>AYSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4362</id>
   <name>BEAUMONT CHASE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6021</id>
   <name>BISBROOKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11300</id>
   <name>STOCKERSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
