<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2057</id>
<name>BROMFIELD</name>
<container>SHROPSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.383551845541</lat>
<lon>-2.76220160557963</lon>
<gazetteerText>BROMFIELD, a village, a township, and a parish in Ludlow district, Salop. The village stands near the confluence of the Onny and the Teme, adjacent to the Shrewsbury and Hereford railway, 2&#189; miles NW by N of Ludlow; and has a station on the railway, an inn, and a head post office, designated Bromfield, Shropshire. The township includes also the sub-townships of Lady-Halton and Priors Halton. Acres, 6,112. Pop., 621. Houses, 115. The parish contains likewise the chapelry of Halford. Acres, 7,174. Real property, &#163;9,457. Pop., 762. Houses, 138. The property is divided among a few. Oakley Park, contiguous to the village, is a fine feature. A small college of secular canons was founded, in the time of Henry I., on the brink of the Teme, below the influx of the Onny; became, in 1159, a Benedictine priory, subject to St. Peter&apos;s Abbey at Gloucester; and was given, in the time of Mary, to Charles Fox. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Hereford. Value, &#163;334.* Patron, R. G. W. Clive, Esq. The church adjoins some remains of the ancient priory; is an ancient structure of various dates, with a tower; and was repaired in 1850. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Bromfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654591</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bromfield,_Shropshire</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10040206</id>
   <status>Tn/CP/AP</status>
   <name>BROMFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10080939</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BROMFIELD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
