<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2855</id>
<name>ATCHAM</name>
<container>SHROPSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6847920742471</lat>
<lon>-2.68429248200663</lon>
<gazetteerText>ATCHAM, a township, a parish, a subdistrict, and a district in Salop. The township lies at the influx of the Tern to the Severn, 2 miles SSW of Upton-Magna r. station, 4 SE of Shrewsbury, and 6&#188; W by N of the Wrekin. It also bears the name of Attingham; and has an inn. The parish includes also the townships of Berwick, Chilton, Cronkhill, Emstray, and Uckington; and has a post office under Shrewsbury. Acres, 3,762. Real property, &#163;4,851. Pop., 406. Houses, 92. The property is divided among a few. Attingham Hall is the seat of Lord Berwick, and contains a fine gallery of paintings, chiefly by the early Italian masters, also a fine collection of Etruscan vases and other antiquities from Herculaneum. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;330. Patron, R. Burton, Esq. The church has a good Norman doorway, an old porch, a reading-desk with carved panels, and an ivy-covered square tower; but is in very bad condition. Charities, &#163;84. Ordericus Vitalis, the historian, born in 1074, was a native.-The subdistrict comprises the parishes of Atcham, Uppington, Leighton, Eaton-Constantine, and Wroxeter. Acres, 12,316. Pop., 1,699. Houses, 347.&#151;The district comprehends also the subdistrict of Battlefield, containing the parishes of Battlefield, Preston-Gubbals, Uffington,-Upton-Magna, and Withington, the extra-parochial tract of Hanghmond-Demesne, and part of the parish of St. Mary-Shrewsbury; the subdistrict of Montford, containing the parishes of Montford, Melverley, Shrawardine, and Fitz; the sub district of Alberbury, containing the parishes of Cardeston and Ford, and part of the parish of Alberbury, portions of which are electorally in Montgomery; the subdistrict of Westbury, conterminate with the parish of Westbury; the subdistrict of Pontesbury, containing the parishes of Pontesbury, Habberley, and Great Hanwood; and the subdistrict of Condover, containing the parishes of Condover, Harley, Shineton, Cound, Kenley, Hughley, Church-Preen, Acton-Burnell, Frodesley, Pitchford, Berrington, Sutton, Stapleton, and Church-Pulverbatch. Poor-rates in 1866, &#163;8,972. Pop. in 1841, 18,842; in 1861, 19,455. Houses, 3,848. Marriages in 1866, 105; births, 538,-of which 36 were illegitimate; deaths, 344,-of which 75 were at ages under 5 years, and 27 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60. 974; births, 5,352; deaths, 3,499. The places of worship in 1851 were 43 of the Church of England, with 9,027 sittings; 9 of Independents, with 1,299 s.; 4 of Baptists, with 433 s.; 5 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 290 s.; 1 of New Connexion Methodists, with 96 s.; 16 of Primitive Methodists, with 1,219 s.; 1 of Calvinistic Methodists, with 125 s.; 1 of Latter Day Saints, with 40 s.; and 1 of Roman Catholics, with 170 s. The schools were 29 public day schools, with 1,703 scholars; 24 private day schools, with 388 s.; and 32 Sunday schools, with 1,391 s. The workhouse is in Berrington. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Atcham/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656852</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atcham</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Atcham</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10005589</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>ATCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10028851</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>ATCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10055246</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>ATCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10080733</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ATCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10088392</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ATCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10559133</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ATCHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>133</id>
<name>SHREWSBURY</name>
<container>SHROPSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7131393833256</lat>
<lon>-2.74776071222679</lon>
<gazetteerText>Shrewsbury, parl. and mun. bor., and co. town of Shropshire, on river Severn, 42 miles NW. of Birmingham and 162 miles NW. of London by rail, 3674 ac., pop. 26.478; 5 Banks, 3 newspapers. Market-days, Wednesday and Saturday. Shrewsbury, with its fine old timbered houses, is one of the most picturesque of English towns. It is situated on a peninsula formed by a bend of the Severn, which is spanned by two stone bridges - the English bridge, leading to the suburb of Abbey-Foregate; and the Welsh bridge, leading to the suburb of Frankwell. Among the chief objects of interest are the remains of the old walls; the ruins of the castle, built immediately after the Conquest; the church of Holy Cross, originally attached to a great Benedictine abbey; the grammar school of Edward VI., now ranking high among public schools; the old markethouse, of time of Elizabeth; and the monuments to Lord Clive and Lord Hill. The Quarry Promenade, along the river side, has a fine avenue of lime trees, planted in 1719. Shrewsbury is a railway centre; and it has glass-staining and malting, linen-thread mfrs., iron foundries, and agricultural-implement works. It was a place of great importance in the frontier wars of the Saxon and Norman periods, and in 1403 was the scene of a great battle between the forces of the Earl of Northumberland and those of Henry IV., in which the earl was defeated and his son, &quot;Hotspur,&quot; slain. Shrewsbury was first chartered by the Conqueror. It returns 1 member to Parliament; it returned 2 members from the time of Edward I. until 1885. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Shrewsbury/StAlkmond/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Shrewsbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Shrewsbury/HolyCrossStGiles/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Shrewsbury/StChad/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Shrewsbury/StJulian/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Shrewsbury/StMary/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shrewsbury</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Shrewsbury</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637891</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>12757566</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10365454</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366112</id>
   <status>EP/EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST GILES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10023750</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10365466</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY HOLY CROSS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366094</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST CHAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10579831</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10365491</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY HOLY CROSS WITH ST GILES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10110981</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366045</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST CHAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366252</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10365442</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10056822</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY AND ATCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12753664</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741078</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>SHROPSHIRE SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12746994</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY AND ATCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366021</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366203</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10365480</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY HOLY CROSS WITH ST GILES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366148</id>
   <status>Ch/CP/AP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST JULIAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366010</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST ALKMUND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546588</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ST CHAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546590</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10199955</id>
   <status>Inc/RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10055982</id>
   <status>Liberty</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10000713</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366033</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST ALKMUND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366240</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366197</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST JULIAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12781210</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10367074</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>UNNAMED</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10366100</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY ST GEORGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10365478</id>
   <status>EP/EP</status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY HOLY CROSS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833039</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHREWSBURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>435</id>
   <name>DAWLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>629</id>
   <name>LUDLOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>631</id>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1106</id>
   <name>LLANIDLOES</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1124</id>
   <name>NEWTOWN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1180</id>
   <name>MARKET DRAYTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2052</id>
   <name>BICTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10216</id>
   <name>CONDOVER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10401</id>
   <name>LILLESHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10522</id>
   <name>WENLOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
