<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2649</id>
<name>MENDHAM</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.3856323984464</lat>
<lon>1.34291213409056</lon>
<gazetteerText>MENDHAM, a village in Hoxne district, Suffolk, and a parish partly also in Norfolk. The village stands on the river Waveney at the boundary with Norfolk, 1&#190; mile ESE of Harleston r. station; and has a postal letter-box under Harleston. The parish comprises 3,144 acres. Real property of the Suffolk portion, &#163;4,286. Pop., 558. Houses, 121. Real property of the Norfolk portion, &#163;1,963. Pop., 221. Houses, 49. There are three manors, Walsham Hall, Mendham King&apos;s Hall, and Priory; and the first belongs to W. S. Holmes, Esq.,-the second and the third, to Sir Robert S. Adair, Bart. The priory is the residence of Capt. T. Wood A Cluniac priory, a cell to Castle-Acre in Norfolk, was founded here, in the time of Stephen, by William, son of Roger de Huntingfield; was given, at the dissolution, to the Brandons; and has left some remains The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value. &#163;122.* Patron, the Rev. E. W. Whitaker. The church is later English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and contains three good brasses of the Freston family, and several mural monuments. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, and a parochial school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/mendham/</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Mendham/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642752</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10068666</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MENDHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
