<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7161</id>
<name>EXNING</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.2628766495067</lat>
<lon>0.383607976512222</lon>
<gazetteerText>EXNING, or Ixning, a village and a parish in the district of Newmarket and county of Suffolk. The village stands in an isolated tract of the county, near Icknield-street and near the Newmarket railway, 2 miles NW of Newmarket; and has a post office under Newmarket. The parish contains also the Newmarket workhouse. Acres, 5, 710. Real property, &#163;10, 824. Pop., 1, 348. Houses, 234. The property is divided among a few. The family of Shepherd had formerly a seat here; and St. Etheldred, the founder of Ely abbey, was a native. Exning Lodge is the seat of the Martins. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Landwade, in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;465.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Canterbury. The church has a tower; contains remains of brasses and old armorial bearings; and is good. There is a Wesleyan chapel. Shepherd&apos;s charity for the poor has &#163;84; church lands yield &#163;66; and other charities have &#163;10. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Exning/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exning</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649799</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10024470</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>EXNING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10254309</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EXNING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10254322</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EXNING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10254401</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EXNING ST AGNES</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3811</id>
   <name>LANDWADE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4626</id>
   <name>SNAILWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
