<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12980</id>
<name>KEWSTOKE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3777145922507</lat>
<lon>-2.94948818784603</lon>
<gazetteerText>KEWSTOKE, a village and a parish, in Axbridge district, Somerset. The village stands on the coast, at Sand bay, 2 miles NNE of Weston-super-Mare r. station, and 9 NW of Axbridge. The parish contains also the hamlets of Milton and Norton. Post town, Westonsuper-Mare. Acres, 4, 008; of which 1, 580 are water. Real property, with Worle, &#163;12, 194. Rated property of K. alone, &#163;6, 600. Pop., 550. Houses, 111. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to John Hellier, Esq. Woodspring priory here was founded in 1210, for Augustinian canons, by William de Courtenay; was dissolved in 1534, when it had a revenue of &#163;111; and is now represented partly by a farm house, partly by a ruined tower, which retains much of its original character. A modern road, through a wood, from K. village to Weston, commands charming views over the Bristol channel to the Welsh mountains; and a flight of about 200 rude stairs, called Kew Steps, leads up to a magnificent view and an ancient camp on Worle Hill. Limestone is quarried. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is Norman and early English; was recently restored; and comprises nave and chancel, with porch and tower. There are a national school, and charities &#163; 4. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Kewstoke/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kewstoke</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/3345387</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10435250</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>KEWSTOKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10435304</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KEWSTOKE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
