<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4819</id>
<name>HAMBLEDON</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.1322529340668</lat>
<lon>-0.623105249257381</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAMBLEDON, a village, a parish, and a district in Surrey. The village stands 1&#189; mile NE of Witley r. station, and 3&#189; S of Godalming; and has a post office under Godalming. The parish comprises 1, 556 acres. Real property, &#163;1, 634. Pop., 557. Houses, 85. The property is divided among a few. A remarkable group of ancient chestnuts is at Burghgate; and an excellent building stone, called the Burghgate stone, is there. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;207.* Patron, the Earl of Radnor. The church is almost entirely modern. The workhouse is at the verge of the parish; and, in 1861, had 133 inmates.&#151;The district comprehends the sub-district of Witley, containing the parishes of Hambledon, Witley, Thursley, Elstead, Pepper-Harrow, Haslemere, Chiddingfold, and Hascombe; and the sub-district of Cranley, containing the parishes of Cranley, Ewhurst, Dunsfold, Bramley, Shalford, St. Martha-on-the-Hill, Wonersh, and Alford, -the last partly in Sussex. Acres, 60, 351. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;, 899. Pop. in 185, 1, 552; in 186, 13, 907. Houses, 2, 724. Marriages in 186, 79; births, 442, -of which 24 were illegitimate; deaths, 207, -of which 62 were at ages under 5 years, and 11 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 868; births, 4, 238; deaths, 2, 336. The places of worship, in 1851, were 17 of the Church of England, with 4, 867 sittings; 5 of Inpendents, with 765 s.; 1 of Baptists, with 100 s.; 1 of Wesleyans, with 124 s.; and 1 undefined, with 130 s. The schools were 16 public day schools, with 1, 095 scholars; 24 private day schools, with 480 s.; 20 Sunday schools, with 1, 404 s.; and 2 evening schools for adults, with 32 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hambledon,_Surrey</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Hambledon</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647581</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42925</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10044121</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>HAMBLEDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135412</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>HAMBLEDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10137676</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>HAMBLEDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163912</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HAMBLEDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10182888</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAMBLEDON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17286</id>
   <name>WAVERLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
