<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5224</id>
<name>GATTON</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.260666915889</lat>
<lon>-0.176491535369014</lon>
<gazetteerText>GATTON, a village and a parish in Reigate district, Surrey. The village stands on the ancient Roman road from Stane-street to Croydon, and near the source of the river Mole, 1 mile WNW of Merstham r. station, and 2&#189; NE by N of Reigate. It took its name from the Roman road or &quot; gate;&quot; is supposed to occupy the site of a Roman fort or station; has yielded Roman coins; ap-pears to have been a place of considerable importance in the middle ages; was made a borough, in 1451, by Henry VI.; sent two members to parliament till disfranchised by the reform bill; and had only about 20 houses and 100 inhabitants at the time of its disfranchisement. The parish comprises 1, 260 acres. Post town, Merstham under Red Hill. Real property, &#163;2, 387. Pop., 191. Houses, 36. The property is divided among a few. Gatton Park is the seat of Lord Monson; possessed the direction and disposal of the quondam borough; and was purchased by the late Lord Monson, in 1830, for &#163;180, 000. The house is a stately edifice, in the Italian style; stands amid beautiful grounds, with a fine lake; has a splendid hall, modelled after the Corsini Chapel at Rome; and contains a rich collection of pictures. Upper Gatton House also is a handsome mansion; and was formerly a seat of the Duke of St. Albans. A small bridge in the parish, called Battle Bridge, was the scene of a great slaughter by women, of Danes fleeing from the battlefield of Ockley, in 851. A white soft stone, used in the construction of Hampton Court, and much valued for ovens and furnaces, was quarried. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;148. Patron, Lord Monson. The church stands in the grounds of Gatton Park; is an ancient structure, seemingly early English; contains a fine collection of Flemish oak carving; and was renovated in 1834. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648769</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42955</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10019023</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10024500</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>GATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10182839</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758558</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>GATTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
