<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9008</id>
<name>SELSEY</name>
<container>SUSSEX</container>
<lat>50.7437538922993</lat>
<lon>-0.781113978678918</lon>
<gazetteerText>SELSEY, a village and a parish in Westhampnett district, Sussex. The village stands on a peninsula, &#189; a milefrom the sea, 6&#189; S W of Bognor r. station, and 8 S of Chichester; is traditionally said to have been once in the centre of the peninsula; was known to the Saxons as Selsea or Seloesea; took that name from two words signifying &quot; Seal&apos;s Island; &quot; was early and long a town of considerable consequence; acquired a monastery about 680, founded by King &#198;delwalch; became in 711 the seat of a bishopric, which was removed in 1075 to Chichester; gave the title of Baron to the family of Peachey; consists now of 3 streets, one of them inhabited chieflyby fishermen; and has a post-office under Chichester. The parish consists of the peninsula; is connected with the main land only by an isthmus, between the head of Pagham harbour and the sea; and comprises 3, 494 acres of land, and 820 of water. Real property, &#163;5, 424. Pop., 900. Houses, 191. About half of the peninsula is believed to have been swept away since the Saxon times. All the surface is a dead level, on the London clay formation, with a rich soil, but interspersed with deep marshes. The coast also is all low; terminates in a headland, called Selsey Bill; and is flanked there by a dangerous circle of shoals. A sea-tract on the S E bears the name of the Park; was a park of the Bishops, stocked with deer, solate as the time of Henry VIII.; and is now an anchorage-ground, with from 1 to 3 fathoms water. The site of the ancient cathedral also is now covered by the sea. The living is a rectory and a vicarage in the diocese of Chichester. Value, &#163;759.* Patron, the Bishop of Chichester. The church stood about 2 miles N E of the village, but is now at its entrance. Nicholls, the ecclesiastical writer who died in 1712, was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Selsey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638219</link>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/SSX/Selsey/index.php</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41746</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10310866</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SELSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10310878</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SELSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10579624</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SELSEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
