<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>941</id>
<name>HANDSWORTH</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5225996699746</lat>
<lon>-1.9190115681101</lon>
<gazetteerText>HANDSWORTH, a town, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in West Bromwich district, Stafford. The town stands contiguous to Warwickshire, on Hockley Brook, near the Birmingham and Wolverhampton railway; is suburban to Birmingham, and averagely 2&#189; miles NNW of the centre of that borough; partakes of the industry and general character of Birmingham; is the seat of the famous Soho manufactory; and has a post office&#8225; under Birmingham, and two stations with telegraph, the one called Soho, the other called Handsworth-Smethwick, on the Birmingham and Wolverhampton railway. The township bears the name of Handsworth-with-Soho. Pop. in 1851, 7, 047; in 1861, 10, 398. Houses, 2, 003. The parish includes also the hamlet of Perry-Barr, and comprises 7, 680 acres. Real property, &#163;48, 532. Pop. in 1851, 7, 879; in 1861, 11, 459. Houses, 2, 179. There are five livings, -H. ST. Mary, H. ST. James, H. ST. Michael, Birchfield, and Perry-Barr; and the first is a rectory, the others vicarages, in the diocese of Lichfield. Value of St. Mary, &#163;1, 500;* of St. James and PerryBarr, each &#163;200;* of St. Michael, &#163;300; of Birchfield, not reported. Patron of St. Mary, the Rev. J. Peel, D.D.; of Perry-Barr, Lord Calthorpe; of the others, the Rector of Handsworth. St. Mary&apos;s church was ancient, but has been mostly rebuilt; includes a recent chapel, with a statue of Watt, by Chantry; and contains a bust of Boulton by Flaxman, and several old monuments. St. James&apos; church was built in 1840; and had assigned to it, in 1854, a definite territory, the pop. of which, in 1861, was 3, 691. St. Michael&apos;s church was built in 1858, at a cost of about &#163;6, 000; and is in the decorated English style. Birchfield church was built in 1864. There are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Roman Catholics, a convent of sisters of mercy, a middle school, national schools, and charities &#163;1 99. The convent is a large edifice in Hunters lane, and the chapel connected with it is very elegant. The middle school was built in 1862, at a cost of &#163;3, 200.&#151;The sub-district is conterminate with the parish. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Handsworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Handsworth,_West_Midlands</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075154</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173607</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278880</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278934</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278958</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278971</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH ST JAMES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278983</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279008</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10485927</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550336</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574432</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574444</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HANDSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12736769</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>STAFFORDSHIRE HANDSWORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
