<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1282</id>
<name>ALDRIDGE</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5942252102221</lat>
<lon>-1.92262858708776</lon>
<gazetteerText>ALDRIDGE, a small town, a parish, and a subdistrict in the district of Walsall, Stafford. The town stands near the Worley canal, 2&#190; miles ESE of Pelsall r. station, and 3&#189; NE of Walsall; and it has a post office under Walsall. An extensive distillery is here; and fine potter&apos;s clay and coal are worked in the neighbourhood. Pop., 1,179. Houses, 234.&#151;The parish includes also the town of Great Barr. Acres, 7,752. Real property, &#163;6,041. Pop., 2,254. Houses, 454. The property is divided among a few. A height called Barr-Beacon, is said to have been a place of Druidical sacrifices; and a pool, called Druid Mere, makes an occasional overflow, and has been popularly imagined to possess some supernatural quality. Barr-Hall-Park is the seat of Sir E. D. Scott, Bart. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;375.* Patron, the Rev. J. F. Smith. The church contains a monument of a Stapleton, and is good. The vicarage of Great Barr is a separate benefice. Jordan&apos;s schools have &#163;118 from endowment, and other charities &#163;64.-The subdistrict comprises two parishes and part of a third. Pop., 7,026. Houses, 1,413. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Aldridge/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657528</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aldridge</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10153724</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>ALDRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10179865</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>ALDRIDGE BROWNHILLS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272270</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ALDRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272282</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ALDRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272294</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>ALDRIDGE BROWNHILLS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550191</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ALDRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12744614</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>ALDRIDGE BROWNHILLS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>92</id>
   <name>PERRY BARR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7877</id>
   <name>GREAT BARR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8509</id>
   <name>SHENSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8589</id>
   <name>WALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
