<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>266</id>
<name>DARLASTON</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5765526212083</lat>
<lon>-2.03109296929617</lon>
<gazetteerText>DARLASTON, a town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Walsall district, Stafford. The town stands near the Bentley canal and the Birmingham and Wolverhampton railway, 1&#189; mile NW by N of Wednesbury; and has a station on the railway, and a post office&#8225; under Wednesbury. It carries on hardware manufacture, in many departments; has iron-foundries, steel-works, and malting mills: and presents the grimy aspect common to places of its class. The parish comprises 901 acres. Real property, &#163;31, 445; of which &#163;4, 423 are in mines, &#163;52 in quarries, and &#163;9, 923 in iron-works. Pop., 12, 884. Houses, 2, 514. The property is subdivided. Coal and ironstone are extensively mined; stone is quarried; and bricks are made. A canal aqueduct, over the Bescot brook, has two arches, and is 120 feet high. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;266.* Patrons, Simeon&apos;s Trustees. The church stands on an eminence, in the centre of the town; and is a plain brick building, with a lofty steeple. St. George&apos;s vicarage, constituted in 1844, is a separate benefice. Value, &#163;150. Patron, alternately the Crown and the Bishop. The church was built in 1852; and is a stone structure, in the early English style, with a north-western tower. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, and charities &#163;6. -The sub-district includes also part of Wolverhampton parish. Acres, 2, 551. Pop., 13, 230. Houses, 2, 582. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Darlaston/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darlaston</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651518</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10028917</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>DARLASTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10041430</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>DARLASTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10276871</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>DARLASTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10276901</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DARLASTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10276913</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DARLASTON ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10276937</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DARLASTON ST GEORGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550210</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DARLASTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12829759</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DARLASTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
