<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7860</id>
<name>ALTON</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9870434461083</lat>
<lon>-1.89720411552752</lon>
<gazetteerText>ALTON, or Alveton, a township, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Cheadle, Stafford. The township lies on the Churnet river, the Uttoxeter canal, and the North Stafford railway, 7&#189; miles NNW of Uttoxeter. It has a station on the railway, a post office under Stafford, and an inn. Real property, &#163;3,853. Pop., 1,173. Houses, 253.&#151;The parish includes also the townships of Farley, Denston, and Upper and Lower Cotton. Acres, 7,379. Real property, &#163;10,325. Pop., 2,250. Houses, 476. The manor belongs to the Earl of Shrewsbury. Alton-Towers, the seat of the Earl, is a splendid edifice, in a variety of styles, built in 1814; and contains a magnificent hall, an armory, 120 feet long, a picture gallery, 150 feet long, with superb collection of pictures, a chapel with stained windows by Pugin, and a state drawing room, with some ornaments of Queen Catherine. The gardens connected with it are richly ornate; and contain a Choragic temple, a Chinese conservatory, an imitation Stonehenge, a pagoda 95 feet high, and a Gothic temple commanding an extensive view. The ruins of a castle of the De Verdons, of the time of Henry II., stand on a rock by the Churnet, 300 feet high. St. John&apos;s hospital, founded by the Talbots, for a warden and fellows, with church and school, is near the castle. An ancient camp, with double fosse, occurs at Bonebury. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;151.* Patron, the Earl of Shrewsbury. The church is modern. Cotton and Denston are separate charges; and there are chapels for Independents, Methodists, and Roman Catho lics, and charities &#163;25.-The subdistrict comprises three parishes. Acres, 9,487. Pop., 2,693. Houses, 564. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Alton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alton,_Staffordshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657407</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10073923</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>ALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272440</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272452</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550142</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ALTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7898</id>
   <name>BRADLEY IN THE MOORS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8020</id>
   <name>CROXDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8061</id>
   <name>FARLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8483</id>
   <name>RAMSHORN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
