<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8582</id>
<name>TRENTHAM</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9686172298769</lat>
<lon>-2.19440981974546</lon>
<gazetteerText>TRENTHAM, a village, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Stone district, Stafford. The village stands on the river Trent, 1&#189; mile W of the North Staffordshire railway, and 3 SSW of Stoke-upon-Trent; is a seat of petty-sessions; gives the title of Viscount to the Duke of Sutherland; and has a post-office under Stoke-upon-Trent, a r. station, and a police station. The township includes the village, and extends into the country. Real property, &#163;5,471. Pop., 645. Houses, 127.&#151;The parish includes five other townships, and comprises 6,900 acres. Pop. in 1851, 2,747; in 1861, 4,611. Houses, 958. T. Park is the seat of the Duke of Sutherland; was altered by Barry into a splendid pile, with rich architectural decorations in the Italian style; has finely-wooded grounds, laid out by Brown, and containing a lake and a mausoleum; and was visited in 1805 by George III.,-in 1832, by the Princess Victoria,-in 1868, by the Prince and Princess of Wales. A nunnery was founded at T., before 683, by one of the Saxon kings; and an Augustinian priory superseded it, in the time o Henry I.; and was given, at the dissolution, to the Brandons. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;100.* Patron, the Duke of Sutherland. The church was rebuilt in 1842. The p. curacy of Butterton is a separate benefice. There are an endowed school with &#163;20 a year, and charities &#163;61.&#151;The sub-district includes also another parish and a liberty. Pop., 6,259. Houses, 1,273. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trentham,_Staffordshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Trentham/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635500</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10295282</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TRENTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10295300</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TRENTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10564086</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TRENTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581424</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TRENTHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
