<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8007</id>
<name>COLWICH</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7962701304812</lat>
<lon>-1.98639164468101</lon>
<gazetteerText>COLWICH, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in the district and county of Stafford. The village stands adjacent to the river Trent, the Grand Trunk canal, and the Trent Valley railway, near the junction of the North Stafford railway, 6&#189; miles ESE of Stafford; is beautifully situated; and has a r. station at the junction, and a post office under Stafford. The parish contains also the townships or hamlets of Fradswell, Bishton, Moreton, Wolseley, Shugborough, Swanmoor, and Mount-Priory, the post office of Wolseley-Bridge, under Stafford, and parts of the townships of Droiuton, Great Haywood, Little Haywood, and Hixon. Acres, 8, 975. Real property, &#163;26, 583. Pop., 1,828. Houses, 371. The property is subdivided. Shugborough Park, a beautiful mansion, amid charming grounds, is the seat of the Earl of Lichfield, and was the birth-place of Lord Anson, the great navigator. The living*is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;514. Patron, the Bishop of Lichfield. The church is ancient; and contains monuments of the Ansons and the Wolseleys. The vicarages of Fradswell, Great Haywood, and Hixon are separate benefices. Charities, &#163;79. -The sub-district contain s six parishes, and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 21, 370. Pop., 4, 322. Houses, 893. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Colwich/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colwich,_Staffordshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652516</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10276469</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>COLWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10276470</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>COLWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10565327</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>COLWICH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
