<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1320</id>
<name>HANLEY</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0232133885957</lat>
<lon>-2.17586805565217</lon>
<gazetteerText>Hanley, parl. and mun. bor., Staffordshire, in The Potteries district, 18 miles N. of Stafford and 147 miles NW. of London by rail -- mun. bor. (wholly in Stoke upon Trent par.), 1648 ac., pop. 48,361; parl. bor. (comprising the mun. bors. of Hanley and Burslem), pop. 75,912; 4 Banks, 2 newspapers. Market-days, Wednesday and Saturday. Hanley was made a mun. bor. in 1857, and a parl. bor. in 1885; it returns 1 member to Parliament. It is a modern town, which owes its prosperity to its vast mfrs. of china, encaustic tiles, and earthenware. It has been called the &quot;Metropolis of the Potteries.&quot; Coal and iron are obtained in the neighbourhood, and many of the inhabitants are employed at furnaces, foundries, brickworks, &amp;c,. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanley</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Hanley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647525</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53370</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53371</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53372</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10096110</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279045</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279057</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279069</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANLEY ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279070</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANLEY ST JUDE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279288</id>
   <status>CB/MB</status>
   <name>HANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280450</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANLEY WITH HOPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550452</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12738882</id>
   <status>PBDivCon</status>
   <name>STOKE ON TRENT HANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741546</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>HANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12836466</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HANLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24801</id>
<name>WELLINGTON</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0243742589668</lat>
<lon>-2.16401736689593</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELLINGTON, a chapelry in Stoke-upon-Trent parish, Stafford; near Stoke r. station. It was constituted in 1845; and its Post town is Stoke-upon-Trent. Pop., 5,555. Houses, 1,144. The property is subdivided. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;290.* Patron, alternately the Crown and the Bishop. The church is good; and there are dissenting chapels. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10280448</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HANLEY ST LUKE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
