<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>902</id>
<name>AUDLEY</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0537266810475</lat>
<lon>-2.29817433423989</lon>
<gazetteerText>AUDLEY, a township, a parish, and a subdistrict in the district of Newcastle-under-Lyne, Stafford. The township lies 3 miles W of Harecastle tunnel on the Grand Trunk canal, 3 S of Alsager r. station, and 5&#188; NW by N of Newcastle-under-Lyne. It has a post office&#8225; under Newcastle-under-Lyne; and it gives the title of Baron to the family of Touchet. Real property, &#163;4,189. Pop., 1,556. Houses, 317. The parish includes also the liberty of Halmer-End, and the townships off Talk-o&apos; th&apos;-Hill, Eardley-End, Knowl-End, Bignall-End, and Park-End. Acres, 8,530. Real property, &#163;30,383,-of which &#163;11,431 are in mines. Pop., 6,494. Houses, 1,330. The property is much subdivided Heleigh Castle, now a ruin, was the seat of the Audleys. Coal and ironstone are worked. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;520.* Patron, the Rev. E. Gilbert. The church was restored in. 1846 and 1856, and has some fine features. The vicarage of Talk o&apos;-th&apos;-Hill is a separate charge. There are Methodist chapels. Vernon&apos;s grammar school has an endowed income of &#163;115, and other charities have &#163;35.-The-subdistrict comprises two parishes and part of a third. Acres, 11,171. Pop., 7,625. Houses, 1,566. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Audley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656792</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audley,_Staffordshire</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10138437</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>AUDLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10167000</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>AUDLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272725</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>AUDLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272750</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>AUDLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272762</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>AUDLEY RURAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550531</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AUDLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833260</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AUDLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
