<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9356</id>
<name>SOUTHAM</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.252382706103</lat>
<lon>-1.38614263303727</lon>
<gazetteerText>SOUTHAM, a small town, a parish, a district, and a division in Warwick. The town stands on a branch of the river Ichene, 2&#190; miles NE of Harbury r. station, and 7&#189; miles ESE of Leamington; was known, at Domesday, as Sucham; gave a night&apos;s lodging to Charles I. and his two sons, on the eve of the battle of Edgehill; is a seat of petty sessions and county courts, and a polling place; and has a post-office&#8225; under Rugby, two banking offices, a hotel, several inns, a church, Independent and Methodist chapels, endowed national schools with &#163;61 a year, an eye and ear infirmary, a mineral spring similar to the waters of Leamington, another spring with intensely cold water, a workhouse, town lands &#163;180, a weekly market on Monday, and a fair on the first Monday of every month. The church is partly decorated English; was repaired and partly rebuilt in 1854; and has a beautiful broach spire.&#151;The parish comprises 2,770 acres. Real property, &#163;9,175. Pop., 1,674. Houses, 253. The manor is divided into 32 shares. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;600.* Patron, the Crown.&#151;The district contains 19 parishes, and 7 extra-parochial tracts. Acres, 50,409. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;5,490. Pop. in 1851,10,504; in 1861, 10,392. Houses, 2,279. Marriages in 1863, 59; births, 314,-of which 22 were illegitimate; deaths, 190,-of which 66 were at ages under 5 years, and 5 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 657; births, 3,457; deaths, 1,959. The places of worship, in 1851, were 19 of the Church of England, with 4,527 sittings; 3 of Independents, with 469 s.; 5 of Wesleyans, with 699 s.; 4 of Primitive Methodists, with 303 s.; 1 of Moravians, with 70 s.; and 1 undefined, with 70 s. The schools were 17 public day-schools, with 1,022 scholars; 22 private day-schools, with 425 s.; and 28 Sunday schools, with 1,783 s.-The division is mainly identical with the district, but less extensive; and is part of Knightlow hundred. Acres, 44,730. Pop. in 1851,9,362. Houses, 2,010. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/Southam/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southam</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Southam</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637488</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=57133</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10005553</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>SOUTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10108731</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>SOUTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10138528</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>SOUTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10207010</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>SOUTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10320288</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SOUTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10320318</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548202</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOUTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580201</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOUTHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9147</id>
   <name>LONG ITCHINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9161</id>
   <name>LADBROKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9176</id>
   <name>LEAMINGTON HASTINGS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9202</id>
   <name>MARTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9227</id>
   <name>NAPTON ON THE HILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9287</id>
   <name>PRIORS HARDWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9331</id>
   <name>RADBOURN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9350</id>
   <name>LOWER SHUCKBURGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9362</id>
   <name>STOCKTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9385</id>
   <name>UFTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
