<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8554</id>
<name>BALSALL</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3767016221403</lat>
<lon>-1.67393780598514</lon>
<gazetteerText>BALSALL, Balshall, or Temple-Balsall, a chapelry in the parish of Hampton-in-Arden, Warwick; 3 miles E of Knowle r. station, and 9 W by S of Coventry. Post Town, Knowle under Birmingham. Real property, &#163;8,864. Pop., 1,140. Houses, 291. The manor was given, in the reign of Stephen, to the Knights Templars; belonged afterwards to the Knights Hospital lers; passed, in the time of Edward VI., to the Earls of Warwick and Leicester, and afterwards to Lady Katherine Leveson; and was bequeathed by that lady for the erection and endowment of an hospital for poor women and boys. A hall Was built by the Tem plars as a commandery or preceptory; and remains of it still exist. The hospital of Lady Leveson was enlarged under an act of Queen Anne; is now an extensive and substantial suite of buildings, in the form of a square, on the border of a large green; and has an income of &#163;1,421. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;50.* Patron, the Governor of Balsall Hospital. The church was built by the Templars, about the middle of the 12th century; is 104 feet long, 39 feet wide, and 57 feet high; and has lofty, pointed, finely-traceried windows, timber roof, and stone stalls. Other charities than the hospital &#163;26. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/Balsall/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636123</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6941086</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42661</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10294423</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>BALSALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10294435</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TEMPLE BALSALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10294484</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BALSALL COMMON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8568</id>
   <name>BEAUDESERT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8573</id>
   <name>BERKSWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9107</id>
   <name>HAMPTON IN ARDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9159</id>
   <name>KNOWLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9166</id>
   <name>LAPWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9206</id>
   <name>MERIDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9255</id>
   <name>PACKWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9274</id>
   <name>PRESTON BAGOT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9337</id>
   <name>ROWINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9477</id>
   <name>WROXALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
