<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9221</id>
<name>MONKS KIRBY</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4447915038303</lat>
<lon>-1.29952908351412</lon>
<gazetteerText>MONKS-KIRBY, a township in Lutterworth district, and a parish partly also in Rugby district, all in Warwickshire. The township lies adjacent to the Fosse way, 2 miles NE by E of Stretton r. station, 2&#190; SW of Watling-street at the boundary with Leicestershire, and 6 NNW of Rugby; and has a post office under Lutterworth. Pop., 596. Houses, 13-4. The parish contains also the hamlets of Pailton, Stretton-under-Foss, Newbold-Revel, and Copston-Magna in Lutterworth district, and the township of Easenhall in Rugby district. Acres, 9,640. Real property, &#163;14,388. Pop. in 1851,1,899; in 1861,1,931. Houses, 429. The manor was known at Domesday, as Chirchberye; was given, by William the Conqueror, to Geoffrey de Wirce; was given by him to the monks of Angiers in Normandy, who then founded here a cell of their abbey; took thence the name of Monks-Kirby; was given by Richard II. to Thomas Mowbray, in exchange for Epworth priory; passed, in the time of Henry VIII., to the Duke of Suffolk; went, by sale, to Lord Fielding; and has descended to the Earl of Denbigh. Newnham-Paddox, a handsome mansion, is the Earl of Denbigh&apos;s seat; and contains a choice collection of family portraits and works of art. Townthorn is the seat of W. Jackson, Esq., brother of the late American general, Stonewall Jackson; and stands on an eminence, with an extensive view. Street-Aston House and Newbold-Revel also are chief residences. A place called Cloudesley-Bush, on the W side of the Fosse way, taken its name from having a mound reputed to have been the burial-place of a Roman soldier called Clandins; and numerous Roman relics, including bricks and substructions, have been found. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Withybrook and the p. curacy of Copston-Magna, in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;3x00. * Patron, Trinity College, Cambridge. The church was built, on the site of an older one, by Geoffrey de Wirce; was rebuilt by the Duke of Suffolk, of the time of Henry VIII.; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with pinnacled tower; contains several ancient monuments of the Fielding; and, in 1867, was likely to be restored. Another church is in Copston-Magna; and is a modern edifie, in the Norman style. There are also, within the parish, a school-church, an Independent chapel, two Baptist chapels, a national school, a grammar school, another school with &#163;30 a year from endowment, and charities &#163;32. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/MonksKirby/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monks_Kirby</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7293964</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=57122</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10042513</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>MONKS KIRBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10317125</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MONKS KIRBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10317150</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MONKS KIRBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10577184</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MONKS KIRBY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9257</id>
   <name>PAILTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9441</id>
   <name>WILLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9454</id>
   <name>WITHYBROOK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
