<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9115</id>
<name>HARTSHILL</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5481475175647</lat>
<lon>-1.51083047185639</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARTSHILL, a village and a chapelry in Mancetter parish, Warwick. The village stands on the river Anker, on the end of a hilly plain, near Watling street, the Coventry canal, the Trent Valley railway, and the boundary with Leicester, 3 miles NNW of Nuneaton r. station; is supposed to occupy the Campus Martins of the Roman Manduessedum; and commands a view in which are seen 45 parish churches. The chapelry includes also the hamlet of Chapel End; which has a postoffice under Atherstone. Real property, &#163;5, 349; of which &#163;398 are in quarries. Pop., 1, 129. Houses, 269. Ruins exist of a Norman castle, built in 1125 by Hugh de Hardreshull. A large wood extends from the W side of the village to nearly the camp at Oldbury. Excellent road metal is quarried; greenstone and iron ore abound; and manganese and copper ore are found. Ribbon making is carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;135.* Patron, the Vicar of Mancetter. The church is a modern edifice, in the Norman style. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, an endowed school with &#163;37 a year, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartshill</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647391</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42668</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10314460</id>
   <status>CP/Hmlt</status>
   <name>HARTSHILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10314471</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARTSHILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
