<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1304</id>
<name>SOLIHULL</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4020132962176</lat>
<lon>-1.78233418389846</lon>
<gazetteerText>SOLIHULL, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, a district, and a division, in Warwick. The town stands near the Birmingham and Warwick railway, and near the B. and W. canal, 7 miles SE of Birmingham; is a seat of petty-sessions, and a polling place; and has a post-office&#8225; under Birmingham, a r. station with telegraph, a town hall, a police station, a cruciform later English church, Independent and Roman Catholic chapels, an endowed grammar-school with &#163;125 a year, another endowed school, a workhouse, and two annual fairs.&#151;The parish includes Shirley chapelry, and comprises 11,296 acres. Real property, &#163;25,230. Pop., 3,329. Houses, 710. Malvern Hall is the seat of F. E. Williams, Esq. A Benedictine nunnery was founded, in the time of Henry II., at Henwood. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;1,455. Patron, the Rev. A. Clive. The p. curacy of Shirley is a separate benefice.&#151;The sub-district contains three parishes, and comprises 19,778 acres. Pop., 7,383. Houses, 1,519.&#151;The district includes also Knowle and Tanworth sub-districts, and comprises 46,015 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;5,192. Pop. in 1851, 11,973; in 1861, 13,231. Houses, 2,859. Marriages in 1863, 71; births, 393,-of which 24 were illegitimate; deaths, 238,-of which 68 were at ages under 5 years, and 8 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 835; births, 3,537; deaths, 2,294. The places of worship, in 1851, were 18 of the Church of England, with 6,086 sittings; 3 of Independents, with 466 s.; 1 of Baptists, with 110 s.; 1 of Wesleyans, with 118 s.; and 2 of Roman Catholics, with 164 s. The schools were 17 public day-schools, with 1,031 scholars; 22 private day-schools, with 387 s.; and 17 Sunday schools, with 1,187 s.-The division contains ten parishes, and is part of Hemlingford hundred. Acres, 35,592. Pop. in 1851, 9,098. Houses, 1,972. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/Solihull/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solihull</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Solihull</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637546</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42685</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10030857</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10039678</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10055866</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10111079</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10144103</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10199918</id>
   <status>UD/CB/MB</status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10320240</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10320252</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10320276</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SOLIHULL URBAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548305</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10579910</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12735480</id>
   <status>CCon/BCon</status>
   <name>SOLIHULL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8574</id>
   <name>BICKENHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8975</id>
   <name>ELMDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9381</id>
   <name>TANWORTH IN ARDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9992</id>
   <name>OLDBERROW</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
