<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11886</id>
<name>MARKET LAVINGTON</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.2735052330255</lat>
<lon>-1.95716404799282</lon>
<gazetteerText>LAVINGTON (EAST), a small town and a parish in Devizes district, Wilts. The town stands in a fertile valley, near the Ridge way, and on the N border of Salisbury plain, 5&#189; miles S of Devizes r. station; is irregularly built; consists chiefly of two streets; is commonly called Market-Lavington; and has a post office&#8225; of that name under Devizes. A workmen&apos;s hall was erected in 1864. A weekly market was formerly held, but has been discontinued; and malting is carried on. The parish contains also the tything of Easterton. Acres, 4, 721. Real property, &#163;7, 574. Pop. in 1851. 1, 721; in 1861, 1, 583. Houses, 381. The decrease of pop. was caused by the removal of machinery works and of a foundry. The manor belonged once to the Plantagenets; and passed to the Beauchamps, the Montagues, and the Bouveries. A mansion, on a picturesque site, about &#189; a mile W of the town, was built in 1866 by the Right Hon. E. P. Bouverie. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;300. * Patron, Christ Church, Oxford. The church stands on an eminence W of the town; is later English, with a steeple; and was restored in 1862. There are chapels for Independents and Baptists, two national schools, and charities &#163;20. Bishop Tanner, author of &quot;Notitia Monastica, &quot; was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/MarketLavington/index.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643025</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10406705</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MARKET LAVINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10406717</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARKET LAVINGTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11727</id>
   <name>EASTERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
