<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11842</id>
<name>IDMISTON</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.1308480079603</lat>
<lon>-1.72160686139689</lon>
<gazetteerText>IDMISTON, a tything and a parish in Amesbury district, Wilts. The tything lies on the Bourne branch or the river Avon, and on the London, Yeovil, and Exeter railway, near Porton r. station, 4 miles SE of Amesbury, and 5&#190; NE by N of Salisbury. Pop., 212. Houses, 46. -The parish contains also the chapelry of Porton, the tythings of Gomeldon and Shripple, and part of the tything of Ford. Post town, Salisbury. Acres, 5, 520. Real property, with Boscombe and Winterbourne-Gunner, &#163;7, 630. Rated property of I. alone, &#163;4, 266. Pop., 542. Houses, 116. The property of Idmiston tything is all in one estate, but that of Porton chapelry is divided. The manor belongs to the Earl of Normanton. A strip along the river is rich water meadow. There are several tumuli and barrows. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Porton, in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;278. Patron, the Bishop of Salisbury. The parish church is ancient; has a wooden tower; was undergoing restoration in 1866; and contains several monuments, one of which is to the Rev. John Bowle, who edited Don Quixote in 6 vols., and was buried in the church in 1788. The church of Porton is tolerable. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/Idmiston/index.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646291</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10405683</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>IDMISTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10405695</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>IDMISTON WITH PORTON AND GOMELDON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11487</id>
   <name>ALLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11594</id>
   <name>BOSCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12031</id>
   <name>NEWTON TONEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12159</id>
   <name>WINTERBOURNE DAUNTSEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12162</id>
   <name>WINTERBOURNE GUNNER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
