<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11634</id>
<name>MAIDEN BRADLEY</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.1463501208252</lat>
<lon>-2.282995960459</lon>
<gazetteerText>MAIDEN-BRADLEY, a village and a parish in the district of Mere; the village and most of the parish in Wilts, the rest of the parish in Somerset. The village stands 4&#188; miles N of Mere, and 5 ESE of Witham r. station; occupies high ground, overlooked by higher but isolated hills; and has a post office under Bath, and a picturesque inn. The parish includes, as its Somerset portion, the hamlet of Yarnfield; and comprises altogether 4,546 acres. Real property of the Wilts portion, 5,118. Pop., 592. Houses, 119. Real property of Yarnfield, returned with Kilmington and Norton-Ferris. Pop., 61. Houses, 13. The property belongs to the Duke of Somerset; and Maiden-Bradley House is the Duke&apos;s seat. An hospital for leprous women was founded here, in the time of Stephen, or in that of Henry II., by Mauasser Bisset; was changed, in 1190, into an Angustinian priory; was given, at the dissolution, to the Seymours; and is now represented by some remains, incorporated with a farm-house. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury-Value, &#163;121.* Patron, Christ Church, Oxford. The church contains monuments of the Seymours, and is good. Charities, &#163;13. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/MaidenBradley/index.htm</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/MaidenBradley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643188</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10400077</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MAIDEN BRADLEY WITH YARNFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10590255</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MAIDEN BRADLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
