<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11799</id>
<name>HEYTESBURY</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.1900949003101</lat>
<lon>-2.09612739630324</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEYTESBURY, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Wilts. The town stands on the river Wiley, and on the Somerset and Weymouth railway, near Salisbury plain, 4 miles SE by E of Warminster; was known, to the Saxons, as Hegtredesbiryg; took afterwards the names of Haresbury, Haseberie, and Heightsbury; is now commonly called Hatchbury; was, in the time of Stephen, the residence of the Empress Mand; was, in 1766, nearly all destroyed by fire, and afterwards rebuilt; consists now chiefly of a single street; possesses interest to tourists as the central point of a region abounding in British, Roman, Saxon, and Danish remains; and gives the title of Baron to the family of A&apos;Court. It sent two members to parliament from the time of Henry VI. till disfranchised by the act of 1832; was a borough by prescription; and is now a seat of courts leet. It has a post office&#8225; under Bath, a railway station, two chief inns, a church, an Independent chapel, a national school, and an endowed hospital. The church dates from the 13th century; was partly rebuilt in 1470; underwent a thorough restoration in 1866, at an expense of about &#163;5, 500; is cruciform; has a massive tower; and contains the burial place of the A&apos;Courts, and a tablet to Cunningham, the antiquary. The hospital was founded in 1470, by Lady Hungerford, for a chaplain, twelve poor men, and one poor woman; was rebuilt in 1769; forms three sides of a square, two stories high; and has an endowed income of &#163;1, 373. A weekly market was formerly held; and two fairs are still held on 14 May and 25 Sept.&#151;The parish comprises 3, 380 acres. Real property, &#163;4, 713. Pop., in 1841, 1, 311; in 1861, 1, 103. Houses, 237. The manor belonged to the Burghershs; and passed to the Badlesmeres, the Hungerfords, the Hastingses, and others. Heytesbury House, the seat of Lord Heytesbury, is on the N side of the town; was partially rebuilt about 1784; contains a fine collection of pictures: and stands in a well wooded park. Cotley Hill rises from the woods of the park; commands a very fine panoramic view; is crowned by a tumulus; and was anciently fortified. Knook castle, Scratchbury camp, Golden barrow, and many other autiquities are in the neighbourhood. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Knook, in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;350. Patron, the Bishop of Salisbury.&#151;The sub-district contains also eleven other parishes, and is in Warminster district. Acres, 27, 546. Pop., 4, 372. Houses, 946.-The hundred contains thirteen parishes, and part of another. Acres, 33, 040. Pop., 5, 572. Houses, 1, 209. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heytesbury</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/Heytesbury/index.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646998</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10134353</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>HEYTESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10140547</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>HEYTESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10404733</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HEYTESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10404812</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEYTESBURY WITH TYTHERINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10404885</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEYTESBURY WITH TYTHERINGTON AND KNOOK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544282</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEYTESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574961</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEYTESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758650</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>HEYTESBURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
