<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9900</id>
<name>HARTLEBURY</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3347573430073</lat>
<lon>-2.23940640897403</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARTLEBURY, a village and a parish in Droitwich district, Worcester. The village stands 1 mile W by N of the junction of the West Midland and Severn Valley railways, 1&#189; E of the river Severn, and 3&#190; S by E of Kidderminster; and has a station at the railway junction, and a post office letter box under Kidderminster. The parish contains also the hamlets of Upper Mitton, Crossway-Green, Norchard, Waresley, Chadwick, Titton, Lincomb, Charlton, Wilden, Torton, and Low Hill. Acres, 5, 493. Real property, &#163;14, 583. Pop. in 1851, 2, 047; in 1861, 2, 115. Houses, 452. The property is subdivided. The manor was given to the Bishops of Worcester by King Buhred. Hartlebury Castle, the seat of the bishops, was built, in the time of Henry III., by Bishop Cantelupe; was seized and destroyed, in 1646, by the parliamentarian force; was rebuilt, of brick, by Bishop Hough; and stands in a park to the W of the village. Ironworks are in Wilden hamlet, near the Worcester and Stafford canal. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;1, 765. Patron, the Bishop of Worcester. The church was rebuilt in 1836; and is a handsome edifice in the Gothic style, with a tower. There are a recent Independent chapel, a free grammar school, founded in 1400, with endowed income of &#163;467, and other charities with &#163;67. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/Hartlebury/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartlebury</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647401</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43140</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10334469</id>
   <status>AP/CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HARTLEBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10334482</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARTLEBURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
