<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>500</id>
<name>REDDITCH</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2831220642582</lat>
<lon>-1.94976081963877</lon>
<gazetteerText>REDDITCH, a town and a township-chapelry in Tardebigg parish, Worcester. The town stands at the boundary with Warwickshire, and at the terminus of abranch railway, 1 mile W of the river Arrow, and 6 E S E of Bromsgrove; has, of late years, undergone great extension; carries on a vast manufacture of needles, fish-hooks, and similar articles; is a seat of petty-sessions and county courts; and has a head post-office, &#8225; a railway station, two banking offices, two chief inns, a police station, a church, five dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholicchapel, a literary and scientific institute, a mixed national school, Wesleyan schools, a fair on the first Monday of Aug., another fair on the third Monday of Sept., and races on Whit-Monday and Whit-Tuesday. The railway goes 4&#190; miles northwestward, into junction with the Midland system at Barnt-Green; was authorized in 1858, on a capital of &#163;35,000 in shares, and &#163;11, 500 in loans; was opened in Sept. 1859; and was leased, in 1865, to the Midland. The church was built in 1855, at a cost of &#163;7, 463; is in the decorated Gothic style; and consists of nave, aisles, and raised chancel, with tower and spire. Bordesley abbey occupied a site in the neighbourhood; and a chapel of it was the only place of worship for Redditch till 1807. The chapelry comprises 1,835 acres. Real property, &#163;17, 265; of which &#163;601 are in the railway, and &#163;100 in gas-works. Pop. In 1851, 4, 802; in 1861, 5, 441. Houses, 1, 110. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, Baroness Windsor. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redditch</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/Redditch/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639557</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075210</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10088630</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10102765</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10343148</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>NORTH REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10343150</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10343215</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10343227</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10343239</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>REDDITCH ST GEORGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12736897</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835139</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12839856</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>REDDITCH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8515</id>
   <name>ALCESTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8519</id>
   <name>GREAT ALNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8530</id>
   <name>ARROW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9117</id>
   <name>HASELOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9250</id>
   <name>OVERSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9343</id>
   <name>SAMBOURNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9877</id>
   <name>FECKENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9920</id>
   <name>INKBERROW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10097</id>
   <name>STOKE PRIOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10129</id>
   <name>WEBHEATH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
