<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6028</id>
<name>LLANFAIR PWLLGWYNGLL</name>
<container>ANGLESEY</container>
<lat>53.2240212779585</lat>
<lon>-4.19448797837189</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANFAIR-PWLLGWYNGYLL, a village and a parish in the district of Bangor and county of Anglesey. The village stands near the Chester and Holyhead railway, and near the Menai strait, 5 miles SW of Beaumaris; takes the latter part of its name, signifying &quot;raging-pool,&quot; from the Swelly rocks whirlpool in the strait; and has a station, of the name of Llanfair, on the railway, and a post office, of the name of Llanfair-Pwllgwyngyll, under Bangor.&#151;The parish contains also the small seaport of Pwllfanog. Acres, 952; of which 100 are water. Real property, &#163;1,403. Pop. in 1851,758; in 1861,695. Houses, 170. The property is divided among a few. Pl&#226;s-Llanfair is the seat of Lord Clarence Paget. Pl&#226;sNewydd demesne, the seat of the Marquis of Anglesey, noticed in our article LLANEDWEN, also is adjacent. Craigy-Ddinas, a rocky eminence, 260 feet high, commands a very rich panoramic view; was formerly crowned with an ancient camp; and is now surmounted by a column 100 feet high, commemorative of the military career of the late Marquis of Anglesey, and bearing aloft a colossal bronze statue by Noble, set up in the autumn of 1860. Building-stone is quarried and shipped. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Llandysilio, in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;250. Patron, the Bishop of Bangor. The church is chiefly modern; retains a portion of an old church, with a remarkable apse; and has a fine broach spire. The churchyard contains an obelisk to the memory of the workmen who died during the construction of the Menai bridge. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/AGY/LlanfairPwllgwyngyll/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644080</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10215390</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANFAIR PWLLGWYNGLL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
