<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2042</id>
<name>LLANDYFRYDOG</name>
<container>ANGLESEY</container>
<lat>53.3435774589477</lat>
<lon>-4.33738109354075</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANDYFRYDOG, a parish and a sub-district in the district and county of Anglesey. The parish lies on the river Dulas, 1&#188; mile NE of Llanerchymedd r. station. Post town, Llanerchymedd, under Bangor. Acres, 3,819. Real property, &#163;3,687. Pop., 706. Houses, 156. The property is much subdivided. Many of the inhabitants are employed in the Parys copper mines. Two wells, formerly reputed holy, are near Lleidr-Dyvrydog stone. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Llanfihangel-Tre&apos;r-Beirdd, in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;457. * Patron, the Bishop of Bangor. The church is dedicated to St. Tyvrydog; occupies the site of one founded in the 5th century; is an ancient structure; and was recently in disrepair. There are a Calvinistic Methodist chapel, and charities &#163;8.&#151;The sub-district contains also eleven other parishes. Acres, 23,38 4. Pop., 4,580. Houses, 1,060. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644114</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/AGY/Llandyfrydog/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10039630</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANDYFRYDOG</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4969</id>
<name>LLANFECHALL</name>
<container>ANGLESEY</container>
<lat>53.3918001045322</lat>
<lon>-4.47077430836131</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANFECHELL, a village and a parish in the district and county of Anglesey. The village stands near the coast, 5 miles WSW of Amlwch, and 5&#189; NW by N of Llanerchymedd r. station; was once a market-town; and now has a post office under Bangor, and fairs on Holy Thursday. 5 and 25 Nov., and 26 Dec.&#151;The parish contains also the village of Tregele, and comprises 3,637 acres. Real property, &#163;1,730. Pop. in 1851, 1,085; in 1861,958. Houses, 245. Verd-antique is quarried, and soapstone is found. Some of the inhabitants are employed also in the Parys copper mines. There are a broken cromlech and several meini-hirion. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bangor. Valne, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Bangor. The church is dedicated to St. Mechell; and is later English, in good condition. Charities, &#163;11, and poors&apos; cottages. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/AGY/Llanfechell/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644074</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10172147</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANFECHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541906</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANFECHELL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2194</id>
   <name>CARREG LEFN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2486</id>
   <name>LLANFAIR YNG NGHORNWY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3051</id>
   <name>LLANBADRIG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4454</id>
   <name>LLANDDEUSANT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4947</id>
   <name>LLANBABO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5760</id>
   <name>LLANFAETHLU</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6606</id>
   <name>LLANRHUDDLAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8691</id>
   <name>RHOSBEIRIO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12387</id>
   <name>LLANRHWYDRYS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12394</id>
   <name>LLANFWROG</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
