<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4461</id>
<name>LLANEILIAN</name>
<container>ANGLESEY</container>
<lat>53.3959861524306</lat>
<lon>-4.30631730250964</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANELIAN, a village and a parish in the district and county of Anglesey. The village stands on the coast, &#190; of a mile SW of Point-&#198;lianus, commonly called Point Lynas, and 2 E of Amlwch r. station. The parish comprises 2,398 acres; and its Post town is Amlwch, Anglesey. Real property, &#163;2,033. Pop. in 1851,1,295; in 1861,1,282. Houses, 318. The property is much subdivided. Many of the inhabitants are employed in the Parys copper mine. A lighthouse stands on Point Lynas; and a signal station which, prior to the time of electo-telegraphing, had one of the semaphores in the line of communication between Holyhead and Liverpool, stands on a considerable ascent about &#188; a mile from the lighthouse. A palace of Caswallon Lawh&#238;r, who flouris.hed about 443, stood on the same eminence as the signal station. A spring, called Ffynnon-Eilian, was formerly a resort of pilgrims, and held in much superstitions veneration. The living is a rectory, united with the chapelries of Coedanna and Rhosbeirio, in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;400. Patron, the Bishop of Bangor. The church is dedicated to St. Eilian or Hilary; occupies the site of one erected in the 5th century; is early English, in good condition, with a steeple; and con tains a screen and stalls. An old chapel adjoins the church; measures 15 feet by 12; contains a wooden altar of the 15th century; and is, or lately was, the scene of an annual wake on the first Friday of Aug. There are a Calvinistic Methodist chapel, and charities &#163;20. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/AGY/Llaneilian/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7294076</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10150917</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANEILIAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10419645</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>UNDIVIDED LANDS COMMON TO LLANEILIAN AND LLANWENLLWYFO PARISHES</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
