<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4946</id>
<name>LLANALLGO</name>
<container>ANGLESEY</container>
<lat>53.3453242188337</lat>
<lon>-4.24440486838093</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANALLGO, a parish or parochial chapelry in the district and county of Anglesey; on the coast, at Moelfre bay, 6 miles E by N of Llanerchymedd r. station. Post town, Llanerchymedd, under Bangor. Acres, 659. Real property, &#163;752. Pop., 430. Houses, 98. The property is snbdivided. Marble of good quality is obtained. A cromlech of large size, resting on seven supports, is near Moelfre. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the rectory of Llanengrad, in the diocese of Bangor. The church claims to have been erected in the 7th century; is cruciform; was recently restored; and is notable for a monument to the numerous persons who perished in the shipwreck of the Royal Charter steam-clipper, on the rocks of Moelfre in 1859. The monument is of marble, cut from the rock on which the Royal Charter struck; has the form of a quadrangular obelisk; and bears, on its four sides, the inscriptions,-&apos; &apos; The Roya. Charter, 2,719 tons register, sailed from MelbourneAustralia, August 26,1859, bound for Liverpool, with 324 passengers and a crew of 103 &apos;&apos;- &apos; &apos; This monument was erected by the public, in memory of those who perished in the shipwreck of the Royal Charter, near Moelfre, on the island of Anglesey, October 26,1859 &apos;&apos;- &apos; &apos; Here lie the remains of 140 of the sufferers, and 45 in the churchyard of Penrhos-Lligwy &apos;,-&quot; The remains of several of the sufferers lie near the following churches, &apos;&apos;-here follows a list of nine churches on the N coast od Anglesey. In the spring of 1866,140 sovereigns were obtained by divers from the wreck of the Royal Charter; and they were as bright as if they had been newly coined. A well, once held in superstitions veneration, is near the church. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/AGY/Llanallgo/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644193</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10171623</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Ch</status>
   <name>LLANALLGO</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
