<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5000</id>
<name>ABERFFRO</name>
<container>ANGLESEY</container>
<lat>53.2131394899387</lat>
<lon>-4.44549040630306</lon>
<gazetteerText>ABERFFRAW, a seaport village, and a parish in the district and county of Anglesey. The village stands at the mouth of the Ffraw rivulet, on a creek of Carnarvon bay, 2&#190; miles WSW of Bodorgan r. station, and 12 SE of Holyhead. It has a post office under Bangor, and an inn. It was formerly a market town; and it still has fairs on 7 March, the Tuesday before Easter, the Wednesday after Trinity, 15 Aug., and 11 Dec. It is now a poor place, inhabited chiefly by fishermen and farm laborurers; but it anciently, for four centuries, till the death of Llewelyn-ap-Griffith, was a capital of the princes of Wales. No remains of the palace exist; but a garden, at the S end of the village, still bears the name of Gardd-y-Llys or &quot;palace-garden.&quot; The eisteddfodds, or assemblies of the bards, were anciently held here; and a spirited commemorative one was held in 1849. The parish comprises 6,114 acres of land, and 138 of water; and it contains eight tythings. Real property, &#163;5,044. Pop., 1,238. Houses, 274. The property is not much divided. A lake, called Llyn Coron, about 2 miles in circumference, lies a little east of the village, and is much frequented by anglers. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;888.* Patron, the Prince of Wales. The old church contains a very interesting doorway of the 12th century, and is in good condition. There are four dissenting chapels, and charities &#163;24. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/AGY/Aberffraw/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aberffraw</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657819</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10175495</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ABERFFRO</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
