<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1104</id>
<name>LLANGEFNI</name>
<container>ANGLESEY</container>
<lat>53.2601758180967</lat>
<lon>-4.30356742875086</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANGEFNI, a small town, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district and county of Anglesey. The town stands on the river Cefni, on the Roman road to Holyhead, and on the Anglesey Central railway, in a pleasant vale, 4&#189; miles NN W of Gaerwen-Junction, and 9 W by S of Beaumaris; was only a small hamlet in the latter part of last century; has risen to provincial importance, in consequence of the advantageousness of its situation as a marketing centre; was raised, by the reform act, to the rank of a borough, uniting with Beaumaris, Holyhead, and Amlwch in sending a member to parliament; is a seat of petty sessions and a polling place; and has a head post office, &#8225; designated Llangefni, Anglesey, a railway station, a banking office, a hotel, a two-arched bridge over the Cefni, a market-house, a church, four dissenting chapels, and a public school. The church is dedicated to St. Cyngar; was rebuilt in 1824; and includes an ancient inscribed stone. A weekly market is held on Thursday; fairs are held on 14 March, 17 Apri1, 10 June, 17 Aug., 15 Sept., 23 Oct., and the six market days before Christmas; and soMe industry, in woollen-manufacture, leather-dressing, and malting is carried on. Pop. in 1851,1,362; in 1861,1,317. Houses, 321.&#151;The parish comprises 2,426 acres. Real property, &#163;4,838. Pop. in 1851,1,799; in 1861,1,696. Houses,.416. The property is not much divided. Tregarnedd, about a mile from the town, succeeded a mansion of the 13th century, was itself built in the time of Henry VII., and is now a farm-house. Ednyfed Fychan, the minis ter of Llewelyn, and the ancestor of the Tudors, resided at Tregarnedd; and his grandson, Sir Gruffydd Llwyd, who eventually suffered death by command of Edward I. at Rhuddlan Castle, was born at Tregarnedd, and sustained a siege in the fortified mansion. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Tregayan, in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;446. * Patron, the Bishop of Bangor.&#151;The sub-district contains also nine other parishes. Acres, 23,259. Pop., 5,431. Houses, 1,263. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/AGY/Llangefni/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llangefni</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644037</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10226004</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANGEFNI</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10226016</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>LLANGEFNI</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541890</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANGEFNI</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12827659</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>LLANGEFNI</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2085</id>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL YSGEIFIOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3192</id>
   <name>CERRIGCEINWEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4350</id>
   <name>HENEGLWYS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6438</id>
   <name>LLANGWYLLOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8996</id>
   <name>TREGAEAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12329</id>
   <name>LLANFFINAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17323</id>
   <name>ANGLESEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
