<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>507</id>
<name>HOLYHEAD</name>
<container>ANGLESEY</container>
<lat>53.3102086012087</lat>
<lon>-4.63232527556256</lon>
<gazetteerText>Holyhead, seaport town and par., on north side of Holyhead Island, Anglesey, 24 miles NW. of Bangor, 60 miles from Dublin, and 261 miles from London - par., 7988 ac. (540 water), pop. 9689; seaport, 330 ac., pop. 8680; P.O., T.O., 2 Banks. Market-day, Saturday. The port possesses 2 fine harbours of refuge for ships of all sizes. Its prosperity is dne to the extensive railway and steamboat traffic, mainly supported by the Dublin mail packets and the London and North-Western Railway. The passage to Dublin takes about 4 hours. At the outer end of the breakwater is a fixed light (Holyhead) 66 ft. above high water and seen 13 miles. Holyhead united with Beaumaris, Amlwch, and Llangefni in returning 1 member till 1885. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/AGY/Holyhead/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holyhead</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Holyhead</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646686</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10038662</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD URBAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10092899</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10111821</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10149241</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10192316</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD RURAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541918</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12827453</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12827465</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12832539</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12845480</id>
   <status>AD_Town</status>
   <name>HOLYHEAD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2538</id>
   <name>BODEDERN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4470</id>
   <name>LLANFAIR YN NEUBWLL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5000</id>
   <name>ABERFFRO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5395</id>
   <name>LLANFACHRETH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5620</id>
   <name>LLANFAELOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6634</id>
   <name>LLANTRISANT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6668</id>
   <name>LLANYNGHENEDL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6689</id>
   <name>LLECHYLCHED</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8692</id>
   <name>RHOSCOLYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9099</id>
   <name>TREWALCHMAI</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>25617</id>
<name>HOLY ISLAND</name>
<container>ANGLESEY</container>
<lat>53.2817982146854</lat>
<lon>-4.61027673444574</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOLY ISLAND, or Holyhead Island, an island in the W of Anglesey; divided, by an isthmus, into the parishes of Holyhead and Rhoscolyn. It extends from NW to SE; measures about 8 miles in length, and about 3&#189; in maximum breadth; and is separated from the rest of Anglesey by a sandy strait, in some places fordable at low water. The turnpike road and the railway cross the strait on a long causeway or embankment, with an arched water way or bridge in the middle, through which a tremendous current rushes at the turn of the tide. A rocky eminence near Rhoscolyn church commands an excellent view of the island, &quot;rivalling, on a clear day, some of the finest portions of the coasts of Italy.&quot; See HOLYHEAD and RHOSCOLYN. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holy_Island,_Anglesey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646683</link>
</links>
</place>
</results>
