<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>16466</id>
<name>AYR</name>
<container>AYRSHIRE</container>
<lat>55.4634795065917</lat>
<lon>-4.63228744940283</lon>
<gazetteerText>Ayr.-- par., parl. and royal burgh, and co. town of Ayrshire, at mouth of river Ayr, 40&#189; miles SW. of Glasgow, 78&#189;, miles SW. of Edinburgh, and 384 miles from London by rail -- par., 6939 ac., pop. 10,182; parl. burgh, pop. 20,812; royal burgh, pop. 8776; 7 Banks, 4 newspapers. Market-days, Tuesday and Friday. The town is connected with Newton and Wallaceton on N. side of the river by the &quot;Auld Brig&quot; and &quot;New Brig,&quot; cerebrated by Burns. There are mfrs. of carpets, woollen goods, and leather; iron foundries; engineering works; and shipbuilding yards. It has extensive docks; coal and iron are the chief exports. The fisheries and the shipping are important. (For statistics, see Appendix.) There are still some fragments of the ramparts of the Fort of Ayr, which was built by Cromwell in 1652. At the S. end of the town is the racecourse, where the Western Meeting takes place annually in September. Ayr unites with Irvine, Campbeltown, Inveraray, and Oban in returning 1 member to Parl. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656708</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayr</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Ayr</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Kyle</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/sct/AYR/Ayr/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10036136</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AYR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10357913</id>
   <status>Burgh</status>
   <name>AYR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10361140</id>
   <status>Burgh</status>
   <name>CITADEL OF AYR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12735820</id>
   <status>DistBCon</status>
   <name>AYR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12744687</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>AYR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12781945</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AYR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12797655</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>AYR CARRICK AND CUMNOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833532</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AYR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12837173</id>
   <status>DoC</status>
   <name>AYR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16517</id>
   <name>MONKTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16605</id>
   <name>NEW CUMNOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16788</id>
   <name>OLD CUMNOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16814</id>
   <name>STRANRAER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16861</id>
   <name>GIRVAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16928</id>
   <name>CAMPBELTOWN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16961</id>
   <name>TARBOLTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16976</id>
   <name>INCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17005</id>
   <name>DALMELLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17057</id>
   <name>MAYBOLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>16611</id>
<name>KILMARNOCK</name>
<container>AYRSHIRE</container>
<lat>55.6110656700197</lat>
<lon>-4.49605507740636</lon>
<gazetteerText>Kilmarnock, parl. burgh, par., and manufactnring town, N. Ayrshire, on Kilmarnock Water, near its confluence with river Irvine, 7&#189; miles E. of Irvine, 23&#189; SW. of Glasgow, and 382 NW. of London by rail - par., 9444 ac., pop. 25,864; burgh, pop. 25,844; 7 Banks, 2 newspapers. Market-days, Tuesday and Friday. The town includes Riccarton suburb, in Riccarton par. Kilmarnock is an ancient place; it originated in an early church dedicated to St Marnock. In 1591 it was made a burgh of barony under the Boyds. Towards the end of the 16th century the weaving of hose and bonnets was introduced, and Kilmarnock has ever since been an important manufacturing town. It has mfrs. of carpets, bonnets, tweeds and winceys, shawls and calicoes, and boots and shoes; but the staple trade now is in connection with iron, Kilmarnock standing in one of the richest mineral fields of Scotland. There are numerous foundries and engineering shops, and at Bonnieton Square, to the W. of the town, are the locomotive works of the Glasgow and South-Western Ry. Kilmarnock is situated in a district famous for its dairy produce, and its annual cheese show is the largest in Scotland. Kilmarnock House, the residence of the Boyds, Earls of Kilmarnock, is now an industrial school. On the NE. side of the town is the Kay Park, near the centre of which is the Burns Monument (1879). The first edition of Burns&apos; poems was printed at Kilmarnock in 1786. Alexander Smith (1830-1867), the poet, was a native. The parl. limits were extended in 1885. The Kilmarnock District of Parliamentary Burghs (Kilmarnock, Dumbarton, Rutherglen, Renfrew, and Port-Glasgow) returns 1 member. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kilmarnock</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645605</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/sct/AYR/Kilmarnock/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10077643</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KILMARNOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10360304</id>
   <status>Burgh</status>
   <name>KILMARNOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12735868</id>
   <status>DistBCon</status>
   <name>KILMARNOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12742897</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>KILMARNOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12753147</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>AYRSHIRE AND BUTE KILMARNOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12755569</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>KILMARNOCK AND LOUDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12781957</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KILMARNOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835565</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KILMARNOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12837239</id>
   <status>DoC</status>
   <name>KILMARNOCK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16361</id>
   <name>BEITH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16522</id>
   <name>IRVINE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16539</id>
   <name>LOUDOUN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16651</id>
   <name>ARDROSSAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16665</id>
   <name>AUCHINLECK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16803</id>
   <name>RICCARTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16893</id>
   <name>DUNDONALD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16911</id>
   <name>AVONDALE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17043</id>
   <name>KILMAURS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17152</id>
   <name>DALRY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>21878</id>
<name>KYLE</name>
<container>AYRSHIRE</container>
<lat>55.5030842332746</lat>
<lon>-4.3656791185629</lon>
<gazetteerText>Kyle, middle dist. of Ayrshire, between river Irvine and river Doon. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645092</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10069130</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KYLE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
