<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5047</id>
<name>MENTMORE</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8780220890245</lat>
<lon>-0.682247891142548</lon>
<gazetteerText>MENTMORE, a village and a parish in the district of Leighton-Buzzard and county of Buckingham. The village stands near the Northwestern railway, 1&#189; mile NNE of the boundary with Herts, 1&#190; SW of the boundary with Beds, 1&#190; NNW of Cheddington Junction r. station, and 4 SSW of Leighton-Buzzard; and has a postoffice under Leighton-Buzzard. The parish contains also the hamlet of Ledburn, and comprises 1,240 acres. Real property, &#163;2,498. Pop., 399. Houses, 70. The property is divided among a few. Mentmore Towers and much of the land belong to Baron de Rothschild. The &apos;Towers stands to the W of the village, commanding an extensive view of the vale of Aylesbury; is a splendid mansion in the Italian style, of Ancaster stone, after designs by Sir Joseph Paxton and G. H. Stokes; and contains a fine collection of Majolica ware. Baron de Rothschild&apos;s stag hounds are kennelled here. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;200.* Patron, Baron de Rothschild. The church is decorated and later English, in good condition. A Baptist chapel is at Ledburn; and the parish shares in Pratt&apos;s charity. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mentmore</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642740</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Mentmore/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42587</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10046506</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MENTMORE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10177133</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MENTMORE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
