<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2140</id>
<name>CHALFONT ST PETER</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6154394764908</lat>
<lon>-0.554307040370565</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHALFONT-ST. PETER, a village and a parish in Amersham district, Bucks. The village stands on the Misbourn rivulet, 5 miles SSE of Amersham, and 6&#188; E by N of Woburn-Green r. station; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a post office under Slough. The parish comprises 4,717 acres. Real property, &#163;7,335. Pop., 1,344. Houses, 303. The property is divided among a few. Chalfont House was built by General Churchill, the brother-in-law of Horace Walpole; owed much of its original character to Walpole&apos;s taste; but has been much altered and improved; and is now the seat of J. Hibbert, Esq. A house called the Grange was for some time the residence of Judge Jeffreys. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;731.* Patron, St. John&apos;s College, Oxford. The church is a brick edifice of 1726, highly improved by Street in 1854; and contains three good brasses. The p. curacy of Gerrard&apos;s Cross is a separate benefice. There are a Baptist chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;25. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/ChalfontStPeter/Index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chalfont_St_Peter</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653393</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42545</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10045964</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CHALFONT ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10115747</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHALFONT ST PETER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
