<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2557</id>
<name>NEWTON LONGVILLE</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9766214115848</lat>
<lon>-0.770015861641028</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWTON-LONGVILLE, or Newaston-Longville, a village and a parish in Newport-Pagnell district, Bucks. The village stands 1 mile S of the Oxford and Bletchley railway, 2 S W of Bletchley r. station, and 10 E S E of Buckingham; and took the latter part of its name froma priory founded in the time of Henry I., as a cell to the Cluniac abbey of St. Faith, at Longueville in Normandy, and given, in 1415, to New College, Oxford. The parish comprises 1, 718 acres. Post-town, Bletchley Station. Real property, &#163;2, 264. Pop, . 547. Houses, 121. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to New College, Oxford. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;330.* Patron, New College, Oxford. The church is partly early English, partly perpendicular; consists of nave, aisles, chancel, and N chapel, with porches and W tower; has, on the outerwall, a statue of St. Faith; and contains piscin&#230;, credence shelves, and a recently-restored ancient font. There are chapels for Baptists and Primitive Methodists, and a national school. Grocyn, the tutor of Erasmus, was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newton_Longville</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641545</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/NewtonLongville/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62609</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10065525</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>NEWTON LONGVILLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10116910</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWTON LONGVILLE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
