<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3746</id>
<name>WENDOVER</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7491864258171</lat>
<lon>-0.728029807903583</lon>
<gazetteerText>WENDOVER, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Wycombe district, Bucks. The town stands at the terminus of a branch of the Grand Junction canal, under the Chiltern hills, 5 miles SE by S of Aylesbury r. station; sent two members to parliament in the times of Edward I. and Edward VII., and from the time of James II. till disfranchised by the reform act of 1832; is a seat of petty sessions; carries on straw-plait manufacture; and has a post-office&#8225; under Tring, a good inn, a police station, a canal-wharf for importation of coals, a literary institution, with reading room and library, an ancient church, chiefly early English, Independent and Baptist chapels, an endowed school with &#163;17 a year, charities &#163;232, a weekly market on Tuesday, and fairs on 13 May and 2 Oct. The parish comprises 5,719 acres. Real property, &#163;7,780. Pop., 1,932. Houses, 411. The manor was held by the Fiennes; passed to the Molins, the Hollands, the Knollys, the Hampdens, and the Verneys; and belongs now to Capt. P. Smith. W. House, W. Hall, W. Lodge, Bucksbridge House, and Cavendish Villa are chief residences. A reservoir of 55 acres is here, and supplies water-power to Weston-Turville and Aylesbury mills. Backham Hilland Coomb Hill command extensive and charming views. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;271.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor.&#151;The sub-district contains 8 parishes. Acres, 19,150. Pop., 5,042. Houses, 1,075. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wendover</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Wendover/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634538</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42522</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093211</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WENDOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10117940</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WENDOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10177650</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WENDOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10563252</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WENDOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582040</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WENDOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582052</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WENDOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582064</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WENDOVER FIRST DIVISION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582076</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WENDOVER SECOND DIVISION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12759447</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>WENDOVER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1503</id>
   <name>THE LEE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2888</id>
   <name>MONKS RISBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2981</id>
   <name>ELLESBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4559</id>
   <name>GREAT HAMPDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
