<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3358</id>
<name>CHALFONT ST GILES</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6362027902587</lat>
<lon>-0.568723961678448</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHALFONT-ST. GILES, a village and a parish in Amersham district, Bucks. The village stands on the Misbourn rivulet, 3 miles SE by S of Amersham, and 6 E by N of Loudwater r. station; and has a post office&#8225; under Slough. The poet Milton resided here during the plague of London in 1665, and finished here his &quot;Paradise Lost;&quot; and the house which he occupied, a half-timbered cottage, still exists, and has his name on its front. The parish comprises 3,641 acres. Real property, &#163;6,117. Pop., 1,217. Houses, 255. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to T. N. Allen, Esq. Vatche House, or the Vache, is a modernized ancient edifice; was long held by the Hare family; belonged previously to the Alstons; and is said to have been built originally on a dairy farm of King John. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;615.* Patron, the Bishop of Oxford. The church is ancient; has a Norman tower; was restored in 1863; and contains brasses and monuments of the Gardiners, the Fleetwoods, the Claytons, and Bishop Hare. There are chapels for Independents, Primitive Methodists, Free Methodists, and Quakers; and the remains of William Penn, the founder of Pennsylvania, and Thomas Ellwood, the friend of Milton, are in the Quakers&apos; burying ground. A school has &#163;58 from endowment; and other charities &#163;100. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chalfont_St_Giles</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/ChalfontStGiles/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653394</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42544</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10008840</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHALFONT ST GILES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10099687</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CHALFONT ST GILES</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
