<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2160</id>
<name>STOKE POGES</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5376936915294</lat>
<lon>-0.585508889645661</lon>
<gazetteerText>STOKE-POGES, a village and a parish in Eton district, Bucks. The village stands 1&#189; mile N of Slough r. station, and has a post-office under Slough. The parish contains also Ditton hamlet, and parts of Slough and Salthill. Acres, 2,500. Real property, &#163;8,275. Pop. in 1851, 1,501; in 1861, 1,600. Houses, 304. The property is much sub-divided. The manor belonged anciently to the Poges; and passed to the Molins, the Hastings, the lawyer Coke, Lord Purbeck, the Gayers, the Halseys, Lady Cobham, and the Penns. S.-Park is the seat of Lord Taunton; S.-Place, of Col. R. H. Vyse; S.-Farm, of Lady Maria Molyneux; and Fairfield Lodge, of J. U. Easson, Esq. Ditton Park belongs to the Duke of Buccleuch; Baylis House, to the Duke of Leeds; and the latter is now used as a Roman Catholic boarding-school. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;500.* Patron, the Duke of Leeds. The church ranges from Norman to later English, and has a tower and spire. The churchyard is the scene of Grey&apos;s &quot;Elegy,&apos;&apos; and contains his tomb. A chapel of ease is at Ditton. There are endowed national schools with &#163;30 a year, an alms-house-hospital with &#163;129, and other charities &#163;46. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoke_Poges</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/StokePoges/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636840</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42564</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10010044</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>STOKE IN SLOUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10010056</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STOKE POGES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10046660</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>STOKE POGES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10188283</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>STOKE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
