<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5430</id>
<name>LECKHAMPSTEAD</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0184886311949</lat>
<lon>-0.944911691770212</lon>
<gazetteerText>LECKHAMPSTEAD, a parish and a sub-district in the district and county of Buckingham. The parish lies on an affluent of the river Ouse, adjacent to the Buckingham canal and to the boundary with Northamptonshire, 3&#190; miles NE by N of Buckingham r. station. Post town, Buckingham. Acres, 2, 522. Real property, &#163;4, 288; of which &#163;14 are in the canal. Pop., 482. Houses, 106. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to H. W. Beauclerk, Esq. Much of the land is under wood. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;517.* Patron, H. W. Beauclerk, Esq. The church is ancient but good; consists of nave, N aisle, S porch, and chancel, with W tower; and contains three sedilia, a piscina, an effigies of a knight, and a brass of 1506. There is a national school. -The sub-district contains also twelve other parishes and two extra-parochial tracts. Acres, 21, 474. Pop., 4, 098. Houses, 908. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Leckhampstead/Index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leckhampstead,_Buckinghamshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644715</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62563</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093545</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LECKHAMPSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10194672</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LECKHAMPSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10561929</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LECKHAMPSTEAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
