<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1484</id>
<name>DENHAM</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5726932417351</lat>
<lon>-0.507151278975171</lon>
<gazetteerText>DENHAM, a parish in Eton district, Bucks: on the river Colne and the Grand Junction canal, at the boundary with Middlesex, 2 miles NNW of Uxbridge r. station. It has a post office under Uxbridge. Acres, 3, 905. Real property, &#163;9, 693. Pop., 1, 068. Houses, 222. The property is divided among a few. Denham place, a large brick mansion, on the site of an ancient manor-house of the Peckhams, has a fine old chapel, with ancient gilded seats; was built, in 1667, by Sir Roger Hill; was often visited by Captain Cook and Sir Humphrey Davy; and was the residence, in 1836, of Lucien and Joseph Buonaparte. Denham Court, a modernized old moated mansion, the seat of N. Lambert, Esq., belonged to Sir W. Bowyer, the friend of Dryden; gave concealment, under Lady Bowyer&apos;s care, to Charles II.; and was the place where Dryden wrote part of his translation of Virgil. A lime avenue of fully &#189; a mile leads to it. Denham is a meet for the Queen&apos;s stag hounds. The. living is a rectory in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;782.* Patron, B. H. W. Way, Esq. The church is of the 14th century; was recently restored; is a beautiful structure; and contains monuments of the Peckhams and Sir Roger Hill, and some fine brasses. There is a Wesleyan chapel. A school has &#163;75 from endowment; and other charities &#163;28. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Denham/Index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denham,_Buckinghamshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651378</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42556</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10009145</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>DENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10065161</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DENHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>26305</id>
<name>DENHAM</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8756444549314</lat>
<lon>-0.895878185746555</lon>
<gazetteerText>DEREHAM, a village in Quainton township and parish, Bucks; 6&#189; miles NW of Aylesbury. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
</results>
