<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6106</id>
<name>IVER</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5238002723502</lat>
<lon>-0.512590486781833</lon>
<gazetteerText>IVER, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Eton district, Bucks. The village stands on the river Colne, near the Grand Junction canal and the boundary with Middlesex, 1&#189; mile WNW of Drayton r. station, and 2&#190; SSW of Uxbridge; dates from ancient times; takes its name from Sir Roger de Ivery, who came in with William the Conqueror; is a scattered place; was once a market town; has still a fair on 10 and 11 July; is a seat of courts leet and baron; and has a post office under Uxbridge. The parish comprises 6, 149 acres. Real property, &#163;15, 336; of which &#163;18 are in fisheries. Pop. in 1851, 1, 985; in 1861, 2, 114. Houses, 429. The property is subdivided. Thorney Farm is said to have been a residence of Oliver Cromwell. Richings Park, now the seat ofMeeking, Esq., was the residence of Lord Bathurst, frequented by the most distinguished wits of his. time; passed from him to the Earl of Hertford; and was frequented, under the auspices of Lady Hertford, by all the poets of her time. A walk adjoining it is specially associated with the memory of Pope, and bears the name of Pope&apos;s Walk. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;11 5. * Patron,Meeking, Esq. The church was restored in 1848, at a cost of &#163;2, 800; and contains monuments to Sir George and Sir Edward Salter, carvers to Charles I. The p. curacy of Iver-Heath is a separate benefice. There are an endowed national school, and charities &#163;117.-The subdistrict contains also four other parishes, and part of another. Acres, 17, 380. Pop., 5, 787. Houses, 1, 204. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Iver/Index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iver</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645990</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42561</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10088902</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>IVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10217969</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>IVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10583731</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>IVER</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23785</id>
<name>IVER HEATH</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5405475347548</lat>
<lon>-0.517508130810904</lon>
<gazetteerText>IVER-HEATH, a chapelry in Iver parish, Bucks; 2&#190; miles WSW of Uxbridge town and r. station. It was constituted in 1862; and it has a post office under Uxbridge. Pop., about 600. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;100.*-Patron,Meeking, Esq. The church was built in 1862, at a cost of &#163;2, 400; and is in the decorated English style. There is an infant school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iver_Heath</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7290170</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10177042</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>IVER HEATH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
