<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>483</id>
<name>LINSLADE</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9173099453618</lat>
<lon>-0.679811006571992</lon>
<gazetteerText>LINCHLADE, or LINSLADE, a village and a parish in the district of Leighton-Buzzard and county of Buckingham. The village stands on the Northwestern railway, the Grand Junction canal, and the river Ouzel, at the boundary with Beds, contiguous to the new LeightonBuzzard r. station, in the NNW vicinity of LeightonBuzzard; is a modern place, of rapid growth, promising to become a town; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a post office under Leighton-Buzzard, several inns, and a fife and drum band.&#151;The parish contains also a small old village of Linchlade, which was once a market town,. and likewise the hamlet of Southcott. Acres, 1,830. Real property, &#163;6,465. Pop. in 1851,1,309; in 1 861, 1,511. Houses, 297. The property is not much divided. The manor belonged formerly to the Beauchamps, and belongs now to W. Pulsford, Esq. A tunnel of the Northwestern railway here is 290 yards long. There are ironstone and a pilgrim&apos;s well. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Oxford. Valne, &#163;120. * Patron, the Bishop of Oxford. The old church stands at the old village, has a tower, and is now used only for burials, and for occasional services in summer. The new church was built in 1849; and, together with a national school, cost about &#163;3,000. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linslade</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Linslade/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644440</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42585</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10084337</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>LINSLADE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10103526</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LINSLADE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
