<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2161</id>
<name>STONE</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7977180048626</lat>
<lon>-0.848947922929755</lon>
<gazetteerText>STONE, a parish, with a village and three hamlets, in Aylesbury district, Bucks; 2&#189; miles WSW of Aylesbury r. station. It has a post-office under Aylesbury. Acres, 2,590. Real property, &#163;5,742. Pop. in 1851, 785; in 1861, 1,094,-of whom 295 were in the Bucks lunatic asylum. Houses, 169. The manor belongs to Dr. J. Lee. Peveraland St. John&apos;s Lodge are chief residences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;390.* Patron, the Royal Astronomical Society. The church is early English, with Norman arches; and was recently restored. There are two Wesleyan chapels and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stone,_Buckinghamshire</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Stone/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636824</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62778</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10031503</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONE WITH BISHOPSTONE AND HARTWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10046683</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10118797</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONE WITH BISHOPSTONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10158709</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>STONE WITH BISHOPSTONE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1540</id>
   <name>UPPER WINCHENDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2148</id>
   <name>HARDWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3408</id>
   <name>WEEDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3671</id>
   <name>CUDDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4548</id>
   <name>ASHENDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4564</id>
   <name>GREAT KIMBLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4589</id>
   <name>WESTCOTT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4591</id>
   <name>LOWER WINCHENDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5768</id>
   <name>WADDESDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5808</id>
   <name>DINTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>2164</id>
<name>STONY STRATFORD</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0569889066328</lat>
<lon>-0.85360342863057</lon>
<gazetteerText>STRATFORD (Stony), a small town and a parish in the district of Potterspury and county of Buckingham. The town stands on Watling-street and the river Onse, 2 miles WSW of Wolverton r. station, and 7&#189; NE by E of Buckingham; is supposed, by some antiquaries, to occupy the site of the Roman Lactodorum; was Edward IV.&apos;s starting-place to Grafton, to marry Elizabeth Woodville; was also the place where Richard III. seized Edward V.; had an Eleanor cross, put up by Edward I., and demolished in 1646; suffered much desolation by an accidental fire in 1742; lost then its later English church of St. Mary Magdalene, all except the tower, which still stands; is a seat of petty-sessions; publishes a weekly newspaper; communicates, by a three-arched bridge, with Old Stratford, on the Northampton side of the Ouse; consists chiefly of one long old street, a market place, and a new street; and has a head post-office,&#8225; three banking offices, a good hotel, a police station, reading rooms, a public hall, a church rebuilt in 1776, but retaining a tower of 1487, three dissenting chapels, a public cemetery of 1856 with two handsome chapels, an endowed grammar-school, national and British schools, charities &#163;426, a weekly corn market on Friday, a monthly cattle market, and fairs on 2 Aug., the Friday after 10 Oct., and the first Friday of Nov.&#151;The parish comprises two ancient parishes, St. Mary Magdalene and St. Giles; and is divided into East Side, which was St. Mary Magdalene, and West Side, which was St. Giles. Acres, 70. Real property of East Side, &#163;2,148,-of which &#163;120 are in gasworks; of West Side, &#163;3,083. Pop. of the whole in 1851, 1,256; in 1861, 1,356. Houses, 263. The manor of East Side belongs to the Radcliffe trustees; and that of West Side, to W. S. Lowndes, Esq. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;185.* Patron, the Bishop of O. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stony_Stratford</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/StonyStratford/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636795</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62618</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10031552</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONY STRATFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10046853</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>STONY STRATFORD EAST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10047468</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>STONY STRATFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10093570</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>STONY STRATFORD WEST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10108354</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>STRATFORD AND WOLVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10117653</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONY STRATFORD ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10177522</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONY STRATFORD ST MARY AND ST GILES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10180326</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>STRATFORD AND WOLVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10462022</id>
   <status>Ch</status>
   <name>ST GILES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10462034</id>
   <status>Ch</status>
   <name>ST MARY MAGDALEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580687</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STONY STRATFORD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7938</id>
   <name>FURTHO</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
