<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1542</id>
<name>WOOBURN</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.589557120083</lat>
<lon>-0.686634832093037</lon>
<gazetteerText>WOOBURN, or Woburn, a village and a parish in Wycombe district, Bucks. The village stands adjacent to the Maidenhead and Oxford railway, 2&#190; miles SW of Beaconsfield; is large and scattered; consists of W.-Town, W.-Green, Cores-End, and Bourne-End; is near Marlow-Road r. station; and has a r. station of W.-Green, a post-office&#8225; of W.-Green under Beaconsfield, a post-office of W. under Beaconsfield, several inns, and fairs on 4 May and 12 Nov. The parish comprises 2,850 acres. Real property, &#163;8,853. Pop. in 1851, 2,026; in 1861, 2,245. Houses, 477. The property is much sub-divided. The manor belonged to Earl Harold; went to the Bishops of Lincoln, who had a palace here; passed to the Lovells, the Comptons, the Goodwins, the Whartons, and the Berties; and belongs now to J. Dupr&#233;, Esq. W. House was the deathplace of Bishop Smith, the founder of Brasenose college; was visited, in the time of the first Lord Wharton, by William III.; was rebuilt in 1750; and is now the seat of A. Gilbey, Esq. There are extensive paper and millboard mills. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, J Dupr&#233;, Esq. The church was restored in 1857. There are four dissenting chapels, a national school, infant schools, a mission-house, and charities &#163;35. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wooburn</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Wooburn/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633675</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42538</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10010809</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WOOBURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10201720</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WOOBURN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3683</id>
   <name>HEDSOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
