<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2883</id>
<name>BURNHAM</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5451490506194</lat>
<lon>-0.6442541281707</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURNHAM, a village, a parish, a subdistrict, and a hundred, in Bucks. The village stands adjacent to the Great Western railway, near the river Thames, 2&#189; miles E by N of Maidenhead; and has a post office&#8225; under Maidenhead. It was formerly a market town; and still has fairs on 25 Feb., 1 May, and 2 Oct. The parish includes also the liberties of Boveney, Boveney-Upper-Side, Britwell, East Burnham, Chippenham, and Wood. Acres, 6,730. Real property, &#163;13,908. Pop., 2,233. Houses, 463. The property is divided among a few. Burnham Grove is the seat of Sir W. Johnson, Bart. An Augustinian Abbey was founded about a mile from the village, in 1265, by Richard, king of the Romans; and given, at the dissolution, to William Tyldesley; and some small remains of it still exist. A fragment of an ancient forest bears the name of Burnham Beeches; consists of venerable beech trees, all pollarded; and has been sketched by many artists. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Boveney, in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;505.* Patron, Eton College. The church is early and decorated English. The p. curacy of Dropmore is a separate benefice. There are an Independent chapel, three schools, and charities &#163;132. Bishop Aldrich, who died in 1556, was a native; and the learned Jacob Bryant was a resident.-The subdistrict contains five parishes, and the greater part of two others; and is in the district of Eton. Acres, 16,580. Pop., 6,134. Houses, 1,196.-The hundred contains thirteen parishes. Acres, 58,371. Pop., 20,534. Houses, 4,247. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Burnham/Index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burnham,_Buckinghamshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654274</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42543</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10082183</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10133981</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10176610</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552382</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570750</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1487</id>
   <name>FARNHAM ROYAL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3684</id>
   <name>HITCHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
