<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1492</id>
<name>HARTWELL</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8065422263701</lat>
<lon>-0.838022323416953</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARTWELL, a parish in Aylesbury district, Bucks; 2 miles SW of Aylesbury r. station. It includes part of the hamlet of Sedrup; and its post town is Aylesbury. Acres, 680. Real property, &#163;2, 3 45. Pop., 137. Houses, 28. The property is owned by J. Lee, Esq. The manor belonged to the De Hertwells, the Lutons, the Stokeses, the Singletons, and the Hampdens; and passed, in the 14th tury, to the Lees. Hartwell House is an old edifice, considerably modernized; was the residence, in 1810-14, of Louis XVIII. and his family; usually, with the out buildings, accommodated about 140 persons during the time of Louis&apos;s residence; is hid from the view of persons on the high road, by a screen of superb trees; contains many memorials of Louis&apos;s family, and of distinguished persons who visited them; and contains also a museum, a fine geological collection, a large quantity of manuscripts, and some interesting pictures. A history of it, by Admiral Smyth, fills two large 4to vols., entitled &quot; &#198;des Hartwellian&#230;.&quot; he geology of the parish and its neighbourhoods very rich. There are also several springs; and over one of them is an Egyptian temple, recently erected, after a design by Bonomi. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Little Hampden, in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;226. * Patron, the Royal Astronomical Society of London. The church was built in 1756; is octagonal, on the model of the charter House at York; has two squaee towers; and bears, in the east window, the arms of the Hampdens, the Lees, and the Harcourts. The only charity is the interest of &#163;100 given by Louis XVIII. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartwell</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Hartwell/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=62775</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10009420</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HARTWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10157470</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARTWELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
