<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5494</id>
<name>EDLESBOROUGH</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8536885781955</lat>
<lon>-0.586751864558411</lon>
<gazetteerText>EDDLESBOROUGH, or Edlesborough, a village and a parish in the district of Leighton-Buzzard and county of Buckingham; and a sub-district partly also in the county of Bedford. The village stands near the boundary with Bedford, and near Icknield-street, 3 miles E by N of Cheddington-Junction r. station and 5&#189; SSE of Leighton-Buzzard. The parish contains also the hamlets of Dagnall, Horton, Hudnall, and Northall; and its post town is Ivinghoe, under Tring. Acres, 4, 579. Real property, exclusive of Horton, &#163;7, 070. Pop., 1, 671. Houses, 369. The property is divided among a few. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Oxford. Valne, &#163;569.* Patron, Earl Brownlow. The church occupies a fine site; contains some old stalls, and two curious brasses; and had a wooden spire, destroyed by lightning in 1828. There are a school-church, a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;46.&#151;The sub-district contains two parishes in Bucks and one in Beds. Acres, 8, 069. Pop, 3, 436. Houses, 743. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edlesborough</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Edlesborough/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650216</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42577</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10116156</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EDLESBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10195950</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EDLESBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547453</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EDLESBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
