<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1037</id>
<name>BEACONSFIELD</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6037883841634</lat>
<lon>-0.633303651841225</lon>
<gazetteerText>BEACONSFIELD, a small town, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Amersham, Bucks. The town stands on an eminence anciently used for beacon-fires, 3 miles NE of Woburn-Green r. station, and 5&#190; S by W of Amersham. It has a post office,&#8225;-B. Bucks; and is a seat of petty sessions, and a polling-place. It consists of four streets, which meet at the centre in a spacious market-place; and it contains the parish church and three dissenting chapels. The church is built of flint and squared stones; comprises nave, chancel, and side aisles, with a western tower; belonged to an Augustinian monastery, founded at Burnham, in 1165, by Richard, Earl of Cornwall; and contains the remains of Edmund Burke, whose seat was in the neighbourhood; and a marble monument to the poet Waller, who owned the manor, is in the churchyard. A weekly market recently ceased; but fairs are held on 13 Feb. and 10 May.&#151;The parish includes also part of Coleshill hamlet. Acres, 4,541. Real property, with the rest of Coleshill, &#163;9,619. Pop., 1,662. Houses, 342. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;545. Patron, Magdalene College, Oxford. Charities, &#163;114.-The subdistrict comprises two parishes and a chapelry. Acres, 9,401. Pop., 3,092. Houses, 65 (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656120</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beaconsfield</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Beaconsfield/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42542</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10028425</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BEACONSFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10045927</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BEACONSFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10115644</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BEACONSFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10212248</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BEACONSFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10565200</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BEACONSFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12748437</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>BEACONSFIELD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3710</id>
   <name>PENN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4573</id>
   <name>SEER GREEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5869</id>
   <name>COLESHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
