<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3660</id>
<name>CHENIES</name>
<container>BUCKINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6702994638946</lat>
<lon>-0.531823842891876</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHENEYS, Chenies, or Islehampstead-Cheneys, a village and a parish in Amersham district, Bucks. The village stands on the verge of the county, on the river Chess, 4&#188; miles E by N of Amersham, and 4&#189; WSW of King&apos;s Langley r. station. It consists of neat cottages, grouped round a pretty green; has a post office of the name of Chenies, under Watford; and gives the title of Baron to the Duke of Bedford. The parish comprises 1, 744 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 399. Pop., 468. Houses, 112. The manor belonged formerly to the Cheynes and the Sapcotes; and passed by marriage, in 1560, to the Russells. The manor-house of the Sapcotes was almost rebuilt by the first Lord Russell, and gave entertainment to Queen Elizabeth in 1570; and a picturesque fragment of it, now a farm-house, still stands adjacent to the church. Chorley-Wood, in the near neighbourhood, is the seat of W. Longman, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Oxford. Value, &#163;380.* Patron, the Duke of Bedford. The church is an ancient edifice, beautifully restored; was the marriage-place, in 1630, of the Countess of Dorset to the Earl of Pembroke; contains two remarkable brasses of the Cheynes; and includes a chapel which has been the burial-place of the Russells since 1556, and which contains a series of magnificent tombs of the Earls and Dukes of Bedford and their children. There is a Baptist chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chenies</link>
<link>http://met.open.ac.uk/genuki/big/eng/BKM/Chenies/Index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653257</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42546</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10045976</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHENIES AND LITTLE CHALFONT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10115759</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CHENIES</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
