<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5626</id>
<name>LLANFIHANGEL CWM DU</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8997498596335</lat>
<lon>-3.18848700345445</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANFIHANGEL-CWMDU, a parish in Crickhowel district, Brecon; on an affluent of the river Usk, and on the Via Julia montana, under the Black mountains, 4&#188; miles NW by N of Crickhowel, and 7&#189; S by E of Talgarth r. station. It is divided into the parcels of Blayney, Cenol, Cilwych, and Tretower; and it contains the village of Cwmd&#251;, which has a post office under Crickhowel. Acres, 10,068. Real property, &#163;5,987. Pop., 1,056. Houses, 240. Penniyarth is a chief residence. Tretower Castle was the seat of the Picards, lords of Ystradyw; was fortified in the time of Henry IV.; and now consists of merely a circular keep, and some ruinous walls. Tretower Court is a mansion of the 15th century, and presents some good features of later English architecture. Vestiges of a Roman station, called the Gaer, contiguous to the Via Julia, are a short way above Cwmd&#251; village. Roman coins, bricks, and other relics have been foundThe living is a rectory in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;40. Patron, the Duke of Beaufort. The church was rebuilt in 1830; has an embattled tower; and includes a Roman stone, brought from the Roman station, and bearing an inscription to &quot;Catacus.&quot; The p. curacy of Tretower is a separate benefice. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/BRE/LlanfihangelCwmDu/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10201354</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL CWM DU</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550660</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CWMDU</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
