<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2373</id>
<name>GLYN</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8897233755924</lat>
<lon>-3.49178476641807</lon>
<gazetteerText>GLYNN, a hamlet in Devynnock parish, Breconshire; on the river Tarrill, 9 miles W by S of Brecon. It includes the chapelry of Illtid. Real property, &#163;1, 526. Pop., 273. Houses, 49. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10052154</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>GLYN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4906</id>
<name>GLYN FACH</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9921881710616</lat>
<lon>-3.09980802826465</lon>
<gazetteerText>GLYNFACH, a hamlet in Llanigon parish, Brecon; - under the Black Mountains, adjacent to Hereford and Monmouth, 2 miles S of Hay. Real property, &#163;351. Pop., 59. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10170242</id>
   <status>Tn/CP/AP</status>
   <name>GLYN FACH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2432</id>
<name>GLYNTAWE</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8380253630696</lat>
<lon>-3.65481866992531</lon>
<gazetteerText>GLYNTAWE, a hamlet-chapelry in Devynnock parish, Breconshire; 7&#189; miles W of Brecon town and r. station. Post town, Brecon. Pop., 99. Houses, 20. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;80. Patron, the Vicar of Devynnock. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10058806</id>
   <status>CP/Hmlt</status>
   <name>GLYNTAWE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10198690</id>
   <status>Tn</status>
   <name>CALLWEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10368133</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CALLWEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23879</id>
<name>GLYN COLLWYN</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8453674172132</lat>
<lon>-3.33568093934565</lon>
<gazetteerText>GLYN-COLLWYN, a hamlet-chapelry and a glen in the S of Brecon. The chapelry 1ies in the glen, on the Brecon and Merthyr railway, 2&#189; miles NE of Dolygaer r. station, and 8 NNE of Merthyr-Tydvil; and is in the parish of Llanvigan. Post town, Merthyr-Tydvil. Pop., 342. Houses, 66. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the rectory of Llanvigan, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. The glen is overhung by the Brecknock Beacons; is about 6 miles long; and possesses grand scenery. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10128195</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GLYNCOLLEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
