<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6376</id>
<name>LLANGATWG</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8343017625148</lat>
<lon>-3.17774946521969</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANGATTOCK, a parish and a sub-district in Crickhowell district, Brecon. The parish lies on the river Usk, opposite Crickhowell, 4&#188; miles NW by N of Clydach r. station; is connected by a bridge with Crickhowell, and intersected by the Brecon canal; comprises the parcel of Penallt, and the parcel of Prisk and Killey; and includes part of the chapelry of Beaufort. Post town, Crickhowell. Acres, 9,597. Real property, &#163;14,666; of which &#163;2,780 are in iron-works, and &#163;400 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851,5,415; in 1861,5,759. Houses, 1,254. Pop. of the Beaufort chapelry portion in 1861,2,992. Houses, 693. The property is not much divided. Llangattock Park, Glanussk Park, Glannsk Villa, and Dany-Park are chief residences. Limestone, ironstone, and coal abound; and the Beaufort iron-works are in the S. A cistvaen was found on Carnohill; and a battle was fought there, in 728, between the Britons and King Ethelbald. The liVing is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Llangeney, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;905.* Patron, the Duke of Beaufort. The church is dedicated to St. Catwg; and is early decorated English, in good condition. There is an Independent chapel. Crickhowell workhouse also is here; and, at the census of 1861, had 119 inmates. Bishops Lloyd and Davies were rectors.&#151;The sub-district is conterminate with the parish. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/BRE/Llangatwg/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644041</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10225875</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANGATWG</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10563320</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANGATTOCK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2973</id>
   <name>LLANELEU</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4906</id>
   <name>GLYN FACH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5626</id>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL CWM DU</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
