<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1109</id>
<name>LLANWRTYD</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1059297363239</lat>
<lon>-3.63612886234019</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANWRTYD, a parish and a sub-district in the district of Llandovery and county of Brecon. The parish lies on the river Irvon, and on the Craven-Arms, Knighton, Llandovery, and Swansea railway, 1 1&#189; miles NE by N of Llandovery; comprises the hamlets of Clawddmadog and Llechweddor; contains mineral wells resorted to by invalids; and has a railway station, designated Llanwrtyd-Wells, and a post office under Builth, Breconshire. Acres, 11,335. Real property, &#163;2,056. Pop., 607. Houses, 117. The property is divided among a few. Dolycoed was a seat of the Joneses, and is now the chief boarding-house for visitors to the wells. Dinas also was formerly a mansion, but is now a farm-house. The parochial surface is wildly mountainous, but includes romantic scenery and many charming walks. A narrow bridge spans the Irvon at Pont-rhyd-y-feir, near Dolycoed. The mineral wells lie in a glen, flanked by lofty heights; were discovered, or brought into notice, in 1732; are chalybeate and sulphureous, of similar quality to those of Harrogate; and are in repute for scorbutic and cutaneous diseases. The sulphureous one emits fetid odours, and is thence called by the Welsh Ffynnon Drewllyd, or &quot;the stinking well. &apos;&apos;The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the vicarage of Llangammarch, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. The church is good; and there are a Presbyterian chapel and an endowed school. The subdistrict contains also Llandulas parish. Acres, 14,555. Pop., 731. Houses, 136. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/BRE/Llanwrtyd/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llanwrtyd_Wells</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643906</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10238158</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANWRTUD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10238160</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>LLANWRTYD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412470</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LLANWRTYD WITHOUT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412500</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LLANWRTYD WELLS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550610</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANWRTYD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2049</id>
   <name>LLANDDEWI ABERGWESYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3221</id>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL ABERGWESYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4962</id>
   <name>LLANDDULAS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8424</id>
   <name>PENBUALLT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8992</id>
   <name>TREFLYS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
