<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8941</id>
<name>TALGARTH</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9644904028568</lat>
<lon>-3.19366773940779</lon>
<gazetteerText>TALGARTH, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Brecon. The village stands on the Hereford and Brecon railway, 8&#189; miles SW of Hay; had anciently a castle; is a borough by prescription; and . has a post-office&#8225; under Hereford, a r. station with telegraph, a good church, three dissenting chapels, an alms-house, charities &#163;31, a weekly market, and eight annual fairs. Real property, &#163;2,965. Pop., 684. Houses, 172.&#151;The parish contains also Trefecca, Pwllywrach, Forest, Grwyne.fawr, and Grwyne-fechan hamlets; and comprises 16,900 acres. Pop., 1,330. Houses, 297. Trefecca house is a chief object of interest. Porthaml belonged to the Vaughans, and Tredustan and Tregunter, to the Gunters. There are a cromlech, and other ancient British relics. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;250. Patrons, the Dean and Canons of Windsor.&#151;The sub-district excludes the two Grwyne hamlets, but includes four other parishes, and a part; and is in Hay district. Acres, 28,155. Pop., 2,476. Houses, 539. The hundred contains 13 parishes, and a part. Acres, 71,621. Pop., 7,685. Houses, 1,643. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/BRE/Talgarth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636307</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10006867</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>TALGARTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10048357</id>
   <status>Cmt</status>
   <name>TALGARTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10306723</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TALGARTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550579</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TALGARTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1520</id>
   <name>BRONLLYS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3304</id>
   <name>GLASBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3489</id>
   <name>LLANDYFALLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6402</id>
   <name>LLANGORS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6678</id>
   <name>LLAN Y WERN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
