<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6454</id>
<name>LLANGYNIDR</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8312430410135</lat>
<lon>-3.25541465823803</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANGUNIDER, or LLANGYNIDER, a parish and a sub-district in Crickhowell district, Brecon. The parish lies on the river Usk, the Brecon canal, and the Trivel tram railway, 4&#188; miles W by N of Crickhowell, and 6 N of Nantyglo r. station; includes a mountain mass called Mynydd-Llangunider; contains a small but beautifully situated village of its own name; contains also the parcel of Vro, and the parcel of Blainey-with-Duffryn; and has a post office under Crickhowell. Acres, 13,908. Real property, &#163;9,244; of which &#163;1,356 are in quarries, and &#163;122 in mines. Pop. in 1851,3,246; in 1861,3,594. Houses, 761. Limestone and coal are worked; and many of the inhabitants are employed in the neighbouring Clydach ironworks. Some scenery, particularly at Buckland-Mill and Duffryn-Crownan, is very fine. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;418. * Patron, the Duke of Beaufort. The church is dedicated to St. Cynydr. Charities, &#163;8.&#151;The sub-district is conterminate with the parish. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/BRE/Llangynidr/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644003</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10227938</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANGYNIDR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3054</id>
   <name>LLANFEUGAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4453</id>
   <name>LLANDDETI</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5093</id>
   <name>CATHEDIN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6616</id>
   <name>LLANSANFFRAID</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
