<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3263</id>
<name>LLANAFAN FAWR</name>
<container>BRECKNOCKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1889182392613</lat>
<lon>-3.54973387861845</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANAFAN-FAWR, a parish in Builth district, Brecon on an affluent of the river Wye, 6 miles NW of Builth town and r. station. It is cut into three divisions,-first, second, and third; it contains, besides these, the hamlet of Llysdinam; and its Post town is Builth, Breconshire. Acres of the three divisions, 7,971; of Llysdinam hamlet, 2,476. Real property of the first div., &#163;1,066; of the second div., &#163;796; of the third div., $1,303; of Llysdinam hamlet, &#163;1,116. Pop. of the whole, 936. Houses, 174. Pop. of Llysdinam, 242 Houses, 39. The surface is hilly, and is largely disposed in pasture. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacies of Llanafan-Fechan and Llanfihangel Bryn-Pabuan, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, $273. * Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church contains a monument of Bishop Avan. A Presbyterian church was founded in 1670. The parish has a share in Powell&apos;s charities.at Brecon. Mab-y-Clochyddyn, a poet of the 14th century, supposed to be Macluff-ap-Llywarch, was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/BRE/LlanafanFawr/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7292189</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10095610</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANAFAN FAWR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3564</id>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL BRYN PABUAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4341</id>
   <name>GWARAFOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4419</id>
   <name>LLANAFAN FECHAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
