<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2189</id>
<name>CAXTON</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2113893037807</lat>
<lon>-0.0935261440624377</lon>
<gazetteerText>CAXTON, a decayed town, a parish, a subdistrict, and a district in Cambridgeshire. The town stands on Ermine-street, 3&#189; miles NNW of North Road r. station, and 9&#189; W of Cambridge; and has a post office&#8225; under Royston and two inns. It had a market from the 13th century till the middle of the 18th; and it still has a fair on the 12th of Oct.&#151;The parish comprises 2,000 acres. Real property, &#163;2,276. Pop., 545. Houses, 97. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged to the D&apos;Eschallerses, the Freviles, the Burgoynes, and others. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;80.* Patrons, the Dean and Canons of Windsor. The church contains some old tombs; and was recently restored. There are a national school and a workhouse. M. Paris, the historian, was a native.-The subdistrict and the district are co-extensive; and contain the parishes of Caxton, Bourn, Knapwell, Elsworth, Longstow, Hatley-St. George, East Hatley, Tadlow, Croydon-cum-Clapton, Arrington, Wimpole, Orwell, Little Eversden, Great Eversden, Kingston, Caldecote, Toft, Hardwicke, Gamlingay, Eltisley, Croxton, Papworth-St. Everard, Little Gransden, Great Gransden, Yelling, and Papworth-St. Agnes,-the last partly and the two previous wholly in Huntingdon-proper. Acres, 49,885. Poor-rates in 1866, &#163;5,414. Pop. in 1861, 10,966. Houses, 2,200. Marriages in 1866, 56; births, 416,-of which 30 were illegitimate; deaths, 236,-of which 113 were at ages under 3 years, and 12 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 733; births, 3,907; deaths, 2,046. The places of worship in 1851 were 26 of the Church of England, with 4,951 sittings; 2 of Independents, with 740 s.; 7 of Baptists, with 1,757 s.; 5 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 688 s.; and 1 of Primitive Methodists, with 70 s. The schools were 17 public day schools, with 1,282 scholars; 8 private day schools, with 196 s.; and 27 Sunday schools, with 1,716 s. The workhouse has capacity for 215 inmates. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Caxton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caxton,_Cambridgeshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653462</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Caxton</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10034450</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>CAXTON AND ARRINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10047638</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CAXTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10119108</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CAXTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10138000</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>CAXTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10155083</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>CAXTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550749</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CAXTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3249</id>
   <name>ELTISLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
