<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2177</id>
<name>BABRAHAM</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1396013260886</lat>
<lon>0.205883091186801</lon>
<gazetteerText>BABRAHAM, anciently Badburham, a village and a parish in Linton district, Cambridge. The village stands on an affluent of the river Cam, near the Gogmagog hills, 2&#189; miles ENE of Whittlesford r. station, and 6&#189; SE of Cambridge. It has a post office under Cam bridge; and was formerly a market town. The parish comprises 2,350 acres. Real property, &#163;2,760. Pop., 304. Houses, 67. The manor belonged to Algar, Earl of Mercia; passed, about the year 1576, into the posses sion of Sir Horatio Palavicini, a Genoese; and now he longs to H. J. Adeane, Esq. Sir H. Palavicini collected the pope&apos;s taxes in England during the reign of Mary; converted them to his own use, and became Protestant, on the accession of Elizabeth; became a favourite of that queen, one of her negotiators in Germany, and a commander of one of her ships against the Spanish armada; and died at his seat in Babraham; and his widow was married to Sir Oliver Cromwell, the uncle of the Protec tor. A curious epitaph on him is given in &quot;Lord Or ford&apos;s Anecdotes of Painting.&quot; The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;106. Patron, H. J. Adeane, Esq. An almshouse and a free school, with income of &#163;134, were founded in 1723 by Lebinus Bush and Judith Bennet; and a monument to her is in the church. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656686</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Babraham</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Babraham/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10047298</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BABRAHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10177923</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BABRAHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
