<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4624</id>
<name>OVER</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3206753989168</lat>
<lon>0.0271023665584903</lon>
<gazetteerText>OVER, a village and a parish in the district of St. Ives and county of Cambridge. The village stands 1 mile E of the river Ouse at the boundary with Hunts, 1&#188; N N E of Swavesey r. station, and 4&#189; E by S of St. Ives; and has a post-office under St. Ives, a neat town hall built in 1849, and two inns. The parish comprises 3, 700 acres. Real property, &#163;9, 307. Pop. in 1851, 1, 256; in 1861, 1, 146. Houses, 236. The principal manor belongs to E. Foster, Esq.; and a smaller one, to Merton College, Oxford. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, Trinity College, Cambridge. The church is ancient and handsome; the W door has a carving of the &quot; Virgin clothed with the sun; &quot; the body has undergone considerable repair; the N aisle was rebuilt in 1847; the tower and spire were renovated, at a cost of &#163;600, in 1864. There are chapels for Baptists and Primitive Methodists, an endowed school with &#163;20 a year, town lands yielding &#163;366, and other charities &#163;15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Over,_Cambridgeshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Over/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640778</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15486</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15481</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15479</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15483</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15484</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15480</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15482</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15485</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10159428</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>OVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10178710</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OVER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
