<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3103</id>
<name>DODDINGTON</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5171998719575</lat>
<lon>0.0546069500742236</lon>
<gazetteerText>DODDINGTON, a village and a parish in North Witchford district, Cambridge. The village stands near the Wisbeach and Cambridge railway, near Wimblington r. station, 4&#188; miles SSW of March; has a post office under March; and was once a seat of the Bishops of Ely-Real property, &#163;15, 355. Pop., 1, 380. Houses, 273. The parish contains also the town of March, and the hamlets of Wimblington and Benwick. Acres, 36, 985. Real property &#163;92, 166. Pop., 8, 722. Houses, 1,894. The manor belongs to Sir A. Peyton, Bart. The surface is fenny; and is bisected by the old river Nen. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Ely; and, till 1868, was the richest benefice in the kingdom; but was then divided into the three rectories of Doddington, March, and Benwick. Value of the three, &#163;7, 306.* Patron, Sir A. Peyton, Bart. There are a Baptist chapel, four Methodist chapels, a national school, an endowed school with &#163;55 a year, town-lands &#163;146, and other charities &#163;702. Nalson, the historian, was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Doddington/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doddington</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651181</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=21901</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10090611</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>DODDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10159052</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DODDINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
