<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5952</id>
<name>ICKLETON</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0638634294837</lat>
<lon>0.159031643423466</lon>
<gazetteerText>ICKLETON, a village and a parish in Linton district, Cambridge. The village stands on Icknield street, adjacent to the Great Eastern railway, near the boundary with Essex, 1&#189; mile NNW of Chesterford r. station, and 5 WSW of Linton; has a post office under Saffron-Walden, and a fair on 22 July; and was once a market town. The parish comprises 2, 672 acres. Real property, &#163;4, 002. Pop., 721. Houses, 159. The manor belongs to the Hon. Mrs. A1gernon Herbert. A Benedictine nunnery was founded here, in the time of Henry II., by the De Veres or the Cantelupes; and was given, at the dissolution, in exchange for other property, to the Bishops of Ely. Roman coins and remains of a Roman villa, together with other Roman relics, were found in 1848. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;85. * Patron, the Bishop of Peterborough. The church consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a lofty tower. Charities, &#163;69. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ickleton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Ickleton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646303</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10159295</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ICKLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10212431</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ICKLETON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1587</id>
   <name>HEYDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2191</id>
   <name>GREAT CHISHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3410</id>
   <name>LITTLE CHISHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6598</id>
   <name>CHRISHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
