<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>614</id>
<name>WHITTLESEY</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5477681567018</lat>
<lon>-0.0961606472721093</lon>
<gazetteerText>WHITTLESEY, a town, two parishes, and a district, in Cambridge. The town stands on the Old Nen river, adjacent to the Peterborough, March, and Ely railway, 5&#189; miles E by S of Peterborough; was known, at Domesday, as Witesie; underwent much recent improvement; is a seat of petty-sessions, and a polling place; and has a post-office&#8225; under Peterborough, a r. station with telegraph, two banking offices, a hotel and several inns, a town hall, reading and newsrooms, a fine ancient church of different dates restored in 1862, another ancient church chiefly decorated English, five dissenting chapels, two endowed schools with &#163;16 and &#163;20 a year, a workhouse, town lands &#163;309, general charities &#163;169, a weekly market on Friday, and fairs on 25 January, 13 June, and 26 Oct. Pop. in 1861, 4,496. Houses, 1,087.-The parishes are St. Mary and St. Andrew; they have long lost their mutual boundaries, so as to be now intermixed; and they include the hamlet and chapelry of Coates, and the hamlet of Eastrea. Acres, 25,131. Real property, &#163;57,136. Pop. in 1851, 7,687; in 1861, 6,966. Houses, 1,592. The manor belongs to J. W. Childers, Esq. Traces of a Roman road are at Eldernell; and several antiquities, including a massive gold ring, have been found there. The livings of St. Mary and St. Andrew are vicarages in the diocese of Ely. Value of St. M., &#163;222; of St. A., &#163;490. Patron of St. M., J. W. Childers, Esq.; of St. A., the Lord Chancellor. The living of Coates was formerly a p. curacy, but is now a rectory; and it has been separately noticed. A small new church is at Ponders-Bridge; and Wesleyan chapels are at Coates and Eastrea.&#151;The district is conterminate with the two parishes. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;5,606. Marriages in 1863, 56; births, 257,-of which 24 were illegitimate; deaths, 134,-of which 50 were at ages under 5 years, and 5 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 518; births, 2,768: deaths, 1,653. The places of worship, in 1851, were 4 of the Church of England, with 2,625 sittings; 1 of Independents, with 300 s.; 2 of Baptists, with 640 s.; 3 of Wesleyans, with 498 s.; 1 of Primitive Methodists, with 70 s.; and 1 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 150 s. The schools were 3 public day-schools, with 467 scholars; 29 private day-schools, with 594 s.; and 10 Sunday schools, with 680 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whittlesey</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Whittlesey/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Whittlesey</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Whittlesey/StAndrew/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Whittlesey/StMary/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634010</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=21904</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10012806</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY URBAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10029648</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10048278</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10067080</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10074990</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10093650</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY RURAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10096601</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10108652</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10159556</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186456</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10203454</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY ST MARY AND ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10206273</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10213976</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550920</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WHITTLESEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2206</id>
   <name>THORNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7183</id>
   <name>FARCET</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
