<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5082</id>
<name>HADDENHAM</name>
<container>CAMBRIDGESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3530005434108</lat>
<lon>0.119232197602673</lon>
<gazetteerText>HADDENHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Ely district, Cambridge. The village stands in the fens, 3 miles N of the Old West river, and 6&#189; SW of Ely r. station; and has a post office under Ely. The parish includes also the hamlets of Aldreth and Hill Row. Acres, 8, 912. Real property, &#163;20, 047. Pop., 1, 976. Houses, 413. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged formerly to the priory of Rochester; and belongs now to the Earl of Hardwicke. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;235. Patron, the Archdeacon of Ely. The church stands on a slight acclivity; is about three centuries old; has a lofty spire, visible for many miles; and was in 1865 in disrepair. A new burial ground was formed in 1862. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, and two free schools with &#163;74 and &#163;38; and one of the schools was rebuilt by subscription in 1863. The subdistrict contains also two other parishes. Acres, 18, 085. Pop., 3, 998. Houses, 860. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haddenham,_Cambridgeshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Haddenham/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647687</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=21906</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10012296</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HADDENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10178538</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HADDENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550725</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HADDENHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
