<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2043</id>
<name>LLANDYGWYDD</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0722491564066</lat>
<lon>-4.53713873596226</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANIDYGWIDID, a parish and a sub-district in the district and county of Cardigan. The parish lies on the river Teifi, at the boundary with Pembrokeshire and Carmarthenshire, and on the Newcastle-Emlyn and Cardigan railway, which was in progress of formation in 1866, 4 miles SE of Cardigan. Post town, Llechryd, under Carmarthen. Acres, 5,595. Real property, &#163;4,453; of which &#163;15 are in fisheries. Pop., 1,028. Houses, 230. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged to the Bishops of St. David&apos;s, who had a palace on it; and it passed to the Griffiths. Llwyndyrus, the seat of the Griffiths is on the site of the episcopal palace; and other chief residences are Stradmore-Vale, Noyadd-Trevawr, Penylan, and Blaenpant. A salmon leap is on the contiguous reach of the Teifi. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;130.* Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church is dedicated to St. Dygwydd; was recently rebuilt; is in the early English style, or local stone, with Bath stone dressings; and has a tower. with wooden spire, 130 feet high. -The sub-district contains also four other parishes in Cardiganshire, and two in Pembrokeshire. Acres, 19,860. Pop., 4,133. Houses, (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/Llandygwydd/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644113</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10039642</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANDYGWYDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10583718</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANDYGWYDD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
