<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20349</id>
<name>LLANBADARN FAWR</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4077914274418</lat>
<lon>-4.05837831759785</lon>
<gazetteerText>Llanbadarnfawr.-- par. and vil., Cardiganshire, in N. of co.- par. (containing Aberystwith), 52,750 ac. (330 water), pop. 14,399; vil., on river Rheidol, 1 mile E. of Aberystwith; P.O. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llanbadarn_Fawr</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/LlanbadarnFawr/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7294034</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10307478</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANBADARN FAWR</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3091</id>
<name>LLANBADARN TREFEGLWYS</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2460163009015</lat>
<lon>-4.13553799757655</lon>
<gazetteerText>ILLANBADARN-TREF-EGLWYS, or LLANBADARNFACH, a parish, with a village, in Aberayron district, Cardigan; on the river Arth, near the coast, 3 miles ENE of Aberayron, and 11 NW of Lampeter r. station. Posttown, Aberayron, under Carmarthen. Acres, 6,283. Real property, &#163;2,488. Pop., 948. Houses, 213. The property is divided among a few. The suffix Tref-Eglwys, in the name of the parish, signifies &apos;&apos;three churches, &apos;&apos;and alludes to the existence formerly of three churches here, two of which have disappeared. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;45. Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church was formerly collegiate, and had a prebend; and it is in good condition. There are two Calvinistic Methodist chapels (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/LlanbadarnTrefeglwys/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10090155</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANBADARN TREFEGLWYS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1618</id>
   <name>CILCENNIN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
