<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10554</id>
<name>CARON UWCH CLAWDD</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.241014091106</lat>
<lon>-3.80235573121551</lon>
<gazetteerText>CARON-UWCH-CLAWDD, or Strata-florida, a township-chapelry in Caron-ys-Clawdd parish, Cardigan; on the Sarn Helen way and the river Teifi, 4 miles NNE of Tregaron r. station, and 22&#189; N by W of Llandovery. It includes the village of Rhydfendigaed; and its Post Town is Tregaron, under Carmarthen. Rated property, &#163;368. Pop., 868. Houses, 181. The property is divided among a few. The surface consists of mountains, intersected by narrow vales. A Cistertian Abbey, often called Ystrad-Flwr Abbey, was founded here, in 1164, by Rhys-ap-Gryfydd, prince of South Wales; burnt down in the wars of Edward I.; restored afterwards to more than its original splendour; and given, at the dissolution, to the Stedmans. It was the repository of the national records from 1156 till 1270, and the scene of a grand assembly of lords and barons in 1238; and was the burialplace of many of the Cambrian princes. It stood on the Teifi, overshadowed by mountains; and was alike secluded and magnificent; but almost the only part of it now remaining is a very beautiful Norman arch, which formed the west entrance to its church. An older but small monastic house stood two miles to the south, at a spot still showing ancient foundations, and called LlanMonachlog, &quot;the old monastery.&quot; The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;80. Patron, W. E. Powell, Esq. The church is a small mean structure within the precincts of the Abbey. There is a Calvinistic Methodist chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/StrataFlorida/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strata_Florida_Abbey</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10368467</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CARON UWCH CLAWDD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4796</id>
   <name>DOETHIE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
