<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3411</id>
<name>CARON IS CLAWDD</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2237130545424</lat>
<lon>-3.90689802885875</lon>
<gazetteerText>TREGARON, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Cardigan. The town stands on the Manchester and Milford railway, 10 miles NE by N of Lampeter; was anciently a borough, disfranchised in 1730; is now a polling place; . and has a post-office&#8225; under Carmarthen, a r. station, a church a Calvinistic Methodist chapel, and fairs on 16 March and 8 Oct. Pop., about 800.&#151;The parish is called also Caron-ys-Clawdd, and has been noticed under that title.&#151;The sub-district includes also 7 townships of Llanddewi-brefi. Acres, 67,288. Pop., 3,978. Houses, 848. The district contains also Gwnnws and Llangeitho sub-district, and comprises 122,050 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;3,882. Pop. in 1851, 10,404; in 1861, 10,737. Houses, 2,247. Marriages in 1863, 75; births, 299,-of which 36 were illegitimate; deaths, 179,-of which 37 were at ages under 5 years, and 8 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 630; births, 3,221; deaths, 1,907. The places of worship, in 1851, were 10 of the Church of England, with 1,764 sittings; 2 of Baptists, with 270 s.; 1 of Wesleyans, with 60 s.; and 15 of Calvinistic Methodists, with 4,574 s. The schools were 4 public day-schools, with 294 scholars; 6 private day-schools, with 158 s.; and 38 Sunday schools, with 4,281 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Tregaron</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/Tregaron/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tregaron</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635531</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10101517</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CARON IS CLAWDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154777</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>TREGARON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10156695</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>TREGARON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548512</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TREGARON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828184</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>TREGARON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
