<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4452</id>
<name>LLANDYSUL</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.081066003173</lat>
<lon>-4.2936626756828</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANDYSSIL, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Newcastle-Emlyn district, Cardigan. The village stands on the river Teifi, at the boundary with Carmarthenshire, and on the Carmarthen and Cardigan railway, 8&#188; E of Newcastle-Emlyn; and has a bridge, a railway station, and a post office,&#8225; under Carmarthen. A weekly market is held on Thursday; a monthly market, on the third Tuesday of the month; and fairs on 2 Jan., 11 Feb., the Thursday before Palm Sunday, the third Thursday after that day, 19 Sept., 31 Oct., and 11 Nov.&#151;The parish is divided into Llandyssil-Is-Kerdin, which includes the hamlet of Llanfrene; and Llandyssil-Uwch-Kerdin, which includes the hamlets of Borthin, Capel-Ddewi, Fairdref, Glandysilved, and Llanvair. Acres, 17,556. Real property of L. Is-Kerdin, &#163;3,167; of IL. Uwch-Kerdin, &#163;4,913. Pop. of the whole in 1851,2,930; in 1861, 2,788. Houses, 682. The property is much subdivided. Allt-yr-Odyn, Waun-Ifor, Gilfachwen, and Llanfair are chief residences. Castell-Hywel, once a mansion, is now a farm-house. Castell-Gwynionydd stood near the church; Maelgwm&apos;s castle stood at Cilygriaig; and Humphrey&apos;s castle stood on the rivulet Cletwr. There are several barrows. The living is two-fold-a vicarage united with the chapelry of Capel-Ddewi, and a sinecure rectory-in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value of the vicarage, &#163;220; * of the rectory &#163;400. Patron of the former, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s; of the latter, Jesus&apos; College, Oxford. The church is partly early English, and was recently in dierepair. There are three recently erected chapels of ease, and chapels for Independents, Baptists, Calvinistic Methodists, Wesleyans, and Unitarians.&#151;The sub-district contains also four other parishes in Cardigan and one in Carmarthen. Acres, 40,722. Pop., 5,934. Houses, 1,396. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llandysul</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/Llandysul/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644107</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10150619</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANDYSUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10389422</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>LLANDYSSIL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548627</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANDYSSUL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6456</id>
   <name>LLANGYNLLO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6649</id>
   <name>LLANWENOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8415</id>
   <name>PENBRYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8985</id>
   <name>TREDREYR</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
