<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20350</id>
<name>LLANDDEWI BREFI</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1802479542489</lat>
<lon>-3.95422749504598</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANDDEWI-BREFI, a village and a parish in Tregaron district, Cardigan. The village stands on the N slope of Craig-Twrch, near the river Teifi, the Sarn-Helen way, and the Lampeter, Tregaron, and Llanidloes railway, which was in course of formation in 1866,3&#188; miles S by W of Tregaron; and has a post office under Carmarthen. It is an ancient place, once important, though now small; it was the scene of a synod, in 519, held for checking Pelagianism, and where St. Dubricins resigned his episcopal or archiepiscopal charge to St. David; it has remains of a collegiate establishment, founded in 1 187 by Bishop Bec; and it was, for a time, intended to be the site of Dr. Burgess&apos;s college, afterwards erected at Lampeter. The parish contains the chapelries of Garthely and Blaenpenal, and the townships of Gwynfil, Llanio, Gogoyan, Garth and Ystrad, Prisk and Carfan, Gorwydd, Dothie-Camddwr, and Dothie-Piscottwr. Acres, 36,252. Real property &#163;6,487. Pop., 2,574. Houses, 532. Foelall is a chief residence. Pl&#226;s Llanfair is a ruined mansion. Much of the land is hill and mountain. A picturesque route, traversable only by a pedestrian, goes from the village up the vale of the Brenig. The Roman station Loventium, on the Sarn-Helen way, was at the site of Llanio farm-house; three stones, with Roman inscriptions were found here, and one of them is used as a seat at the farm-door; coinspottery, and other Roman relics also have been found, and the foundations of an ancient building, called Caer; Castell, were discovered in a neighbouring field. A battle was fought in the parish in 1073, when the princes of Powys vanquished Rhys ap Owen and Rhyddarch ap Caradog. The living is a p. curacy, united with the p. curacy of Llanbadarn-Odwyn, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;146. Patrons, the Earl of Lisburne and R. Price, Esq. The church is early English, modernized; was founded in 1187, by Bishop Bec; and contains some old monuments. A pillar stone, 7 feet high, called St. David&apos;s staff, also is here. The p. curacies of Garthely and Blaenpenal are separate benefices. There is an endowed school with &#163;10 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llanddewi_Brefi</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/Llanddewibrefi/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10193047</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>LLANDDEWIBREFI</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12796778</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LLANDDEWI BREFI</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
