<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6590</id>
<name>LLANNARTH</name>
<container>CARDIGANSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1710311973436</lat>
<lon>-4.27912238322179</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANARTH, a parish in Aberayron district, Cardigan; on the rivulet Lethi or Llethy down to the coast; 4&#188; miles SSW of Aberayron, and 13 WNW of Lampeter r. station. It has a post office under Carmarthen, and fairs on 12 Jan., 12 March, 17 June, 22 Sept., and the Wednesday after 12 Dec.; and it includes the hamlets of Dre, Fach, Gafriw, Gelli, Goytre, Hir, Llyffannog, Mochros, Talybonllwyd, and Werr. Acres, 15,044; of which 25 are water. Real property, &#163;6,034. Pop. in 1 851,2,337; in 1861,2,216. Houses, 524. The property is divided among a few. Noyadd-Llanarth beLonged formerly to the Gryffiths, and belongs now to Lord Kensington. Wern belonged, in the time of Henry VII., to the Lloyds; and gave entertainment to that monarch, on his way to Bosworth field. Ancient camps are at Pen-y-gaer and Castell-Moeddyn. The living is a vicarage, united with vicarage of Llanina, in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;120. * Patron, the Bishop of St. Davids. The church consists of nave and chancel, with a massive tower; contains some curious monuments; and was in disrepair in 1866. An inscribed stone, bearing a cross, with four circular holes at the junction of the arms, and associated with a wild legendary story, was in the churchyard, and has been removed into the tower. A school, with capacity for about 120 children, was built in 1859, at a cost of &#163;700; and is surmounted with a bellcott and a spirelet. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CGN/Llannarth/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llanarth,_Ceredigion</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644187</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10236381</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANNARTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>670</id>
   <name>ABERAERON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1122</id>
   <name>NEW QUAY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3091</id>
   <name>LLANBADARN TREFEGLWYS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3149</id>
   <name>LLANDYSILIOGOGO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4351</id>
   <name>HENFYNYW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4960</id>
   <name>LLANDDEWI ABER ARTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6405</id>
   <name>LLANGRANNOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6577</id>
   <name>LLANLLWCHAEARN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6610</id>
   <name>LLANRHYSTYD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6614</id>
   <name>LLANSANFFRAID</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
