<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3582</id>
<name>BUNBURY</name>
<container>CHESHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1172478429412</lat>
<lon>-2.64993776428211</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUNBURY, a township, a parish, and a subdistrict in the district of Nantwich, Cheshire. The township lies on the Chester canal and the Chester and Crewe railway, near the Calveley station, 3&#189; miles SSE of Tarporley; and it has a post office&#8225; of the name of Higher Bunbury, under Tarporley, and fairs on 11 and 12 Feb., and 30 and 31 July. Acres, 1,140. Real property, &#163;4,229. Pop., 990. Houses, 209. The parish contains also the townships of Tiverton, Tilstone-Fearnall, Beeston, Alpraham, Calveley, Wardle, Haughton, Spurstow, Ridley, Peckforton, and Burwardsley. Acres, 16,830. Real property, &#163;28,879. Pop., 4,727. Houses, 927. The manor belonged to Hugh Lupus; and passed to the Bunburys. A college for a master and six chaplains was founded here, in 1386, by Sir Hugh de Calveley; and was purchased from the Crown, in the time of Elizabeth, by Thomas Aldersey of London, who gave the income for charitable uses. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacies of Peckforton and Calveley, in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;117.* Patrons, the Haberdashers&apos; Company. The church is later English; has a side chapel and a pinnacled tower; was injured by the royalists in 1643; underwent complete restoration in 1865; and contains monuments of Calveley, the Cheshire hero of the 14th century, and Beeston, the commander against the Spanish armada. The p. curacies of Tilstone and Burwardsley are separate benefices. There are seven dissenting chapels, two national schools, and charities &#163;46.-The subdistrict contains three parishes and part of another. Pop., 7,959. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.ukbmd.org.uk/genuki/chs/bunbury.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bunbury,_Cheshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654334</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10063700</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BUNBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10112965</id>
   <status>CP/Tn/AP</status>
   <name>BUNBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542080</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BUNBURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
