<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>663</id>
<name>BOWDON</name>
<container>CHESHIRE</container>
<lat>53.373848176015</lat>
<lon>-2.36733415533864</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOWDON, or Bowden, a village, a township, and a parish in Altrincham district, Cheshire. The village stands on the Roman road from Kinderton, adjacent to the Manchester, Knutsford, and Northwich railway, near the river Bollin, &#188; of a mile SW of Altrincham; and it has a station on the railway, with refreshment rooms and telegraph, and a post office under Manchester. It enjoys fine air and charming environs; and is a favourite resort of ruralizing parties from Manchester.-The township includes the village, and comprises 828 acres. Real property, &#163;14,322. Pop., 1,827. Houses, 301.&#151;The parish contains also the townships of Altrincham, Baguley, Timperley, Hale, Ashley, Dunham-Massey, Carrington, Partington, and Bollington. Acres, 17,971. Real property, &#163;90,900. Pop., 14,822. Houses, 2,779. The property is not much divided. The manor belonged to the priory of Birkenhead; and was given, by Henry VIII., to the see of Chester. Dunham Park is the seat of the Earl of Stamford, and has fine grounds. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;460.* Patron, the Bishop of Chester. The church stands on elevated ground; was rebuilt after the model of the previous one, in the later English style, in 1860, at a cost of about &#163;12,000; and comprises nave, chancel, aisles, transepts, chapel, and vestry, with a tower. The p. curacy of St. John is a separate charge, constituted in 1866. Patron, the Bishop ofThe church was completed in 1867, at a cost of &#163;5,350; and is in the early English style, and cruciform. The chapelries of Altrincham, Carrington, Dunham-Massey, Ringway, and Timperley, are separate benefices. There are numerous dissenting-chapels, numerous public schools, and charities &#163;414. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.ukbmd.org.uk/genuki/chs/bowdon.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bowdon,_Greater_Manchester</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655069</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10085238</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BOWDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109632</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BOWDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10111754</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BOWDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10112825</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOWDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10218019</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>UNNAMED</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570130</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BOWDON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1453</id>
   <name>MILLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3545</id>
   <name>BOLLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
