<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5060</id>
<name>WRENBURY</name>
<container>CHESHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0326488213227</lat>
<lon>-2.61554927509441</lon>
<gazetteerText>WRENBURY, a village, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Nantwich district, Cheshire. The village stands on the river Weaver, the Ellesmere canal, and the Crewe and Shrewsbury railway, 5 miles SW of Nantwich; and has a post-office under Nantwich, a r. station, an inn, and fairs on 25 March and 25 Sept. The township is called W.-with-Frith, and comprises 2,078 acres. Real property, &#163;3,631. Pop., 531. Houses, 103. The manor belongs to the Marquis of Cholmondeley. W. Hall is the seat of Major Starkey.&#151;The parish includes 5 other townships and a part; and comprises 15,698 acres. Pop., 2,505. Houses, 484. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, the Vicar of Aeton. The church is plain. There are four Methodist chapels, an endowed school with &#163;12 a year, and charities &#163;79.&#151;The sub-district contains also Baddiley parish and parts of Audlem and Malpas; and comprises 30,139 acres. Pop., 6,033. Houses, 1,229. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wrenbury</link>
<link>http://www.ukbmd.org.uk/genuki/chs/wrenbury.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633489</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10010603</id>
   <status>Ch</status>
   <name>WRENBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10158187</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WRENBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10177601</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>WRENBURY CUM FRITH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542108</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WRENBURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2124</id>
   <name>MARBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2902</id>
   <name>WOODCOTT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5684</id>
   <name>NORBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
