<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>950</id>
<name>LYMM</name>
<container>CHESHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3789483645101</lat>
<lon>-2.47198420653391</lon>
<gazetteerText>LYMM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Altrincham district, Cheshire. The village stands on the Bridgewater canal, near the Manchester, Warrington, and Garston railway, 1&#188; mile SSE of the river Mersey, 1&#188; SW of the river Bollin, and 4&#189; ESE of Warrington; and has a station on the railway, a post office&#8225; under Warrington, a police station, an old cross, gas-works, and fairs on 5 May and 5 Nov. The police station is a neat small building, containing four cells. The cross is partly cut out of solid rock, and is in fine preservation. The gas-works were erected in 1862. The parish contains also the hamlets of Heatley-Heath and Cliffe-Lane, and the places called Crouchley-Lane, Burford-Lane, LymmBooths, Oughtrington, Broom edge, Reddish, and Stat ham; and it extends to the Mersey and the BollinAcres, 4,284. Real property, &#163;18,377; of which &#163;200 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851,3,156; in 1861,3,769. Houses, 735. The manor is divided. Lymm Hall, an ancient edifice, formerly moated, is the seat of J. Barratt, Esq. Oughtrington Hall is the seat of A. F. Payne, Esq.; Statham Lodge, of P. Stubs, Esq.; Beechwood, of G.Dewhurst, Esq. There are many recent Villas and well built houses. Tanning and fustian-cutting are carried on. The living is a rectory of two medieties in the diocese of Chester. Value of the first med., &#163;349;* of the second med., &#163;249. * Patron of the first, E. Leigh, Esq.; of the second, R. E. E. Warburton, Esq. The old church dated from about 1322; and, except the W window and the lower part of the tower, was taken down in 1850. The new church was built in 1851; is in the early decorated style; comprises nave, aisles, transepts, and chancel, with a tower; has a fine E window, put up in 1865 in memory of the late rector, the Rev. W. M&apos;Iver; and includes, in the N aisle, a private chapel in lieu of one in the old church. Two chapels of ease are in Oughtrington and Broomedge. An Independent chapel was built, in 1863, at a cost of about &#163;3,200. There are also chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, an endowed grammar school, parochial schools, a mixed school, an infant school, and charities &#163;95.&#151;The sub-district contains also Warburton parish, and parts of three other parishes. Acres, 18,170. Pop., 7,395. Houses, 1,398. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.ukbmd.org.uk/genuki/chs/lymm.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lymm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643309</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10045381</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LYMM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10090453</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LYMM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154870</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>LYMM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173814</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>LYMM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541979</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LYMM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
