<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1528</id>
<name>WEAVERHAM</name>
<container>CHESHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2504743264849</lat>
<lon>-2.57730451031969</lon>
<gazetteerText>WEAVERHAM, a village, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Northwich district, Cheshire. The village stands near the river Weaver, 1 mile E by S of Acton r. station, and 3&#188; W by N of Northwich; and has a post-office&#8225; under Northwich, and fairs on 8 April and 8 Oct.-The township includes a small part of Whitegate parish, contains Milton hamlet, and comprises 3,528 acres. Real property, &#163;8,774. Pop., 1,530. Houses, 337.&#151;The parish includes 5 other township; and, with the Whitegate part of W. township, comprises 7,634 acres. Pop., 2,782. Houses, 596. The property is subdivided. Four manors belong to A. H. S. Barry, Esq.; and Acton manor, with Gorstage Hall, belongs to R. Ashton, Esq. Sandway Bank is the seat of J. B. Littledale, Esq. Bricks and tiles are made. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;340.* Patron, the Bishop ofThe church was restored in 1855. There are five Methodist chapels, an endowed grammar-school with &#163;55 a year, a national school, and charities &#163;60. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634623</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10010445</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WEAVERHAM CUM MILTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10117641</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEAVERHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542169</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEAVERHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3019</id>
   <name>COGSHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3248</id>
   <name>LITTLE LEIGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3535</id>
   <name>BARTINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3559</id>
   <name>BARNTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3597</id>
   <name>CUDDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5011</id>
   <name>HARTFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5573</id>
   <name>ACTON BRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17288</id>
   <name>VALE ROYAL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
