<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4576</id>
<name>TARVIN</name>
<container>CHESHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1928828477825</lat>
<lon>-2.74373722332936</lon>
<gazetteerText>TARVIN, a village, a township, and a parish, in Great Boughton district, Cheshire. The village stands 3 miles NE of Waverton r. station, and 5&#189; E of Chester; was once a market-town; and has a post-office&#8225; under Chester, and fairs on 20 Apriland 2 Dec.-The township includes Oscroft hamlet, and comprises 2,007 acres. Real property, &#163;5,886. Pop., 1,074. Houses, 244. The manor belongs to Mrs. Milburn.&#151;The parish contains also ten other townships, and comprises 10,571 acres. Pop. in 1851, 3,511; in 1861, 3,319. Houses, 680. The living is a vicarage, with the chapelries of Duddon and Kelsall, in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;600.* Patron, the Bishop ofThe church is chiefly later English, and has a fine tower. The p. curacy of Ashton-Hayes and the donative of Hargrave are separate benefices. Three dissenting chapels, an endowed grammar-school, and a national school are in T. township; and various places of worship and public schools are in the other townships. Charities, &#163;276. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.ukbmd.org.uk/genuki/chs/tarvin.html</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/GreatBoughton</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tarvin</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636190</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075397</id>
   <status>PLU</status>
   <name>TARVIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154649</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>TARVIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10157845</id>
   <status>AP/CP/Tn</status>
   <name>TARVIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10177285</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TARVIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10214786</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>TARVIN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3692</id>
   <name>PRIORS HEYS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2511</id>
   <name>CLOTTON HOOFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3583</id>
   <name>BURTON BY TARVIN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3712</id>
   <name>FOULK STAPLEFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3599</id>
   <name>DUDDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6163</id>
   <name>BRUEN STAPLEFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5418</id>
   <name>HOCKENHULL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3622</id>
   <name>IDDINSHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
