<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>666</id>
<name>TARPORLEY</name>
<container>CHESHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1678885861868</lat>
<lon>-2.64783267253986</lon>
<gazetteerText>TARPORLEY, a small town, a township, and a parish, in Nantwich district, Cheshire. The town stands 2 miles N of Beeston r. station, and 10 ESE of Chester; dates from considerably ancient times; is a polling place, and the headquarters of the Cheshire Hunt; consists chiefly of one winding-street, about &#189; a mile long; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a hotel, a market-hall conjoined with the hotel, a good public hall, a police station, an ancient church restored in 1868, a Wesleyan chapel built in 1867, Baptist and Primitive Methodists chapels, a literary and scientific institution, an endowed national school with &#163;20 a year, charities &#163;77, a weekly market on Thursday, and three annual fairs.-The township comprises 1,144 acres. Real property, &#163;4,904. Pop., 1,212. Houses, 255.&#151;The parish includes three other townships, and comprises 6,057 acres. Pop., 2,577. Houses. 529. Portal Lodge, Salters-Well house , and Arderne Hall are chief residences. Beeston Rock is surmounted by ruins of an ancient stronghold. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;704.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Chester, Lord Binning, Sir P. Egerton, Bart., and the Hon. Miss Arden. Two dissenting chapels, two national schools, and a charity school are in the parts beyond T. township. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.ukbmd.org.uk/genuki/chs/tarporley.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tarporley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636209</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10010032</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TARPORLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10063000</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>TARPORLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109668</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>TARPORLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10117150</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TARPORLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10172792</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>TARPORLEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5993</id>
   <name>RUSHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
