<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6630</id>
<name>LLANSTEFFAN</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7810860908194</lat>
<lon>-4.40241536003352</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANSTEPHAN, a village and a parish in the district and county of Carmarthen. The village stands at the mouth of the river Towy, opposite Ferryside village and r. station, and 8 miles SSW of Carmarthen; is embossomed in trees, at the water&apos;s edge; and has a post office&#8225; under Carmarthen. The parish contains also the villages of Llanybree and Laques. Acres, 6,710; of which 1,690 are water. Real property, &#163;5,875; of which &#163;100 are in quarries. Pop., 1,229. Houses, 277. The property is divided among a few. Llanstephan Pl&#226;s is the seat of Sir James Hamilton, Bart. Llanstephan Castle stands conspicuously on a bold headland, at the mouth of the Towy; is supposed to occupy the site of either an ancient British or Roman fortalice; was built, in 1138, by the sons of a Merioneth prince; went soon into the possession of the Flemings and the Normans; was taken, in 1145, by Rhys ap Gruffyd; resisted a siege while in his possession; was taken and dismantled, in 1254, by Llewelyn ap Gruffyd; consists now of considerably extensive ruined walls; and forms a picturesque object, as seen from the opposite side of the river. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Llangunnock, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;101. Patrons, Messrs. Morris and W. Lloyd, Esq. The church is dedicated to St. Stephen, and is good. The vicarage of Llanybree is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Independents and Calvinistic Methodists. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llansteffan</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643942</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Llanstephan/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10237490</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANSTEFFAN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6460</id>
   <name>LLANGYNOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10950</id>
   <name>LLANDILO ABERCOWIN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
