<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8414</id>
<name>PEN BRE</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7057713925378</lat>
<lon>-4.30564729524175</lon>
<gazetteerText>PEMBREY, a sea-port town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Llanelly district, Carmarthen. The town stands on the river Burry, the Kidwelly canal, and the South Wales railway, at the foot of Pembrey hill or Mynydd-Pembre, 5&#189; miles W by N of Llanelly; is called also Burry-Port; has a r. station with telegraph of the name of Pembrey, and a post-office&#8225; under Llanelly, of the name of Burry-Port; and carries on considerable shipments of coal, brought from the Gwendraeth valley, by way of Kidwelly and the Kidwelly canal. Its harbouris inside the Cefn-Sidan sand; was constructed in 1819; has a pier 1, 200 feet long, with at least 12 feet of water; and has also a lighthouse, showing a fixed light 35 feet high. Another harbour, called the New or Burry harbour, was constructed in 1 825. Extensive copper worksare adjacent. Pembrey hill commands remarkably fineviews over the circumjacent bays and waters to theheights of Somerset. The parish comprises 14, 705 acres of land, and 12,030 of water. Rated property, &#163;9, 564. Pop. in 1851, 3, 310; in 1861, 4, 145. Houses, 822. The property is not much divided. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Llandwry, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;69.* Patron, the Earl of Ashburnham. The church is good; and contains a monument to the Empress Josephine&apos;s niece, who was wreckedhere in a French ship in 1828. A Wesleyan chapel, in the pointed style, was built in 1867.&#151;The sub-district contains also the parish of Kidwelly, and comprises 31, 905 acres. Pop., 5, 797. Houses, 1, 208. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Pembrey/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pembrey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640506</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10289130</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>PEN BRE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552588</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PEMBREY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
