<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3592</id>
<name>ABERGWILI</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8900578387126</lat>
<lon>-4.24738642634668</lon>
<gazetteerText>ABERGWILLY, a village and a parish in the district and county of Carmarthen. The village stands at the confluence of the Gwilly with the Towy, and on the Llandilo and Carmarthen railway, 1&#189; mile NE of Carmarthen. It has a station on the railway, and a post office under Carmarthen. Fairs are held on 4 May, 23 June, 2 and 27 Oct. The palace of the Bishop of St. David&apos;s, an edifice in the Tudor style, built in 1830, is adjacent. Merlin&apos;s hill, an eminence on the side of a dell, nearly 1&#189; mile above the village, is said to have been the birthplace and the favourite haunt of the sorcerer Merlin; and a rocky cavity near its summit still bears the name of Merlin&apos;s Chair. A battle was fought in the neighbourhood, in 1020, between Llewelyn-ab-Sytsylt and the adventurer Run.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlets of Cricklas, Glantawy, Hengil, Veney, and Ystyngwilly. Acres, 10,748. Real property, &#163;9,078. Pop., 2,197. Houses, 451. The property is much subdivided. There are slate quarries. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;172.*Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The ancient church was made collegiate in 1287, but was annexed in 1531 to the college at Brecon. The present church is a handsome edifice, in the early English style, with a spire. A sub-parochial church stands at Llanfihangel-Uwchgwilly, and is served by a perpetual curate, on a salary of &#163;75, appointed by the Vicar. There are Independent, Baptist, and Calvinistic-Methodist chapels, and charities &#163;14. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Abergwili/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abergwili</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657808</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10113489</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ABERGWILI</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5393</id>
   <name>LLANEGWAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6458</id>
   <name>LLANGYNNWR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6568</id>
   <name>LLANLLAWDDOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6597</id>
   <name>LLANPUMSAINT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17200</id>
   <name>CARMARTHENSHIRE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
