<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2851</id>
<name>LLANDYBIE</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8099165880359</lat>
<lon>-4.00744506604639</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANDEBIE, or LLANDYBIE, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Llandilo-Fawr district, Carmarthen. The village stands on the river Marlais, adjacent to the Llanelly and Vale of Towey railway, under Mynydd-Du, 5 miles S of Llandilo-Fawr; is a pretty place, contiguous to an escarpment of dolomitic rock forming the N boundary of the Carmarthen coal-field; and has a station on the railway, a post office under Carmarthen, and fairs on Whit-Wednesday and the Wednesday after Christmas. -The parish contains also the hamlets of Derwidd, Pistill, Garn, Ferenfawr, Glyntay, Blayne, Piode, and TyrRosser. Acres, 10,710. Rated property, &#163;5,305. Pop., 2,821. Houses, 591. The property is subdivided. Glynhir is the seat of W. Du Buisson, Esq.; and in the grounds around it is a cascade, of 30 feet in fall. Derwidd House was the seat of the Vaughan and Stepney families; and it contains some furniture of seemingly about the time of Henry VIII. Blainan and Dyffryn also are chief residences. Coal and limestone are worked. The coalmeasures here are very remarkably contorted; and the limestone.at Tair-Carn-Isaf is rolled into view within the E and W lines of the coal-field. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;180. * Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church is dedicated to St. Tybie; has a lofty embattled tower; is in good condition; and contains a monument to Sir Henry Vaughan, who was in the army of Charles I. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Welsh Methodists, and Wesleyans.&#151;The sub-district contains also two other parishes and part of another. Acres, 29,481. Pop., 6,344. Houses, 1,3 40. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llandybie</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644115</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Llandybie/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10080599</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANDYBIE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552746</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANDYBIE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12798246</id>
   <status>ExP</status>
   <name>LANDS BELONGING IN EQUAL PROPORTIONS TO LLANDEBIE AND LLANDILOFAWR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4970</id>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL ABERBYTHYCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
