<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4408</id>
<name>LAUGHARNE</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7597391350468</lat>
<lon>-4.48021660583611</lon>
<gazetteerText>LAUGHARNE&#151;pronounced Larne&#151;a small town and a parish in the district and county of Carmarthen. The town stands at the influx of the rivulet Corran to the estnary of the Taf, 5 miles SSE of St. Clears r. station, and 12 SW of Carmarthen; was anciently called Abercorran; was afterwards called Tal Llacharn, then simply Llacharn; has a ruined Norman castle, which gave occasion to its change of name; was incorporated by charter of Sir Guido de Brian, about the year 1300; is governed by a portreeve, aldermen, and other officers; is a seat of petty sessions, a sub-port to Llanelly, and a cheap watering-place; consists chiefly of one long street, well-built and clean; and has a post-office&#8225; under St. Clears, a town-hall, a church, four dissenting chapels, national and infant schools, and charities &#163;94. The castle was built soon after the Norman conquest; was destroyed in 1215, by Llewelyn ap Gorwerth; was rebuilt by Sir Guido de Brian; was taken, in 1644, by General Laugharne; was taken again, in 1645, after three weeks&apos; siege, by Cromwell; was then dismantled; presents now a massive appearance, quadrangular and ivy-clad, with round towers at the corners; and is now enclosed, a modern residence having been built on part of the ground. The church is early English and cruciform; and contains monuments of the Laugharnes, and one of Judge Powell. A weekly market is held on Friday; fairs are held on 6 May and 28 Sept.; and a small coasting trade is carried on. Ruins of Roche castle, respecting which history says nothing, are about a mile distant. Dean Tucker of Gloucester, who died in 1799, was a native. Pop. in 1851,1,481; in 1861,1,394. Houses, 322.&#151;The parish comprises 8,883 acres of land, and 5,820 of water. Real property, &#163;10,195. Pop. in 1851,2,011; in 1861,1,868. Houses, 424. The living is a vicarage, united with the rectory of Llansadwrnen, in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;414.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Winton. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Laugharne/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laugharne,_Wales</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644816</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018730</id>
   <status>Ldsp</status>
   <name>TALACHARN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10149563</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LAUGHARNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10382233</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>LAUGHARNE TOWNSHIP</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10956</id>
   <name>LLANSADURNEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
