<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6613</id>
<name>LLANSADWRN</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9702365662626</lat>
<lon>-3.91749342845777</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANSADWRN, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Llandovery district, Carmarthen. The village stands on a branch of the river Towy, 2&#189; miles N by W of Llangadock r. station, and 5&#189; SW of Llandovery; is a considerable place; and has fairs on 13 Aug. and 29 Oct. The parish comprises 7,064 acres; and its posttown is Llangadock, under Carmarthen. Real property, &#163;5,074. Pop., 1,099. Houses, 239. The property is subdivided. Abermarlias is the seat of Lady L. Foley, and occupies the site of the seat of Rhys ab Thomas. The land is hilly. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Llanwrda, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;165.* Patron, Lady L. Foley. The church is good. There are an alms house for four maiden gentlewomen, and a free school, both of them founded and endowed, in 1731, by Lady L. Cornwallis; and these and other charities have &#163;319 a year.&#151;The sub-district contains also the parish of Llanwrda. Acres, 11,505. Pop., 1,710. Houses, 358. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Llansadwrn/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643955</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10237051</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANSADWRN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552680</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANSADWRN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>10956</id>
<name>LLANSADURNEN</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7574166242577</lat>
<lon>-4.49763476447224</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANSADWRNEN, a parish in the district and county of Carmarthen; on Carmarthen bay, 1&#189; mile SW of Laugharne, and 5 S by E of St. Clears r. station. Post town, Laugharne, under St. Clears. Acres, 1,644; of which 150 are water. Real property, &#163;1.265. Pop., 194. Houses, 35. The property is divided among a few. Limestone is worked. The living is a rectory, annexed to the vicarage of Laugharne, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. The church was rebuilt in 1861; is in the decorated English style; and consists of nave and chancel, with vestry and tower. Judge Powell, who tried the seven bishops, resided at Broadway, now a ruin. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Llansadwrnen/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643956</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10237075</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LLANSADYRNIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10382415</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANSADURNEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
