<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6385</id>
<name>LLANGELER</name>
<container>CARMARTHENSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0091468120336</lat>
<lon>-4.36114347711705</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANGELER, a village and a parish in the district of Newcastle-in-Eimlyn, and county of Carmarthen. The village stands on the river Teifi, at the boundary with Cardigan, near the Newcastle-Emlyn and Lampeter railway, and under the Penboyr hills, 5 miles E by S of Newcastle-Emlyn; and has a post office under Carmarthen. The. parish is cut into two sections, lower and upper; and comprises 7,999 acres. Real property, &#163;5,128. Pop. in 1851,1,681; in 1861,1,573. Houses, 366. The property is subdivided. Llys Newydd belonged formerly to the Lloyds, and is now the seat of W. Lewis, Esq. Dolhaidd-fach is the seat of Captain Elliot. The living is twofold, a vicarage and a sinecure rectory, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value of the vicarage, &#163;136;* of the rectory, &#163;244. Patron of the former, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s; of the latter, St. David&apos;s College. The church is dedicated to St. Celert; was rebuilt in 1860; is in the early English style; and consists of nave and chancel, with vestry and bell-turret. A spring, called St. Celert&apos;s well, is near the church. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/CMN/Llangeler/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644034</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10226077</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANGELER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1120</id>
   <name>NEWCASTLE EMLYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2852</id>
   <name>LLANDYFRIOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3518</id>
   <name>CENARTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3902</id>
   <name>CYNWYL ELFED</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4469</id>
   <name>LLANFAIRORLLWYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4541</id>
   <name>BRYN GWYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4643</id>
   <name>CILRHEDYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5025</id>
   <name>BETWS IFAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11000</id>
   <name>PENBOYR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11237</id>
   <name>HENLLAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
