<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3413</id>
<name>MEVAGISSEY</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.2781083683437</lat>
<lon>-4.7946396830969</lon>
<gazetteerText>MEVAGISSEY, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in St. Austell district, Cornwall. The village stands on a beautiful bay of its own name, 5&#189; miles S of St. Austell r. station; took its name from two saints, St. Mevan and St. Issey; is a sub-port to Fowey, with a pier and a capacious harbour; conducts so extensiVe a in one year in its bay,-though the quantity of late has very greatly declined; carries on also an import trade in coal, timber, salt, and other things; has long had a bad name for dirt and fishy malodour; was so fearfully scourged by cholera in 1849 that its inhabitants moved into tents till it was cleansed; and has a post office&#8225; under St. Austell, a good inn, a coast-guard station, a market on Saturdays, and a fair on St. Peter&apos;s day. The parish contains also the hamlets of Penwarne, Tregiskey, and Trelaven. Acres, 1,344. Real property, &#163;4,829. Pop. in 1851,2,022; in 1861,1,914. Houses, 450. Penwarne and Pentuan belong to the Tremaynes; Tregiskey and Trelaven belonged formerly to the Grenvilles, but belong now also to the Tremaynes; and Porthhilly belongs to the Hoblyns. The surface is hilly. The bay measures 3 miles across the entrance, and 1&#188; mile thence to the head; is bounded on the N by Black Head, 153 feet high,-on the S by Chapel Point, commanding a fine view of the coast eastward to the entrance of Plymouth sound; and has a depth of 18 feet within the village-pier at high water of spring tides. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;200.* Patrons, the Representatives of J. Benbow, Esq. The church is ancient, and has lost its tower. There are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, and a national school.&#151;The sub-district contains also three other parishes. Acres, 12,874. Pop., 4,575. Houses, 1,003. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mevagissey</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Mevagissey/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642687</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10090726</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MEVAGISSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10101621</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MEVAGISSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542819</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MEVAGISSEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1623</id>
   <name>GORRAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6118</id>
   <name>ST MICHAEL CARHAYS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14544</id>
   <name>ST EWE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
