<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3865</id>
<name>LUXULYAN</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.4011979304559</lat>
<lon>-4.75665919300531</lon>
<gazetteerText>LUXULION, or LUXULYAN, a village and a parish in Bodmin district, Cornwall. The village stands 4 miles WSW of Lostwithiel r. station, and 6 S by W of Bo dmin; and has a post office under Bodmin, and fairs on 2 July and 7 Oct. The parish comprises 5,354 acres. Real property, &#163;3,945; of which &#163;47 are in mines. Pop. in 1851,1,439; in 1861,1,329. Houses, 275. The decrease of pop. arose partly from decline in the working of granite and stream-tin. The property is divided among a few. Prideaux is the seat of SirRashleigh, Bart.; occupies the site of a castle, said to have been built before the Norman conquest; and is itself an ancient quadrangular edifice, with stairs of granite. Prideaux Warren, on a height adjoining the mansion, is the vestige of an ancient earthwork. Granite quarries have long been worked; and a branch railway goes from them to a line of mineral railway, running to the coast. The granite is of a very beautiful kind; furnished the material for the lighthouse and beacon on Plymouth breakwater; and furnished also the block of 70 tons out of which the sarcophagus of the Duke of Wellington was formed. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;230. * Patron, SirRashleigh, Bart. The church is ancient but good; has a tower; and was the depository of the stannary records during the civil war. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Bible Christians, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luxulyan</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Luxulyan/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643333</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10121760</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LUXULYAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160200</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LUXULYAN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
