<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2817</id>
<name>ST GLUVIAS</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1837984937392</lat>
<lon>-5.12395487329478</lon>
<gazetteerText>GLUVIAS (St.), a village and a parish in Falmouth district, Cornwall. The village stands near the upper end of a branch of Falmouth harbour, &#188; mile E by N of Penryn town and railway station; appears to have had an endowed church before the Conquest; and figures in Domesday book; but is now of small importance. The parish includes also the town of Penryn, which has a head post office. Acres, 2, 899; of which 290 are water. Real property, &#163;12, 193. Pop., 4, 760. Houses, 941. The property is much subdivided. The rocks include granite and felspar, and yield oxide of iron. Enys has belonged to the family of Enys since the time of Edward I.; and is famed, in old writings, for its fine gardens. Bohelland or Bailland barn, about &#189; a mile N of the church, was the scene of the murder which formed the plot of Lillo&apos;s play, called &quot;the Penryn Tragedy, &quot; a title changed by Coleman into &quot;Fatal Curiosity. &quot; Bostrow was the seat of the Pendarves family. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Budock, in the diocese of Exeter. Value, not reported. Patron, the Bishop of Exeter. The church is large and handsome; and contains monuments of the Pendarves family. The vicarage of Penwerris is a separate benefice. A collegiate church anciently stood at Glaseney, in Budock, but has disappeared. There are a Weslevan chapel, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StGluvias/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Gluvias</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10079664</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ST GLUVIAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10179919</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST GLUVIAS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
