<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3856</id>
<name>NORTH HILL</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.5643015155691</lat>
<lon>-4.44781446280215</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTHILL, or North Hill, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Launceston district, Cornwall. The village stands near the river Lynher, 7&#189; miles S W by S of Launceston r. station; and has a post-office under Launceston, and fairs on the last Monday of April, 8 Sept., and the first Thursday of Nov The parish contains also the hamlets of Bathpool, Coads-Green, Congdon-Shop, Illand, and Trebartha; and extends northward to the river Inny. Acres, 6, 732. Real property, &#163;7, 350. Pop. in 1851, 1, 193; in 1861, 1, 263. Houses, 254 &quot; The property is subdivided. Trebartha Hall is a chief residence; belonged once to the Spoures and the Trebarthas; and belongs now to F. Rodd, Esq. King Arthur&apos;s Bedis a rock-basin on Trewortha tor. Good building-stoneabounds; granite is extensively worked and exported; some stream-tin works have been opened; and manganese has been found. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;538.* Patron, F. Rodd, Esq. The church is an ancient and good granite structure; has agroined porch, and a lofty pinnacled tower; and containstwo monuments to the Vincents and the Spoures. Chapels of ease were formerly at Trebartha and Landreyne. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Bryanites, a national school, and charities &#163;5.&#151;The sub-district contains alsothree other parishes. Acres, 25,088. Pop., 5, 508. Houses, 1, 114. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/NorthHill/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641337</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10121425</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>NORTH HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160054</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTH HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542777</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NORTH HILL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2217</id>
   <name>LEWANNICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
