<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1067</id>
<name>LOSTWITHIEL</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.4107211801896</lat>
<lon>-4.67449753344256</lon>
<gazetteerText>LOSTWITHIEL, a town and a parish in Bodmin district, Cornwall. The town stands in a deep valley, on the river Fowey, and on the Cornwall railway, 5 miles SSE of Bodmin; was originally called Lestwithiel, signifying the &quot;lofty palace;&apos;&apos; was founded, together with &quot;a palace &apos;&apos;or stannary court at it, by Richard, Earl of Cornwall; sent two members to parliament from the time of Edward II., till disfranchised by the act of 1832; was visited by Charles I. in 1644, prior to the flight of Essex to Fowey, and by the Prince of Wales in 1864; is governed, under a charter of George II., by a mayor, six aldermen, and seventeen councillors; was long the seat of the county courts of Cornwall; retains a monument of its former importance in the stannary court or county buildings; and has a head-post office, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, a banking office, a good inn, a picturesque old bridge, a town hall, a market-house, a church, three dissenting chapels, a mechanics&apos; institute, a free grammar school, a girls&apos; national school, and charities &#163;19. The stannary court is in good preservation; was an oblong massive structure, flanked by graduated buttresses, and ornamented with the duchy arms; is built chiefly of local slate, without ashlar; has semicircular arches, constructed of thin slate lamin&#230;; and includes portions which were used as the shire-hall and the prison. The town hall is a neat edifice of 1740. The church is chiefly of the 14th century; has an early English tower, with a decorated octagonal lantern and spire; has also a fine E window; and contains a curious octagonal sculptured font, and several old monuments. A weekly market is held on Friday; fairs are held on 31 March, 10 July, 4 Sept., and 13 Nov.; a cattle show is held on 12 Dec.; some business is done in tanning and wool stapling; and trade is carried on in connexion with neighbouring mines.&#151;The parish comprises 110 acres. Real property, &#163;2,038; of which &#163;25 are on the railway. Pop., 1,017. Houses, 229. The manor belonged to the Duchy of Cornwall; was purchased, about the end of last century, by the Earl of Mount Edgecumbe; and was conveyed to the corporation. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;96. Patron, the Earl of Mount Edgecumbe. A House of Mercy, about &#189; a mile from the town, was founded in 1862. The fine ruin of Restormel Castle crowns an eminence about 1 mile to the N. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lostwithiel</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Lostwithiel/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643583</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10013902</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LOSTWITHIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10028474</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>LOSTWITHIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10041727</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>LOSTWITHIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10048862</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LOSTWITHIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10220658</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>LOSTWITHIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758819</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>LOSTWITHIEL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1614</id>
   <name>DULOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1628</id>
   <name>LANREATH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2602</id>
   <name>LANLIVERY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3463</id>
   <name>ST WINNOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3837</id>
   <name>BOCONNOC</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3839</id>
   <name>BROADOAK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5112</id>
   <name>ST PINNOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
