<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2609</id>
<name>ST ENDELLION</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.5825108756945</lat>
<lon>-4.83020876095035</lon>
<gazetteerText>ENDELLION, or St. Endellion, a parish in Bodmin district, Cornwall; on the coast, 4z miles N by E of Wadebridge, and 13 NW of Bodmin Road r. station. It contains Port Quin; and its post town is Wadebridge, Cornwall. Acres, 3, 729. Real property, &#163;5, 059. Pop., 1, 192. Houses, 281. The property is subdivided. Roscarrock House, formerly the seat of the ancient family of Roscarrock, stands on a hill, is now a ruin, was castellated and loop-1xoled, had a massive granite archway entrance, and retains much of a formidable aspect. Slaty quartz, mandelstone, copper ore, lead ox e, manganese, and antimony are found; an export trade in slates and pilchards is carried on; and a fair is held on 12 Sept. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter; and there are attached three prebends, -Bodmin or Kings, Trehaverock, and Mornays. Value of the rectory, &#163;196;* of Bodmin prebend, &#163;63; of Trehaverock, &#163;115; of Mornays, not reported. Patron of the rectory, the Lord Chancellor; of Bodmin prebend, Mr. Basset; of Trehaverock, not reported; of Mornays, the Hon. A. M. Agar. The church stands on a hill; dates from the time of Henry VI.; has a lofty tower; and is weather-stained, but good. There are chapels for Wesleyans, U. Free Methodists, and Bible Christians. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StEndellion/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10067911</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST ENDELLION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10122200</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST ENDELLION</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
