<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5107</id>
<name>ST BURYAN</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.0722729398605</lat>
<lon>-5.6178257694001</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURYAN (St.), a parish and a subdistrict in Penzance district, Cornwall. The parish lies 4&#190; miles E by N of Lands-End, and 4&#190; SW of Penzance r. station; and has a post office under Penzance. Acres, 6,964. Real property, &#163;8,359. Pop., 1,428. Houses, 290. The property is divided among a few. The surface consists largely of black granite hills. A small town, of ancient note, was here; but is now represented by only a few cottages. An oratory was founded at it, at an early period, by St. Buriena, a holy woman from Ireland. A secular college also was founded here in 909, by Athelstane; changed afterwards into an exempt deanery; and destroyed, in the time of the Commonwealth, by Shrubshall, governor of Pendennis Castle. A number of Druidical remains, including the Merry Maidens, the Boscawen-Un, and the Rosmodrevy circles, occur among the hills. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter; and till 1864 was united with Levan and Sennen. Value, &#163;570.* Patron, the Crown. The church stands on a wild open eminence, 415 feet high; has a lofty tower, commanding a view to the Scilly Islands; is an ancient edifice, greatly altered by modern renovations; and contains a fine carved screen, and a curious coffinshaped monument with a Norman-French inscription. An ancient chapel, called the Sanctuary, stands about a mile to the SE. Attorney-general Noy, of the time of Charles I., was a native. The subdistrict contains three parishes. Acres, 11,592. Pop. 2,488. Houses, 502. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Buryan</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StBuryan/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10014268</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST BURYAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10179701</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ST BURYAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542649</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ST BURYAN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1762</id>
   <name>SENNEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5882</id>
   <name>ST LEVAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
