<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6036</id>
<name>GWINEAR</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1857638947521</lat>
<lon>-5.35024130814654</lon>
<gazetteerText>GWINEAR, a village and a parish in Redruth district, Cornwall. The village stands near the Cornwall railway, 2&#189; miles ENE of Hayle; and has a station, of the name of Gwinear Road, on the railway, and a post office under Hayle. The parish includes also the hamlets of Cathebedron, Drannock, Fraddam, Tregortha, Camhell Green, Revala, Relistian, and Wall. Acres, 4, 611. Real property, &#163;9, 660; of which &#163;3, 540 are in mines, &#163;5 in quarries, and &#163;407 in railways. Pop. in 1851, 2, 635; in 1861, 2, 880. Houses, 551. The property is much subdivided. Two old seats, now farm houses, Rosewarne and Lanyon, are near the village; the former once the property of the Arundels of Lauherne, -the latter the seat of the Lanyons, one of whom was Capt. Lanyon, who accompanied Cook in his voyages round the world. The rocks include slate, much copper ore, and some silver. The coppermines of Herland, Wheal Carpenter, Wheal Alfred, and Wheal Relistian are within the limits, but are no longer worked. Many coins of the later Roman emperors have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;287.* Patron, the Bishop of Exeter. The church has a north aisle built by the Arundels, and containing a marble monument to one of their family; and is good. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a nation al school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gwinear</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Gwinear/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647728</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10121395</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GWINEAR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10214026</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>GWINEAR GWITHIAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10215717</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GWINEAR</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
