<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5688</id>
<name>WENDRON</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1406643339936</lat>
<lon>-5.23392041553481</lon>
<gazetteerText>WENDRON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Helston district, Cornwall. The village stands 2&#190; miles NNE of Helston, and 7&#189; SSE of Camborne r. station; and has fairs on 18 May and 27 July. The parish includes Helston, which has a head post-office, designated Helston, Cornwall. Acres, exclusive of Helston, 13,029; inclusive of H., 13,320. Real property, exc. of H., &#163;17,133,-of which &#163;4,282 are in mines; inc. of H., &#163;27,818,-of which &#163;10 are in iron-works, and &#163;60 in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, exc. of H., 5,320,-inc. of H., 8,675; in 1861, exc. of H., 6,008,-inc. of H., 9,851. Houses, exc. of H., 1,165; inc. of H., 1,917. The increase of pop., in the rural parts, arose from the working of a tin mine. Druidical circles are at Carnmenellis and the Nine Maidens. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;876.* Patron, Queen&apos;s College, Oxford. The vicarage of Helston and the p. curacy of Carnmenellis are separate benefices. There are several dissenting chapels, and charities &#163;8.&#151;The sub-district excludes Helston, but includes Sithney parish, and comprises 18,927 acres. Pop., 9,314. Houses, 1,822. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Wendron/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wendron</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634537</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10014554</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WENDRON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10203612</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WENDRON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542480</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WENDRON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
