<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3860</id>
<name>LANIVET</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.4488437183574</lat>
<lon>-4.76365090386119</lon>
<gazetteerText>LANIVET, a village and a parish in Bodmin district, Cornwall. The village stands 2&#190; miles SW by S of Bodmin, and 4 W of Bodmin Road r. station; and has a post-office under Bodmin, and a fair on 16 June. The parish contains also the hamlets of Bodwanick, Lamorick, Tremore, and St. Lawrence. Acres, 5,396. Real property, &#163;5,593; of which &#163;200 are in mines. Pop., 1,151. Houses, 234. The property is divided chiefly among eight. St. Benet&apos;s is a chief residence; and has been formed by restoring and modernizing parts of an ancient monastery. The monastery is supposed to have been a cell of Monte Casino abbey, near Naples; the cloisters have been taken down; the main buildings are incorporated with the present mansion; and both these and a ruined tower are apparently of later English character. The adjacent tract is a richly wooded vale, amid a bleak country. There are a few tin-streams, and some recently developed tin-lodes. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;667.* Patron, H. Borrow, Esq. The church is ancient; has a tower; and stands embosomed in trees. The churchyard contains two ancient stone crosses, 10 and 11 feet high. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Bible Christians, a school, and charities &#163;151, accruing from the monastery lands. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lanivet</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644889</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Lanivet/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10048758</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LANIVET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10121528</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LANIVET</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
