<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5106</id>
<name>ST AGNES</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.2961262042388</lat>
<lon>-5.19836139308927</lon>
<gazetteerText>AGNES (St.), a town, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Truro, Cornwall. The town is a seaport, on a small bay of Bristol Channel; 4 miles N of Chacewater r. station, and 9 NW by W of Truro. It has a post office&#8225; under Scorrier; and is the centre of a rich mining district. A weekly market is held on Thursday; and an annual fair on 1 May. The harbour is small and can be entered only near high water, and only by vessels of not more than 100 tons&apos; burden. Coal, lime, and slate are imported. Most of the inhabitants are con nected with neighbouring mines.&#151;The parish comprises 8,294 acres of land, and 60 of water. Real property, &#163;10,324,-of which &#163;2,514 are in mines. Pop., 6,550. Houses, 1,395. The property is much subdivided. Granite is the prevailing rock; and copper, tin, and iron are worked. The scenery of coast and surface is picturesque. St. Agnes&apos; Beacon, 621 feet high, immediately NW of the town, shows remarkable deposits of sand and clays at heights of from 300 to 400 feet; and was a beacon station during the French war, and a chief station of the Trigonometrical survey. Harmony Cot, 2 miles from the town, on the road to Perran Porth, was the birthplace of the painter Opie. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;280.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Exeter. The church was built in 1482, has been restored, and shows interesting features. Chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, are in the parish. Ruins of ancient chapels are at Mawla and St. Agnes&apos; Well.-The subdistrict comprises two parishes. Acres, 19,694. Pop., 9,509. Houses, 1,998. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Agnes,_Cornwall</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Agnes,_Isles_of_Scilly</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StAgnes/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10122119</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST AGNES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10179683</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>ST AGNES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542390</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ST AGNES</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4652</id>
<name>ST AGNES</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>49.8910680450852</lat>
<lon>-6.3399124057758</lon>
<gazetteerText>AGNES (St.), One of the Scilly Islands, near the southern extremity of the group, separated on the NE from St. Mary&apos;s by St. Mary&apos;s Sound. It consists of two parts, St. Agnes-proper and the Gugh, divided from each other by high water of spring tides. The former measures about 1 mile by &#189;; the latter, about &#190; of a mile by &#188;. Much of the land is fertile and well cultivated. St. Agnes-proper displays some interesting features, contains a church, and is crowned by a light house, 72 feet high, having a revolving light, with one minute flash. The Gugh has a curious rock pillar 9 feet long, and several stonecovered barrows. Pop., 200. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10160390</id>
   <status>IslParPart/CP</status>
   <name>ST AGNES</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
