<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1097</id>
<name>PHILLACK</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1948380505428</lat>
<lon>-5.41215206216954</lon>
<gazetteerText>PHILLACK, a parish and a sub-district in Redruth district, Cornwall. The parish lies on St. Ives bay, the river Hayle, and the West Cornwall railway, around Hayle r. station, and 4 miles S E by E of St. Ives. It contains the hamlets of Angarrack, Guilford, Logans, and Venton-League; it contains also part of the sea-port village of Hayle, which has a head post-office; and it hasfairs on 20 June and 4 Aug. Acres, 3, 237; of which 330 are water. Real property, &#163;24, 283; of which &#163;21,055are in mines, &#163;160 in iron-works, and &#163;400 in railway s. Pop. in 1851, 4, 800; in 1861, 5, 381. Houses, 1,022. The property is subdivided. Penpol, Bodriggy, and Riviere are chief residences. Drifting sand has largelyencroached on the land from the shore, and formsmenacing towns. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Gwithian, in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;540.* Patron, the Rev. F. Hockin. The church, excepting the tower, was rebuilt in 1856. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a national school. Gwithianchurch, except the tower, was rebuilt in 1866.&#151;The sub-district contains also Gwithian and Gwinear parishes. Acres, 10, 481. Pop., 9,035. Houses, 1, 741. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phillack</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Phillack/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640321</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10014165</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PHILLACK WITH GWITHIAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10049015</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>EAST PHILLACK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10075002</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>PHILLACK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10122053</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PHILLACK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10206650</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WEST PHILLACK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221304</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>PHILLACK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542546</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PHILLACK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
