<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1622</id>
<name>FORRABURY</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.6851784532456</lat>
<lon>-4.69521889505665</lon>
<gazetteerText>FORRABURY, or Fotherbury, a parish in Camelford district, Cornwall; on the coast, 5 miles NNW of Camelford, and 17&#189; N of Bodmin-Road r. station. It includes part of the town of Boscastle, which has a post office under Camelford. Acres, 508. Real property, with Minster, &#163;4, 123. Rated property of F. alone, &#163;1, 233. Pop., 366. Houses, 83. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to J. R. Avery, Esq. Slaty anthracite, dark shale, and manganese occur. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;70.* Patron, J. R. Avery, Esq. The church stands above Boscastle, adjacent to the lofty headland of Willabark; is dedicated to St. Simphorian, who is traditionally said to have been buried in it; has a tower, without a bell; and is in good condition. An ancient granite cross, on a limestone pedestal, is outside the churchyard, and commands a view of the coast. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Forrabury/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649193</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10013550</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FORRABURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10013562</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FORRABURY AND MINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10067492</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>FORRABURY AND MINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10121310</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FORRABURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
