<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>183</id>
<name>ST IVES</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.2008444015234</lat>
<lon>-5.48504636917766</lon>
<gazetteerText>St Ives.-- mun. bor., seaport town, and par. with ry. sta., Cornwall, on St Ives Bay, 8 miles NE. of Penzance, 1890 ac., pop. 6445; P.O.,T.O., 2 Banks. Market-days, Wednesday and Saturday. St Ives (said to take its name from St Iva, an Irish missionary lady of 5th century) has boat building, rope and seine making, &amp;c., but its principal business is the pilchard fishery, which is extensively prosecuted. Many of the inhabitants are employed in the neighbouring mines; and there are exports of copper, tin, and slates. The harbour is provided with a pier and breakwater, and is defended by a battery. St Ives was incorporated in 1639; it returned 2 members to Parliament from the time of John until 1832, and 1 member from 1832 until 1885. St Ives Bay is 44 miles across the entrance, and penetrates 2&#189; miles S.; on E. side of bay, on Godrevy Island, is a lighthouse 86 ft. high, with flashing light (Godrevy) 120 ft. above high water and seen 15 miles. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StIves/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Ives,_Cornwall</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638778</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10026180</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10122582</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10138050</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160649</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10214671</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542613</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741376</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>CORNWALL WESTERN OR ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12753615</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12757554</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828743</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ST IVES</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1646</id>
   <name>TOWEDNACK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
