<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>734</id>
<name>HAYLE</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1809054281905</lat>
<lon>-5.42279666474384</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAYLE, or HEYL, a small seaport in St. Erth and Phillack parishes, Cornwall; on the river Hayle, and the Cornwall railway, 4 miles SE of St. Ives. It is a sub-port to St. Ives; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a railway station with telegraph, and a causeway, across the river, 1,140 feet long. The harbour is below the causeway; has commodious wharfs, and canals with flood-gates; can be entered, at spring tides, by vessels of 200 tons burden; and has two fixed lights, 81 and 59 feet high, put up in 1840. A coasting trade is carried on in the exportation of copper ore and tin, and in the importation of coal, timber, and general merchandise. Steam-vessels ply regularly to Bristol. A railway, for mineral traffic, 17&#188; miles long, goes to Redruth. The smelting of copper was formerly done on a large scale; and there are now steam-engine works, and iron and brass-foundries. There is also a chapel of ease to Phillack. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647258</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10067923</id>
   <status>Tn</status>
   <name>HAYLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10122223</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HAYLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135904</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HAYLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154340</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HAYLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10587347</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAYLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833751</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAYLE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1097</id>
   <name>PHILLACK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
