<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5880</id>
<name>ST COLUMB MAJOR</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.4305089895315</lat>
<lon>-4.93084336033656</lon>
<gazetteerText>COLUMB-MAJOR (St.), a small town and a parish in St. Columb district, Cornwall. The town stands on an eminence, the reputed site of a Danish fort, on the left side of the river Trent, 9 miles NW of St. Austell r. station, and 14 NNE of Truro. It consists chiefly of one good street; contains some good new Gothic houses; is a seat of petty sessions and a polling-place; and has a head post office, &#8225; of the name of St. Columb, Cornwall, a banking office, two chief inns, a market-house, a parish church, five dissenting chapels, and a workhouse. One of the inns was kept by Polkinhorne, the famous wrestler. The church is chiefly of the 13th century; presents features of much beauty; consists of aisled nave, aisled chancel, and a transept, with pinnacled tower; and has a curious font, and monuments of the Hoblyns, the Vyvyaus, the Bealinges, the Pendarvises, and the Arundels. A college for six priests stood adjacent to the church, and was destroyed by accidental fire in 1701. A weekly market is held on Thursday; and fairs on the Thursday after Mid-Lent Sunday, and after 12 Nov. The parish comprises 12, 697 acres. Real property, &#163;14, 153. Pop., 2, 879. Houses, 587. The property is sub-divided-Granite, felspar, tin, copper, cobalt, and bismuth are found. The ancient camp, called Castle-an-Dinas, is 2 miles SE of the town; and there are several Druidical monuments. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;1, 515.* Patron, the Rev. Dr. Walker. Charities, &#163;50. Bislhop Arundel, who died in 1504, was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/StColumbMajor</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Columb_Major</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StColumbMajor/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10027718</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>ST COLUMB MAJOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10030110</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>ST COLUMB MAJOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160420</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST COLUMB MAJOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10197545</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>ST COLUMB MAJOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10209651</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST COLUMB MAJOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542741</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ST COLUMB</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12830208</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ST COLUMB</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
