<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3193</id>
<name>MARAZION</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1273124775997</lat>
<lon>-5.46422665013257</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARAZION, or MARKET-JEW, a small town, a chapelry, and a sub-district, in Penzance district, Cornwall. The town stands on Mounts bay, under a hill, near the West Cornwall railway, 3&#188; miles E by N of Penzance; was formerly called Marghasjewe and Marghasion; is called, by Leland, Marhasdethon or Forum-Jovis, -and by the editors of the old Mag. Brit., Market-Jupiter, Market-Jew, or Market-Ju; is supposed, by some writers, to have been settled or inhabited by Jews, for collecting and selling tin, and to have been named by them MaraZion, signifying &quot;Bitter-Zion;&apos;&apos; appears to have been once a place of considerable consequence, both as a seat of trade, and as the head-quarters of pilgrims to St. Michael&apos;s Mount; was pillaged by the French in the time of Henry VIII., and by the Cornish rebels in that of Edward V.; obtained a charter from Queen Elizabeth, vesting its government in a mayor, 8 aldermen, and 12 capital burgesses; lost much of its importance by the suppression of the neighbouring priory, and the growing prosperity of Penzance; was not included in any of the schedules of the new municipal act; is irregularly aligned, and indifferently built; is connected with St. Michael&apos;s Mount by a causeway 1,200 feet long, but above water during only 4 hours of every 12 of the tide; carries on rope-making, a large pilchard fishery, an import trade in coal, iron, and timber, and some business in connexion with neighbouring mines; and has a head post office&#8225; of the name of Marazion, Cornwall, a railway station, of the name of Marazion-Road, three inns, a church, four dissenting chapels, a public school, and charities &#163;10. The church stands at some distance, and was recently rebuilt. The chapels are for Independents, Quakers, Wesleyans, and United Free Methodists. A weekly market is held on Saturday; and fairs, chiefly for cattle, are held on 20 March and 20 Sept.-The chapelryincludes the town, and is in the parish of St. Hilary. Acres, 871; of which 190 are water. Real property, &#163;4,260. Pop. in 1851,1,379; in 1861,1,545. Houses, 312. A large tract of marsh was reclaimed by Dr. Moyle. The land is notable for producing a superior variety of turnip. Asbestos, actinolite, iron-ore, and other rare and useful minerals are found. About 1,000 Roman coins were discovered at the reclaiming of the marsh. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;66. * Patron, the Vicar of St. Hilary.&#151;The sub-district contains also the rest of St. Hilary parish, all Perranuthnoe parish, and St. Michael&apos;s Mount extra-parochial tract. Acres, 4,909. Pop., 5,098. Houses, 1,037. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marazion</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Marazion/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643076</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093703</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>MARAZION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10134468</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>MARAZION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160248</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARAZION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542625</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MARAZION</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1639</id>
   <name>ST HILARY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2905</id>
   <name>ST MICHAELS MOUNT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6059</id>
   <name>PERRANUTHNOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
