<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4653</id>
<name>ST CLEER</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.5059066668253</lat>
<lon>-4.48260495699297</lon>
<gazetteerText>CLEER (St.), a parish in Liskeard district, Cornwall; on the moors, near the Cornwall railway, 2&#189; miles N by W of Liskeard. It has a post office under Liskeard. Acres, 11, 263. Real property, &#163;26, 107; of which &#163;17, 446 are in mines. Pop., 3, 931. Houses, 717. The property is subdivided. Granite, hornblende, felspar, copper ore, lead ore, soapstone, asbestos, and other minerals are found. Copper and lead are extensively mined; and upwards of 1, 000 persons are employed in one of the mines. St. Cleer Down, a stony eminence 753 feet high, and Sharpitor, or Sharp Point Tor, a beautiful cone, about 1, 200 feet high, command extensive views. St. Cleer&apos;s well was anciently used as a ducking pool for insane persons; is enclosed by the ivy-clad ruin of a chapel; and adjoins an ancient cross, about 9 feet high. Two inscribed Saxon monuments, called the Half Stone and the Other Half Stone, are about &#190; of a mile WNW of the church; and were found, by a recent investigation, to surmount a subterranean sepulchral chamber. The Cheesewring, which we have separately noticed, three large Druidical circles, called the Hurlers, and a cromlech, called the Trevethy Stone, or the Grave-house, are within the parish. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;245.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is early English, with a walled-up Norman doorway; and has a tower 97 feet high. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StCleer/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10122168</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST CLEER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160418</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ST CLEER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
