<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4647</id>
<name>GULVAL</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1482485143063</lat>
<lon>-5.54331441831407</lon>
<gazetteerText>GULVAL, a village and a parish in Penzance district, Cornwall. The village stands in a deep, wooded vale, at the northern extremity of Mounts bay, near the CornWall railway, 1&#188; mile NE of Penzance. The parish comprises 4, 357 acres of land, and 190 of water. Post town, Penzance. Real property, &#163;6, 500; of which &#163;220 are in the railway, and &#163;18 in quarries. Pop., 1, 743. Houses, 332. The property is much subdivided. The manor anciently belonged to the Halse family; was given by them to the priory of St. Germain; and bore the name of LanistIey. The rocks are granite and schists; an have yielded much ore in mining operations. A tract which was long a bare moor is nom partly disposed in fields, and partly overgrown with briers and ivy. Gulval Carn, on that tract, commands a fine view of Mounts bay and Penzance. An ancient inscribed stone is at a stream, and was long used there as a foot bridge. A chalybeate spring is near Maddern, and was once the object of a singular superstition. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;449. Patron, the lord Chancellor. The church was built in the 15th century; is in good condition; and contains a register chest and some old monuments. An ancient cross is in the churchyard. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Bible Christians, a national school, and charities &#163;15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gulval</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Gulval/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647768</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10160029</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GULVAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10203521</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GULVAL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3893</id>
   <name>ZENNOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17208</id>
   <name>PENWITH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
