<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3859</id>
<name>LANDEWEDNACK</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>49.9765937504052</lat>
<lon>-5.20725744597001</lon>
<gazetteerText>LANDEWEDNACK, a parish, with a village, in Helston district, Cornwall; on the coast, 11 miles SSE of Helston, and 22 SSW of Falmouth r. station. It includes the Lizard, Kinance Cove, Asparagus Island, the Devil&apos;s Bellows, and Cadgewith village, which are noticed in their own alphabetical places; and it contains the post-office of Lizard, under Helston. Acres, 1,999. Real property, &#163;1,867; of which &#163;50 are in quarries. Pop., 429. Houses, 91. The manor belonged to the Earl of Mortaigne, and passed to the Hawkinses. The coast scenery, the rocks, and the minerals, are highly interesting. Serpentine of remarkable beauty, and susceptible of high polish, is worked; and bricks and tiles are made. The Balk of Landewednack is a remarkable cliff; and the Cove of Landewednack is a place of the pilchard fishery. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;253.* Patron, P. V. Robinson, Esq. The church has a Norman door and a pinnacled tower; contains an ancient inscribed font and several monuments; and is said to have been the place where the last sermon in Cornish was preached. The churchyard contains the remains of a number of persons who died of plague in 1645. An ancient granite cross is between the village and the Lizard. There are chapels for Wesleyans and United Free Methodists, a parochial school, and a life-boat station. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Landewednack/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644967</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093697</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LANDEWEDNACK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10121498</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LANDEWEDNACK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
