<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3866</id>
<name>MARHAMCHURCH</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.7982105660292</lat>
<lon>-4.51272498886506</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARHAM-CHURCH, a village and a parish in Stratton district, Cornwall. The village stands near the Bude canal, 1&#190; mile from the coast, 2 SSW of Stratton, and 14&#189; NW by N of Launceston r. station; was known, at Domesday, as Maromcerch; and has a post office under Stratton, Cornwall, and fairs on the Wednesday after 25 March and on 12 Aug. The parish extends to the coast; and comprises 2,645 acres of land, and 75 of water. Real property, &#163;3,296. Pop., 581. Houses, 124. The manor belonged, at Domesday, to the Earl of Mortaigne; and passed to the Pynes, the Rolles, the Trefusis, and others. An inclined plane of the Bude canal, worked by a water-wheel, is in the parish; and there is an iron foundry. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;344. * Patrons, Messrs. Maxwell. The church is ancient but good, has a tower, and contains some old monuments. There are chapels for Wesleyans, Bible Christians, and United Free Methodists, and a parochial school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marhamchurch</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Marhamchurch/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643040</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10121929</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MARHAMCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160297</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARHAMCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3154</id>
   <name>JACOBSTOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5547</id>
   <name>WEEK ST MARY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6119</id>
   <name>WHITSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
