<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2602</id>
<name>LANLIVERY</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.4024985763844</lat>
<lon>-4.70924823575402</lon>
<gazetteerText>LANLIVERY, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Bodmin district, Cornwall. The village stands on an affluent of the river Fowey, 1&#190; mile WSW of Lostwithiel r. station, and 6 S by E of Bodmin.&#151;The parish comprises 6,790 acres. Post-town, Lostwithiel. Real property, &#163;8,026; of which &#163;574 are in mines, and &#163;75 in railways. Pop., 1,657. Houses, 348. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Duchy of Cornwall. Restormel Castle here crowns a hill, overlooking the wooded valley of the Fowey; was originally a palace of the Norman Earls of Cornwall; stood unroofed and much defaced in the time of Henry VIII.; was, nevertheless, garrisoned by the parliamentarians against Charles I., and taken by the royalists in 1644; and is now a circular ivy-mantled ruin, with a gate-house on the W, a projecting tower on the ENE, and an encompassing deep moat. Restormel House, at the foot of the hill, belongs to the Duchy of Cornwall, but is the residence of C. B. Sawle, Esq. Restormel mine is worked for iron; and was entered by Queen Victoria, when she visited Cornwall. Granite is largely quarried. The railway from the end of the Pier canal to Roche, a distance of 7 miles, crosses the Rock&apos;s Mill valley, within the parish, on a viaduct of ten arches, about 95 feet high. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;228.* Patron, N. Kendall, Esq. The church is ancient; has a fine pinnacled tower; and was recently in bad condition. There are two Wesleyan chapels, a free school, and charities &#163;14. &#151;The sub-district contains three other parishes. Acres, 18,391. Pop., 5,118. Houses, 1,089. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lanlivery</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Lanlivery/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644888</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10067571</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LANLIVERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10093727</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LANLIVERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10121530</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LANLIVERY URBAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10122557</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LANLIVERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542431</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LANLIVERY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
