<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5635</id>
<name>PERRANARWORTHAL</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.2120268100161</lat>
<lon>-5.12234512684637</lon>
<gazetteerText>PERRANARWORTHAL, a village and a parish in Falmouth district, Cornwall. The village stands in adeep dell, at the head of Restronguet creek, and at themouth of the Kennal rivulet, near Perranwell r. station, and 3&#188; miles N by W of Penryn; is sometimes called Perran-Wharf; and has a post-office, designated Perranar-worthal, Cornwall. The parish contains also the village of Perranwell, and comprises 1, 796 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 710; of which &#163;135 are in iron-works. Pop. in 1851, 1, 634; in 1861, 1, 517. Houses, 323. The manor belonged formerly to the Mohuns and the Pendarveses, and belongs now to J. Bassett, Esq. The dell around the village is densely wooded; presents a delightful contrastto the rough adjacent hills; and presents the additionalfeature of a large iron-foundry. The minerals include lead, tin, and arsenic; and there is a mineral spring. The living is a vicarage, annexed to the vicarage of Stithians, in the diocese of Cornwall. The church isdedicated to St. Piran, the patron of tinners; and aspring, called St. Piran&apos;s well, is in the vicinity. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Bible Christians, and amechanics&apos; institution. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perranarworthal</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Perranarworthal/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640365</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10096686</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PERRAN AR WORTHAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10201883</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>PERRANARWORTHAL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
