<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3877</id>
<name>ST BREOCK</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.4992569932341</lat>
<lon>-4.85080682590528</lon>
<gazetteerText>BREOCK (St.), a parish in St. Columb district, Cornwall; on the river Camel, including part of the town of Wadebridge, and 10 miles NW of Bodmin-Road r. station. Post Town, Wadebridge, Cornwall. Acres, 8,287; of which 270 are water. Real property, &#163;6,852. Pop., 1,866. Houses, 402. The property is divided among a few The manor belonged once to the Morices; and passed to the Molesworths. An eminence called the Beacon is crowned by a cromlech, and commands a fine view. A mineral traffic is carried on, by railway, with Bodmin and Camelford. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;859.* Patron, the Rev. G. S. Prior. The church occupies a picturesque site; contains some old monuments and two brasses; and is in good condition. There are chapels for Independents, Bible Christians, and Wesleyans. The parish bore the name of Pawton at the Domesday survey. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/StBreock/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10014256</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ST BREOKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10122144</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST BREOCK</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3838</id>
<name>BREAGE</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1179619898014</lat>
<lon>-5.35203074367467</lon>
<gazetteerText>BREAGE, or St. Breage,-pronounced Brague-a village, a parish, and a subdistrict in the district of Helston, Cornwall. The village stands on the coast, 3 miles W of Helston, and 6&#189; S by E of Gwinear Road r. station; and has a post office under Helston, and a fair on 19 June. It is said to have been founded by the Irish St. Breaca. The parish comprises 7,056 acres of land and 105 of water. Real property, &#163;12,212; of which &#163;4,883 are in mines. Pop., 5,173. Houses, 1,037. Much of the property belonged formerly to the Godolphin family; and belongs now to the Duke of Leeds. Godolphin mansion is now used as a farmhouse. Godolphin hill and Tregonning hill rise to altitudes of 495 and 596 feet; consist of granite; and are rich in minerals. China clay is worked out of part of Godolphin hill, and sent to neighbouring ports for shipment. Huel-Vor or WhealVor tin mine is in the same hill; has been worked in lodes 30 feet wide; extends upwards of 1&#188; mile under ground; and has yielded, at times, a clear profit of &#163;10,000 in three months. The living is a vicarage with Germoe in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;760. Patron, the Crown. The church contains the remains of Mrs. Godolphin. The vicarage of Godolphin and that of Cury and Gunwalloe are separate benefices. Charities, &#163;8. Lord Treasurer Godolphin was a native.-The subdistrict includes also the parish of Germoe. Acres, 8,448. Pop., 6,188. Houses, 1,253. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breage,_Cornwall</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Breage/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654835</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10120550</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BREAGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10178915</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BREAGE WITH GERMOE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542455</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BREAGE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
