<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2608</id>
<name>PROBUS</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.2952292007353</lat>
<lon>-4.94862979384454</lon>
<gazetteerText>PROBUS, a village and a sub-district, in Truro district, and a parish partly also in St. Austell district, Cornwall. The village stands on ground 305 feet above sea-level, near the Cornwall railway, 2&#189; miles S S W of Grampound-Road r. station, and 5 N E of Truro; is anancient place; was once a market-town; and has a head post-office, &#8225; designated Probus, Cornwall, an inn, and fairs on 5 and 23 April, 5 July, and 17 Sept. The parish contains also part of Grampound, and comprises 8, 113 acres. Real-property, exclusive of the part of G., &#163;9, 485. Pop., exc. of the part of G., 1, 353. Houses, 285. Pop. of the whole, 1, 449. Houses, 304. The manor was given, by Edward the Confessor, to a college of 5 prebends; and belongs now toH. Hawkins, Esq. Trehane is the seat of the Rev. W. Stack-house. Walvedon was forfeited, in the time of Elizabeth, by Tregion. A Roman camp of 7 acres is near Carvoza. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;509.* Patron, the Bishop of Exeter. The church is later English, all of wrought granite, covered with sculptures; has a tower, similar to that of Magdalen college, Oxford, and 125 feet high; was recently restored; and contains monuments of the Hawkinses, and two brasses. There are a Wesleyan chapel, an endowed school with &#163;10 a year, and charities &#163;100. The sub-district excludes the part of Grampound, but includes seven other parishes. Acres, 21, 670. Pop., 3, 702. Houses, 813. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Probus,_Cornwall</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Probus/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639880</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10067856</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PROBUS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160352</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PROBUS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10542376</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PROBUS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
