<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>735</id>
<name>LUDGVAN</name>
<container>CORNWALL</container>
<lat>50.1516977727918</lat>
<lon>-5.48656898119033</lon>
<gazetteerText>LUDGVAN, or LUDJAN, a village and a parish in Penzance district, Cornwall. The Village stands on a rising ground, 1 mile WNW of Marazion r. station, and 3 NE of Penzance; was anciently called Ludaham; commands a charming view southward over St. Michael&apos;s mount and bay; and has a post office under Penzance, and a cattle fair on 2 Oct. The parish contains also Crowlas hamlet, and several other hamlets. Acres, 4,584; of which 40 are water. Real property, &#163;6,984; of which &#163;418 are in railways. Pop., 3,480. Houses, 673. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged, at Domesday, to the Earl of Mortaigne; passed to the Ferrers, the Champernownes, the Willoughbys de Broke, and the Paulets; and belongs now to J. J. Rogers, Esq. Varfell was the residence of Sir Humphrey Davy, in his early years; and belonged, for several generations, to his ancestors. Mining operations are largely carried on. Granitic and schistose rocks abound; and tin and copper ores are obtained. A granitic rock very rich in mica, and known as Ludgvan stone, was once in much request, but appears to be now exhausted. A ditched-ditched camp, called Castle-an-Dinas, and measuring 436 feet in diameter, occupies the summit of the highest hill, and commands extensive views. Earthworks, thrown up by the parliamentarian force, at the siege of St. Michael&apos;s mount, are on the road to Marazion. A mineral spring is at Collurian. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Exeter. Value, &#163;800. Patron. alternately the Duke of Cleveland and the Earl of Sandwich. The church has a fine Norman arch; was repaired and enlarged in 1840; and contains tablets of the Davy family, and the remains of Dr. Borlase, author of the &quot;Antiquities and Natural History of Cornwall, &apos;&apos;and for 52 years rector of the parish. There are six chapels for Wesleyans, two for Primitive Methodists, one for Bible Christians, a national school, and charities &#163;4. Remains of an ancient chapel are at Collurian. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/Cornwall/Ludgvan/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ludgvan</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643427</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10080095</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LUDGVAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109851</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>LUDGVAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135916</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>LUDGVAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160194</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LUDGVAN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
