<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3793</id>
<name>STANWIX</name>
<container>CUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.9241170419969</lat>
<lon>-2.92321567855013</lon>
<gazetteerText>STANWIX, a village, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Carlisle district, Cumberland. The village is suburban to Carlisle; stands on the Roman wall and on the river Eden, close to the bridge communicating with Carlisle; occupies the site of the Roman station Congavata; and has a post-office under Carlisle. The township comprises 425 acres. Real property, &#163;4,998. Pop., 935. Houses, 226. The parish contains 7 other townships, and comprises 6,158 acres. Pop., 2,356. Houses, 514. The property is subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Carlisle. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop ofThe church was rebuilt in 1841; and was partly destroyed by fire, but restored in 1843. The rectory of Houghton is a separate benefice. There are a reformatory school, a national school, and charities &#163;7.&#151;The sub-district includes two other parishes, and comprises 13,840 acres. Pop., 3,801. Houses, 812. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanwix</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CUL/Stanwix/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637032</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10012170</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STANWIX</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10119583</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>STANWIX RURAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544488</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STANWIX</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1564</id>
   <name>HETHERSGILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1571</id>
   <name>NICHOL FOREST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1577</id>
   <name>SCALEBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2173</id>
   <name>BURGH BY SANDS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2868</id>
   <name>WESTLINTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3743</id>
   <name>ARTHURET</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3774</id>
   <name>KIRKANDREWS NETHER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4604</id>
   <name>KINGMOOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6505</id>
   <name>ROCKCLIFFE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>16929</id>
   <name>CANONBIE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
