<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>255</id>
<name>HOLME CULTRAM</name>
<container>CUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.8526744284467</lat>
<lon>-3.34377514974149</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOLME-CULTRAM, a parish in Wigton district, Cumberland; on the Carlisle and Silloth railway, the river Waver, and the Solway frith, around the village of Abbeytown and the town of Silloth, which have stations on the railway, and post offices under Carlisle. It contains the townships of Abbey-Holme, Holme-ST. Cuthbert, Holme-East-Waver, and Low Holme; and comprises 24, 920 acres of land, and 14, 042 of water. Real property, &#163;26, 926. Pop. in 1851, 3, 212; in 1861, 3, 867. Houses, 743. The increase of pop. was caused by the opening of the railway, and by the forming of the new town and port of Silloth. The property, in most parts, is much subdivided. The coast appears, from various records, to have undergone very great changes by irruption of the sea. A Cistertian abbey, noticed in our article Abbey Holme, was a centre of much influence, and a place of considerable events. King Alexander of Scotland plundered it in 1216; Edward I. of England was at it in 1300; Robert Bruce partially demolished it in 1322, though his father had been buried in it; and Michael Scott, the reputed wizard, was a monk in it, and, together with his magic books, was buried within its enclosure. Wolsty Castle, a fortress erected by the abbots to secure their treasures, books, and charters from the sudden forays of the Scots, stood a short distance to the W. There are a steam mill, and brick and tile works. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Carlisle. Value, &#163;170.* Patron, the University of Oxford. The church is a renovated portion of the old abbey buildings. The chapelries of Newton-Arlosh, Holme-ST. Cuthbert, and Low Holme, are separate benefices, in patronage of the Vicar. There are good national schools. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CUL/HolmCultram/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10027597</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HOLME CULTRAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10047493</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>HOLM CULTRAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10111407</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HOLME CULTRAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10198719</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HOLM CULTRAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>328</id>
   <name>ASPATRIA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2200</id>
   <name>WESTNEWTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2587</id>
   <name>SKINBURNESS MARSH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3362</id>
   <name>LANGRIGG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3409</id>
   <name>HOLME LOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3758</id>
   <name>BROMFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4602</id>
   <name>HOLME ABBEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5070</id>
   <name>HOLME EAST WAVER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5420</id>
   <name>HOLME ST CUTHBERT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
