<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5406</id>
<name>WETHERAL</name>
<container>CUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.8668018302911</lat>
<lon>-2.82516009253834</lon>
<gazetteerText>WETHERAL, a village, a township, and a sub-district, in Carlisle district, and a parish partly also in Brampton district, Northumberland. The village stands on the river Eden, adjacent to the Newcastle and Carlisle railway, 4&#188; miles ESE of Carlisle; enjoys charming environs; and has a post-office under Carlisle, a r. station, and a public green. The township comprises 4,458 acres. Real property, &#163;6,569. Pop., 666. Houses, 129. The parish includes 5 other townships, and comprises 11,778 acres. Pop. in 1851, 3,165; in 1861, 3,377. Houses, 723. The property is subdivided. Corby Castle, originally a castellated edifice, but now modernised with a new Grecian front, is the seat of the Howards. A Benedictine priory, a cell to St. Mary&apos;s of York, was founded a little S of W. village in 1088, by Ranulph de Meschines; was given, at the dissolution, to the Dean and Chapter of Carlisle; and is now represented by a later English gateway, surmounted by an embattled tower. A railway viaduct, of 5 arches, with roadway 90 feet above the surface of the water, and another bridge of 7 arches, and 480 feet in length, cross the Eden. Delightful walks lie along the river, above the village: and lead to three caves called Wetheral Safeguards, cut deeply in a precipice 40 feet above the water. A summer-house, called the Folly, stands on a high site, a little further up the river; and commands a superb view. Red free-stone and alabaster are worked. The living is a rectory, united with Warwick, in the diocese of Carlisle. Value, &#163;300.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter ofThe church is chiefly later English or Tudor, with a modern tower. The vicarages of Scotby and Holme-Eden are separate benefices. There are endowed schools with &#163;33 a year.&#151;The sub-district excludes Little Corby township, but includes two other parishes. Acres, 16,861. Pop., 3,886. Houses, 814. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wetheral</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CUL/Wetheral/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634218</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10071987</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WETHERAL WITH WARWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10193606</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WETHERAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544490</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WETHERAL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1547</id>
   <name>CARLATTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2199</id>
   <name>WARWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2889</id>
   <name>CUMWHITTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4598</id>
   <name>CUMREW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5996</id>
   <name>AINSTABLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
