<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5709</id>
<name>MARSTON ON DOVE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8716545540798</lat>
<lon>-1.64741344001684</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARSTON-UPON-DOVE, a township and a parish in the district of Burton-upon-Trent and county of Derby. The township lies on the river Dove at the boundary with Stafford, and on the North Staffordshire railway, 1 mile WNW of Tutbury-Junction r. station, 3&#188; WNW of Ryknield-street, and 5 NNW of Burton-upon-Trent. Real property, &#163;2,070. Pop., 103. Houses, 16. The parish contains also the townships of Hoon, Hatton, and Hilton; the last of which has a post office under Derby. Acres, 4,775. Real property, &#163;8,898. Pop., 1,211. Houses, 268. The property is subdivided. The manors of Marston and Hoon belong to the Duke of Devonshire, and that of Hilton belongs to the Executors of the late W. E. Mousley, Esq. Hilton Cottage is the seat of J. H. Mousley, Esq. The Wakelyn is an ancient, gabled, curiously ornamented, half-timber mansion. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;200. * Patron, the Duke of Devonshire. The church is early English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with tower and lofty spire; and contains a fine Norman font. There are, in Hilton, chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists, and an endowed school with &#163;30 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/MarstononDove/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marston_on_Dove</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7300220</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018900</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON UPON DOVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10076020</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON ON DOVE WITH SCROPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10204033</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARSTON ON DOVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10288617</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON ON DOVE WITH SCROPTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
