<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6176</id>
<name>HOPE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3613703507966</lat>
<lon>-1.78721371349745</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOPE, a village and a township in Chapel-en-leFrith district, and a parish partly also in Bakewell district, Derby. The village stands on the river Noe, 1 &#188; mile ENE of Castleton, and 7 &#189; N by E of Miller&apos;s Dale r. station; had a church in the time of the Confessor; was a market town under the Fitz-Warrens, who had a castle near it; comprises now a picturesque group of good houses; and has a post office under Sheffield, and a cattle-market on the last Wednesday of every month.-The township comprises 2, 672 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 506. Pop., 398. Houses, 87. The manor belongs to Joseph Hall, Esq.&#151;The parish contains also the townships of Aston, Brough and Shatton, Thornhill, Hope-Woodlands, Fernilee, Fanrfield, Stoke, Bradwell, and Grindlow; the lordships of Hazlebadge and Highlow; and the hamlets of Nether Padley, Great Hucklow, Little Hucklow, Offerton, and Abney. Acres, 38, 563. Real property, &#163;25, 587; of which &#163;150 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 4, 604; in 1861, 5, 107. Houses, 1, 013. The property is much subdivided. Some of the manors belong to the Duke of Devonshire; and that of Thornhill belongs to Col. Leslie. The surface, to a large extent, is moor and mountain; but it includes many picturesque and romantic Roman station is believed to have been in Brough; and many Roman relics, including a bust of Apollo, urns, bricks, and coins, have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300. * Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Lichfield. The church is a handsome edifice, with tower and spire. The vicarage of Fairfield is a separate benefice. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a free school, and charities &#163;73. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hope,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Hope/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646640</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018663</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HOPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10219164</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HOPE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2756</id>
<name>HOPE WOODLANDS</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4224151695144</lat>
<lon>-1.79988234498657</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOPE-WOODLANDS, a township in Hope parish, Derby; 6 miles NE of Tideswell. Acres, 20, 259. Real property, &#163;2, 246. Pop., 227. Houses, 41. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hope_Woodlands</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7298163</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10076262</id>
   <status>Hmlt/CP</status>
   <name>HOPE WOODLANDS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
