<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>22980</id>
<name>GREAT WILNE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8733745581355</lat>
<lon>-1.33283446299112</lon>
<gazetteerText>Wilne, Great (or Far Wilne), hamlet, Ashton upon Trent par., Derbyshire, &#189; mile S. of Church Wilne. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10022435</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WILNE WITH DRAYCOTT</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>20877</id>
<name>CHURCH WILNE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8823643531358</lat>
<lon>-1.33269648015191</lon>
<gazetteerText>WILNE, a liberty and a parish in Shardlow district, Derbyshire. The liberty lies on the river Derwent, 1&#188; mile SE of Draycott r. station, and 7 ESE of Derby; and bears the name of Church-Wilne or Little Wilne. Pop., 140. Houses, 30. The parish contains also Hopwell hamlet, Draycott liberty, which has a post-office under Derby, Breaston chapelry, which has a postal pillar-box under Derby, and Risley chapelry, which has a post-office under Nottingham. Acres, 8,500. Rated property, &#163;7,573. Pop., 2,095. Houses, 460. The property is much subdivided. Hopwell Hall, Draycott Hall, Draycott House, Draycott Field House, and Risley Hall are chief residences. There are cotton and lace manufactories. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300. Patron, the Bishop of L. The church is ancient. The rectories of Breaston and Risley are a conjoint separate charge. There are two Methodist chapels, an endowed school with &#163;378 a year, and charities &#163;27. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Wilne/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10089566</id>
   <status>Ch</status>
   <name>WILNE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
