<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4060</id>
<name>HAYFIELD</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3855353595035</lat>
<lon>-1.92004131456138</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAYFIELD, a village, a township, a chapelry, a sub-district, and a district, in Derby. The village stands among the mountains of High Peak, near the river Kinder and the Peak canal, at the terminus of the Manchester, Hyde, Marple, New Mills, and Hayfield railway, 5 miles S by E of Glossop; and has a post-office&#8225; under Stockport, a railway station, and a fair on 12 May.&#151;The township includes the village; comprises the hamlets of Great Hamlet, Phoside, and Kinder; and is in Glossop parish. Pop. in 1851, 1,757; in 1861, 2,156. Houses, 446. The manor belongs to the Duke of Devonshire. There are cotton-mills, calico print-works, and paper-mills.&#151;The chapelry includes the township, extends also into Chapel-en-le-Frith; is all in Glossop parish; and was constituted in 1837. Rated property, &#163;5,504. Pop., 3,359. Houses, 693. The property is much subdivided. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;180. Patrons, Freeholders. The church was rebuilt in 1819, and has a tower. There are three dissenting chapels, an endowed national school, and some charities.&#151;The sub-district contains the townships of Hayfield, Mellor, and Beard, Thornsett, Ollersett, and Whittle, all in Glossop parish, and the township of Disley-Stanley, in Stockport parish, Cheshire. Pop., 10,976. Houses, 2,182.&#151;The district comprehends also the sub-district of Glossop, containing the townships of Glossop-Dale, Padfield, Hadfield, Dinting, Whitfield, Chunall, Simmondley, Charlesworth, Chisworth, and Ludworth, all in Glossop parish. The two sub-districts are two poor-law unions, with work-houses in respectively Beard and Glossop-Dale. Acres of the district, 48,855. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;17,295. Pop. in 1851, 29,712; in 1861, 32,176. Houses, 6,362. Marriages in 1862, 157; births, 1,108,&#151;of which 72 were illegitimate; deaths, 692,&#151;of which 295 were at ages under 5 years, and 7 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,959; births, 10,769; deaths, 7,212. The places of worship, in 1851, were 7 of the Church of England, with 5,817 sittings; 6 of Independents, with 3,410 s.; 1 of Baptists, with 248 s.; 1 of Quakers, with 200 s.; 13 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 4,174 s.; 7 of Primitive Methodists, with 1,993 s.; 2 of the Wesleyan Association, with 416 s.; and 2 of Roman Catholics, with 794 s. The schools were 20 public day schools, with 1,717 scholars; 33 private day schools, with 1,305 s.; 46 Sunday schools, with 7,918 s.; and 6 evening schools for adults, with 157 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hayfield</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Hayfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Hayfield</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647260</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10029340</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>HAYFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109309</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>HAYFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10111791</id>
   <status>PLU</status>
   <name>HAYFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127592</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>HAYFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163640</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAYFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544713</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAYFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10560135</id>
   <status>RegD</status>
   <name>HAYFIELD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
