<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>649</id>
<name>DRONFIELD</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3042270482392</lat>
<lon>-1.47575995001522</lon>
<gazetteerText>DRONFIELD, a village, a township, and a sub-district in Chesterfield district, Derby; and a parish partly also in Ecclesall-Bierlow district. The village stands on a branch of the river Rother, 5&#189; miles W of Eckington r. station, and 6 NNW of Chesterfield; is a neat place, with many respectable houses; was known at Domesday as Dranefield; has a post office&#8225; under Sheffield, and fairs on the Wednesday after 12 March, 25 April, 11 Aug., and the Thursday after 12 Oct.; and was formerly a market-town. The township includes the village, and extends into the country. Real property, &#163;10, 940; of which &#163;2, 184 are in mines. Pop., 2, 998. Houses, 641.&#151;The sub-district contains also four other. townships of Dronfield parish, and a chapelry in Stavely parish. Acres, 19, 340. Pop., 5, 689. Houses, 1, 189. The parish comprises the townships of Dronfield, Unstone, Coal-Aston, Holmesfield and Little Barlow in Chesterfield district, and those of Dore and Totley in Ecclesall-Bierlow district. Acres, 15, 580. Real property, &#163;25, 873; of which &#163;2, 196 are in mines. Pop., 6, 013. Houses, 1, 265. The property is much subdivided. Coal is worked; hardware is manufactured; and there is a sulphureous spring. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;224.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church stands on an elevation near the village; is decorated English; has a fine tower and spire; had formerly a chantry; and contains a brass of two priests of 1399. The p. curacies of Dore and Holmesfield are separate benefices. There are an Independent chapel, a Baptist chapel, seven Methodist chapels, two free schools, and charities &#163;149. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dronfield_Woodhouse</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dronfield</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Dronfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650967</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10063036</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>DRONFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109292</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>DRONFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127361</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DRONFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10205608</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>DRONFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10218391</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>DRONFIELD WOODHOUSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544816</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DRONFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10572605</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DRONFIELD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
