<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4063</id>
<name>HORSLEY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9963124543283</lat>
<lon>-1.43147745582224</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORSLEY, a township, a parish, and a sub-district in Belper district, Derby. The township lies adjacent to the Derby, Little Eaton, and Ripley railway, &#189; a mile from Coxbench station, 1&#190; E of the river Derwent, and 2&#189; SE of Belper Real property, &#163;1, 982; of which &#163;100 are in quarries. Pop., 468. Houses, 102. The parish contains also the townships of Horsley-Woodhouse and Kilbourne; and its post town is Coxbench, under Derby. Acres, 2, 792. Real property, &#163;7, 764; of which &#163;1, 300 are in mines, and &#163;100 in quarries. Pop., 2, 250. Houses, 473. The property is not much divided. The manor belongs to the Rev. H. W. Sitwell. Stainsby House, Horsley House, and Kilbourne Hall are chief residences. Horston Castle was built here, in the early part of the 13th century, by Ralph de Burun; but has been destroyed. coal mining has been extended; and tanning, nail making, and the manufactory of hosiery are carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of LichfieldValue, &#163;170. *-Patron, the Rev. H. W. Sitwell. The church stands on an eminence; is early English; was restored in 1860; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with tower and lofty spire. There are a Wesleyan chapel, two national schools, and an infant school in Horsley township; Wesleyan and Primitive Methodist chapels, and an infant school, in Horsley-Woodhouse; and Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, and a girls&apos; school, in Kilbourne. Charities, &#163;22.&#151;The sub-district contains also two other parishes and parts of two more. Acres, 9, 672. Pop., 5, 930. Houses, 1, 230. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horsley,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Horsley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7294813</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10127660</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163705</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORSLEY WOODHOUSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10182621</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10188453</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HORSLEY WOODHOUSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544634</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
