<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4078</id>
<name>GREAT LONGSTONE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.252589395918</lat>
<lon>-1.69688416665258</lon>
<gazetteerText>LONGSTONE (GREAT), a village, a township, and a chapelry in Bakewell parish, Derby. The village stands on high ground, under a lofty range of hills, called Longstone Edge, near the Derby and Buxton railway, 3 miles NW by N of Bakewell; consists of one long street; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Bakewell. The township bears the name of Great Longstone-with-Holme. Real property, &#163;5,292; of which &#163;990 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851,564; in 1861,683. Houses, 130. The increase of pop. arose from the temporary presence of labourers at the forming of the railway. The manor and much of the land belong to the Duke of Devonshire. Longstone Hall, an ancient mansion at the W end of the village, is the seat of T. Gregory, Esq. Holme Hall is the residence of T. J. Gisborne, Esq.&#151;The chapelry includes also Little Longstone township, and part of Wardlow. Pop., 925. Houses, 173. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;190.* Patron, the Vicar of Bakewell. The church is old; comprises nave and chancel, with a small tower; and contains monuments of the noble family of Eyre. There are two dissenting chapels, respectively in Great Longstone and Little Longstone; and there is a commodious school, built in 1862, and endowed with &#163;25 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Longstone</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648064</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Longstone/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018857</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONGSTONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10099997</id>
   <status>Ch</status>
   <name>LONGSTONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127889</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>GREAT LONGSTONE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1819</id>
   <name>PILSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4059</id>
   <name>HASSOP</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4817</id>
   <name>LITTLE LONGSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5245</id>
   <name>ROWLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
