<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1166</id>
<name>MATLOCK</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.143320596533</lat>
<lon>-1.56775887541709</lon>
<gazetteerText>Matlock, town and par., Derbyshire, on river Derwent - par., 4539 ac., pop. 6093; town (ry. sta. Matlock Bridge), 17 miles NW. of Derby and 144 miles NW. of London by rail, pop. 4395; 1 Bank, and P.O., T.O., and 3 Banks at Matlock Bridge; the par. contains Matlock Bath, town with ry. sta., 1 mile S. of Matlock, pop. (including Scarthin Nick) 1698; P.O., T.O.; Market-day, Saturday; also Matlock Bank, 1 mile N. of Matlock; P.O., T.O. Matlock Bath is the celebrated place for medicinal waters, which were first used for curative purposes in 1698. The locality is likewise famed for its beautifully romantic scenery. There are several large stalactite caverns. Most of the inhabitants of the town of Matlock are engaged in the mfr. of cotton goods and spar ornaments; but there are also paper mills (at Matlock Bath), corn mills, and bleachworks, and in the vicinity are lead-mines. The rising district of Matlock Bank is well known for its hydropathic establishments. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matlock</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matlock_Bath</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Matlock/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642910</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10062135</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10062147</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>THE MATLOCKS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10067388</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BATH AND SCARTHIN NICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10070612</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10076031</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109310</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127970</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10153852</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BATH AND SCARTHIN NICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154686</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163833</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544683</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833489</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>323</id>
   <name>NORTH DARLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>109</id>
   <name>SOUTH DARLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4148</id>
   <name>TANSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2350</id>
   <name>CRICH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4158</id>
   <name>WINSTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1750</id>
   <name>BIRCHOVER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4144</id>
   <name>STANTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3815</id>
   <name>BEELEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4035</id>
   <name>DARLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3206</id>
   <name>ELTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4040</id>
   <name>DETHICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4153</id>
   <name>WENSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>5709</id>
<name>MARSTON ON DOVE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8716545540798</lat>
<lon>-1.64741344001684</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARSTON-UPON-DOVE, a township and a parish in the district of Burton-upon-Trent and county of Derby. The township lies on the river Dove at the boundary with Stafford, and on the North Staffordshire railway, 1 mile WNW of Tutbury-Junction r. station, 3&#188; WNW of Ryknield-street, and 5 NNW of Burton-upon-Trent. Real property, &#163;2,070. Pop., 103. Houses, 16. The parish contains also the townships of Hoon, Hatton, and Hilton; the last of which has a post office under Derby. Acres, 4,775. Real property, &#163;8,898. Pop., 1,211. Houses, 268. The property is subdivided. The manors of Marston and Hoon belong to the Duke of Devonshire, and that of Hilton belongs to the Executors of the late W. E. Mousley, Esq. Hilton Cottage is the seat of J. H. Mousley, Esq. The Wakelyn is an ancient, gabled, curiously ornamented, half-timber mansion. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;200. * Patron, the Duke of Devonshire. The church is early English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with tower and lofty spire; and contains a fine Norman font. There are, in Hilton, chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists, and an endowed school with &#163;30 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/MarstononDove/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marston_on_Dove</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7300220</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018900</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON UPON DOVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10076020</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON ON DOVE WITH SCROPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10204033</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARSTON ON DOVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10288617</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON ON DOVE WITH SCROPTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4079</id>
<name>MAPLETON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0269442107133</lat>
<lon>-1.74868625422868</lon>
<gazetteerText>MAPPLETON, a village and a parish in Ashborne district, Derby. The village stands on the river Dove, at the boundary with Stafford, 1&#190; mile NW of Ashborne r. station; is a pleasant place; has a post office under Ashborne, a bridge over the Dove, and a good inn; and is a resort of anglers. The parish comprises 778 acres. Real property, &#163;2,202. Pop., 185. Houses, 39. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to J. G. Johnson, Esq. The living is a rectory, annexed to the vicarage of Ashborne, in the diocese of Lichfield. The church is good; and has a dome, surmounted by an urn. There are alms houses for three widows of clergymen, and some other charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Mappleton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mapleton,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643081</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10127920</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MAPLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10196309</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MAPLETON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4818</id>
<name>MACKWORTH</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9400663868682</lat>
<lon>-1.53338036288151</lon>
<gazetteerText>MACKWORTH, a township and a parish in Belper district, Derbyshire. The township lies on an affluent of the river Derwent, 3 miles WNW of Derby r. station; contains remains of a fine old gateway, formerly an entrance to Mackworth Castle, belonging to Lord Scarsdale; and has a post office under Derby. Real property, &#163;2,984. Pop., 278. Houses, 53. The parish contains also the township of Markheaton, and comprises 3,400 acres. Real property, &#163;7,819. Pop., 525. Houses, 95. The property is divided among a few. The manors, with Markheaton Hall, belong to W. Mundy, Esq. Thornhill is the seat of Miss E. Trowell. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;155.* Patron, WMundy, Esq. The church is decorated English; consists of nave, aisles, and deep chancel, with fine tower and octagonal spire; was restored in 1851; has a memorial E window to F. N.Mundy, Esq.; and contains a modern font of Caen stone. There are a parochial school, and charities &#163;35. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mackworth</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Mackworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643249</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018882</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MACKWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10070594</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MACKWORTH ST FRANCIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163810</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MACKWORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5898</id>
<name>MAPPERLEY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9821041624683</lat>
<lon>-1.3588722537045</lon>
<gazetteerText>MAPPERLEY, a township in Kirk-Hallam parish, Derbyshire; on the Nutbrook canal, 2 miles NW of Ilkeston r. station, and 7 NE by N of Derby. It has a post office under Derby. Acres, 972. Real property, &#163;1,556. Pop. in 1851,359; in 1861,435. Houses, 90. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of coal mines and iron-works in the adjacent parishes of Denby and West Hallam. There are a chapel of ease, a Wesleyan chapel, a slightly endowed Sunday school, and an infant school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mapperley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7294815</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10188180</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MAPPERLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10210057</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>MAPPERLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2710</id>
<name>MARKEATON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9404593185558</lat>
<lon>-1.51376177082827</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARKEATON, a township in Mackworth parish, Derbyshire; on an affluent of the river Derwent. 1&#189; mile NW of Derby. Real property, &#163;4,835. Pop., 247. Houses, 42. The manor belonged to the Earls of Chester; passed to the Touchets; and, with Markeaton Hall, belongs now to W. Mundy, Esq. The Hall was built in 1755, and stands in a spacious park. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markeaton</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10070600</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>MARKEATON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>6014</id>
<name>MARSTON MONTGOMERY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9397191741719</lat>
<lon>-1.79717415810296</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARSTON-MONTGOMERY, a village and a parish, in the district of Uttoxeter and county of Derby. Thc village stands 1&#190; mile E of the river Dove at the boundary with Stafford, 2&#189; ESE of Rocester-Junction r. station, and 4&#190; NE of Uttoxeter; is a scattered place; and has a post office under Ashborne. The parish comprises 2,471 acres. Real property, &#163;3,950. Pop., 405. Houses, 87. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;140. Patron, the Rev. J. Greene. The church stands on an eminence; and consists of nave and chancel, with a tower. There are a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;6. s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/MarstonMontgomery/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marston_Montgomery</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642965</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10127932</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10214439</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MARSTON MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2694</id>
   <name>CUBLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>23924</id>
<name>MARLPOOL</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0064886014978</lat>
<lon>-1.34270758168672</lon>
<gazetteerText>Marlpool, 1 mile from Heanor, in co. and 8 miles NE. of Derby; P.O. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643002</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10052105</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARLPOOL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24501</id>
<name>MATLOCK BANK</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1440699394079</lat>
<lon>-1.54096961796674</lon>
<gazetteerText>MATLOCK-BANK, a hamlet in Matlock parish, Derbyshire; near Matlock-Bridge. It has one large hydropathic establishment, three others of considerable size, and four smaller ones, all delightfully situated, and containing excellent accommodation. It has also an Independent chapel and a Primitive Methodist chapel; and the former was built in 1866, is in the early English style, has a tower and spire, contains 540 sittings, and cost about &#163;2,100. Bridge House is the residence of J. Cash, Esq.; and Balmoral House, of Mr. A. Morrell. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642909</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10127968</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BANK</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25957</id>
<name>MATLOCK BRIDGE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1378282315062</lat>
<lon>-1.55449119783515</lon>
<gazetteerText>MATLOCK-BRIDGE, a hamlet in Matlock parish, Derbyshire; on the river Derwent, and on the Manchester and Buxton railway, &#189; a mile NW of Matlock village. It has a station on the railway, a post office under Matlock-Bath, and a Wesleyan chapel. A company was formed in 1866 to erect at it a hotel, a market-hall, and assembly-room; and the market-hall was opened in 1868. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
</results>
