<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2385</id>
<name>STONY MIDDLETON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2719173199713</lat>
<lon>-1.67693657965708</lon>
<gazetteerText>MIDDLETON-STONEY, a village and a chapelry in Hathersage parish, Derby. The village stands at the entrance of Middleton dale, on an affluent of the river Derwent, 3&#189; miles N by E of Hassop r. station, and 4&#189; N by E of Bakewell; is a very picturesque place, with some houses at the foot of cliffs, and others on successive ledges of steep rock; and has a post office under Sheffield, and a warm spring with baths. The spring is supposed to have been known and used by the Romans; was covered by erections of old date; and is now enclosed in baths rebuilt by the late Lord Denman. The chapelry comprises 1,310 acres. Real property, &#163;2,191. Pop., 608. Houses, 132. The property is much subdivided. Stoney-Middleton House is the seat of Lord Denman. Middleton dale is a highly romantic glen. The rocks are chiefly limestone, and they abound in lead ore. Several lime-kilns are in the dale; and there are places for smelting ore and manufacturing barytes. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;110. Patron, the Vicar of Hathersage. The church was rebuilt in 1767; retains a tower of more ancient date; and has the form of an octagon. There are chapels for Presbytcrians and Wesleyans, an endowed school, and charities &#163;20. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/StoneyMiddleton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoney_Middleton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636796</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10053687</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>STONY MIDDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10072542</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONY MIDDLETON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2691</id>
   <name>CALVER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
