<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1769</id>
<name>HARTINGTON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1505117893779</lat>
<lon>-1.7968302411411</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARTINGTON, a village, a parish, four townships, and a sub-district, in Derbyshire. The village stands on the river Dove, at the boundary with Staffordshire, 3 miles W of the Cromford and High Peak railway, 8 miles SW by W of Bakewell r. station, and 10&#189; N by W of Ashborne; has a bridge over the Dove, and a post office, &#8225; under Ashborne; and gives the title of Marquis to the Duke of Devonshire. A weekly market is held on Wednesday; and fairs are held on 12 Feb., 2 April, and the Wednesday before the last Thursday of April.&#151;The parish consists of the townships of H. Town-Quarter, H. NetherQuarter, H. Middle-Quarter, and H. Upper-Quarter; the two first in the district of Ashborne, the third in that of Bakewell, the fourth in that of Chapel-en-le-Frith. Acres of the whole, 24, 160. Real property, of H. T. Q., &#163;4, 339, -of which &#163;160 are in quarries; of H. N. Q., &#163;3, 790; of H. M. Q., &#163;3, 844; of H. U. Q., &#163;5, 991, -of which &#163;860 are in mines, and &#163;43 in quarries. Pop. of H. T. Q. 495; of H. N. Q., 329; of H. M. Q., 326; of H. U. Q., 1, 190. Houses, 107, 84, 69, and 248. H. T. Q. contains the village; H. M. Q. is conterminate with EarlSterndale chapelry; and H. U. Q. contains the chapelry of Burbage. The property of the parish is subdivided; the manor belonged anciently to the Ferrers, who had a castle on it; belonged in the time of Charles I. to Villiers; and belongs now to the Duke of Devonshire. Iron ore and many other minerals are in H. T. Q., but have been little worked. The quarries and works of the Buxton Lime company are in H. U. Q., and they employ several hundred men, and produce about 63, 000 tons of lime a year. The mountains, moors, and vales of the parish are interesting to at once geologists, antiquaries, and tourists; and the northern tracts of it contribute attractions to the neighbourhood of Buxton. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;249. * Patron, the Duke of Devonshire. The church is ancient; was restored in 1858; and has transepts, and a pinnacled tower. Burbage living is a p. curacy, of the value of &#163;100, in the patronage of the Duke of Devonshire; and the church of it was built in 1861, is in the early Norman style, and has a low square tower. EarlSterndale is separately noticed. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a school with &#163;9, and other charities with &#163;29. A new school-House was built in 1865.&#151;The sub-district contains H. T. Q. and H. N. Q. townships, Parwich parish, and parts of Ashborne and Bradbourne parishes; and is in the district of Ashborne. Acres, 29, 671. Pop., 1, 652. Houses, 332. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartington_Upper_Quarter</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartington_Nether_Quarter</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartington_Town_Quarter</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647404</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartington</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Hartington/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018584</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>HARTINGTON TOWN QUARTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127543</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HARTINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127555</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HARTINGTON MIDDLE QUARTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127567</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>HARTINGTON UPPER QUARTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163626</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>HARTINGTON NETHER QUARTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10182566</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARTINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10563884</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HARTINGTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8508</id>
   <name>SHEEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
