<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3205</id>
<name>DARLEY ABBEY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9423595556631</lat>
<lon>-1.483546131498</lon>
<gazetteerText>DARLEY-ABBEY, or Little Derby, a chapelry or liberty in the district and county of Derby; on the river Derwent, adjacent to the Derby and Leeds railway, 1&#188; mile N of Derby. Post town, Derby. Real property, &#163;4, 322. Pop., 967. Houses, 161. A small Augustinian priory was founded here, in the time of Henry I., by the Abbot of St. Helens; and given, at the dissolution, to the Wests. A mansion, called Darley Abbey, is now the seat of T. W. Evans, Esq. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, T. W. Evans, Esq. The church is modern. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/DarleyAbbey/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darley_Abbey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651516</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093867</id>
   <status>CP/ExP</status>
   <name>DARLEY ABBEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127038</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DARLEY ABBEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4035</id>
<name>DARLEY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1676225365953</lat>
<lon>-1.5804383542834</lon>
<gazetteerText>DARLEY, a township and a parish in Bakewell district, Derby. The township lies on the river Derwent, adjacent to the Rowsley railway, 5 miles SE by S of Bakewell; and has a station on the railway, a post office, of the name of Darley-Dale, under Matlock-Bath, and fairs on 13 May and 27 Oct. Real property, &#163;6, 221; of which &#163;211 are in quarries. Pop., 1, 574. Houses, 314. The parish contains also the township of Wensley and Snitterton. Acres, 7, 104. Rated property, &#163;10, 400. Pop., 2, 156. Houses, 451. The property is much sub-divided. Darley Hall is a chief residence. Good sandstone is found; lead ore is mined; and manufactures of stockings, cotton, and paper are carried on. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;434.* Patron, the Bishop of Lichfield. The church is partly Norman, and very good; and the churchyard has a yew-tree, 33 feet in girth of trunk. The p. curacy of Cross-Green or South Darley, constituted in 1845, is a separate benefice. . Value, &#163;94. Patron, the Rector of Darley. The church is tolerable. There is a Wesleyan chapel. A school has &#163;32 from endowment; and other charities &#163;5. A priory of Black canons was built at Darley, in the time of Henry II., by Hugh, dean of Derby. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darley_Dale</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7298139</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10097034</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DARLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127002</id>
   <status>AP/CP/Tn</status>
   <name>DARLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>109</id>
<name>SOUTH DARLEY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1440087082295</lat>
<lon>-1.6009975826028</lon>
<gazetteerText>South Darley, local government dist., Darley par., Derbyshire, 2007 ac., pop. 679. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7294847</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10003088</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SOUTH DARLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10018110</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH DARLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10075324</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SOUTH DARLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>323</id>
<name>NORTH DARLEY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1724259004191</lat>
<lon>-1.57619095664321</lon>
<gazetteerText>North Darley, local government dist., Darley par., Derbyshire, 6 m. SE. of Bakewell, 5142 ac., pop. 1848. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10042811</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>NORTH DARLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10138840</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>NORTH DARLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
