<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2350</id>
<name>CRICH</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.094304289413</lat>
<lon>-1.4810691899377</lon>
<gazetteerText>CRICH, a township in Belper district, and a parish in Belper, Chesterfield, and Bakewell districts, Derby. The township adjoins the Cromford canal and the river Derwent, near Wingfield and Whatstandwell-Bridge r. stations, 4 miles W by S of Alfreton; has a post office under Derby; was formerly a market-town; and still has fairs on Old Lady-day and Old Michaelmas-day. Acres, 3, 770. Pop., 2, 829. Houses, 612.&#151;The parish contains also the townships of Wessington and Tansley. Acres, 5, 878. Real property, &#163;11, 800; of which &#163;100 are in mines, and &#163;2, 427 in quarries. Pop., 3, 970. Houses, 858. The property is much subdivided. Lead mines, in limestone, at Crich-Cliffs, are very valuable. Crich-Cliffs are conspicuous hills; and Crich-Stand, on their summit, has an altitude of 995 feet above the level of the sea, and commands an extensive view. Many of the inhabitants are employed in a bobbin-mill and in stocking-weaving. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;170.* Patrons, Trustees. The church is handsome, and has a tower and spire. The rectory of Tanslee and the vicarage of Wessington are separate benefices. There are six dissenting chapels, a national school, and charities &#163;9. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crich</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651993</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Crich/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10051599</id>
   <status>Tn/AP/CP</status>
   <name>CRICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10070156</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CRICH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
