<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5764</id>
<name>PENTRICH</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0572359350028</lat>
<lon>-1.40935877366898</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENTRICH, a township and a parish in Belper district, Derby. The township lies adjacent to Ryknield-street, the Cromford canal, the river Derwent, and the Midland railway, 2&#189; miles S S W of Alfreton, and 2&#189; E N E of Ambergate r. station; and once had a weekly market. Real property, &#163;4, 147; of which &#163;1, 600 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 486; in 1861, 585. Houses, 116. The parish contains also the chapelry of Ripley, which has a post-office under Derby. Acres, 3, 889. Real property, &#163;40,007; of which &#163;19, 458 are in mines, and &#163;7, 647 in ironworks. Pop. in 1851, 3, 557; in 1861, 5, 829. Houses, 1, 166. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of collieries and ironworks. The property is much subdivided. The manor of Pentrich belongs to the Duke of Devonshire; and that of Ripley, to J. Woolley, Esq., and the executors of the late J.Topham, Esq. Butterley Hall, Butterley Carr, Scarsdale House, and the Elms, are chief residences. A tunnel of the Cromford canal is here, 8, 898 feet long. A Roman settlement was at Coneygree. Serious disturbances, with destruction of several houses, occurred in 1817. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, the Duke of Devonshire. The church is ancient but good; stands on a rising ground; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and contains several ancient monuments. The p. curacy of Ripley is a separate benefice. There are a Calvinistic chapel and a parochial school in Pentrich; and five dissenting chapels, a mechanics&apos; institute, and a national school in. Ripley. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentrich</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Pentrich/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640395</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10184575</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PENTRICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10206133</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>PENTRICH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
