<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5244</id>
<name>REPTON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8128856558409</lat>
<lon>-1.53285883206427</lon>
<gazetteerText>REPTON, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Derby. The village stands on an affluent of the river Trent, 1&#188; mile S E of Willington and Repton r. station, and 4&#188; N E of Burton-upon-Trent; was known, in the Saxon times, as Hreopandune, Reppandune, and Repindon; was a seat of the Mercian kings; was afterwards a market-town; and now has a post-office&#8225; under Burton-upon-Trent, and fairs on the third Monday of April and Nov. The parish contains also the chapelry of Bretby and the hamlet of Milton. Acres, 6, 440. Real property, &#163;12, 207. Pop., 2, 177. Houses, 444. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Sir R. Burdett, Bart., and Sir J. H. Crewe, Bart. R. Park and the Hayes are chief residences. A nunnery was founded here before 660; was the burial-place of Ethelbald I.; was burnt by the Danes in 873; and is believed to be represented by a curious extant crypt beneath the parish church. A black priory was founded on the site of the nunnery, in 1172, by Matilda, wife of Earl Ranulph; was given, at the dissolution, to the Thackers; and is represented by part of the buildings of the grammar school. A discovery was made, in Jan.1867, within the grammar school&apos;s grounds, of a structure supposed to have been used by the monks for the manufacture of encaustic tiles. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;140.* Patron, Sir J. H. Crewe, Bart. The church is chiefly Norman, includes portions of later dates, and has a fine spire, 198feet high. The donative of Bretby is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, an endowed grammar school, and charities &#163;27. The school is a large building; had Lightfoot the Hebraist as an usher, and Shaw the Staffordshire historian, and Scott the translator of the &quot; Arabian Nights, &quot; as pupils; is a conjoint institution with Etwall hospital; and has &#163;2, 569 a year from endowment, and two exhibitions of &#163;50 a year at either Oxford or Cambridge.&#151;The sub-district contains also 7 other parishes, and parts of 3 others; and is in Burton-upon-Trent district. Acres, 27, 430. Pop., 6, 484. Houses, 1, 280. The hundred bears the name of Repton and Gresley; and contains 22 parishes, and parts of 6 others. Acres, 55, 938. Pop. in 1851, 21, 800: in 1861, 23, 859. Houses, 5,042. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Repton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Repton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639489</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10084015</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>REPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10140780</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>REPTON AND GRESLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173693</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>REPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10184587</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>REPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550490</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>REPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578966</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>REPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578978</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>REPTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4136</id>
<name>SHARDLOW</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8711785822846</lat>
<lon>-1.34428918267126</lon>
<gazetteerText>SHARDLOW, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Derbyshire. The village stands near the river Trent, 2 miles S of Draycott r. station, and 6&#189; E S E of Derby; and has a post-office under Derby. The parish contains also the village of Great Wilne, and comprises 1, 580 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 848. Pop. in 1851, 1, 121; in 1861, 945, of whom 136 were in the workhouse. Houses, 191. The property is subdivided. S. Hall is the seat of J. Sutton, Esq. Cavendish Bridgeover the Trent, near the village, was built in 1771, at a cost of &#163;3, 333. The Trent and Mersey canal joins the Trent about &#189; a mile below the village, and has here timber and coal wharves. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, J. Sutton, Esq. The church is good, and has a pinnacled tower. There are chapels for Wesleyans and New Connexion Methodists, and a parochial school.&#151;The sub-district contains six parishes and parts of three others. Acres, 11, 586. Pop., 4, 454. Houses, 959. The district comprehends also the sub-districts of Spondon, Stapleford, Melbourne, and Castle-Donington. Acres, 73, 290. Poor-rates in 1863, &#163;13, 221. Pop. in 1851, 32, 322; in 1861, 31, 113. Houses, 7,006. Marriages in 1863, 191; births, 1,030, of which 91 were illegitimate; deaths, 612, of which 197 were at ages under 5 years, and 24 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 2,060; births, 10, 118; deaths, 6, 443. The places of worship, in 1851, were 44 of the Church of England, with 10, 966 sittings; 6 of Independents, with 1, 173 s.; 10 of Baptists, with 2, 371 s.; 1 of Quakers, with 200 s.; 31 of Wesleyans, with 4, 997 s.; 6 of New Connexion Methodists, with 1, 421 s.; 15 of Primitive Methodists, with 1, 289s.; 4 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 435 s.; 1 of Moravians, with 227 s.; and 1 of the New Church, with 110s. The schools were 43 public day schools, with 3, 132 scholars; 70 private day schools, with 1, 595 s.; 84 Sunday schools, with 6, 580 s.; and 5 evening schools for adults, with 95 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shardlow</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Shardlow</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638127</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Shardlow/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10005097</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>SHARDLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10022113</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHARDLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10042823</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>SHARDLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10131674</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>SHARDLOW AND GREAT WILNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10220786</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>SHARDLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544737</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHARDLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12751631</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>DERBYSHIRE SOUTHERN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12757815</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>DERBYSHIRE SOUTHERN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
