<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2363</id>
<name>HARTSHORNE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7855092930713</lat>
<lon>-1.5215121482477</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARTSHORN, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in the district of Ashby-de-la-Zouch, and county of Derby. The village stands 3 miles W of the boundary with Leicestershire, and 3 &#189; NW of Ashby-de-le-Zouch r. station: and has a post office under Burton-upon-Trent. The parish comprises 2, 510 acres. Real property, &#163;6, 618. Pop. in 1851, 1, 350; in 1861, 1, 541. Houses, 315. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of coal mining and pottery manufacture. The property is divided among a few. An old manor House is occupied by Mrs. Mansfield. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;540. * Patrons, the Earl of Chesterfield and Nadin, Esq. The church is ancient, with a tower; and was partly re-built in 1835. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, an endowed school with &#163;77, other charities with &#163;13, a handsome new girls&apos; school, mainly supported by the rector.&#151;The sub-district contains also three other parishes, parts of two more, and an extra-parochial tract in Derbyshire, and parts of three parishes in Leicestershire. Acres, 14, 007. Pop., 6, 207. Houses, 1, 319. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartshorne</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Hartshorne/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647390</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10003040</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>HARTSHORN AND SEALS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10051903</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HARTSHORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10070454</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARTSHORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551626</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HARTSHORN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574602</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HARTSHORN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
