<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>810</id>
<name>BRAMPTON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2427803073515</lat>
<lon>-1.4964528664142</lon>
<gazetteerText>BRAMPTON, a parish in Chesterfield district, Derby; 3&#189; miles W by N of Chesterfield r. station. It includes the village of Culthorpe; and has two post offices, of the names of Old Brampton and New Brampton, under Chesterfield. Acres, 8,820. Real property, &#163;10,141. Pop., 4,927. Houses, 1,051. The property is much subdivided. Brampton Hall is the seat of the Dicksons. Coal and iron ore are found; and pottery-ware, lace, and stockings are manufactured. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Lichfield. The parish church is tolerable. St. Thomas&apos;s church is a Gothic structure with a tower; was erected in 1832, at a cost of &#163;2,930; and is served by a rector, with income of &#163;300,* appointed by the bishop. There are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, an endowed school, two national schools, and charities &#163;74. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/OldBrampton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brampton,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641039</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10070065</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BRAMPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10137226</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BRAMPTON AND WALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10174557</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BRAMPTON AND WALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570323</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BRAMPTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
