<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3816</id>
<name>BEIGHTON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3438800123394</lat>
<lon>-1.36149941036571</lon>
<gazetteerText>BEIGHTON, a parish and a subdistrict in the district of Rotherham and county of Derby. The parish lies on the river Rother, and on the Eckington and Sheffield railway, 3 miles N of Eckington; contains a charmingly situated village of its own name; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Sheffield. Acres, 3,070. Real property, &#163;8,864,-of which &#163;4,000 are in mines. Pop. 1,284. Houses, 263. Medicinal waters, which have been long in repute, are at Birley; and scythes and sickles are manufactured at Hackenthorpe. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;312.* Patron, Earl Manvers. The church was partly restored, partly rebuilt, in 1869. There are a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;34.-The subdistrict, in addition to Beighton parish in Derby, comprises two parishes and part of another in Yorkshire. Acres, 10,656. Pop., 3,279. Houses, 675. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beighton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Beighton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656000</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10012533</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BEIGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10120044</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BEIGHTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>607</id>
   <name>HANDSWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2945</id>
   <name>ECKINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11231</id>
   <name>ASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11982</id>
   <name>CATCLIFFE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13846</id>
   <name>ORGREAVE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14396</id>
   <name>TREETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
