<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3240</id>
<name>KNIVETON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0445591132891</lat>
<lon>-1.69045943776797</lon>
<gazetteerText>KNIVETON, a parish, with a village, in Ashborne district, Derby; 3 miles NE of Ashborne r. station. Post town, Ashborne. Acres, 2, 240. Real property, . &#163;3, 683. Pop., 315. Houses, 73. Most of the land is. rich pasture. Here are a cotton mill and lime worksThe living is a p. curacy in the diocese of LichfieldValue, &#163;64. Patron, John Harrison, Esq. The church is ancient; and has a good Norman door, and a low tower and spire. There are a Primitive Methodist chapel, a free school, and charities &#163;11. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kniveton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Kniveton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645149</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018791</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KNIVETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10094938</id>
   <status>Ch/CP/AP</status>
   <name>KNIVETON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5498</id>
<name>BRADBOURNE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0865705266952</lat>
<lon>-1.67606479908302</lon>
<gazetteerText>BRADBOURNE, a township in Ashborne district, and a parish in Ashborne and Bakewell districts, Derby. The township lies on an affluent of the river Dove, 5 miles NNE of Ashborne r. station. Real property, &#163;2,733. Pop., 144. Houses, 28.&#151;The parish contains also the townships of Brassington, Ballidon, and Aldwark, the hamlet of Lea-Hall, and the chapelry of Atlow; and its Post Town is Brassington, under Wirksworth. Acres, 6,253. Real property, &#163;13,699. Pop., 1,187. Houses, 248. The property is subdivided. Bradbourne Hall is a chief residence. Tissington Hall is the seat of Sir William Fitzherbert, Bart. Limestone is abundant. Roman coins have been found. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Ballidon, in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;119. Patron, the Duke of Devonshire. The church has a Norman tower, and is good. The chapelries of Brassington and Atlow are separate benefices. Charities, &#163;21. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bradbourne</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Bradbourne/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655002</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10126708</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BRADBOURNE WITH BALLIDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10196164</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BRADBOURNE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
