<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5223</id>
<name>MICKLEOVER</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8972429689682</lat>
<lon>-1.53943070495956</lon>
<gazetteerText>MICKLEOVER, a village, a township, and a parish in Derbyshire; the village and the township in the district of Burton-upon-Trent, and the parish partly also in the district of Shardlow. The village stands near Ryknield-street, 3&#189; miles SW of Derby r. station; and has a post office under Derby. The township includes the village, and extends into the country. Real property, &#163;5,550. Pop. in 1851,791; in 1861,1,101. Houses, 165. The increase of pop. was caused by the erection of the County lunatic asylum. The parish contains also the townships of Findern and Littleover. Acres, 5,330. Real property, &#163;13,086. Pop. in 1851,1,809; in 1861, 2,104. Houses, 386. The property is much subdivided. The Pastures is the seat of Sir Hugh S. Blane, Bart.; the Limes, of Mrs. Wright; the Manor House, ofE. Newton, Esq.; the Lodge, of the Hon. and Rev. A. L. Powys; and Mickleover House, of M. Harvey, Esq. The County lunatic asylum stands on an estate of 79 acres, &#190; of a mile SW of the village; was built in 1851, and extended in 1862; has capacity for 350 patients; and is a splendid structure. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelries of Findern and Littleover, in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;562.* Patron, Lord Scarsdale. The church is geometric decorated English: was restored in 1859; and consists of nave, S aisle, and chancel, with a tower. There are churches also in Findern and Littleover, chapels for Baptists and Primitive Methodists in Mickleover, and a Wesleyan chapel and a free school in Findern. Charities, &#163;87. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Mickleover/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mickleover</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642640</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093880</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MICKLEOVER ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10182797</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MICKLEOVER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
