<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2696</id>
<name>TIDESWELL</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2820557221164</lat>
<lon>-1.79480166797652</lon>
<gazetteerText>TIDESWELL, a small town, a township, and a sub-district, in Bakewell district, and a parish partly also in Chapel-en-le-Frith district, Derby. The town stands in a valley almost surrounded with bleak hills, 2&#189; miles N of Millers-Dale r. station, and 6&#190; E by N of Buxton; is said to have got its name from a well which was intermittent, but which has long ceased to be so; dates from very early times; is a polling place; and has a post-office&#8225; under Sheffield, a hotel, a decorated English church with pinnacled tower, three dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, an endowed grammar-school with &#163;227 a year, charities &#163;32, a weekly market on Wednesday, and five annual fairs. -The township includes the town, and extends into the country. Real property, &#163;4,750. Pop., 2,057. Houses, 423.&#151;The parish contains also Litton and Wheston hamlets, and Wormhill township; and comprises 10,950 acres. Pop., 3,512. Houses, 697. T. manor belongs to the Duke of Devonshire; Litton manor, to Lord Scarsdale; Wormhill manor, to T. W. Bagshawe, Esq. Much of the surface exhibits romantic scenery. Lead mines are in Litton; and cotton-mills are in Litton and at Cressbrook. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;230.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of L. The p. curacy of Wormhill is a separate benefice. A Methodist chapel is in Litton.&#151;The sub-district contains 10 townships, 2 lordships, 8 hamlets, and a chapelry. Pop., 9,016. Houses, 1,864. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Tideswell/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tideswell</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635851</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10053730</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TIDESWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10070200</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TIDESWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544701</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TIDESWELL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3004</id>
   <name>WHESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
