<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1589</id>
<name>ASHOVER</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1644545347999</lat>
<lon>-1.49328484097528</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHOVER, a village, a township, a parish, and a sub district in Derby. The village stands in a deep narrow valley, near the rivers Amber and Milntown, 3 miles WNW of Stretton r. station, and 7 SSW of Chesterfield. It is a place of great antiquity; had a church at Domes day; and was once a market-town. Fairs are still held at it on 25 April and 15 Oct.; and it has a post office under Chesterfield. Lace-making is carried on. Tam bour-working and stocking-weaving also were once pro minent; but the former has ceased, and the latter is de clining.-The township includes the village, and is in the district of Chesterfield. Acres, 9,180. Real pro perty, &#163;9,732. Pop., 2,351. Houses, 542.&#151;The parish includes also the chapelry of Dethwick-Lea, in the district of Belper. Acres, 11,290. Real property, &#163;13,206. Pop., 3,286. Houses, 748. The property is much sub divided. Limestone is quarried; and lead ore was formerly mined. Overton Hall was the seat of Sir Jo seph Banks, the president of the Royal Society. Deth wick was the seat of the Babingtons; one of whom was executed for treason against Queen Elizabeth. Lea Hurst, a fine Gothic mansion, is the seat of the Nightin gales. Robin Hood&apos;s Mark, a rocking-stone about 26 feet in circuit, is on a slope of Ashover Common; and the Turning-stone, a remarkably shaped block 9 feet high, supposed to have been an object of Druidical veneration, is about 200 yards further off. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;540.* Patron, the Rev. J. Nodder. The church was built in 1419, and recently repaired; is surmounted by an embattled tower, and a handsome spire; has a grand window of stained glass, set up in 1845; and contains tombs of the Babingtons and two brasses. an endowed school, at High Ashover, has &#163;28, and other charities &#163;12. The p. curacy of Dethwick-Lea is a separate benefice. There are Wesleyan and Primitive Methodist chapels.-The subdistrict of Ashover is in Chesterfield district, and contains two parishes, and parts of three others. Acres, 21,234. Pop., 10,757. Houses, 2,106. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Ashover/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656930</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashover</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10012429</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Tn</status>
   <name>ASHOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10048047</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASHOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544798</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ASHOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10568936</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ASHOVER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
