<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4848</id>
<name>YOULGREAVE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1648820303223</lat>
<lon>-1.68975719791343</lon>
<gazetteerText>YOULGREAVE, a township and a parish in Bakewell district, Derby. The township lies 4&#189; miles SSW of Bakewell r. station; contains a village of its own name; and has a post-office under Bakewell. Real property, &#163;6,189; of which &#163;1,291 are in mines. Pop., 1,230. Houses, 264. The manor belongs to the Duke of Rutland. The parish contains six other townships, and comprises 12,200 acres. Pop., 3,738. Houses, 838. The property is much subdivided. Lombardale Hall is. the seat of the Bateman family, and contains a large museum of local antiquities. There are, in the parish, a complete Druidical circle and many barrows. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;210.* Pattron the Duke of Devonshire. The church is ancient. The rectory of Elton and the vicarage of Winster are separate benefices. There are four dissenting chapels, a reading room, and an endowed school with &#163;25 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Youlgreave</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Youlgreave/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633346</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10165544</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>YOULGREAVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10204306</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>YOULGREAVE WITH MIDDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10583135</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>YOULGREAVE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2702</id>
   <name>GRATTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3034</id>
   <name>HARTHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4081</id>
   <name>MIDDLETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4812</id>
   <name>NETHER HADDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5901</id>
   <name>GREAT ROWSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
