<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1166</id>
<name>MATLOCK</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.143320596533</lat>
<lon>-1.56775887541709</lon>
<gazetteerText>Matlock, town and par., Derbyshire, on river Derwent - par., 4539 ac., pop. 6093; town (ry. sta. Matlock Bridge), 17 miles NW. of Derby and 144 miles NW. of London by rail, pop. 4395; 1 Bank, and P.O., T.O., and 3 Banks at Matlock Bridge; the par. contains Matlock Bath, town with ry. sta., 1 mile S. of Matlock, pop. (including Scarthin Nick) 1698; P.O., T.O.; Market-day, Saturday; also Matlock Bank, 1 mile N. of Matlock; P.O., T.O. Matlock Bath is the celebrated place for medicinal waters, which were first used for curative purposes in 1698. The locality is likewise famed for its beautifully romantic scenery. There are several large stalactite caverns. Most of the inhabitants of the town of Matlock are engaged in the mfr. of cotton goods and spar ornaments; but there are also paper mills (at Matlock Bath), corn mills, and bleachworks, and in the vicinity are lead-mines. The rising district of Matlock Bank is well known for its hydropathic establishments. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matlock</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matlock_Bath</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Matlock/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642910</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10062135</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10062147</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>THE MATLOCKS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10067388</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BATH AND SCARTHIN NICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10070612</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10076031</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109310</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127970</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10153852</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BATH AND SCARTHIN NICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154686</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163833</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544683</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833489</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MATLOCK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>323</id>
   <name>NORTH DARLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>109</id>
   <name>SOUTH DARLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4148</id>
   <name>TANSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2350</id>
   <name>CRICH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4158</id>
   <name>WINSTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1750</id>
   <name>BIRCHOVER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4144</id>
   <name>STANTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3815</id>
   <name>BEELEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4035</id>
   <name>DARLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3206</id>
   <name>ELTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4040</id>
   <name>DETHICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4153</id>
   <name>WENSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>24501</id>
<name>MATLOCK BANK</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1440699394079</lat>
<lon>-1.54096961796674</lon>
<gazetteerText>MATLOCK-BANK, a hamlet in Matlock parish, Derbyshire; near Matlock-Bridge. It has one large hydropathic establishment, three others of considerable size, and four smaller ones, all delightfully situated, and containing excellent accommodation. It has also an Independent chapel and a Primitive Methodist chapel; and the former was built in 1866, is in the early English style, has a tower and spire, contains 540 sittings, and cost about &#163;2,100. Bridge House is the residence of J. Cash, Esq.; and Balmoral House, of Mr. A. Morrell. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642909</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10127968</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MATLOCK BANK</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25957</id>
<name>MATLOCK BRIDGE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1378282315062</lat>
<lon>-1.55449119783515</lon>
<gazetteerText>MATLOCK-BRIDGE, a hamlet in Matlock parish, Derbyshire; on the river Derwent, and on the Manchester and Buxton railway, &#189; a mile NW of Matlock village. It has a station on the railway, a post office under Matlock-Bath, and a Wesleyan chapel. A company was formed in 1866 to erect at it a hotel, a market-hall, and assembly-room; and the market-hall was opened in 1868. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
</results>
