<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4077</id>
<name>LONGFORD</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9356375662255</lat>
<lon>-1.68096154136228</lon>
<gazetteerText>LONGFORD, a township and a parish in Ashborne district, Derby. The township lies on an affluent of the river Dove, 5&#190; miles SSE of Ashborne r. station; and has a post office under Derby. Real property, &#163;5,312. Pop., 500. Houses, 95. The parish contains also the townships of Hollington, Rodsley, and Alkmonton, and the liberty of Hungry-Bentley. Acres, 3,920. Real property, &#163;10,418. Pop., 1,157. Houses, 228. The property is not much divided. The manors of Longford, Hollington, and Rodsley belong to the Hon. E. K. W. Coke; and that of Hungry-Bentley belongs to Lord Vernon. Longford Hall is the seat of the Hon. E. K. W. Coke. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;700. * Patron, W. Evans, Esq. The church is partly Norman; was restored in 1843; comprises nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and contains monuments to the Coke family. The vicarage of Alkmouton is a separate benefice. There was once a chapel in Hungry-Bentley. There are a national school in Longford township; a Primitive Methodist chapel in Hollington; Wesleyan chapels in Rodsley and in Thurvaston; a national school for boys and girls, an endowed school, with &#163;40 a year, and alms houses with &#163;55, founded by the Coke family. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Longford,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Longford/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643692</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10052075</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONGFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10127877</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LONGFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10576465</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LONGFORD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1823</id>
   <name>RODSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2707</id>
   <name>HOLLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3191</id>
   <name>ALKMONTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4023</id>
   <name>HUNGRY BENTLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
