<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4135</id>
<name>SAWLEY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8858129087587</lat>
<lon>-1.29950522524281</lon>
<gazetteerText>SAWLEY, a village, a township, and a parish, in Shardlow district, Derbyshire. The village stands on the river Trent, near the Grand Trunk canal and the Derby and Nottingham railway, 8&#189; miles E S E of Derby; was once a market town; and has a post-office under Derby, a r. station, and a fair on 12 Nov. The township contains also Wilsthorpe village, and comprises 1, 915 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 557. Pop., 1,082. Houses, 252. The parish contains likewise the township of Long Eaton, and comprises 3, 834 acres. Pop. in 1851, 1, 934; in 1861, 2, 633. Houses, 588. The increase of pop. arose fromfacilities of railway communication, and from erection of steam-factories. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to the Earl of Harrington. The constructing of railway -carriage and railway -wheel works, and the making of fancy nets, are carried on. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Lichfield. The church is ancient, and has a tower and lofty spire. The p. curacy of Long Eaton is a separate benefice. Three dissenting chapels, a national school, and charities &#163;34, are in Sawley; and five dissenting chapels, a national school, and alms-houses are in Long Eaton. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sawley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638476</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Sawley/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10022095</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>SAWLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10053584</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SAWLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10131650</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>SAWLEY AND WILSTHORPE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
