<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>324</id>
<name>WIRKSWORTH</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0848266958706</lat>
<lon>-1.5681028147195</lon>
<gazetteerText>WIRKSWORTH, a town, a township, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Derbyshire. The town stands in a valley, nearly surrounded by hills, at the terminus of a branch of the Midland railway, and at the southern extremity of a mining region, 13&#190; miles NNW of Derby; was known to the Saxous as Werchesvorde; belonged, before the Norman conquest, to Repton abbey; passed, through the Ferrerses and other s, to the Duchy of Lancaster; is a seat of petty-sessions and county courts, and a polling place; carries on malting, and the manufacture of silk, gingham, and tape; engages largely in the working of neighbouring lead mines; publishes a weekly newspaper; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a r. station, a banking office, two hotels, a police station, a moot-hall of 1814, a temperance hall, a church of the 13th century, with chancel restored in 1855, and with a tower and spire, four dis senting chapels, a mechanics&apos; institution, an endowed grammar-school rebuilt in 1828, with &#163;180 a year, alms houses with &#163;55 a year, other charities &#163;186, a weekly market on Tuesday, and five annual fairs. Pop. in 1861, 2,592. houses, 637.-The township comprises 8,497 acres. Real property, &#163;18,615; of which &#163;5,142 are in mines, &#163;1,346 in quarries, and &#163;148 in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 3,923; in 1861, 3,717. Houses, 900.&#151;The parish contains four townships in Belper district, five in Ashborne district, and two in Bakewell district; and comprises 14,154 acres. Pop. in 1851, 7,498: in 1861, 7,098. Houses, 1,623. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of L. The vicarages of Middleton and Idridgehay, and the p. curacy of Cromford, are separate benefices.&#151;The sub-district contains the four W. townships of Belper district, and two townships and a chapelry of other parishes. Acres, 14,348. Pop., 6,072. Houses, 1,388.-The hundred contains 13 parishes and 6 parts. Acres, 72,177. Pop. in 1851, 22,503; in 1861, 23,901. Houses, 5,242. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wirksworth</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Wirksworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633774</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10029351</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10042835</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10053810</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10112230</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10185622</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10218500</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544660</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582751</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12742204</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>DERBYSHIRE WESTERN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5877</id>
   <name>ASHLEYHAY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4068</id>
   <name>KIRK IRETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5199</id>
   <name>BRASSINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2998</id>
   <name>CARSINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1758</id>
   <name>CROMFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3429</id>
   <name>MIDDLETON BY WIRKSWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>669</id>
   <name>BONSALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2365</id>
   <name>HOGNASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1588</id>
   <name>ALDERWASLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1776</id>
   <name>IDRIDGEHAY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
