<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>695</id>
<name>HEANOR</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0278959758079</lat>
<lon>-1.3553709319688</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEANOR, a village, a township, and a parish in the district of Basford and county of Derby. The village stands near the Erewash river, canal, and railway, and the boundary with Notts, 1 mile WSW of Langley mills r. station, and 6 E by S of Belper; is lighted with gas, and governed by a board of health; was formerly a market town; and has now a post office&#8225; under Derby, and fairs on Old Martinmas day and 23 Nov.-The township comprises 1, 535 acres. Real property, &#163;8, 264; of which &#163;303 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 3, 427; in 1861, 4, 084. Houses, 846. The increase of pop. arose from the operations of a building society, and from the extension of coal mining and iron manufacture.&#151;The parish contains also the township of Shipley, and the hamlets of Codnor and Loscoe. Acres, 6, 870. Real property, &#163;24, 157: of which &#163;6, 826 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, subdivided. Heanor Hall is the seat of John Ray, Esq. Hosiery and silk blonde lace are extensively manufactured. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;169. * Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is early English; belonged once to Dale abbey; consists of nave, S aisle, and chancel, with a square tower; contains several monuments to the Mundy family, and one to the native sculptor, Samuel Watson; and was recently in rather bad condition. A new cemetery, with two conjoint chapels, surmounted by tower and spire, was opened in 1858. The vicarage of Codnor is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Quakers, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and charities &#163;10. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heanor</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Heanor/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647227</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018640</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEANOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10070480</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HEANOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135187</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HEANOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10187473</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HEANOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574791</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEANOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12836478</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEANOR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>765</id>
   <name>EASTWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2349</id>
   <name>CODNOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7278</id>
   <name>BRINSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
