<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1784</id>
<name>MELBOURNE</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8243551249968</lat>
<lon>-1.4226732206671</lon>
<gazetteerText>MELBOURNE, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Shardlow district, Derbyshire. The town stands on an affluent of the river Trent, and on the Derby and Ashby-de-la-Zouch railway, completed from Derby to Melbourne in 1867, but not to Ashby till after June 1869; is 7 miles, by railway, SSE of Derby; has a station on the railway, a post office&#8224; under Derby, several inns, a market-place, a church, five dissenting chapels, a public cemetery, an athen&#230;um, an endowed national school, and charities &#163;20; and gave the title of Viscount to the family of Lamb. The church is chiefly Norman, with a tower of much later date; was recently restored internally, at a cost of &#163;3,000; and. contains monuments, of the 14th and the 17th centuries, to the Hardinge family. The Independent chapel was enlarged in 1865. The Sweden borgian chapel was built in 1864, at a cost of &#163;1,000; and is a neat small structure, in the Gothic style. The public cemetery lies about &#188; of a mile from the town, and was formed at a cost of &#163;2,000. The atheu&#230;um was opened in 1854, as a mechanics&apos; institute; and was built by subscription. A weekly market is held on Saturday evenings; and the manufacture of silk and thread goods is carried on.&#151;The parish contains also the township of Kings-Newton, and comprises 3,290 acres. Real property, &#163;12,420; of which &#163;110 are in gas-works. Pop., 2,621. Houses, 620. The manor belonged, at Domesday, to the Crown; passed to the Beauchamps and the Lancasters; and belongs now to the Marquis of Hastings. A royal castle stood here; was several times visitcd by King John; was the prison, for 19 years, of the Duke of Bourbon, taken at the battle of Agincourt; was dismantled in 1460; and is now represented by only a small portion of the outer walls. A palace of the Bishops of Carlisle stood on the S bank of the pool; and was several times visited by King John. Melbourne-Hall belongs to Viscountess Palmerston; occupies the site of a palace of the Bishops of Carlisle; was built by Sir Thomas Coke in 1712; was the place where Baxter began to write his &quot;Saints&apos; Rest;&apos;&apos; and has gardens in the Dutch style, introduced by William III. Kings-Newton Hall belonged to the Hardinge family, gave entertainment to Charles II., and was destroyed by fire in 1859. Marketgardening is extensively carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;200.* Patron, the Bishop of Lichfield.&#151;The sub-district contains also three other parishes, parts of two others, an extraparochial tract, and Derby-Hills liberty. Acres, 15,143. Pop., 4,694. Houses, 1,087. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melbourne,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Melbourne/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642801</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018936</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MELBOURNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10182750</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MELBOURNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544749</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MELBOURNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10576969</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MELBOURNE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2360</id>
   <name>FOREMARK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3259</id>
   <name>TICKNALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5250</id>
   <name>STANTON BY BRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10611</id>
   <name>BELTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10646</id>
   <name>BREEDON ON THE HILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10675</id>
   <name>CASTLE DONINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10723</id>
   <name>DISEWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10962</id>
   <name>KEGWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11131</id>
   <name>LOCKINGTON HEMINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11296</id>
   <name>STAUNTON HAROLD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
