<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3429</id>
<name>MIDDLETON BY WIRKSWORTH</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1010800183172</lat>
<lon>-1.59121310718426</lon>
<gazetteerText>MIDDLETON-BY-WIRKSWORTH, a village, a township, and a chapelry in Wirksworth parish, Derby. The village stands 1 mile NW by N of Wirksworth r. station, and 2 WSW of Cromford; is a considerable place; and has a post office under Wirksworth. The township includes the village, and extends into the country. Real property, &#163;2,129; of which &#163;252 are in quarries, and &#163;34 in mines. Pop., 964. Houses, 221. Ash-Hill is the seat of W. Wheatcroft, Esq. Excellent marble is quarried, and lead ore is mined.-T he chapelry includes also Ible, Griff-Grange, Ivonbrook-Grange, and parts of Wirksworth, Cromford and Hopton townships; and was constituted in 1847. Pop., 1,133. Houses, 259. Most of Griff-Grange belongs to the trustees of the late P. Gell, Esq.; and all IvonbrookGrange belongs to Lord Scarsdale. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Vicar of Wirksworth. The church was built in 1839 at a cost of &#163;1,200; and contains 413 sittings. There are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, and a neat new school, in M. township; a chapel for Primitive Methodists in Ible township; and a school church in Ivonbrook-Grange. Charities, &#163;25. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/MiddletonWirksworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Middleton-by-Wirksworth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642595</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10102066</id>
   <status>CP/Hmlt</status>
   <name>MIDDLETON BY WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10128043</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MIDDLETON BY WIRKSWORTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4815</id>
   <name>HOPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>4081</id>
<name>MIDDLETON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1652706826885</lat>
<lon>-1.7067943737985</lon>
<gazetteerText>MIDDLETON, a township, conjoint with Smerril, in Youlgreave parish, Derby; 5 miles SSW of Bakewell. Acres, 2,300. Real property, &#163;3,115. Pop., 244. Houses, 50. Lombardale Hall is the seat of the Batemans; and was the residence of the late T. Bateman, Esq., who investigated the antiquities of the county, and formed a large museum. Arborlowes Ring is a complete Druidical circle; and there are many barrows, in which Celtic relics have been found. A chapel of ease was built in 1865; and there is a dissenting chapel, built by the late T. Bateman, Esq. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/MiddletonYoulgreave/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Middleton-by-Youlgreave</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642594</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10128020</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>MIDDLETON AND SMERRILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2385</id>
<name>STONY MIDDLETON</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2719173199713</lat>
<lon>-1.67693657965708</lon>
<gazetteerText>MIDDLETON-STONEY, a village and a chapelry in Hathersage parish, Derby. The village stands at the entrance of Middleton dale, on an affluent of the river Derwent, 3&#189; miles N by E of Hassop r. station, and 4&#189; N by E of Bakewell; is a very picturesque place, with some houses at the foot of cliffs, and others on successive ledges of steep rock; and has a post office under Sheffield, and a warm spring with baths. The spring is supposed to have been known and used by the Romans; was covered by erections of old date; and is now enclosed in baths rebuilt by the late Lord Denman. The chapelry comprises 1,310 acres. Real property, &#163;2,191. Pop., 608. Houses, 132. The property is much subdivided. Stoney-Middleton House is the seat of Lord Denman. Middleton dale is a highly romantic glen. The rocks are chiefly limestone, and they abound in lead ore. Several lime-kilns are in the dale; and there are places for smelting ore and manufacturing barytes. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;110. Patron, the Vicar of Hathersage. The church was rebuilt in 1767; retains a tower of more ancient date; and has the form of an octagon. There are chapels for Presbytcrians and Wesleyans, an endowed school, and charities &#163;20. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/StoneyMiddleton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoney_Middleton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636796</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10053687</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>STONY MIDDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10072542</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONY MIDDLETON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2691</id>
   <name>CALVER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
