<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4833</id>
<name>MORLEY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9709578695483</lat>
<lon>-1.40449136263627</lon>
<gazetteerText>MORLEY, a township and a parish in Belper district, Derbyshire. The township lies 2&#189; miles E of Little Eaton r. station, and 4&#188; NE of Derby; and has a pillar letter-box under Derby. Real property, &#163;2,933. Pop., 230. Houses, 54. The parish contains also the township of Smalley, and comprises 3,513 acres. Real property, &#163;5,992. Pop. in 1851,1,090; in 1861,951. Houses, 213. The property is subdivided. Morley Hall is the seat of R. S. W. Sitwell, Esq.; and Smalley Manor House is the seat of John Radford, Esq. Traces exist of a Roman road. The living is a rectory, united with the chapelry of Smalley, in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;663. * Patron, alternately E. D. Sitwell, Esq. and the Trustees of the late Sir Hugh Bateman, Bart, The church, excepting the tower, was rebuilt in 1850; is in the decorated English style; comprises nave, N aisle, and chancel, with pinnacled tower; and contains some brasses and old monuments of the Stathums and the Sacheverells, and two recent monuments to W. Turbutt, Esq., and the Rev. R. B. Turbutt. There are a Wesleyan chapel in Morley, a chapel of ease and a Baptist chapel in Smalley, national schools in both Morley and Smalley, alms houses with &#163;30 a year in Morley, and charities &#163;50 in Smalley. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morley,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Morley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6619991</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10021832</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MORLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10165143</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MORLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
