<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1286</id>
<name>STAVELEY</name>
<container>DERBYSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2685297320287</lat>
<lon>-1.35178860716453</lon>
<gazetteerText>STAVELEY, a village, a township, and a parish, in Chesterfield district, Derby. The village stands near the Midland railway, 4 miles NE of Chesterfield; and has a post-office&#8225; under Chesterfield, a r. station with telegraph, and a mechanics&apos; institute with library and reading room. The township comprises 6,682 acres. Real property, &#163;27,548; of which &#163;14,170 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 3,998; in 1861, 6,831. Houses, 1,207. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of coal and iron works. The manor belongs to the Duke of Devonshire.&#151;The parish includes Great Barlow chapelry, and comprises 10,442 acres. Pop. in 1851, 4,634; in 1861, 7,513. Houses, 1,344. Ringwood Hall is the seat of R. Barrow, Esq. The Staveley coal and iron works employ upwards of 3,000 persons; and there are manufactories of spades and shovels, a brush manufactory, and corn, cake, and bone-mills. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;706.* Patron, the Duke of Devonshire. The church was enlarged in 1864. The p. curacy of Barlow is a separate benefice. A chapel of ease is at Handley; an endowed hospital, with a chapel, is at Woodthorpe; and a Wesleyan chapel, an endowed school, and charities &#163;80 are at Staveley. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/DBY/Staveley/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Staveley,_Derbyshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636995</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10022265</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>STAVELEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10053663</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STAVELEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10131820</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STAVELEY AND BARROWHILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10153864</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>STAVELEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580535</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STAVELEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12829504</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STAVELEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
