<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8643</id>
<name>RHIWABON</name>
<container>DENBIGHSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9800058500564</lat>
<lon>-3.0212776992477</lon>
<gazetteerText>RUABON, or Rhiwabon, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Wrexham district, Denbigh. The town stands on an affluent of the river Dee, and on the Chester and Shrewsbury railway, adjacent to Offa&apos;s dyke and Wat&apos;s dyke, 4&#189; miles S S W of Wrexham; derives interest from the vicinity of the splendid mansion of Wynnstay, the seat of W. W. Wynn, Bart., and of other handsome seats; conducts much business in connexion withneighbouring iron-works and collieries; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a head post-office, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, a hotel, a church, five dissenting chapels, a grammar school and alms-houses with &#163;200 a year from endowment, another school with &#163;23, other alms-houseswith &#163;50, and other charities &#163;193. The church standsclose to the park-gates of Wynnstay; and contains a curious monument of a son of Sir John Wynn of Gwydir, amarble effigies by Rysbrach of Sir W. Wynn, a statue by Nollekens of Lady Wynn, daughter of the Duke of Buckingham, an altar-tomb of the Eyton family of date 1526, and a monument of Powel who died in 1590, who was anative and vicar, and who wrote &quot; Annotations on Giraldus, &quot; and published &quot; Caradoc&apos;s History of Wales.&quot; Fairs are held on the last Friday of Feb., 22 May, and 20 Nov. The parish includes the townships of Ruabon, Bellan, Bodulltin, Christionydd-Coed, Christionydd-Kenrick, Dynhille-Issa, Dynhille-Ucha, Hafod, Morton-Anglicorum, Morton-Above, Morton-Below, and Ryd-dalt. Acres, 14, 364. Real property, &#163;70, 440; of which &#163;23,012 are in mines, &#163;109 in quarries, &#163;21, 360 in iron-works, and &#163;300 in railway s. Pop. in 1851, 11, 507; in 1861, 14, 343. Houses, 3, 151. The increase of pop.arose from the extension of coal mining. The property is subdivided. Pen-y-Gardden is the seat of Lady Marshall. Plas-Madoc is supposed to have been once a residence of the Princes of Wales, and is now the seat ofH. Whalley, Esq. Plas-Hinas was the seat of Mrs. Rowland. A camp, called Gardden, is on an eminenceabout &#190; of a mile from the town; is defended, in many parts of its circuit, by concentric dykes; and, in its area, shows traces of ancient dwellings. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;588.* Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The p. curacies of Rhos-y-Medre and Rhos-Llannerchrugog are separate benefices.&#151;The sub-district contains also Erbistock parish, and comprises 15, 966 acres. Pop., 14, 680. Houses, 3, 225. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ruabon</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/DEN/Ruabon/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639014</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10298337</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RHIWABON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547532</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RUABON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12782871</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RUABON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>940</id>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1070</id>
   <name>ELLESMERE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1105</id>
   <name>LLANGOLLEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1521</id>
   <name>BRYMBO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2012</id>
   <name>HOPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3725</id>
   <name>BROUGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3840</id>
   <name>CEFN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3844</id>
   <name>CHIRK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8710</id>
   <name>RHOSLLANNERCHRUGOG</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11718</id>
   <name>LLAY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
