<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1616</id>
<name>CERRIGYDRUIDION</name>
<container>DENBIGHSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0417652074835</lat>
<lon>-3.59273630132815</lon>
<gazetteerText>CERRIG-Y-DRUIDION, a village and a parish in the district of Corwen and county of Denbigh. The Village stands on a headstream of the river Dee, on the quondam mail road from London to Holyhead, 10 miles WNW of Corwen r. station, and 13 SSW of Denbigh; and has a post office under Corwen, and fairs on 14 March, 27 April, 27 Aug., 20 Oct., and 7 Dec. The parish includes also the townships of Clustyblaidd, Cwmpenanner, Gwernheurn, Hafod-y-Maidd, Llaethwryd, Park, and Voel. Acres, 11,586. Assessed property, in 1815, &#163;4,016. Pop., 1,243. Houses, 266. The property is much subdivided. The land lies high, and is chiefly moor and upland pasture. A collection of large stones, including cistvaens, was formerly at the village; but has disappeared. An ancient British fort, with a circular rampart, was on Pen-y-Gaer, about a mile to the east; and is said to have been the place where Caractacus was taken prisoner; but is now reduced to slight vestiges. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;500.* Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church is tolerable; and there is a Calvinistic Methodist chapel. An almshouse has &#163;98; and other charities &#163;104. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/DEN/Cerrigydrudion/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299984</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10013239</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CERRIGYDRUIDION</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8479</id>
   <name>PENTREFOELAS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
