<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13888</id>
<name>STALBRIDGE</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.9525020263484</lat>
<lon>-2.37252865441944</lon>
<gazetteerText>STALBRIDGE, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Sturminster district, Dorset. The town stands on an affluent of the river Stour, adjacent to the Somerset and Dorset railway, 6 miles E by N of Sherborne; was known, at Domesday, as Staplebridge; contains a beautiful ancient cross, about 30 feet high; and has a post-office&#8225; under Blandford, a r. station with telegraph, an inn, a partial1y restored ancient church, Independent and Wesleyan chapels, a national school, a fortnightly market on Monday, and fairs on 6 May and 4 Sept. The parish includes three tythings, and comprises 5,681 acres. Real property, &#163;12,179; of which &#163;50 are in quarries. Pop., 1,929. Houses, 411. The manor belonged to Sherborne abbey; passed to the Seymours, the Audleys, the Boyles, and the Walters; and belongs now to the Marquis of Westminster. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;888.* Patron, Corpus Christi College, Cambridge.&#151;The sub-district contains six parishes. Acres, 15,678. Pop. 4,422. Houses, 967. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/Stalbridge/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stalbridge</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637111</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10459023</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>STALBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10459084</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STALBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10565315</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STALBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580470</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STALBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13578</id>
   <name>BISHOPS CAUNDLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13590</id>
   <name>STOURTON CAUNDLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13591</id>
   <name>CAUNDLE MARSH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13633</id>
   <name>FOLKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13651</id>
   <name>HAYDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13670</id>
   <name>HOLWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13686</id>
   <name>LEWESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13691</id>
   <name>LONGBURTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14033</id>
   <name>NORTH WOOTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
