<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13693</id>
<name>WEST LULWORTH</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.6294232508147</lat>
<lon>-2.24762158214092</lon>
<gazetteerText>LULWORTH (WEST), a village and a parish in Wareham district, Dorset. The Village stands under Bindon hill, 5 miles SSW of Wool r. station, and 8&#189; SW by W of Wareham; curves over a length of nearly a mile to the coast; has a post office under Wareham, and a good inn; contains some lodging-houses; is a coast-guard station; and communicates twice a week in summer by steamer with Weymouth. The acreage of the parish is returned with East Lulworth. Real property, &#163;1,549. Pop., 446. Houses, 95. A cove at the end of the village is one of the most romantic inlets on the Dorset coast; has a circular outline, overhung all round by lofty cliffs of chalk and sand; opens to the sea by a narrow passage, between two bluffs of Portland stone; and exhibits, in its engirdling cliffs, a section of all the geognostic formations between the oolite and the chalk. A rock about a mile from the cove is pierced with a natural arch about 40 feet high; and a face of cliff, about a furlong E of the cove, exhibits a number of petrified trees. The living is a Vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;130.* Patron, the Bishop of Salisbury. The church is an old dilapidated structure, with a small tower. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Lulworth</link>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/WestLulworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634353</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10453914</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>WEST LULWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10453926</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST LULWORTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13596</id>
   <name>CHALDON HERRING</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
