<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13702</id>
<name>MARNHULL</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.9661908784288</lat>
<lon>-2.30166246094728</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARNHULL, a village and a parish in Sturminster district, Dorset. The village stands 1 mile E of the river Stonr, 1&#190; SE of the boundary with Somerset, and 3 N of Sturminster-Newton r. station; is large and irregularly built; and has a post office under Blandford. The parish contains also the hamlets of Burton, Keutisford, and Thornton. Acres, 3,751. Real property, with Fifehead-Magdalen, &#163;11,390. Rated property of M. alone, &#163;7,491. Pop., 1,444. Houses, 327. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to John Hussey, Esq. Nash Court is the chief residence; has belonged to the Husseys since the time of Charles II.; was the birthplace of Giles Hussey, the ingenions painter, who drew by the mnsical scale; and contains some choice paintings of the old masters. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;800.* Patron, R. W. Kennard, Esq. The church is large and good, and has a tower. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Roman Catholics, and a parochial school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marnhull</link>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/Marnhull/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643001</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10454130</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MARNHULL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10454141</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARNHULL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13630</id>
   <name>FIFEHEAD MAGDALEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13663</id>
   <name>HINTON ST MARY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13698</id>
   <name>MANSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13981</id>
   <name>TODBER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
