<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13753</id>
<name>NETHERBURY</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.7753318889938</lat>
<lon>-2.76032763916615</lon>
<gazetteerText>NETHERBURY, a tything, a parish, and a sub-district, in Beaminster district, Dorset. The tything lieson the river Brit, 1&#189; mile S S W of Beaminster, and 4&#188; N W of Poorstock r. station; and has a post-office under Brid port. The parish contains also the tythings of Ashe, Bowood, and Melplash, and part of the hamlet of Loscombe. Acres, 6, 225. Real property, &#163;15, 245. Pop. in 1851, 2,066; in 1861, 1,875. Houses, 419. The decrease of pop. was caused mainly by a decline in theflax and hemp trade. The property is much subdivided. The manor-house, formerly the seat of the More family, is now a farm-house. Strode House and Parnham Houseare chief residences. The land is very fertile; and iswatered by numerous streamlets, traversing wooded ravines. A considerable area is occupied by cider orchards. Limestone, very rich in fossils, is quarried. Two flaxmills were long in operation; and there is an iron foundry. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Ashe, in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, the Bishop of Salisbury. The church is later English, in good condition, with a tower; and the chancelwas recently restored, and contains a monument to one of the More family. The p. curacy of Melplash is a separate benefice. There was formerly a chapel of ease at Mangerton. There are several dissenting chapels, amixed national school, a grammar-school with &#163;140 a year from endowment, and charities &#163;64.&#151;The sub-district contains also six other parishes. Acres, 20, 366. Pop., 4, 971. Houses, 1,051. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/Netherbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netherbury</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641789</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10455595</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NETHERBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10455613</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NETHERBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10538658</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NETHERBURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13519</id>
   <name>BETTISCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13703</id>
   <name>MARSHWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13795</id>
   <name>PILSON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13937</id>
   <name>STOKE ABBOTT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
