<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14045</id>
<name>YETMINSTER</name>
<container>DORSET</container>
<lat>50.8852012445909</lat>
<lon>-2.56805450271604</lon>
<gazetteerText>YETMINSTER, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Dorset. The village stands on the Dorchester and Yeovil railway, 4&#190; miles SSE of Yeovil; was once a market-town; and now has a post-office under Sherborne, a r. station, and fairs on 23 Apriland 1 Oct. The parish includes Leigh and Chetnole chapelries, and comprises 4,321 acres. Real property, &#163;8,646. Pop. in 1851, 1,333; in 1861, 1,430. Houses, 294. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, the Bishop of S. The church is old. A chapel of ease is in Chetnole: and the vicarage of Leigh is a separate benefice. There are two national schools, and charities &#163;121.&#151;The sub-district contains 14 parishes and an extra-parochial tract, and is in Sherborne district. Acres, 20,715. Pop., 4,298. Houses, 904.-The hundred contains 7 parishes, and is in Cerne and Sherborne divisions. Acres, 2,336 and 6,767. Pop. in 1851, 384 and 1,769. Houses, 71 and 361. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yetminster</link>
<link>http://www.uk-genealogy.org.uk/genuki/DOR/Yetminster/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633366</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10091561</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>YETMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10462964</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>YETMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10462990</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>YETMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10538622</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>YETMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13516</id>
   <name>BEER HACKETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13604</id>
   <name>CHETNOLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13654</id>
   <name>HILFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13666</id>
   <name>HOLNEST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13685</id>
   <name>LEIGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13687</id>
   <name>LILLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13718</id>
   <name>MELBURY OSMOND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13858</id>
   <name>RYME INSTRINSECA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13935</id>
   <name>STOCKWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
