<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6905</id>
<name>SPRINGFIELD</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.7470512672335</lat>
<lon>0.504988723552174</lon>
<gazetteerText>SPRINGFIELD, a suburb and a parish in Chelmsford district, Essex. The suburb stands on the river Chelmer, adjacent to Chelmsford; communicates with that town by two bridges, crossing two branches of the river; takes its name from numerous springs, falling into the Chelmer; contains wharves, gasworks, and the county jail; and has a post-office under Chelmsford. The jail was built in 1825, at a cost of &#163;56,000; and has capacity for 330 male and 42 female prisoners. The parish comprises 2,878 acres. Real property, &#163;13,300; of which &#163;786 are in canal-cuts from the Chelmer. Pop. in 1861, 2,566; of whom 242 were in the jail. Houses, 536. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;1,016.* Patron, the Rev. A. Pearson. The church was erected in 1867. A chapel of ease was built in 1843. Charities, &#163;42. Goldsmith resided sometime at S., and is supposed to make allusions to it in his &quot;Deserted Village.&quot; Strutt, the author of &quot;Sports and Pastimes,&apos;&apos; was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6693125</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10246799</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SPRINGFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10246805</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SPRINGFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10246817</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SPRINGFIELD HOLY TRINITY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6546</id>
   <name>BOREHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6557</id>
   <name>BROOMFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6959</id>
   <name>GREAT WALTHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6960</id>
   <name>LITTLE WALTHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17453</id>
   <name>ESSEX</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
