<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>589</id>
<name>WIVENHOE</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.8714319187992</lat>
<lon>0.966629823272683</lon>
<gazetteerText>WIVENHOE, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Lexden district, Essex. The town stands on the river Colne and on the Tendring Hundred railway, 4 miles SE of Colchester; forms, with Brightlingsea and Rowhedge, a member of the cinque port of S and wich; serves as the Colchester out-port, where the larger kind of vessels receive and discharge their cargoes; carries on ship and yacht building, and fishing; occupies a gentle declivity, with a good view of the river; and has a post-office&#8225; under Colchester, a r. station with telegraph, two inns, a good quay, a custom-house , a decorated English church, an Independent chapel of 1846, a public cemetery of 1858, nationa1 and British schools, charities &#163;11, and a fair on 4 Sept. The parish comprises 1,572 acres of land, and 25 of water. Real property, &#163;5,858. Pop. in 1851, 1,672; in 1861, 1,843. Houses, 419. The manor belonged, at Domesday, to R. Gernon; passed, through the De Batailes, the Suttons, and other s, to the De Veres, Earls of Oxford; and was sold, in 1657, to N. Corsellis, ancestor of the present owner. W. Hall is the residence of SirW.De Crespigny, Bart.; and W. Park, of J. G. Rebow, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;440.* Patron, N.Corsellis, Esq.&#151;The sub-district includes Brightlingsea parish. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wivenhoe</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633717</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15281</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15283</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15284</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15287</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15288</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15285</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15280</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15282</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15286</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10108184</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WIVENHOE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10249089</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WIVENHOE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10249090</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WIVENHOE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10538026</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WIVENHOE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6515</id>
   <name>ALRESFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6699</id>
   <name>ELMSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6713</id>
   <name>FRATING</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
