<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6965</id>
<name>SOUTH WEALD</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.6258273577204</lat>
<lon>0.271526013481474</lon>
<gazetteerText>WEALD (South), a parish in Billericay district, Essex; containing Brentwood, with post-office and r. station. Acres, 5,037. Real property, &#163;14,889; of which &#163;200 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 3,588; in 1861, 5,209. Houses, 840. Pop., exclusive of Brentwood, in 1851, 1,383; in 1861, 2,116. Houses, 307. Weald Hall was the birthplace of Queen Mary; was also the residence of Sir Anthony Brown; and is now the residence ofJ. Tower, Esq. Boyles Court, Oakhurst, Pilgrims Hall, Great Ropers, Rochetts, Mascalls, Ditchleys, and How-Hatch also are chief residences. The Essex lunatic asylum, an edifice in the Tudor style with accommodation for about 700 patients, a school-house and ten alms houses in the Tudor style, built in 1856, a Belvedere tower near the church, and a new cemetery opened in 1860, are prominent objects. There are a chalybeate spring and traces of an ancient camp. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;656.* Patron, the Bishop of R. The church was recently restored, at a cost of about &#163;10,000; and has a fine tower. The p. curacy of Brentwood is a separate benefice. See Brentwood. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=63842</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=63843</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10248590</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SOUTH WEALD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10248607</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH WEALD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6791</id>
   <name>KELVEDON HATCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
