<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6754</id>
<name>CASTLE HEDINGHAM</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.9975182660973</lat>
<lon>0.60313931717487</lon>
<gazetteerText>CASTLE-HEDINGHAM, a village and a parish in Halstead district, Essex. The village stands on the river Colne, and on the Colne Valley railway, 4&#189; miles NW of Halstead; is a seat of petty sessions and a pollingplace; and has a post office under Halstead, a railway station, and an inn. Fairs are held on 14 May and 25 July. A grand castle was built on an adjacent eminence, in the early part of the 12th century, by Aubrey de Vere, Earl of Oxford; was the death-place of Queen Maud; made a great figure in the wars in the time of King John; was the scene of a sumptuous entertainment to Henry VII.; suffered much demolition, in 1592, by Edward de Vere; and was reduced to ruin, in 1666, in the first Dutch war. Only the keep of it now stands; and this is pure Anglo-Norman, 62 feet wide, 55 feet broad, and about 100 feet high,-the walls, from 10 to 13 feet thick,-the height disposed in five storeys, pierced with loop-holes and narrow windows. A Benedictine nunnery and an hospital also were founded here by the De Veres,-the former in 1198, the later in 1250;-part of the nunnery is now a farm house. The parish comprises 2,429 acres. Real property, &#163;6.027. Pop., 1,203. Houses, 300. The property is divided among a few. The manor passed from the De Veres to the Ashursts and the Houghtons; and belongs now to A. Majendie, Esq. The parish is notable for its produce of Essex hops. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;100. Patron, A. Majendie, Esq. The church dates from the time of King John; shows Norman traces; has a tower of 1616; and contains monuments of the De Veres and the Ashursts. There are a large Independent chapel and several alms-houses. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Hedingham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653579</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10241972</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CASTLE HEDINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10241984</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CASTLE HEDINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574810</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEDINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574821</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEDINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574833</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEDINGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
