<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6545</id>
<name>BOCKING</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.903024902962</lat>
<lon>0.563838274530537</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOCKING, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Braintree district, Essex. The village stands on the left bank of Blackwater river, and on the Braintree railway, adjacent to Braintree; forms a suburb of that town; consists chiefly of one long street; and is a seat of petty sessions. A trade in baizes, called &quot;bockings,&quot; was at one time prominent; and a manufacture of silk and crape is now carried on. The parish includes also Bocking-street and Bocking-Church-street, &#190; and 2 miles distant from Braintree, both with post offices under that town, and the former situated on the branch Roman road from Chelmsford. Acres, 4,607. Real property, &#163;15,156. Pop., 3,555. Houses, 768. The property is much subdivided. The man or was given by Ethelred to the see of Canterbury; and belongs now to the corporation of the sons of the clergy. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;923.* Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church is early English; had anciently three altars and five chantries; and contains some monuments and two brasses. There are an Independent chapel, much improved in 1869, a charity school with &#163;50, and other charities with &#163;172. Dr. Dale, the author of &quot;Pharmacologia,&quot; was a native. The subdistrict contains five parishes. Acres, 11,507. Pop., 5,281. Houses, 1,171. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.nivek-systems.co.uk/genuki/ESS/Towns/Bocking/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10235042</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BOCKING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10235054</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOCKING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10235066</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOCKING ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10538312</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BOCKING</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
