<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6835</id>
<name>NAVESTOCK</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.651735802349</lat>
<lon>0.224700759219776</lon>
<gazetteerText>NAVESTOCK, a village and a parish in Ongar district, Essex. The village, which consists of four scattered hamlets, Navestock Side, Horseman Side, Cuddlesmere Green, and Navestock Heathstands near the river Roding, 5 miles S S W of Ongar r. station, and 6&#188; N N E of Romford; and has a post-office under Romford. Acres, 4, 329. Real property, &#163;6, 417. Pop., 928. Houses, 178. The property is much subdivided. The manor was given by King Edgar to St. Paul&apos;s cathedral, and by Queen Mary to the ancestor of Earl Waldegrave; and, with Navestock Park, belongs now to the Dowager Countess of Waldegrave. Dudbrook House, the seat of the Countess, Navestock Hall, Abbotswick House, and Bois Hall, are chief residences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;424.* Patron, Trinity College, Oxford. The church is large and good; and consists of nave, S aisle, and chancel, with wooden tower and shingled spire. There are a parochial school, and charities &#163;51. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navestock</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641856</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15614</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15617</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15611</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15615</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15613</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15618</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15612</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15616</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10244900</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NAVESTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10244912</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NAVESTOCK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
