<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>894</id>
<name>BRIGHTLINGSEA</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.8164840922633</lat>
<lon>1.02643666626807</lon>
<gazetteerText>BRIGHTLINGSEA, a village and a parish in Lexden district, Essex. The village stands on the estuary of the Colne, opposite Mersea island, at a terminus of the Tendring Hundred railway, 8 miles SE by S of Colchester; is a sub-port to Colchester, and a member of the cinque port of Sandwich; and has a post office&#8225; under Colchester, and a recently erected temperance hall. Fairs are held on the first Thursday of June and 15 Oct.; and a large trade is carried on in the fishing of sprats and oysters. The parish comprises 3,560 acres; of which 470 are water. Real property, &#163;7,081. Pop., 2,585. Houses, 589. The property is sub-divided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;213.* Patron, the Bishop of Peterborough. The church has a tower nearly 100 feet high, serving as a sea-mark; and contains brasses of a merchant, a nun, and W. Beriffe, 1579. There are a chapel of ease in Gothic architecture, and chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Swedenborgiaus. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.nivek-systems.co.uk/genuki/ESS/Towns/Brightlingsea/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brightlingsea</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654711</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10166779</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BRIGHTLINGSEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10235315</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BRIGHTLINGSEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10235327</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BRIGHTLINGSEA</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6828</id>
   <name>EAST MERSEA</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
