<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6685</id>
<name>DOVERCOURT</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.9314651487554</lat>
<lon>1.2639455751876</lon>
<gazetteerText>DOVER-COURT, a parish in Tendring district, Essex; at the mouth of the estuary of the river Stour, and on the Harwich branch of the Eastern Union railway, 2 miles WSW of Harwich. It has a station on the railway, and two post offices, of the names of Lower Dover-Court and Upper Dover-Court, under Harwich. Acres, 2, 966; of which 1, 220 are water. Real property, &#163;6, 270. Pop., 1, 231. Houses, 232. The property is subdivided. Lower Dover-Court is a suburb to Harwich; and Upper Dover-Court includes fine terrace-lines of houses, a great number of villas and other fine residences, a first-class hotel, a spa and assembly-rooms, sea-walls and marine drives, all of recent construction, and is becoming a favourite watering resort. The land is noted for fine hard elm. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Harwich-St. Nicholas, in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;221. Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is of brick; was built in 1821, at a cost of &#163;20, 000; and occupies the site of a previous church, which dated from the 13th century, had a guild and a famous crucifix, and contained a tomb to Secretary Clarke, killed in 1666 in action against De Ruyter. The crucifix was reputed to be miraculous, and attracted many pilgrims; and three men were executed in 1532 for carrying it off and burning it. See Harwich. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dovercourt</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651047</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10238821</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>DOVERCOURT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10238857</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DOVERCOURT</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6869</id>
   <name>RAMSEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
