<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6755</id>
<name>SIBLE HEDINGHAM</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.9716636025366</lat>
<lon>0.56967164106394</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEDINGHAM-SIBLE, a village and a parish in Halstead district, Essex. The village stands adjacent to the river Colne and the Colne-Valley railway, near CastleHedingham r. station, 3&#188; miles NW of Halstead; and has a post office under Halstead, a public reading room and library, and a fair on Easter Tuesday. The parish comprises 5, 394 acres. Real property, &#163;10, 998. Pop., 2, 123. Houses, 508. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to Robert Bigod, and passed to the De Veres. Upwards of 40 acres are under hops. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;905. * Patron, the Rev. H. Warburton. The church is decorated English, in good condition; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and contains memorials of Sir John Hawkhood, who figured as a warrior in the time of Edward III., and was a native of the parish. There are a Baptist chapel, a national school, an ancient chantry house now used as an alms house, and charities &#163;76. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637871</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10241996</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SIBLE HEDINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10242009</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SIBLE HEDINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6715</id>
   <name>GESTINGTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6717</id>
   <name>GOSFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6754</id>
   <name>CASTLE HEDINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6949</id>
   <name>TOPPESFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6989</id>
   <name>GREAT YELDHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6990</id>
   <name>LITTLE YELDHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7120</id>
   <name>NORTH WOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
