<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6926</id>
<name>TENDRING</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.8788266970094</lat>
<lon>1.11509953162344</lon>
<gazetteerText>TENDRING, a village, a parish, a district, and a hundred, in Essex. The village stands 1&#189; mile from the Thorpe and Walton railway, and 7 SE of Manningtree; and has a post-office under Colchester, and a fair on 21 Sept. The parish comprises 2,827 acres. Real property, &#163;4,801. Pop., 929. Houses, 168. The property is much subdivided. The manor, with the Manor-house , belongs to J. Cardinall, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;840.* Patron, Baliol College, Oxford. The church was recently restored and enlarged. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and a workhouse.&#151;The district contains 32 parishes, and is divided into 5 sub-districts. Acres, 89,803. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;15,211. Pop. in 1851, 27,710; in 1861, 27,105. Houses, 5,745. Marriages in 1863, 165; births, 894,-of which 48 were illegitimate; deaths, 532, -of which 188 were at ages under 5 years, and 21 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,835; births, 8,507; deaths, 5,579. The places of worship, in 1851, were 31 of the Church of England , with 9,754 sittings; 2 of Independents, with 660 s.; 3 of Baptists, with 540 s.; 20 of Wesleyans, with 4,384 s.; 5 of Primitive Methodists, with 404 s.; 1 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 110 s.; 1 of the New Church, with 31 attendants; and 1 undefined, with 420 s. The schools were 19 public day-schools, with 1,317 scholars; 54 private day-schools, with 1,003 s.; 36 Sunday schools, with 2,840 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 6 s.-The hundred is mainly identical with the district. Acres, 90,057. Pop. in 1851, 25,111; in 1861, 24,620. Houses, 5,523. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Tendring</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tendring_(village)</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7300551</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10027809</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>TENDRING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10031345</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>TENDRING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10139053</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>TENDRING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10168673</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TENDRING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173310</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>TENDRING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10247342</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TENDRING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10247354</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TENDRING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581114</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TENDRING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581126</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TENDRING</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
