<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6812</id>
<name>FOULNESS</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.5944725604519</lat>
<lon>0.947733783507093</lon>
<gazetteerText>FOULNESS, an insular parish in Rochford district, Essex. It lies on the S side of the lowest reach of the river Crouch; terminates there in a point or headland, which is Foulness-proper; is separated, on the W, from Wallasea island, by a narrow strait, -and on the SW, from smaller islands, by other narrow straits; is bounded, on the SE and E, by the North sea; and takes its name from being a haunt of myriads of wild fowl. Its central part lies 4 miles ESE of Burnham, and 9 NE of South-end r. station; and has a post office under Chelmsford, and a fair on 10 July. Its circuit, not reckoning the saltings toward the sea, is computed at about 20 miles. Its area comprises 6, 310 acres of land, and 22, 195 of water. Real property, &#163;9, 313; of which &#163;13 are in fisheries. Pop., 681. Houses, 109. The property is divided among a few. The land is mostly low and marshy; and is all protected by an embanking wall. The lower tracts are disposed in pasturage; and the higher ones produce good crops of corn, clover, mustard, and cole-seed. Oysters of prime quality are taken adjacent to its shores. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, G. Finch, Esq. The church was built in 1850. A previous church was originally a chapel of ease. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649144</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10244031</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FOULNESS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10244043</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FOULNESS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
