<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6708</id>
<name>FINCHINGFIELD</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.9794234210483</lat>
<lon>0.464766547940027</lon>
<gazetteerText>FINCHINGFIELD, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Braintree district, Essex. The village stands on an affluent of the river Pant, 5 miles ENE of Thaxted, and 6&#189; SW of Yeldham r. station; and has a post office under Braintree. The parish comprises 8, 387 acres. Real property, &#163;14, 455. Pop., 2, 441. Houses, 531. The property is much subdivided. The manor was held, in the reign of Edward III., by John de Compes, for the service of turning the spit at his coronation. A few acres are under hops. The straw-plait trade has employed many of the inhabitants, but recently underwent depresssion. The parish is a meet for the East Essex hounds. Both the head living and another living called St. John&apos;s are vicarages in the diocese of Rochester. Value of the former, &#163;733;* of the latter, &#163;200.* Patron of the former, the Rev. J. Stock; of the latter, the Bishop of Rochester. The churches of both are good; and there are an Independent chapel, and charities &#163;111.&#151;The sub-district contains four parishes. Acres, 16, 706. Pop., 5, 289. Houses, 1, 168. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finchingfield</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649442</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10239394</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FINCHINGFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10239400</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FINCHINGFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10538336</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FINCHINGFIELD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6541</id>
   <name>BIRDBROOK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6561</id>
   <name>HELION BUMPSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6562</id>
   <name>STEEPLE BUMPSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6756</id>
   <name>HEMPSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6892</id>
   <name>GREAT SAMPFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6893</id>
   <name>LITTLE SAMPFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6906</id>
   <name>STAMBOURNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
