<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6607</id>
<name>GREAT COGGESHALL</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.8822470960204</lat>
<lon>0.673134576973212</lon>
<gazetteerText>COGGESHALL, a town and a sub-district in the district of Witham, Essex. The town is chiefly in Great Coggeshall parish, partly in Little Coggeshall; and stands on the Roman road from Colchester, and on the river Blackwater, 2 &#189; miles N by W of Kelvedon r. station, and 6 E by S of Braintree. Its site is partly low ground, partly the acclivity of a pleasant hill. A Roman station, either Ad Ansam or Canonium, is supposed by some antiquaries to have been here; and remains of a Roman villa have been found. A Cistertian abbey was founded in the vicinity, within Little Coggeshall parish, and a three-arched bridge built over an adjacent artificial cut of the Blackwater, by King Stephen; and a small part of the abbey still exists. The town has a post office&#8225; under Kelvedon, two banking offices, two chief inns, a parish church, five dissenting chapels, a free school, and six alms-houses. The church is perpendicular English, with a tower; and was repaired in 1847, and thoroughly renovated in 1854; and a plan for farther improvement on it, at the cost of about &#163;2, 000, was executed in 1864. A weekly market is held on Thursday; and a fair on Whit-Tuesday. There are two silk factories, and a patent isinglass and gelatine factory. Pop., 3, 166. Houses, 714.&#151;The sub-district contains the two Coggeshall parishes and two others. Acres, 7, 634. Pop., 4, 954. Houses, 1, 083. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coggeshall</link>
<link>http://www.nivek-systems.co.uk/genuki/ESS/Towns/Coggeshall/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652640</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10236915</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>COGGESHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10236940</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>COGGESHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10236964</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>COGGESHALL WITH MARKSHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10236976</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GREAT COGGESHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10556521</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>COGGESHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10571893</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>COGGESHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10571900</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>COGGESHALL AND TEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6551</id>
   <name>BRADWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6609</id>
   <name>LITTLE COGGESHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6706</id>
   <name>FEERING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6776</id>
   <name>LAYER BRETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6829</id>
   <name>MESSING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6856</id>
   <name>PATTISWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>6609</id>
<name>LITTLE COGGESHALL</name>
<container>ESSEX</container>
<lat>51.8612242981766</lat>
<lon>0.678003844844638</lon>
<gazetteerText>COGGESHALL (Little), a parish in Witham district, Essex; containing a small part of the town of Coggeshall. Acres, 830. Real property, &#163;3, 597. Pop., 429. Houses, 85. The living is incorporated with Great Coggeshall. There were once two churches, the one monastic and long ago demolished, the other parochial and now partially restored. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652640</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10237002</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LITTLE COGGESHALL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
