<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2026</id>
<name>LLANASA</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3323321560129</lat>
<lon>-3.32995287406648</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANASA, or LLANASAPH, a parish in Holywell district, Flint; on the estuary of the Dee at its mouth, on Offa&apos;s dyke, and on the Chester and Holyhead railway, between Mostyn and Prestatyn stations, 6&#189; miles NW by N of Holywell. It has a post office under Holywell; and it contains the townships of Axton, Gronant, Gwespyr, Kelston, Picton, Trelogan, and Trewaclod. Acres, 10,809; of which 4,959 are water. Real property, &#163;9,199; of which &#163;920 are in quarries, and &#163;24 in mines. Pop. in 1851,2,732; in 1861,2,882. Houses, 595. The property is divided among a few. Talacre, a modern mansion, is the seat of Sir Piers Mostyn, Bart.; Gyrn, a castellated mansion, is the seat of E. Bates, Esq.; and Golden Grove is the seat of Col. Morgan. Llanasa Hill, or Corseddan, has an altitude of about 700 feet, and is crowned by a signal-tower. The Point of Air at the Dee&apos;s mouth, has an iron lighthouse, standing on nine pillars; and shows two fixed lights,-the one 49 feet above highwater mark, and visible at the distance of 11 miles, -the other at the height of only 12 feet, and intended to guide the navigation of vessels over the sands. A valuable freestone, which furnished the material for Liverpool workhouse, is quarried at Gwespyr; and coal, iron ore, and lead ore, are found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;297. * Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church was rebuilt in 1737; has windows of stained glass, said to have been brought from Basingwerk abbey; and contains several old monuments. There are endowed schools with &#163;22 a year, and other charities &#163;15. The Rev. H. Parry, the friend of Pennant, was vicar. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/FLN/Llanasa/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644185</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10039162</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANASA</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8386</id>
   <name>NEWMARKET</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
