<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8407</id>
<name>OVERTON</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9671588536062</lat>
<lon>-2.93049539668234</lon>
<gazetteerText>OVERTON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in the district of Ellesmere and county of Flint. The village stands on an eminence adjacent to the river Dee, 2 miles N of the boundary with Salop, and 4&#189; N N W of Ellesmere r. station; was known at Domesday as Ovreton; is a seat of petty sessions and a polling-place; unites with Flint, Holywell, Mold, Caeswys, Caergwrle, Rhuddlan, and St. Asaph, in sending a member to parliament; is, as a borough, conterminate with the parish; enjoys delightful environs, with most lovely views of the Dee; was once a market-town; and has a post-office&#8225;under Ruabon, and toll-free fairs on the Saturday after 7 March, the Monday before Holy Thursday, and the Saturday after 2 Oct. The parish contains also the hamlets of Clog, Knolton, and Maesgwaylod. Acres, 4, 398. Real property, &#163;6, 846. Pop. in 1851, 1, 479; in 1861, 1, 397. Houses, 296. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged anciently to Robert Fitzhugh; and passed to Robert de Crevec&#339;nr, the Stranges, and others. A castle was built here by Madoc ab Meredydd, prince of Powis; and has left some traces. Knolton Hall is the seat ofR. Cotton, Esq.; Gwernhaelod, of the Fletchers; and Bryn-y-Pys, of E. Peel, Esq. A barrow and ancient camp are in Gwernhaelod park. The first Duke of Wellington spent considerable portions of his boyhood at Bryn-y-Pys. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;551. The church is cruciform and good. The churchyard contains some old yews. Charities, &#163;34.&#151;The sub-district contains also Penley chapelry. Acres, 6, 434. Pop. in 1815, 1,885: in 1861, 1, 779. Houses, 387. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/FLN/Overton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overton-on-Dee</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640764</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10288599</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>OVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10402621</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>OVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546795</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OVERTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
