<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2012</id>
<name>HOPE</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1145478125263</lat>
<lon>-3.05332385790678</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOPE, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in the district of Wrexham; the village and the parish in Flintshire, the sub-district partly also in Denbighshire. The village stands on the river Alen, near Watt&apos;s Dyke, Offa&apos;s Dyke, and the Chester and Mold railway, 5 &#189; miles SE by E of Mold; is included in the borough of Caergwrle, whose centre is a mile distant; belonged at Domesday to Gislebert, -afterwards to the Earls of Chester, the Stanleys, and others; was a place of some importance in the time of Edward the Black Prince; consists now of three wide parallel streets, intersected by three others at right angles; and has a post office under Mold, Flintshire, a railway station, and a fine old bridge over the Alen.&#151;The parish includes the borough of Caergwrle, and the townships of Cymmau, Estyn, Hope-Owen, Rhanberfedd, Shordley, Uwch-y-Mynydd-Isaf, and Uwch-y-Mynydd-Uchaf; and is sometimes called QueensHope or Estyn. Acres, 9, 166. Real property, &#163;13, 983. Pop. in 1851, 2, 792; in 1861, 3, 121. Houses, 6 48. The property is much subdivided. Hope Castle, on the summit of a lofty rock, is of unknown origin; belonged, in the time of Owen Gwynedd, to Gryffydd Maelor; was given, by Edward I., to Queen Eleanor; and consists now of a mntilated circular tower, and a few fragments of walls. Caer-Estyn, an ancient British post, is on a confronting eminence. Roman coins, tiles, bricks, and other relics have been found. Limestone is worked, and has afforded many interesting fossils. Ironworks were formerly in the neighbourhood. There are two mineral springs. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;291. * Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church has a monument to Sir John Trevor, comptroller of the navy in the time of Elizabeth; and it was reported, in 1 859, to need repair. The rectory of Llanfynydd is a separate benefice. Charities, &#163;16.&#151;The sub-district contains also parts of three other parishes. Acres, 26, 903. Pop., 1 1, 297. Houses, 2, 319. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/FLN/Hope/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hope,_Flintshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646641</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10038649</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HOPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12823411</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOPE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9092</id>
   <name>TREUDDYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>23172</id>
<name>HOPE OWEN</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1232775899434</lat>
<lon>-3.04615701156342</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOPE-OWEN, a township in Hope parish, Flint. Real property, &#163;2, 284. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10198021</id>
   <status>Tn</status>
   <name>HOPE OWEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
