<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20660</id>
<name>BAGILLT</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2686577890806</lat>
<lon>-3.17117282303014</lon>
<gazetteerText>BAGILLT, a village, a township, and a chapelry in Holywell parish, Flint. The village stands on the S side of the estuary of the Dee, contiguous to the Chester and Holyhead railway, 2 miles NW of Flint, and 2&#188; SE of Holywell. It has a station on the railway, and a post office&#8225; under Holywell; and is a sub-port to Chester. The tract round it is rich in minerals, and yields a great output of coals; and the village itself is the seat or centre of extensive lead, iron, and alkali works. So large a quantity of lead ore as 100,000 tons, accompanied by 42,000 ounces of silver, has been annually smelted. One of the adjacent hills bears the name of Bryn-Dychwelwch, signifying &quot;the hill of retreat;&quot; and was the place at which Owen Gwynedd sounded his retreat from the pursuit by Henry II. Bagillt Hall, in the vicinity, is an old seat of the Griffiths.-The township bears the name of Ba gillt-Fawr, and includes the hamlets of Bagillt-Bach and Bagillt-Fechan. Real property, &#163;7,040; of which &#163;927 are in mines.&#151;The chapelry was constituted in 1844. Pop., 2,935. Houses, 687. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;155.* Patron, the Vicar of Holywell. The church is in the early English style, and was opened in 1839. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Wesleyans, and Welsh Methodists. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656636</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10175938</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BAGILLT</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
