<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8300</id>
<name>NANNERCH</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.208629730241</lat>
<lon>-3.27151914036332</lon>
<gazetteerText>NANNERCH, a township and a parish in Holywell district; the township and most of the parish in Flintshire, the rest of the parish in Denbighshire. The township lies under Moel-Arthur, 4&#189; miles S W of Bagillt r.station, and 5 W S W of Flint; and has a post-office under Mold, Flintshire. The parish contains also the townships of Llan, Cwm, and Trefechan, in Flintshire, and the township of Penbedw in Denbighshire. Acres of the Flint portion, 1,849. Real property, &#163;1, 633. Pop., 275. Houses, 59. Acres of the Denbigh portion, 943. Real property, &#163;887. Pop., 58. Houses, 13. The property is divided among a few. Penbedw Hall belonged formerlyto the Mostyns; is now the seat of W. Buddicom, Esq.; was long noted for a rich old library, containing a collection of illuminated books; and stands in grounds whichhave a Druidical circle and a tumulus. Limestone has been quarried, and lead and iron ores have been worked. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;292.* Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church is good, and contains a monument of the wife of R. Mostyn, Esq., grand-daughter of Sir Kenelm Digby. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/FLN/Nannerch/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nannerch</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641905</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10149850</id>
   <status>Tn</status>
   <name>LLAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10285112</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>NANNERCH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
