<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4346</id>
<name>HALKYN</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2254581116071</lat>
<lon>-3.20120150809974</lon>
<gazetteerText>HALKIN, a village and a parish in Holywell district, Flintshire. The village stands under Halkin mountain, 2&#189; miles SW of Flint r. station, and 3&#188; SE of Holywell; and has a post office under Holywell. The parish includes the townships of Hendre-Figillt, Lugyn-y-Llan and Lugyn-y-Wern. Acres, 3,140. Real property, &#163;5,282; of which &#163;1,897 are in mines, and &#163;30 in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 1,777; in 1861, 1,334. Houses, 320. The decrease of pop. was occasioned by decrease in the working of lead mines. The property is divided among a few. Halkin Castle, built in 1827, is a seat of the Marquis of Westminster. Halkin mountain commands fine views; has, at its south end, an ancient British camp; and is there 1,020 feet high. The rocks abound in mineral wealth, principally lead ore, calamine, coal, limestone, and potter&apos;s clay. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;312.* Patron, the Bishop of Llandaff. The church is tolerable. The vicarage of Rhos-y-Coe is a separate benefice. There is a Calvinistic Methodist chapel. Roberts, who wrote &quot;the History of the Cymry,&quot; was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/FLN/Halkyn/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halkyn</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647629</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10036987</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HALKYN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10147190</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HALKYN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
