<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2944</id>
<name>DISERTH</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3126262402491</lat>
<lon>-3.41798932548276</lon>
<gazetteerText>DYSERTH, or Diserth, a parish in the district of St. Asaph and county of Flint; near the sea, the river Clwyd, and the vale of Clwyd and the Chester and Holyhead railways, 1&#190; mile E by N of Rhuddlan r. station, and 4 NNE of St. Asaph. It has a post office under Rhyl. Acres, 3, 348; of which 1, 464 are water. Rated property, &#163;2, 206. Pop., 1, 098. Houses, 267. The property is divided among a few. Lead mining is carried on at Talargoch. An ancient castle, of early Norman structure, stood on a lofty scarped rock; was defended, on one side, by a deep fosse cut in the solid rock; was strengthened, in 1241, by Henry III.; and was demolished, about 1261, by the Welsh under Llewelyn; and it is now represented by only a few fragments. An oblong double, transepted, ivy-clad building, called Siambre-Wen or &quot;the white chamber, &quot; stands immediately below the castle-rock; and is regarded by some antiquaries as an ecclesiastical edifice, -by others, as the residence of the later constables of the castle, -by others as an enclosure over a holy well. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;113.*-Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church has part of a Jesse window, and contains memorials of the Conways of the 17th century; and the churchyard contains some remarkable ancient tombstones, and a mutilated sculptured ancient cross. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/FLN/Dyserth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650584</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10083552</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>DISERTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
