<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3749</id>
<name>CAERWYS</name>
<container>FLINTSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2584940341966</lat>
<lon>-3.31441294924899</lon>
<gazetteerText>CAERWYS, a small town and a parish in Holywell district, Flint. The town stands 5 miles SW by W of Holywell r. station, and 6 E of St. Asaph; and has a post office under Holywell. It is thought to occupy the site of a Roman station; it was the scene of the court of the last Prince Llewellyn; it witnessed Eisteddfodau, or congresses of bards and minstrels, at various periods till 1798; it was the seat of the county assizes till 1672; and it unites with Flint, and other places, in sending a member to parliament; but, as a borough, includes the townships of Tre&apos;dre and Tref-Edwyn. It comprises four streets, crossing each other in the centre; and has a townhall, a church, and three dissenting chapels. Markets are held on Tuesdays; and fairs on the 2d Tuesday of Jan., 5 March, the last Tuesday of April, Trinity Thursday, the Tuesday after 7 July, 29 Aug., and 5 Nov. Pop., 637. Houses, 150.&#151;The parish includes also the townships of Bryngwyn-Issa, and Bryngwyn-Ucha. Acres, 2,603. Real property, &#163;2,952. Pop., 853. Houses, 208. The manor belongs to Lord Mostyn. Maes-Mynam, the site of the residence of Prince Llewellyn, is SW of the town. A tumulus is about a mile NE of the town; other tumuli are on the hills to the W; and an ancient camp is on a summit to the N. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;425.* Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. Lloyd, the friend of Pennant, was vicar; and Bishop Wynne was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caerwys</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654086</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/FLN/Caerwys/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10117999</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CAERWYS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
