<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14563</id>
<name>LLANRHIDIAN</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.6081020950337</lat>
<lon>-4.16933011560791</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANRHIDIAN, a parish, comprising the hamlets L. Lower and L. Higher, in Swansea district, Glamorgan; on the coast of the Gower peninsula, 3 miles SSW of Loughor r. station, and 10 W of Swansea. It includes the chapelry of Penclawdd, which has a postoffice under Swansea; and it has fairs on Palm-Monday, 20 June, and 20 Oct. Acres of L. Lower, 12,958; of which 4,190 are water. Real property, &#163;1,590. Pop., 525. Houses, 111. Acres of L. Higher, 9,106; of which 3,155 are water. Real property, &#163;1,725. Pop., 1,468. Houses, 283. Well preserved remains of Weobley Castle stand on an eminence overlooking the river Burry. Copper ore, limestone, and freestone are worked. Cefn-Bryn ridge commands a rich and extensive panoramic view; and is crowned with the famous cromlech, called Arthur&apos;s Stone, and with numerous cairns and Druidical circles. Arthur&apos;s Stone figures in the Welsh Triads as &apos; &apos; the big stone of Sketty, &apos;&apos;and one of the wonders of Wales; it comp rises a mass of millstone-grit, about 20 tons in weight, with four supporters 5 feet high; and it stands in a hollow, which is nearly filled with rough stones. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Penclawdd, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;99. Patrons, the Trustees of G. Morgan, Esq. There are two churches. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llanrhidian_Higher</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Llanrhidian/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llanrhidian_Lower</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643965</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10236903</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANRHIDIAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10375976</id>
   <status>CP/ExP</status>
   <name>CEFN Y BRYN COMMON LAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10486210</id>
   <status>CP/PA</status>
   <name>LLANRHIDIAN LOWER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10486221</id>
   <status>CP/PA</status>
   <name>LLANRHIDIAN HIGHER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
