<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8409</id>
<name>OXWICH</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.5533359833641</lat>
<lon>-4.16650609640872</lon>
<gazetteerText>OXWICH, a parish and a bay in Swansea district, Glamorgan. The parish lies on the W side of the bay, in the Gower peninsula, 10 miles S W of Gower-Road r.station, and 12 S W by S of Swansea. Post-town, Swansea. Acres, 1, 602; of which 405 are water. Real property, &#163;717. Pop., 328. Houses, 62. The property is much subdivided. Oxwich Castle stands on a promontory, running out to Oxwich point; was founded, in the time of Henry VIII., by Sir Rice Mansell; and is partlya large later English mansion, carried along at the complete elevation of a curious sixstoried tower. Bacon Hole is a stalactitic cave, in which bones were found infour successive deposits; first, bones of ox, red deer, roebuck, and fox, in alluvial earth; next, bones of bear, ox, and deer, beneath a layer of stalagmite; next, bones of mammoth, rhinoceros, hy&#230;na, wolf, bear, ox, and deer, beneath another layer of stalagmite; next, bones of Mammoth, badger, and polecat, beneath a third layer ofstalagmite; and below the last, on the limestone floor, were found shells of Clansilia nigricans, Littorina littoralis, bones of birds, and arvicola. The mammoth boneswere remarkably large, and are preserved in the Swanseamuseum. Michin Hole is another cave to the W of Bacon Hole, but has not any bone remains. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Nicholaston, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. The church is Norman, ingood condition; and contains an altar-tomb of Sir Rice Mansell. The bay washes also the parishes of Nicholaston, Penmaen, and Pennard; is flanked by Oxwich pointon the W, and by Pwlldu point on the E; measures 4&#189; miles, across the entrance, between these points; penetrates to the extent of 2&#188; miles; has St. Kit&apos;s knoll in the middle, and a depth of from 3 to 10 fathoms water; and is the finest bay in Gower. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Oxwich/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640713</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10288654</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>OXWICH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
