<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8382</id>
<name>NEWCASTLE</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.5299084000455</lat>
<lon>-3.60656771730998</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWCASTLE, two hamlets, a parish, and a hundred, in Glamorgan. The hamlets are Higher Newcastle and Lower Newcastle; they lie on the river Ogmore and the South Wales railway, within and around the town of Bridgend; and they take their name from an ancientcastle, the outer walls and a Norman doorway of whichstill exist. H. N. includes the villages of Aberkenfigg, Angeltown, and Penyvae. Real property, &#163;3, 443; of which &#163;2,000 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 822; in 1861, 1, 357. Houses, 236. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of collieries, and of coke and iron-works. Real property of L. N., &#163;1, 873. Pop. in 1851, 714; in 1861, 887. Houses, 192. The parish consists of the two hamlets, and is in Bridgend district. Post-town, Bridgend. Acres, 2, 870. Pop. in 1861, 2, 244. Houses, 428. The property is subdivided. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacies of Bettws, Laleston, and Tythegston, in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;360.* Patron, the Bishop of Llandaff. The church stands on a conspicuous site in Bridgend; and is good. The hundred contains twelve parishes. Acres, 71, 276. Pop.in 1851, 20, 157; in 1861, 24, 575. Houses, 4, 771. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Newcastle/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7297851</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10082092</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>NEWCASTLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10149526</id>
   <status>Ldsp</status>
   <name>NEWCASTLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10287790</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Hmlt</status>
   <name>NEWCASTLE HIGHER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10485022</id>
   <status>Tn/CP/Hmlt</status>
   <name>NEWCASTLE LOWER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10485034</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>NEWCASTLE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
