<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>883</id>
<name>CAERPHILLY</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.5981315336668</lat>
<lon>-3.25432510989353</lon>
<gazetteerText>CAERPHILLY, a village, a chapelry, a subdistrict, and a hundred in Glamorgan. The village is in the hamlet tract of Energlyn, in the parish of Eglwysilan; and stands on a plain, surrounded by barren mountains, adjacent to the Rumney railway, near the Rumney river, 7&#189; miles by road, and 9&#189; by railway, N by W of Cardiff. It most probably was founded by the ancient Britons. A monastery early stood at it, dedicated to St. Cnydd; and was burnt, in 831, by the Saxons. A fortalice seems to have been built at it soon after the Conquest; was dismantled, in 1219, by Rhys Vychan; rebuilt in 1221, by John do Brasse; enlarged and strengthened by Ralph Mortimer and Hugh de Spencer; used as a fastness, by the Spencers, for plundering the circumjacent country; made the refuge of Edward II., in his flight from his rebellions barons; sustained then a very vigorous and obstinate siege; was held, in 1400, by Owen Glendower, but then was &quot;a fortress great in ruins;&quot; and ceased thereafter to be much noticed in history. The ruins of it, now extant, cover an area of 30 acres; display remarkable magnificence; and include outworks, gateways, towers, a grand hall 7 feet by 30, and a ponderous leaning tower, 80 feet high, much shattered, 10 feet out of the perpendicular, and supposed to have sustained its injuries from a steam explosion at the time of the great siege. Tennyson resided sometime in the vicinity; lays the scene of his &quot;Idylls of the King&quot; in the immediate neighbourhood; and seems to refer to the castle in the following lines:- All was ruinous: Here stood a shattered archway, plumed with fern; And here has fallen a great part of a tower, Whole, like a crag that tumbles from the cliff, And, like a crag, was gay with wilding flowers. The village is an irregular assemblage of small houses, contiguous to the castle. It was formerly a borough; it has a post office&#8225; under Cardiff, a railway station, and an inn; and it is a seat of petty sessions. Markets are held on Thursdays; and fairs on 5 April, Trinity Thursday, 19 July, 25 Aug., 9 Oct., 16 Nov., and the Thursday before Christmas. Some blanketing and woollen shawls are made; and numerous collieries and iron works are in the neighbourhood. Pop., with Energlyn, 1,047. Houses, 237.&#151;The chapelry includes all Energlyn and part of Bedwas, and was constituted in 1850. Pop., 1,193. Houses, 264. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;300. Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Llandaff. The church is in the later English style; and there are chapels for Baptists, Calvinistic Methodists, and Wesleyans.-The subdistrict contains six parishes, and part of another; and is in the district of Cardiff. Acres, 27,164. Pop., 10,012. Houses, 2,089.-The hundred contains four parishes, and parts of three others. Acres, 62,966. Pop., 67,612. Houses, 13,358. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caerphilly</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654089</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10150528</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CAERPHILLY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163766</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CAERPHILLY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10196279</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>CAERPHILLY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10367980</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>CAERPHILLY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10367992</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CAERPHILLY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12745849</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>GLAMORGANSHIRE EASTERN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12752866</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>GLAMORGANSHIRE CAERPHILLY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12753068</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>CAERPHILLY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12823423</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CAERPHILLY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12830440</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CAERPHILLY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1254</id>
   <name>BEDWAS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1778</id>
   <name>EGLWYSILAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9284</id>
   <name>VAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
