<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8469</id>
<name>PEN RHYS</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.5650748087436</lat>
<lon>-4.1959776575182</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENRICE, a village and a parish in Swansea district, Glamorgan. The village stands near the W side of Oxwich bay, in the Gower peninsula, 9 miles S W of Loughor r. station, and 10 W S W of Swansea; was once a market-town; and has fairs on 17 May, 17 July, 17 Sept., and 11 Dec. The parish contains also the hamlet of Pilton-Green; and its post town is Swansea. Acres, 2, 248; of which 45 are water. Real property, &#163;1, 254. Pop., 307. Houses, 70. The name Penrice was originally written Pen-rhys; applies properly to a headland of the parish; and was taken from Rhys-ab-Caradoc, who was killed here. The property is much subdivided. P. Castle was built by the Earl of Warwick, to secure hisacquisitions in Gower; passed to the Penrices, the Mansells, and the Talbots; and is now a ruin, consistingchiefly of some large inwardly-rounded towers. Amodern mansion, the seat ofR. Talbot, Esq., stands adjacent to the ruins, embowered in wood; and was built in 1782, out of materials from Margam abbey. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;53. Patron, N. V. E. Vaughan, Esq. The church is Norman and cruciform; has been restored; and is remarkable for the beauty of its situation. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Penrice,_Swansea</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Penrice/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640417</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10291100</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PEN RHYS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
