<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8782</id>
<name>ST FAGANS</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.4909877345818</lat>
<lon>-3.27313909117078</lon>
<gazetteerText>FAGAN (St.), a village and a parish in Cardiff district, Glamorgan. The village stands on the river Ely, adjacent to the South Wales railway, 4 miles W of Cardiff; was almost rebuilt by the late Hon. R. W. Clive; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Cardiff. The parish comprises 2, 241 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 717; of which &#163;12 are in quarries. Pop., 506. Houses, 101. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged, in the 12th century, to Sir Peter de Vele; passed to the Gibbons and the Lewises; and came to Earl Amhurst. A castellated mansion, at the village, was built by Sir Peter de Vele; a square, high-gabled, picturesque house, within that mansion&apos;s court, was built by the Gibbons; and this is now the seat of Baroness Windsor. A battle, between an insurgent army of about 8, 000 and the army of Cromwell, was fought at St. Fagan in 1648. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Llanilterne, in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;417.* Patron, the Dowager Countess Amhurst. The church was restored, in 1860, at a cost of &#163;2, 000. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/StFagans/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Fagans</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10302201</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST FAGANS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6809</id>
   <name>MICHAELSTON SUPER ELY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8785</id>
   <name>ST GEORGE SUPER ELY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
