<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10777</id>
<name>LLANSAMLET</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.6563141783767</lat>
<lon>-3.88985938548991</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANSAMLET, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Neath district, Glamorgan. The village stands on the river Tawe and the Swansea canal, near the Swansea Vale railway, 3&#189; miles NNE of Swansea; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Neath. The parish is cut into two divisions, higher and lower; and comprises 6,735 acres of land, and 2,100 of water. Real property of the higher div., &#163;8,730; of which &#163;5,900 are in mines. Pop. in 1851,1,477; in 1861,1,860. Houses, 368. Real property of the lower div., &#163;9,059; of which &#163;260 are in mines, and &#163;20 in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 2,799; in 1861,3,243. Houses, 645. The property is subdivided. Glanbrane and Gwernllwynwith are chief residences. There are coal mines and copper works; and they give a dismal aspect to the landscape. The railway, on both sides of L. station, traverses steep inclines. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Kilvey, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;300. Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church was recently in disrepair. There are a Calvinistic Methodist chapel, and charities &#163;7.&#151;The sub-district is conterminate with the parish. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llansamlet</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Llansamlet/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7300396</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10237129</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LLANSAMLET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377249</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANSAMLET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551237</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANSAMLET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12796134</id>
   <status>Tn/Hmlt/CP</status>
   <name>LLANSAMLET HIGHER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12796146</id>
   <status>Hmlt/CP/Tn</status>
   <name>LLANSAMLET LOWER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
