<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1052</id>
<name>ABERDAR</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.7089880808017</lat>
<lon>-3.45368153675004</lon>
<gazetteerText>ABERDARE, a town, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Merthyr-Tydvil, Glamorgan. The town stands at the confluence of the Dare and the Cynon, 4 miles SW of Merthyr-Tydvil, and 24 NNW of Cardiff. A railway and a canal connect it with Cardiff; and a junction branch, 1&#189; mile long, connects it with the railway from Merthyr-Tydvil to Neath. The scenery around it is picturesque. Extensive collieries and ironworks are adjacent; and these have raised the place, since about the year 1835, from the condition of a village to the condition of a large and flourishing town. The town has a telegraph station, a head post office,&#8225; two hotels, three banking offices, an elegant church called St. Elvan&apos;s, another church in the French pointed style built in 1865, two other churches, several dissenting chapels, a public park formed in 1868, markets on Wednesday and Saturday, and three annual fairs. The parish contains the hamlets of Cefnpennar, Cwmdare, Forchaman, and Llwydcoed; and is all within the parliamentary burgh of Merthyr-Tydvil. Acres, 16,310. Real property in Cefnpennar, &#163;32,867,-of which &#163;23,096 are in mines and ironworks; in Cwmdare, &#163;32,794, -of which &#163;12,374 are in mines and ironworks; in For chaman, &#163;54,871,-of which &#163;31,718 are in mines and ironworks; in Llwydcoed, &#163;29,874,-of which &#163;26,457 are in mines and ironworks. Pop. of the parish in 1841, 6,471; in 1861, 32,299. Houses, 5,834. The property is subdivided. Abernant House, the seat of one of the principal proprietors, adjoins the town. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelries of St. Elvan, Hirwain, and St. Mary, in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;305.* Patron, the Marquis of Bute. The vicarage of St. Fagan and the p. curacy of Mountain-Ash are separate. Value of St. F., &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of L. The Welsh poet Owen was a native, and the dissenting theologian E. Evans died here.-The subdistrict comprehends three parishes. Pop., 37,487. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aberdare</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Aberdare/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657835</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10098555</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ABERCWMBOI</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10155794</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ABERDAR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10215547</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>ABERDAR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551365</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ABERDARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740025</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>ABERDARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12826916</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>ABERDARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828871</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ABERDARE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1109</id>
   <name>LLANWRTYD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2056</id>
   <name>LLANFAIR AR BRYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3853</id>
   <name>CRAI</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5421</id>
   <name>BLAEN GWRACH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5943</id>
   <name>IS CLYDACH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6736</id>
   <name>MAES CAR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8433</id>
   <name>PENDERYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9526</id>
   <name>YSBYTY YSTWYTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10769</id>
   <name>RUGOS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
