<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1139</id>
<name>BRITON FERRY</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.6354240071043</lat>
<lon>-3.81080326660944</lon>
<gazetteerText>BRITON-FERRY, a village and a parish in Neath district, Glamorgan. The village stands at the mouth of the Neath river, the end of the Neath canal, and the terminus of a short branch of the South Wales railway, 2&#189; miles SSE of Neath; and has a head post office.&#8225; Large docks were formed here in 1861 and previous years, aided by &#163;20,000 from the Vale of Neath Railway Company; they comprise a tidal and floating area of 27 acres, and are provided with Armstrong&apos;s hydraulic machinery; and they will afford shipping accommodation to the mineral districts of Aberdare and Merthyr-Tydvil, nearer than that at Cardiff. The village is likewise the port of Neath; has undergone much recent increase; and promises soon to be an important town. The parish bears also the name of Llansawel; and comprises 1,593 acres. Real property, &#163;8,640; of which &#163;2,400 are in iron-works. Pop., 3,781. Houses, 627. The manor belonged formerly to the Mansells; and belongs now to the Earl of Jersey. The local scenery and the distant views are very fine. The view from a hill includes great part of the basin and screens of Bristol channel; and that from the churchyard is celebrated by Mason. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;124. Patron, the Earl of Jersey. The church is good, quaint, and pretty. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Briton_Ferry</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/BritonFerry/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654668</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10009388</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>BRITON FERRY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10375411</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BRITON FERRY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12827131</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BRITON FERRY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
