<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20351</id>
<name>LLANGYFELACH</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.6720695278763</lat>
<lon>-3.95830903838255</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANGAFELACH, or LLANGYFELACH, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred in Glamorgan. The village stands near the river Tawe, the Swansea canal, and the Vale of Neath railway, 4 miles WNW of Llansamlet r. station, and 3&#189; N of Swansea; and has a fair on 1 March.&#151;The parish contains also the village of Morriston, which has a post office under Swansea; and it includes the hamlets of Clase, Penderry, Mawr, and Rhyndwy-Clydach. Acres, 27,305. Real property, &#163;31,751; of which &#163;6,470 are in mines, and &#163;3,074 in the canal. Pop. in 1851,10,895; in 1861,13,219. Houses, 2,687. The property is much subdivided. The manor formerly belonged to Brecon college. Much of the land is naturally barren, and not a little has an aspect of extreme desolation. Copper-works and collieries employ a large proportion of the inhabitants; and they greatly disfigure the landscape. The fluoric or arsenical acids from the copper works keep down the naturally poor vegetation; the heaps of slag are an eye-sore; and the clouds of smoke from the numerous chimneys bedim the atmosphere. Many of the workmen and the colliers reside in the large village of Morriston. A battle was fought within the parish in 990, when Howel, prince of South Wales, was beaten. Some Roman relics have been found. The living is a vicarage, united with the o. curacy of Gorseinon, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;300. Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church is dedicated to St. Cyvelach; is a modern edifice, separated from the tower of an ancient one; and contains monuments to the Llewelyns of Penlergare. The p. curacies of Morriston and Clydach are separate benefices. There are chapels for Independents, Calvinistic Methodists, and Wesleyans, and charities &#163;29.&#151;The sub-district contains only the Clase hamlet of the parish, including the village of Morriston; but contains also the parish of St. John-near-Swansea, and the higher division of Swansea parish; and is in Swansea district. Pop., in 1851,9,812; in 1861, 14,553. Houses, 2,990.-The hundred contains the parishes of Llangafelach, Llansamlet, and Llanguick. Acres, 48,690. Pop. in 1851,11,829; in 1861,17,923. Houses, 3,611. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llangyfelach</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Llangyfelach/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7300393</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10226211</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>LLANGYFELACH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227641</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANGYFELACH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551249</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANGAFELACH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
