<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1127</id>
<name>PENARTH</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.4355328639415</lat>
<lon>-3.18469608734417</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENARTH, a sea-port and a parish in Cardiff district, Glamorgan. The sea-port adjoins Penarth-head, 3 miles S of Cardiff; is practically a suburb and a sub-port of Cardiff; communicates, by branch railway, with the railways at Cardiff; and has a post-office&#8225; under Cardiff, and a large dock. The dock was begun in 1851, and completed in 1865; is 2, 100 feet long, and 370 feet wide; covers an area of 17&#189; acres; has a basin of 3 acres, a lock of 400 feet by 300, and a sea-entrance 60 feet wide, with a depth of 35 feet over the sill at spring tides; and admits larger vessels than any other dock in the Bristolchannel. The parish comprises 1, 142 acres of land, and 365 of water. Real property, in 1860, &#163;4, 648; of which &#163;23 were in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 105; in 1861, 1, 406. Houses, 192. The living is a rectory, united with therectory of Lavernock, in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;187. Patron, the Baroness Windsor. The church was rebuilt in 1866, at a cost of about &#163;10,000; and is in the early English style and cruciform, with a tower. Achantry of Llandongh priory was here. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Penarth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640496</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Penarth/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10289075</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PENARTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10289087</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>PENARTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551160</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PENARTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12747901</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>CARDIFF SOUTH AND PENARTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12827969</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>PENARTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2163</id>
   <name>CAERAU</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2835</id>
   <name>LAVERNOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3014</id>
   <name>LECWITH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6808</id>
   <name>MICHAELSTON LE PIT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8761</id>
   <name>ST ANDREWS MAJOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
