<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4945</id>
<name>LOUGHOR</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.6558668528661</lat>
<lon>-4.05456737969904</lon>
<gazetteerText>LOUGHOR, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in the district of Llanelly and county of Glamorgan. The town stands on the river Loughor and on the Julian way, adjacent to the South Wales railway, 7 miles WNW of Swansea; occupies the site of the Roman station Leucarum; was once a place of considerable note, but now is practically a mere village; had a castle of Henry Beauchamp, built about 1100, taken by the Welsh in 1150, and given by Edward Il. to the Despencers; retains a ruined square tower of the castle; is a borough, nominally governed by a portreeve and 12 aldermen, and uniting with Swansea, Neath, and Kenfigg in sending a member to parliament; ranks as a sub-port to Swansea; and has a station on the railway, and fairs on 2 June and 10 Oct. A modern bridge takes the highway here across the river; and a bridge upwards of a &#188; of a mile long takes across the railway. The Spitty copperworks are on the opposite bank, and give employment to some of the inhabitants. Roman coins and other relics have been found; and two small Roman camps are near. Real property of the town, &#163;1,776; of which &#163;100 are in mines. Pop. in 1851. 821; in 1861,876. Houses, 198. -The parish includes a considerable rural tract; and comprises 3,589 acres of land, and 410 of water. Posttown, Llanelly. Real property, &#163;3,753; of which &#163;600 are in mines. Pop. in 1851,1,099; in 1861,1,238. Houses, 260. The property is not much divided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;180. Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is good.&#151;The sub-district contains also Llangennech parish and Berwick hamlet. Pop., 3,970. Houses, 788. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loughor</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Loughor/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643561</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10171544</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LOUGHOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10192523</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>LOUGHOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10200817</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>LLWCHWR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552576</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LOUGHOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12798260</id>
   <status>PA</status>
   <name>LOUGHOR BOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12798271</id>
   <status>PA</status>
   <name>LOUGHOR PARISH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2476</id>
   <name>LLANDEILO TAL Y BONT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3395</id>
   <name>CLAS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6147</id>
   <name>GOWERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6156</id>
   <name>LLANEDI</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6764</id>
   <name>MAWR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10778</id>
   <name>PENDERI</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
