<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10774</id>
<name>LLANGYNWYD</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.5879953242709</lat>
<lon>-3.63418074099159</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANGONOYD, or LLANGYNWYD, a parish in Neath and Bridgend districts, Glamorgan; on the upper part of the river Llynvy, and on the Llynvy railway, on which it has a station, 6 miles NNW of Bridgend. It comprises the hamlet of Higher Llangonoyd in Neayh district, and the hamlets of Middle Llangonoyd, Lower Llangonoyd, and Cwmdu in Bridgend district; and it contains the villages of Maesteg and Spelter-Works, each of which has a post office under Bridgend. Acres of Higher L., 6,544. Pop. in 1851,1,496; in 1861, 2,187. Houses, 409. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of the iron and coal trades. Acres of Middle L., 3,076. Pop. in 1851,329; in 1861,324. Houses, 60. Acres of Lower L., 2,027. Pop. in 1851,304; in 1861,337. Houses, 68. Acres of Cwmdu, 3,813. Pop. in 1851,3,350; in 1861,4,154. Houses, 797. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of the iron manufactory. Real property of the parish, &#163;20,921; of which &#163;7,270 are in mines, and &#163;8,903 in iron-works. The surface is hilly. Cevn Udva is an ancient seat of the Mackworths. There are ruins of an old castle, and remains of several ancient camps. The parish was a retreat of Edward II. in his adversity. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelries of Baidan, Maesteg, and Spelter-Works, in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;300. * Patron, the Bishop of Llandaff. The church is dedicated to St. Cynwyd. There are a chapel of ease at Maesteg, several dissenting chapels, a national school, and three British schools. A ruined chapel is in Baidan. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Llangynwyd/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llangynwyd</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643996</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10115050</id>
   <status>Cmt</status>
   <name>LLANGYNWYD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10228270</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANGYNWYD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377079</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>LLANGYNWYD CANOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377134</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>LLANGYNWYD LOWER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10484844</id>
   <status>Hmlt/CP/Tn</status>
   <name>LLANGYNWYD UCHAF</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
