<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10758</id>
<name>BAGLAN</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.6204422427269</lat>
<lon>-3.81305135154676</lon>
<gazetteerText>BAGLAN, a parish in Neath district, Glamorgan; on the E side of the mouth of Neath river, and on the South Wales railway, 1&#188; mile S by W of Briton Ferry r. station, and 3&#188; S of Neath. It comprises the hamlets of Lower Baglan and Upper Baglan; and its Post Town is Briton Ferry, under Neath. Acres, 6,479; of which 1,240 are water. Real property, &#163;3,471; of which &#163;550 are in mines. Pop. of Lower Baglan, 456. Houses, 92. Pop. of Higher Baglan, 259. Houses, 28. The scenery possesses much beauty and some romance; and the higher grounds command very brilliant views. Earl Jersey&apos;s park spreads away, in extensive woods, over several bold hills; and Baglan House, the mansion in it, though without attraction as a building, possesses interest as once the resort of Mason, who wrote here his elegy: Coventry is dead! attend the strain, Daughters of Albion. Coal and fire-clay are worked. The living is a vicarage, annexed to the vicarage of Aberavon, in the diocese of Llandaff. The church is very picturesquely situated; and there is a Calvinistic Methodist chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6692309</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Baglan/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baglan</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10007628</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Hmlt</status>
   <name>BAGLAN HIGHER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376117</id>
   <status>CP/Hmlt</status>
   <name>LOWER BAGLAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10485095</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>BAGLAN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
