<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1778</id>
<name>EGLWYSILAN</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.5869385593529</lat>
<lon>-3.25860032541482</lon>
<gazetteerText>EGLWYS-ILAN, a parish in Cardiff district, Glamorgan; adjacent to the river Taf, the Taf Valley railway, and the Cardiff and Merthyr-Tydvil canal, 2&#189; miles SE by E of Newbridge Junction r. station, and 9&#189; NW of Cardiff. It contains the hamlets of Energlyn, Park, Hendredenny, Glyntaf, and Rhydyboithan; and its post town is Pont-y-Pridd. Acres, 13, 619. Real property, &#163;18, 661; of which &#163;1, 936 are in mines, &#163;1, 000 in iron-works, &#163;67 in quarries, &#163;170 in railways, and &#163;85 in the canal. Pop. in 1851, 5, 110; in 1861, 6, 383. Houses, 1, 343. The property is not much divided. Vann belonged to the Lewises, and passed to the Earl of Plymouth. Energlyn is the seat of the Goodriches. Coal, iron, and tin are worked; and manufactories in pottery and in other departments are carried on. The increase in population between 1851 and 1861 arose from the extension of mining and manufacturing operations. The Taf well here has had much repute in rheumatic ailments. Pont-y-Pridd, with its elegant bridge, and Caerphilly, with its interesting antiquities, are within the parish. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Eglwys-Drindod, in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;150.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Llandaff. The church is good. The rectory of Caerphilly and the vicarage of Glyntaf are separate benefices. Alldworth&apos;s school for girls, at Caerphilly, has &#163;60 from endowment. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/Eglwysilan/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10018778</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EGLWYSILAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551341</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EGLWYSILAN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
