<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1128</id>
<name>PONT Y PRIDD</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.6001350641815</lat>
<lon>-3.32694328457546</lon>
<gazetteerText>PONTYPRIDD, a small town in Lantwit-Vairdre and Llanwonno parishes, Glamorgan; on the river Taff. and on the Taff Vale railway, at the junction of the Rhondabranch to Treherbet, 13 miles N W by N of Cardiff. Itsname signifies &quot;the bridge of the earthen hut, &quot; and alludes to a mud house which stood on its site, and to afamous bridge constructed over the Taff, in 1755 and previous years, by the self-taught architect William Edwards, whose biography is narrated in the &quot; Pursuit of Knowledge.&quot; The bridge stands on a site where the riveris broad and the banks are low; exhibits ingenuity ofcontrivance to overcome the disadvantageousness of the site; and is of one arch, 140 feet in span, 35 feet high, and 15 feet broad. The town has a head post-office, &#8225; a railway-station with telegraph, two good inns, and a church in the Norman style, erected in 1838; and it carries on much trade in connexion with neighbouring iron-works and collieries. A poor-law district of Pontypriddwas formed in 1863, out of the district of Merthyr-Tydvil. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pontypridd</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Pontypridd</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640104</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10221330</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>PONTYPRIDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10292876</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>PONT Y PRIDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10292888</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>PONT Y PRIDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10292906</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PONT Y PRIDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10561530</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PONTYPRIDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12738638</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>PONTYPRIDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740827</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>GLAMORGANSHIRE PONTYPRIDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828019</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>PONTYPRIDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828020</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>PONTYPRIDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12830804</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PONTYPRIDD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2484</id>
   <name>LLANFABON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
