<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20213</id>
<name>CADOXTON JUXTA BARRY</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.4155413325197</lat>
<lon>-3.25120360087795</lon>
<gazetteerText>CADOXTON-JUXTA-BARRY, a parish in Cardiff district, Glamorgan; on the coast, 4&#190; miles S of St. Fagans r. station, and 6&#189; SW of Cardiff. Post Town, Sully, under Cardiff. Acres, 1,028; of which 80 are water. Real property, &#163;1,009. Pop., 279. Houses, 64. There are remains of a castle; and lime is worked The living is a rectory in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;100. Patron, R. F. Jenner, Esq., and others. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/GLA/CadoxtonJuxtaBarry/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654105</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10117501</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Ch</status>
   <name>CADOXTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>20214</id>
<name>CADOXTON JUXTA NEATH</name>
<container>GLAMORGAN</container>
<lat>51.6727938791194</lat>
<lon>-3.80067708404614</lon>
<gazetteerText>CADOXTON, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict in Neath district, Glamorgan. The village stands on the Sarn-Helen Roman way and the river Neath, adjacent to the Neath canal and the Vale of Neath railway, &#189; a mile N of Neath; and is within Neath borough. The parish includes the hamlets of Blaenhonddan, Dyffryn-Clydach, Coedfrank, Ynis-y-mond, Upper Dylais, Lower Dylais, Lower Neath, Middle Neath, and Upper Neath; and extends about 15 miles from Briton-Ferry to Pont-Neath-Vaughan. Post Town, Neath. Acres, 32,060; of which 905 are water. Real property, &#163;49,268; of which &#163;22,891 are in mines, and &#163;4,800 in iron-works. Pop. in 1841, 5,794; in 1861, 8,209. Houses, 1,600. The property is subdivided. The surface is hilly, and displays much fine scenery. Aberpergwm, the seat of the Williams family, is remarkably picturesque. Ynis-las, Cadoxton Lodge, and Cadoxton Place also are chief residences. Coal and ores abound; and the Neath Abbey iron-works, the Crown and Mines Royal copper-works, and many other large mineral or manufacturing establishments are within the parish. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Crynant, in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;240.* Patron, R. H. Miers, Esq. The church is good; and contains the pedigree of the Williams family, engraved on sheets of copper. The vicarages of Skewen and Aberpergwm, are separate benefices. There is a chapel of ease at Crynant. There are also chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Calvinistic Methodists. The parish, under a modified form of its name, gives title to Earl Cadogan. The subdistrict contains part of Cadoxton parish and the whole of another. Acres, 27,304. Pop., 7,522. Houses, 1,462. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10010329</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CADOXTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10488813</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>CADOXTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551146</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CADOXTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
