<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10339</id>
<name>AVENING</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6821419003834</lat>
<lon>-2.17047269848147</lon>
<gazetteerText>AVENING, a parish in Stroud district, Gloucester; 3&#189; miles S of Brimscombe r. station, and 6 SSE of Stroud. It lies within the parliamentary borough of Stroud; has a post office under that town; and includes the hamlets of Aston, Forest-Green, Freeholds, West-End, Bell-Street, and Windsors-Edge, and part of the chapelry of Nailsworth. Acres, 4,428. Real property, &#163;5,448. Pop., 2,070. Houses, 479. The manor belonged anciently to the nunnery of Caen in Normandy; and passed to the Shepheards. A large tumulus, known as the Longstone, and supposed to be the sepulchre of a Danish chief occurs in a field near Gatcombe Park; and there are several barrows in which human skeletons have been found. A small manufacture of woollen cloth is carried on. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;769.* Patron, the Hon. L. H. Harman. The church is thought to have been erected by an abbess of Caen. The p. curacies of Nailsworth and Inchbrook are separate charges. There are three dissenting chapels, a school with &#163;22 a year from endowment, and other charities &#163;9. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656756</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avening</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Avening/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19081</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19083</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19084</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19077</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19078</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19080</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19079</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19082</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10355345</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>AVENING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10355357</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>AVENING</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
