<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11466</id>
<name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9606790835286</lat>
<lon>-1.9741351922895</lon>
<gazetteerText>WINCHCOMB, a small town, a parish, and a district, in Gloucester. The town stands on the river Isborne, under the Cotswolds, at the terminus of the Winchcomb and Midland railway, 6&#190; miles NE of Cheltenham; was known, at Domesday, as Wincelcombe; had a mitred Benedictine abbey, founded in 798 by King Kenulph, destroyed by the Danes, and rebuilt as a secular college in 985 by Bishop Oswald; was a residence and the burial-place of King Kenulph; numbers amongst its natives Bishop Tideman and the physician Merret; is a borough by prescription, with two bailiffs and eight burgesses, possessing little jurisdiction; is also a seat of petty sessions and county courts; carries on industry in a silk factory, a large paper mill, a tan-yard and skin-yard, and four flour-mills; and has a post-office&#8225; under Cheltenham, a banking office, a police station, a neat recent town hall, a reading room, a mechanics&apos; institute, an early English and Tudor parish church, Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, two endowed schools with &#163;70 a year, a national school, a workhouse, charities &#163;48, a weekly market on Saturday, and five annual fairs.&#151;The parish includes eleven hamlets, and comprises 5,700 acres. Real property, &#163;13,486. Pop., in 1851, 2,824; in 1861, 2,937. Houses, 634. Sudeley Castle, Postlip Hall, Corndean Hall, and the Abbey are chief residences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;200.* Patron, Lord Sudeley. A chapel of ease and a Wesleyan chapel are at Gretton; and a ruined Norman Chapel is at Postlip.&#151;The district contains 21 parishes and 3 parts; and is divided into Guiting and Cleeve sub-districts. Acres, 57,494. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;4,667. Pop. in 1851, 10,136; in 1861, 10,082. Houses, 2,245. Marriages in 1866, 65; births, 335,0 of which 23 were illegitimate; deaths, 172,-of which 58 were at ages under 5 years, and 9 at ages above 85. Marriages in the 10 years 1851-60, 630; births, 3,027; deaths, 1,843. The places of worship, in 1851, were 26 of the Church of England, with 4,584 sittings; 5 of Baptists, with 655 s.; 3 of Lady Huntingdon&apos;s Connexion, with 518 s.; and 5 of Wesleyans, with 723 s. The schools were 16 public day-schools, with 534 scholars; 14 private day-schools, with 172 s.; 32 Sunday schools, with 1,500 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 25 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Winchcombe/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winchcombe</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Winchcomb</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633860</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10004007</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10024006</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10026039</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10029650</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10395574</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10395586</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE WITH GRETTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10395598</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE WITH GRETTON AND SUDELEY MANOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10469892</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582684</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582696</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582702</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE NORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582714</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE SOUTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10313</id>
   <name>ALDERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10485</id>
   <name>CHARLTON ABBOTS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10589</id>
   <name>DIDBROOK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10806</id>
   <name>TEMPLE GUITING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10808</id>
   <name>GUITING POWER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10810</id>
   <name>HAILES</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10836</id>
   <name>HAWLING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11087</id>
   <name>PINNOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11173</id>
   <name>SEVENHAMPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11332</id>
   <name>SUDELEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
