<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10825</id>
<name>HARESFIELD</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7921936187324</lat>
<lon>-2.28315324647934</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARESFIELD, a parish and a sub-district in Wheatenhurst district, Gloucester. The parish lies on the Bristol and Gloucester railway, and on the Berkeley canal, 3 miles N of Stonehouse, and 4&#189; NW of Stroud; and has a station on the railway, and a post-office under Stonehouse. Acres, 2,155; of which 175 are water. Real property, &#163;8,208; of which &#163;2,501 are in the railway, and &#163;300 in the canal. Pop., 612. Houses, 134. The property is divided among a few. The manor, with Haresfield Court, belongs to John D. T. Niblett, Esq. An ancient camp is at Broad Ridge. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;260.* Patron, John D. T. Niblett, Esq. The church is ancient; is supposed to have been built by the prior of Llanthony abbey; comprises nave, two chancels, and a porch, with tower and spire; and was recently repaired. Charities, &#163;15.&#151;The sub-district contains eight parishes. Acres. 13,157. Pop., 3,314. Houses, 707. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Haresfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647483</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15828</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15824</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15823</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15825</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15826</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15829</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15822</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15827</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10378266</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HARESFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10378278</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARESFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553179</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HARESFIELD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
