<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10846</id>
<name>HENBURY</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5278758098168</lat>
<lon>-2.65028477815442</lon>
<gazetteerText>HENBURY, a village, a tything, a parish, and a hundred, in Gloucester. The village stands on the S W.verge of the county, near the Fosse way and the estuary of the Severn. 4&#189; miles NW of Bristol r. station: is a and has a post office under Bristol. The tything comprises 1, 490 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 314. Pop., 423. Houses, 96.&#151;The parish contains also the tythings of Kings-Weston, Lawrence-Weston, Stowick, Compton, Charlton, Aust, and Redwick and Northwick; and is chiefly in the district of Clifton, but partly in that of Thornbury. Acres, 15, 409; of which 5, 820 are water. Real property, &#163;25, 757. Pop., 2, 482. Houses, 492. The manor belongs to Sir Greville Smyth, Bart., and E. Colston, Esq. Blaise Castle is the seat of J. S. Harford, Esq. Henbury Hill, on which Blaise Castle stands, had a double ditched Roman camp; has yielded many Roman coins and other relics; and commands an exceedingly varied and beautiful view. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelries of Hallen, Aust, and Northwick, in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;840.* Patrons, Sir G. Smyth, Bart., Mrs. Colston, and the Rev. G. Gore. The church is early English; was repaired and enlarged in 1833; and comprises nave, aisles, and two porches, with low square tower. There are chapels for Baptists, Quakers, and Wesleyans, national schools, an endowed grammar school with &#163;349, another endowed school with &#163;235, and other charities with &#163;267.-The hundred is cut into two divisions, lower and upper; the former containing Westbury-onTrym parish and part of Henbury; the latter containing Compton-Greenfield, Stoke-Gifford, and Yate parishes, and parts of Henbury and Tytherington. Acres of the whole, 27, 622. Pop., 7, 377. Houses, 1, 416. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Henbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647117</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10030997</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>HENBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10378734</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HENBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10378758</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HENBURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11073</id>
   <name>SEVERN BEACH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
