<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10819</id>
<name>HARDWICKE</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.813411384719</lat>
<lon>-2.30315989552249</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARDWICKE, a village and a parish in Wheatenhurst district, Gloucestershire. The village stands near the Gloucester and Berkeley canal, 2 miles W of Haresfield r. station, and 4 SW by S of Gloucester; and gives the title of Earl to the family of Yorke. The parish comprises 2,378 acres. Post-town, Gloucester. Real property, &#163;6,139; of which &#163;867 are in the canal. Pop. 625. Houses, 113. The manor belonged formerly to the Botelers and the Tryes, and belongs now to T. B. L. Baker, Esq. Hardwicke Court, a modern edifice, is the seat of Mr. Baker. Other chief landowners are J. C. Hayward and J. D. Niblett, Esqs. The living is a vicarage, annexed to the vicarage of Standish, in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. The church is early English and Tudor; consists of nave, aisle, and chancel, with porch and tower; contains monuments of the Tryes, and a very ancient font; and was repaired in 1850. There is a reformatory school, founded by Mr. Baker, the oldest in the kingdom; and it has accommodation for 45 boys. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hardwicke,_Gloucestershire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Hardwicke/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647489</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15814</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15815</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15817</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15818</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15820</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15821</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15816</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15819</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10378151</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>HARDWICKE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10987</id>
   <name>LONGNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
