<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11001</id>
<name>MITCHELDEAN</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8637165970918</lat>
<lon>-2.49107672658601</lon>
<gazetteerText>MITCHELDEAN, MITCHELL-DEAN, or DEAN-MAGNA, a village and a parish in Westbury-on-Severn district, Gloucester. The village stands in Dean Forest, 1 mile E of the boundary with Hereford, 2 S of MitcheldeanRoad r. station, and 5 NNW of Newnham; is an ancient place; takes its name partly from the word &quot;mickle &apos;&apos;or. great, and partly from its situation in Dean forest; and has a post office,&#8225; of the name of Mitcheldean, under Newnham, a good inn, a police station, and fairs on Easter Monday and 12 Oct. The parish comprises 680 acres. Real property, &#163;2,637. Pop., 689. Houses, 144. The property is divided among a few. The manor and much of the land belong to the representatives of the 1ate Maynard Colchester, Esq. The Wilderness is the seat of Mrs. H. Davis. Coal and iron ore are worked in the neighbourhood. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;176.* Patrons, the representatives of the late M. Colchester. The church is chiefly later English; was recently restored; consists of nave, S aisle, two N aisles, chancel, and porch, with tower and lofty spire; and contains an ancient font, some wall-paintings of the time of Edward IV., and several old monuments. There are an Independent chapel, an endowed school with &#163;81 a year, and charities &#163;27. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Mitcheldean/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642412</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=23259</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10383808</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MITCHELDEAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10383810</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MITCHELDEAN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4239</id>
   <name>LEA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10306</id>
   <name>ABENHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10980</id>
   <name>LONGHOPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
