<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>446</id>
<name>KINGSWOOD</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.4600102348485</lat>
<lon>-2.50151785510852</lon>
<gazetteerText>KINGSWOOD, a village and a chapelry in Bitton parish, Gloucester. The village stands near the Bristol and Gloucester railway, between Stapleton and Mangotsfield stations, 3&#189; miles NE by E of Bristol; and has a post office&#8224; under Bristol.&#151;The chapelry was constituted in 1821. Pop., 4, 699. Houses, 986. The property is much subdivided. The land was anciently a royal chase or forest, or literally a King&apos;s wood. Most of the inhabitants are employed in collieries and shoe making; and some in market gardens. A great work of religions reformation was done here under the preaching of Wesley and Whitefield; and a classical school, for the sons of preachers, was established by Wesley. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;100.* Patron, the Bishop of Gloucester and Bristol. The church is a square structure, in the pointed style, with a tower 90 feet high; and has a handsome interior, and a stone pulpit. There are an Independent chapel, national schools, and the Bristol reformatory. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645418</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10003982</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>KINGSWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10074198</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>KINGSWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10381964</id>
   <status>Hmlt/CP</status>
   <name>KINGSWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10382038</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KINGSWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549760</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KINGSWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12735492</id>
   <status>CCon/BCon</status>
   <name>KINGSWOOD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1193</id>
   <name>MANGOTSFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1194</id>
   <name>STAPLETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10818</id>
   <name>HANHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10835</id>
   <name>HAWKESBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11053</id>
   <name>OLDLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11111</id>
   <name>PUCKLECHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11275</id>
   <name>SISTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11456</id>
   <name>WESTERLEIGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11463</id>
   <name>WICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12473</id>
   <name>BRISLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>10939</id>
<name>KINGSWOOD</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.616461406756</lat>
<lon>-2.37599284700173</lon>
<gazetteerText>KINGSWOOD, a village and a parish in Dursley district, Gloucester. The village stands 1 mile NE of carries on manufactures in woollen cloth; and has a post office under Wootton-under-Edge. The parish comprises 2, 350 acres. Real property, &#163;6, 443. Pop. in 1851, 1, 227; in 1861, 1, 061. Houses, 268. The decrease of pop. was caused by depression in the cloth manufacture. The property is divided. The land anciently formed part of an extensive forest, superintended by the constable of Bristol castle. The manor belongs now to R. H. Blagden Hale, Esq. A Cistertian priory, a cell to Tintern abbey, was founded here, in 1139, by William de Berkeley; was removed, for a time, to Rodmorden and Tutbury; was re-founded here in 1170; was given, by Queen Elizabeth, to the Thynnes; and remains of it still exist near the parish church. woollen cloth factories are at Kingswood Mills and Nind Mills; and there is a brewery. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;99.* Patrons, the Parishioners. The church comprises nave, aisles, and chancel; and contains monuments of the Berkeleys and others. There are an Independent chapel, a free school with &#163;50 a year, and charities &#163;149. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/KingswoodBristol/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645417</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/KingswoodWotton/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10381927</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>KINGSWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10381952</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KINGSWOOD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
