<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10883</id>
<name>HORSLEY</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.674572075943</lat>
<lon>-2.22501891259137</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORSLEY, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Stroud district, Gloucester. The village stands under the Cotswolds, 3 miles SW of Minchinhampton, and 5 S of Stroud r. station; was once a market town, and a place of more importance than now; consists chiefly of old houses, irregularly built; and has a post office under Stroud, and a police station. The parish includes also the hamlet of Chaseridge, the village of Nailsworth, and the hamlets of Barton-End, Down-End, Newmarket, Rockness, Shortwood, Nupp-End, and Walkley-Wood. Acres, 4, 082. Real property, exclusive of Nailsworth, &#163;8, 545; of which &#163;10 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 2, 931; in 1861, 2, 558. Houses, 630. The decrease of pop. was caused by the closing of cloth mills. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Townsend Stephens, Esq. A Tudor manor house, with chapel attached, is at Chavenage. An ancient priory, a cell to St. Martin du Tours, stood near the church; passed to Bruton abbey, to the Dennys, and to the Stephenses; and is now represented by only a gateway. The woollen manufacture, though much declined, is still carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;199.* Patron, the Bishop of Gloucester and Bristol. The church is perpendicular English; and consists of nave, transept, and chancel, with a tower. There is a chapel of ease at Shortwood. The p. curacy of Chaseridge is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, an endowed national school, and charities &#163;100.&#151;The sub-district contains also the parish of Avening. Acres, 8, 510. Pop., 4, 628. Houses, 1, 109. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Horsley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646554</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19095</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19096</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19097</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19100</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19098</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19093</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19094</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19099</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10379817</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10379829</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552825</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
