<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>21463</id>
<name>HILLSLEY</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6051921484892</lat>
<lon>-2.33359293456615</lon>
<gazetteerText>HILLESLEY, HILLSLEY, or HILDESLEY, a tything and a chapelry in Hawkesbury parish, Gloucester. The tything lies under the Cotswolds, 2&#190; miles S by E of Wotton-under-Edge, and 3&#189; ENE of Wickwar r. station. Real property, &#163;2, 355. Pop., 451. Houses, 121. The chapelry includes also the hamlet of Kilcott; and was constituted in 1852. Post town, Wotton-under-Edge. Pop., 574. Houses, 146. The property is subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;71.* Patron, the Bishop of Gloucester and Bristol. The church was rebuilt in 1851; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with porch and bell turret. The previous church was an ancient chapel, with a chantry; and many interesting remains of it were discovered at the founding of the present edifice. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Hillesley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646886</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10379120</id>
   <status>Ch</status>
   <name>HILLESLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10379167</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HILLESLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>10858</id>
<name>HILL</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6600086303258</lat>
<lon>-2.51767661500332</lon>
<gazetteerText>HILL, a parish in Thornbury district, Gloucester; adjacent to the river Severn, 4 miles N of Thornbury, and 5&#189; W by S of Dursley Junction r. station. Posttown, Berkeley. Acres, 2, 476; of which 510 are water. Real property, &#163;4, 146. Pop., 216. Houses, 44. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Herbert Jenner, Esq. Hill Court is an ancient mansion, supposed to occupy the site of a monastery of the 12th century. The living is a donative in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;250.* Patron, Herbert Jenner, Esq. The church is ancient but good; and has a tower and spire. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Hill/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646900</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10379039</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10379118</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
