<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11100</id>
<name>PRESTBURY</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9157036899861</lat>
<lon>-2.04055935282927</lon>
<gazetteerText>PRESTBURY, a village and a parish in Cheltenham district, Gloucester. The village stands under the Cotswolds, 2 miles N E of Cheltenham r. station; was once a market-town; suffered great devastation by fire in the time of Henry VII.; and has a post-office under Cheltenham. The parish contains also the hamlet of Noverton and the Pittville pump-room, gardens, and drives. Acres, 3,022. Real property, &#163;11, 423. Pop., 1, 297. Houses, 268. The landed property is divided chiefly among four. Prestbury House is the seat ofCapel, Esq.; the Priory, of the Rev. J. Edwards; and there are other good residences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;234.* Patron, the Rev. J. Edwards. The church is old but good; comprises nave, aisles, and chancel, with embattled tower; and contains several fine mural monuments. There are a national school, an alms-house for ten persons, and charities &#163;30. F. Philipps the antiquary was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prestbury,_Gloucestershire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Prestbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7298562</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10208520</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>PRESTBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10386718</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PRESTBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10386720</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PRESTBURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>290</id>
   <name>STOW ON THE WOLD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9552</id>
   <name>CURBRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9924</id>
   <name>LEAFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9971</id>
   <name>MILTON UNDER WYCHWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9972</id>
   <name>MINSTER LOVELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10169</id>
   <name>SHIPTON UNDER WYCHWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10405</id>
   <name>BOURTON ON THE WATER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10544</id>
   <name>BISHOPS CLEEVE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11135</id>
   <name>LITTLE RISSINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11466</id>
   <name>WINCHCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
