<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10395</id>
<name>BITTON</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.4357258506863</lat>
<lon>-2.45735103013068</lon>
<gazetteerText>BITTON, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Keynsham, and county of Gloucester. The village stands near the confluence of the Boyd and the Avon, adjacent to the Julian way, 2 miles NE of Keynsham r. station, and 6 SE of Bristol; and it has a post office under Bristol.&#151;The parish includes also Hanham chapelry and Oldland hamlet, with Kingswood village. Acres, 7,156. Real property, &#163;28,319; of which &#163;1,594 are in mines. Pop., 9,630. Houses, 2,032. The property is much subdivided. Coal and iron ore are worked; and the workers at them, in last century, were noted for vicious character, and for reclamation by the preaching of Wesley and his associates. Traces of many Roman antiquities have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;390.* Patron, the Bishop of Gloucester and Bristol. The church is partly Norman, partly perpendicular English; and has a good tower. The vicarages of Hanham, Oldland, and Kingswood are separate benefices. There are a Wesleyan chapel, national schools, and charities &#163;26.-The subdistrict comprises three parishes. Acres, 8,267. Pop., 5,071. Houses, 1,063. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Bitton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655536</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10357214</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BITTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10357275</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BITTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549747</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BITTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10569886</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BITTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1243</id>
   <name>ST GEORGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
