<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11292</id>
<name>CHIPPING SODBURY</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5366617776575</lat>
<lon>-2.39114642649278</lon>
<gazetteerText>SODBURY (Chipping), a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Gloucester. The town stands-on a declivity, adjacent to the river Frome, 1&#190; mile E of Yate r. station, and 10&#189; NE of Bristol; is a seat of petty-sessions, and a polling place; is governed by a bailiff and 12 burgesses; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a banking office, two chief inns, an old town hall with rebuilt front, a police station, an ancient church with pinnacled tower, Baptist and Quakers&apos; chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a literary society, a reading room and library, an endowed grammar-school, a national school, town-lands, &#163;288, a market on the first Tuesday of every month, and fairs on Holy Thursday and 24 June.&#151;The parish comprises 120 acres. Real property, &#163;2,805. Pop., 1,112. Houses, 249. The manor belongs to W. H. H. Hartley, Esq. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;167.* Patron, the Vicar of Old Sodbury.&#151;The sub-district contains also 5 other parishes. Acres, 14,115. Pop., 5,252. Houses, 1,091. -The district comprehends also the sub-districts of Marshfield, Hawkesbury, and Iron-Acton; and comprises 62,356 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;8,087. Pop. in 1851, 18,256; in 1861, 18,763. Houses, 4,020. Marages in 1863, 76; births, 656,-of which 40 were illegitimate; deaths, 457,-of which 200 were at ages under 5 years, and 15 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60,944; births, 5,954; deaths, 3,591. The places of worship, in 1851, were 27 of the Church of England, with 7,913 sittings; 10 of Independents, with 2,049 s.; 5 of Baptists, with 1,105 s.; 1 of Quakers, with 120 s.; 1 of Unitarians, with 25 s.; 6 of Wesleyans, with 1,206 s.; 3 of Primitive Methodists, with 280 s.; 1 undefined, with 20 s.; and 1 of Roman Catholics, with 120 s. The schools were 26 public day-schools, with 1,630 scholars; 32 private day-schools, with 496 s.; 31 Sunday schools, with 2,478 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 3 s. The workhouse is in Yate. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653137</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/ChippingSodbury</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/ChippingSodbury/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001973</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>CHIPPING SODBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10028164</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>CHIPPING SODBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10107623</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>SODBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10167644</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>CHIPPING SODBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10196863</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>CHIPPING SODBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10391283</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SODBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10391325</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CHIPPING SODBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10391404</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHIPPING SODBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553222</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHIPPING SODBURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
