<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11314</id>
<name>KINGS STANLEY</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7274580015436</lat>
<lon>-2.26035461758809</lon>
<gazetteerText>KINGSTANLEY, or Kings-Stanley, a village and a parish in Stroud district, Gloucester. The village stands on the Stroudwater canal, 1&#189; mile S of Stonehouse r. station, and 3&#189; SW of Stroud; is a considerable place; carries on cloth manufacture; and has a post office under Stonehouse. The parish comprises 1, 679 acres, and is all within Stroud borough. Real property, &#163;7, 561; of which &#163;14 are in quarries. Pop., 2, 038. Houses, 488. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the Mercian kings; passed to the Maltraverses, the Arundels, and others; and belongs now to W. Leigh and S. S. Marling, Esqs. Stanley Park, the seat of Mr. Marling, is a handsome mansion. Traces of a Roman camp are within the parish; and Roman altars and other relics have been found. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, Jesus College, Cambridge. The church is good, and has a tower. The parsonage is ancient, and was recently restored and enlarged. A new church, at Selsley, for a newly constituted chapelry, was built in 1862; and is in the early geometric style. There are a Baptist chapel, a national school, a British school, and charities &#163;15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/KingsStanley/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/King's_Stanley</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15873</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15872</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15870</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15874</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15871</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15876</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15869</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15875</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10024596</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>KINGS STANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10391763</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>KINGS STANLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10409147</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KINGS STANLEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11474</id>
   <name>WOODCHESTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
