<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10718</id>
<name>FROCESTER</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7262211655958</lat>
<lon>-2.31797751516596</lon>
<gazetteerText>FROCESTER, a village and a parish in Wheatenhurst district, Gloucester. The village stands under Camley Pike, adjacent to the Bristol and Gloucester railway, 5 miles W by S of Stroud; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Stonehouse. The parish comprises 1,833 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 938; of which &#163;1, 386 are in railways. Pop., 262. Houses, 59. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged formerly to the Huntleys; and belongs now to the Earl of Ducie. The manor-house, Frocester Court, is of the time of Elizabeth; and it gave that sovereign a night&apos;s lodging in 1574. A grand residence of the abbots of Gloucester was in the parish; and an ancient conventual barn, 210 feet, is still standing. Camley Pike, in the vicinity of the village, is a conical hill, commanding an extensive and very fine view. The living is a vicarage, with Chapel, in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Valne, &#163;229.* Patron, the Rev. H. W. Bloxsome. The church is modern, and has a neat tower. Charities, &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Frocester/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649032</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15813</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15806</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15807</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15808</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15810</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15811</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15809</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15812</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10374698</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FROCESTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374704</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FROCESTER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
