<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>725</id>
<name>TETBURY</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6387382459436</lat>
<lon>-2.15703196034009</lon>
<gazetteerText>TETBURY, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Gloucester. The town stands on a rising-ground, 7 miles SSW of Tetbury-Road r. station, and 11 SW of Cirencester; is supposed to occupy the site of an ancient British strength, called Caer-Bladon; had anciently a monastic establishment, afterwards called Hacket-Court; is a seat of petty sessions; consists chiefly of four streets, meeting at a centre; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a banking office, two chief inns, a town hall, a market house, a police station, an assembly-room at one of the inns, a parochial church of 1784 with old tower and spire, a chapel of ease built in 1848, four dissenting chapels, a literary institute with library and reading room, an endowed grammar-school with &#163;360 a year, another endowed school with &#163;60, alms-house s, a workhouse, charities &#163;653, a weekly market on Wednesday, and six annual fairs. Pop. in 1861,2,285. Houses, 491.&#151;The parish includes four tythings, and comprises 4,582 acres. Real property, &#163;14,099; of which &#163;60 are in gasworks. Pop., 3,274. Houses, 690. The manor belongs to a local charity. Elmstree house , Upton Grove, and the Priory are chief residenccs. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol-Value, &#163;1,000.* Patron, Stanton, Esq.&#151;The sub-district contains 7 parishes. Acres, 16,259. Pop, 4,640. Houses, 974.&#151;The district includes also Didmarton sub-district, and comprises 25,641 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;2,441. Pop. in 1851, 6,254; in 1861, 6,110. Houses, 1,287. Marriages in 1863, 39; births, 164,-of which 3 were illegitimate; deaths, 109,-of which 33 were at ages under 5 years, and 4 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 423; births, 1,880; deaths, 1,130. The places of worship, in 1851, were 15 of the Church of England, with 3,521 sittings; 1 of Independents, with 240 s.; 2 of Baptists, with 450 s.; 1 of Wesleyans, with 144 s.; 2 undefined, with 460 s.: and 1 of Latter Day Saints, with 70 s. The schools were 11 public day-schools, with 545 scholars; 9 private day-schools, with 138 s.; and 15 Sunday schools, with 908 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Tetbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tetbury</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Tetbury</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636083</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19141</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19149</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19143</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19144</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19146</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19147</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19148</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19151</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19142</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19145</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=19150</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10055672</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135734</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10137743</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10153335</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10185579</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10207617</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10392949</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10392974</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10392986</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>TETBURY UPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10470523</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552989</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581138</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TETBURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10377</id>
   <name>BEVERSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11268</id>
   <name>SHIPTON MOYNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
