<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10835</id>
<name>HAWKESBURY</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5893600795981</lat>
<lon>-2.31281883896324</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAWKESBURY, a tything, a parish, and a sub-district, in Chipping-Sodbury district, Gloucester. The tything lies under the Cotswolds, 3 miles W of the boundary with Wilts, 4 NW by N of Chipping-Sodbury, and 4 ESE of Wickwar r. station; has a post office, of the name of Hawkesbury-Upton, under Chippenham, a police station, and a fair on the last Friday of Aug.; and gave the title of Baron to the Earls of Liverpool. Real property, &#163;3, 554. Pop., 466. Houses, 108.&#151;The parish contains also the tythings of Upton, Hillesley, Little Badminton, and Saddlewood-with-Tresham and Killcott. Acres, 9, 770. Real property, &#163;14, 234. Pop., 2, 173. Houses, 499. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to Sir George S. Jenkinson, Bait. A fine tower, erected in 1846, to General Lord R. E. H. Somerset, stands on the brow of a hill, commanding a fine view There are traces of a Roman road. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Tresham, in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;350. * Patron, Sir George S. Jenkinson, Bart. The church is of various dates, chiefly later English; consists of nave, S aisle, and chancel, with a tower; and contains monuments of the Jenkinsons. The vicarage of Hillesley is a separate benefice. There are chapels of ease at Tresham and Little Badminton, chapels for Independents, Baptists, and Primitive Methodists, two national schools, and charities &#163;44.&#151;The sub-district contains also six other parishes. Acres, 20, 668. Pop., 4, 156. Houses, 920. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Hawkesbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647293</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10378497</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HAWKESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10378503</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAWKESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553180</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAWKESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574729</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAWKESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574730</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAWKESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10593566</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAWKESBURY NORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10593578</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAWKESBURY SOUTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10884</id>
   <name>HORTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11297</id>
   <name>LITTLE SODBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
