<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10990</id>
<name>MARSHFIELD</name>
<container>GLOUCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.4576574916335</lat>
<lon>-2.31869848440123</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARSHFIELD, a small town, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Chipping-Sodbury district, Gloucester. The town stands under the Cotswolds, 1&#188; mile E of the boundary with Wilts, 2 N of the boundary with Somerset, 4&#190; N by W of Box r. station, and 7 NNE of Bath; consists chiefly of one street, nearly a mile in length; is governed by a bailiff, with liberties 16 miles in circuit; and has a post office &#8225; under Chippenham, a police station, a church, three dissenting chapels, an endowed school with &#163;61 a year, alms houses with &#163;97, and other charities &#163;280. The church is of the 15th century; comprises nave, three aisles, and chancel, with porch and tower; and contains several tablets and monuments. A weekly market is held on Tuesday; fairs are held on 24 May and 24 Oct.; and malting and brewing are carried on.&#151;The parish contains also thevillages of Becks, Rocks, and Weston-Town, and the hamlets of Oakford and Ayford. Acres, 5,845. Real property, &#163;11,249. Pop. in 1 851,1,648; in 1861,1,742. Houses, 375. The manor belongs to the Rev. Dr. Horlock. Ashwick House belonged to the Webbs, passed to the Horlocks, and is now the seat of John Orred, Esq. Rocks House, or the Rocks, a fine mansion, on an eminence with extensive view 3 miles SE of the town, was the seat of the late D.Wrangham, Esq. Some IDruidical stones are near Becks. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;409. * Patron, New College, Oxford.&#151;The sub-district contains also five other parishes. Acres, 16,177. Pop., 4,103. Houses, 867. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/GLS/Marshfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642981</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10134470</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>MARSHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10383316</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARSHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10383444</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553209</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MARSHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10331</id>
   <name>COLD ASHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
