<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4765</id>
<name>HIGHCLERE</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.3367186378345</lat>
<lon>-1.35707031846345</lon>
<gazetteerText>HIGHCLERE, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Kingsclere district, Hants. The village stands 7 miles W of Kingsclere and 4&#189; S by W of Newbury r. station; is a beautiful place; and has a post office under Newbury. The parish comprises 3, 391 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 045. Pop., 446. Houses, 94. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged to the bishops of Winchester; was given, by Edward VI., to the Fitzwilliams; passed to the Sawyers and the Herberts; and belongs now to the Earl of Carnarvon. A palace of the bishops of Winchester stood here, and was succeeded by a mansion of the Herberts. That mansion, now Highclere castle, the seat of the Earl of Carnarvon, is a stately pile, partly ancient, partly altered, partly modern; has pinnacles, perforated work, flanking towers, and a magnificent W front tower; contains some valuable pictures; and occupies a spot 587 feet in elevation above sea level, amid a wooded and very picturesque park, upwards of 13 miles in circuit. Siddon hill, covered with wood, 940 feet high, and commanding splendid and very extensive views, is within the park; and Beacon hill, 900 feet high, crowned by ancient fortifications, and also commanding very grand views, is close without the gates. Many tumuli are on the neighbouring downs; and a circular camp of about 8 acres, is on Ladle hill, 1 &#189; mile E of Beacon hill. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;400. * Patron, the Earl of Carnarvon. The old church was built, in the time of Charles II., by Sir Robert Sawyer; was rebuilt in 1828, and repaired in 1859; and contains several interesting monuments. The new church was founded, close to the park, in 1869. There are a national school, and charities &#163;11. Millar, the antiquary, was a native.&#151;The sub-district contains seven parishes. Acres, 19, 500. Pop., 3, 257. Houses, 702. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Highclere</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646972</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/Highclere/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56809</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10162087</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HIGHCLERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10169379</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HIGHCLERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10494229</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HIGHCLERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543332</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HIGHCLERE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
