<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4776</id>
<name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.1128060572848</lat>
<lon>-1.47471806666589</lon>
<gazetteerText>STOCKBRIDGE, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Hants. The town stands on the river Test and on the Andover railway, 7 miles S of Andover; was the place where the Empress Maud was overtaken by Stephen&apos;s soldiers, after her escape from Winchester castle; sent two members to parliament from the time of Elizabeth, till disfranchised by the reform act of 1832; consists of one long street; and has a post-office&#8225; under Winchester, a hotel, a r. station with telegraph, a town hall, a police station, a church rebuilt in 1867, an Independent chapel, a parochial school, a workhouse, two training establishments for race-horses, races near Danebury hill in June, a weekly market on Thursday, and a lamb fair on 10 July.&#151;The parish comprises 1,115 acres. Real property, &#163;2,611. Pop. in 1851, 1,066; in 1861, 935. Houses, 198. The manor belongs to G. G. Maitland, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;198. Patron, Lady Barker Mill.&#151;The sub-district contains 9 parishes. Acres, 20,649. Pop., 3,577. Houses, 758.&#151;The district includes also Broughton sub-district, and comprises 45,343 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;5,316. Pop. in 1851, 7,480; in 1861, 7,286. Houses, 1,538. Marriages in 1863, 46; births, 246,-of which 18 were illegitimate; deaths, 134,-of which 36 were at ages under 5 years, and 4 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 471; births, 2,089; deaths, 1,430. The places of worship, in 1851, were 14 of the Church of England, with 2,028 sittings; 1 of Independents, with 258 s.; 3 of Baptists, with 465 s.; 1 of Quakers, with 12 s.; 3 of Wesleyans, with 414 s.; 5 of Primitive Methodists, with 164 s.; 3 of the Wesleyan Association, with 394 s.; and 1 undefined, with 100 The schools were 13 public day-schools, with 854 scholars; 5 private day-schools, with 92 s.; and 16 Sunday schools, with 798 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stockbridge,_Hampshire</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Stockbridge</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/Stockbridge/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636895</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56861</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001640</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10005231</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10100290</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10137834</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10162221</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10198458</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10497140</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543551</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580560</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12759290</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>STOCKBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2325</id>
   <name>LECKFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2995</id>
   <name>LONGSTOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17185</id>
   <name>TEST VALLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
