<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2328</id>
<name>NEWTOWN</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.3657555422101</lat>
<lon>-1.31790185641489</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWTOWN-NEAR-NEWBURY, a village and a parish in the district of Newbury and county of Hants. The village stands on the river Enbourne at the boundary with Berks, 2 miles S by E of Newbury r. station; and has a post-office under Newbury. The parish comprises 475 acres. Real property, &#163;741. Pop., 276. Houses, 62. The manor belongs to the Earl of Carnarvon. Newtown House is the chief residence. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the rectory of Burghclere, in the diocese of Winchester. The church was rebuilt in 1865; is in the early English style, of flint and Bathstone; and has an octagonal tower, painted glass windows, polished oak roof, and tesselated pavement. There are a Baptist chapel, and an endowed school with &#163;10 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/Newtown/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641524</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050560</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>NEWTOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10134547</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>NEWTOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10196607</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWTOWN ST LUKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10495180</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NEWTOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10514629</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NEWTOWN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>20388</id>
<name>NEWTOWN</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>50.7129022494833</lat>
<lon>-1.39797187016386</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWTOWN, a decayed town and a chapelry in Calbourne parish, Isle of Wight. The town stands on acreek of its own name, 1 mile S by W of the Solent, and 4&#188; E of Yarmouth: was originally called Francheville; belonged anciently to the Bishops of Winchester; received from Aymer, half-brother of Henry III., a charter which was confirmed by several kings; passed to the Crown in the time of Edward I.; was destroyed by the Danes in 1001, and by the French in 1377; was rebuilt, after the latter date, under the name of Newtown; never re-acquired its previous importance, in consequence ofits trade having been attracted mainly to Newport; retained sufficient importance in 1585 to be then invested with the privilege of sending two members to parliament; continued to send them till the passing of the reform actin 1832, when it was disfranchised; fell gradually and continuously, not withstanding its borough character, into a state of decadence; is now so reduced as to comprise only a way-side inn, a small church, a town hall of 1699, a farm-house, and about a score of cottages; and presents memorials of its former greatness in the names of houseless lanes at and near it, as High-street, Gold-street, Kay-street, Drapers-alley. The church was rebuilt in 1837; incorporates a fragment of a previous old church; and is a high-shouldered building, in the early English style. Several large salterns are on the shores of the creek, below the church. A good harbour is in the creek&apos;s mouth, and admits vessels of 500 tons. Pop. of the town in 1861, 99. Houses, 22. The chapelry has no defined limits; and is annexed to therectory of Calbourne, in the diocese of Winchester. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newtown,_Isle_of_Wight</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641525</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10072268</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWTOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10200337</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>NEWTOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12759009</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>NEWTOWN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23153</id>
<name>NEWTOWN</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>50.9135762986964</lat>
<lon>-1.13077578813221</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWTOWN, a hamlet in Soberton parish, and a chapelry partly also in Hambledon parish, Hants. The hamlet lies 3&#188; miles E of Bishops-Waltham r. station, and 11&#189; N of Portsmouth. The chapelry was constituted in 1851. Post-town, Soberton, under Southampton. Pop. in 1861, 635. Houses, 141. Pop. of the Soberton section, 554. Houses, 123. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;168.* Patrons, Three Trustees. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10094975</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWTOWN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24034</id>
<name>NEW TOWN</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>50.909798530194</lat>
<lon>-1.385477915916</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEW TOWN, a chapelry in Southampton, St. Mary and South Stoneham parishes, Hants; on Southampton-water at the Southwestern railway, in the E N E suburbs of Southampton. It was constituted in 1853. Post-town, Southampton. Pop. in 1861, 3, 348. Houses, 618. The South Stoneham portion is part of Portswoodtything. Pop., 945. Houses, 188. The living is a p.curacy in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;300. Patron, the Bishop of Winchester. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Town,_Southampton</link>
</links>
</place>
</results>
