<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3913</id>
<name>BISHOPSTOKE</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>50.9680007962108</lat>
<lon>-1.30867918667269</lon>
<gazetteerText>BISHOPSTOKE, a village and a parish in Winchester district, Hants. The village stands on the river Itchen, about a mile E of a station of its own name on the Southwestern railway, whence the branches go off toward Gosport and Salisbury, and 6&#189; miles NNE of Southampton. It is large and well built; includes a spacious cheese-market, a square enclosure with sheds and stores, constructed in 1852; and has a post office&#8225; under Winchester. A hotel, with posting establishment, adjoins the railway station. The parish comprises 3,360 acres. Real property, &#163;6,342. Pop., 1,390. Houses, 281. The property is divided among a few. The manor was held, in the time of Edward VI., by Bishop Bale. The villa and fine gardens of the Garnier family noticed by Loudon are here. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;437.* Patron, the Bishop of Winchester. The church was built in 1825, and has a square tower. There is a Wesleyan chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/BishopStoke/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655557</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bishopstoke</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41979</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10123045</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BISHOPSTOKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10493020</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BISHOPSTOKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10589253</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BISHOPSTOKE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2670</id>
   <name>STOKE PARK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5813</id>
   <name>FAIR OAK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
