<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5925</id>
<name>OWSLEBURY</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.001267373067</lat>
<lon>-1.26578496806209</lon>
<gazetteerText>OWSLEBURY, a village and a parish in Winchester district, Hants. The village stands 2&#189; miles E of the Southwestern railway, and 4&#189; S S E of Winchester; and has a post-office under Winchester. The parish contains also the hamlets of Baybridge, Hurst-Common, Marwell, and Rosehill. Acres, 5, 331. Real property, &#163;5, 377. Pop., 843. Houses, 193. The property is much sub-divided. The manor belongs to the Mildmays of Dog-mersfield. Rosehill belongs to the Earl of Nor thesk. Marwell Hall is the seat of W. Long, Esq. A residence of the bishops of Winchester was anciently at Marwell Manor Farm; but is now represented by only plain doorways of the 14th and 15th centuries, and by a moat. Owslebury down is a meet for the Hambledon hounds. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;169.* Patron, the Vicar of Twyford. The church is early decorated English, and cruciform; was recently restored and enlarged; has a central tower; and was the last church in Hants in which mass was celebrated. The p. curacy of Colden-Common is a separate benefice. There are a national school with &#163;14 a year from endowment, and charities &#163;16. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/Owslebury/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640742</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41990</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10142854</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OWSLEBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10211554</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>OWSLEBURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3156</id>
   <name>UPHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5892</id>
   <name>MORESTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
