<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2804</id>
<name>WHITCHURCH</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.2439357949967</lat>
<lon>-1.32807276810267</lon>
<gazetteerText>WHITCHURCH, a small town, a parish, and a district, in Hants. The town stands &#189; mile S of the South-western railway, and 12 N of Winchester; is a borough by prescription, governed by a mayor and a bailiff; sent two members to parliament, till disfranchised by the reform act of 1832; is a polling place; and has a post-office&#8225; under Mitcheldever Station, a r. station with telegraph, a banking office, a good inn, a town hall, a restored early English church, four dissenting chapels, a mechanics&apos; institute, national schools, a workhouse, charities &#163;94, a silk factory, and fairs on the third Thursday of June and 19 and 20 Oct.&#151;The parish includes Charlcott, Freefolk-Priors, and Cold Henley tythings; and comprises 6,142 acres. Real property, &#163;6,869; of which &#163;25 are in gasworks. Pop., 1,962. Houses, 429. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;205.* Patron, the Bishop of W.&#151;The district contains 8 parishes. Acres, 29,513. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;4,563. Pop. in 1851, 5,619; in 1861, 5,522. Houses, 1,209. Marriages in 1863, 29; births, 170,-of which 12 were illegitimate; deaths, 113,-of which 39 were at ages under 5 years, and 4 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 370: births, 1,836; deaths, 1,233. The places of worship, in 1851, were 7 of the Church of England, with 2,349 sittings; 3 of Independents, with 675 s.; 2 of Baptists, with 620 s.; 6 of Wesleyans, with 470 s.; 3 of Primitive Methodists, with 390 s.; and 1 of Latter Day Saints, with 20 s. The schools were 6 public day-schools, with 565 scholars; 6 private day-schools, with 128 s.; and 14 Sunday schools, with 1,002 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/Whitchurch/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitchurch,_Hampshire</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Whitchurch</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634130</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56813</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10055507</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10061180</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10075439</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10077679</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10079202</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143093</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143391</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH WITH TUFTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10189457</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH WITH TUFTON AND LITCHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10497930</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543423</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10595551</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12759484</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2336</id>
   <name>TUFTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3524</id>
   <name>HUNTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5156</id>
   <name>WONSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5638</id>
   <name>FREEFOLK MANOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
