<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1080</id>
<name>FARNBOROUGH</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.2858040162598</lat>
<lon>-0.759375915332556</lon>
<gazetteerText>FARNBOROUGH, a parish on the NE border of Hants, and a sub-district and a district in Hants and Surrey. The parish lies on the Southwestern railway and on the Basingstoke canal, 6 miles NNE of Farnham; has a station with telegraph on the main line of the railway, and also a station on the Reading branch; and has a head post office, &#8225; called Farnborough Station, another post office, called Farnborough, under Farnborough Station, &#190; of a mile distant, and a third post office, &#8225; called Farnborough Road, under Farnborough Station, 2 miles distant. Acres, 2, 208. Real property, &#163;3, 040. Pop., exclusive of military, in 1851, 477; in 1861, 1, 600. Houses, 144. The property is not much divided. A society was formed in 1862, for the purchase of free-hold land on advantageous sites, to assist builders and others with advances in covering it with buildings; and arrangements were made for purchasing 230 acres of land, and a hotel, between the Farnborough station and the Aldershot camps. The north camp is within this parish; and, at the census of 1861, had 3, 929 military; so that the entire pop. then was 5, 529. The Farnborough station, or that on the main Southwestern line, is one of the four &quot;gates&quot; of the camps; and has the advantage of being accessible from London by uninterrupted run. There are some tumuli. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;250.* Patron, W. Scott, Esq. The church is old; and there are some small charities. See Aldershot.&#151;The sub-district contains also the parishes of Yateley and Long Sutton in Hants, and the parishes of Puttenham, Seal-with-Tongham, and part of Ash in Surrey. Acres, 24, 142. Pop., 11, 190. Houses, 1, 260.&#151;The district comprehends also the sub-district of Headley, containing the parishes of Headley, Kingsley, and Bramshott, all in Hants. Acres, 39, 571. Poor-rates in 1862, &#163;4, 651. Pop. in 1851, 7, 839; in 1861, 14, 318. Houses, 1, 925. Marriages in 1860, 81; births, 325, -of which 15 were illegitimate; deaths, 200, -of which 63 were at ages under 5 years, and 3 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 629; births, 2, 519; deaths, 1, 580. The places of worship in 1851 were 11 of the Church of England, with 3, 088 sittings; 1 of Independents, with 110 s.; 2 of Baptists, with 145 s.; 1 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 90 s.; and 4 of Bible Christians, with 344 s. The schools were 13 public day schools, with 779 scholars; 10 private day schools, with 207 s.; 11 Sunday schools, with 707 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 20 s. The district is composed of Farnborough, Ash, and Headley incorporations, under Gilbert&apos;s act; and it has workhouses in Farnborough, Ash, and Headley. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/Farnborough/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Farnborough</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649672</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Farnborough,_Hampshire</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56736</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10014890</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FARNBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10139892</id>
   <status>Inc</status>
   <name>FARNBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143135</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FARNBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221018</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>FARNBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10444226</id>
   <status>RegD</status>
   <name>FARNBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10493924</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FARNBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543691</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FARNBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5647</id>
   <name>COVE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17243</id>
   <name>RUSHMOOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
