<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5172</id>
<name>SOUTH STONEHAM</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>50.9367242880079</lat>
<lon>-1.37515973146692</lon>
<gazetteerText>STONEHAM (South), a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Hants. The parish lies on the river Itchin and the Southwestern railway, around Portswood r. station; contains an ancient village of its own name, and the post-offices of Portswood and Bittern, under Southampton; is partly within Southampton borough; comprises five tythings; and is cut ecclesiastically into the sections of South Stoneham, Westend St. James, Portswood-Christchurch, Portswood-St. Dennis, and Bittern. Acres, 8,877. Real property, &#163;33,225. Pop. in 1851, 4,961; in 1861, 7,761. Houses, 1,528. The property is much subdivided. The head living is a vicarage in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;500.* Patron, the Rector of Southampton-St. Mary. The church is good. The other livings are separately noticed.&#151;The sub-district contains also Botley parish, and comprises 10,764 acres. Pop., 8,621. Houses, 1,709.&#151;The district comprehends also Millbrook and St. Mary-Extra sub-districts, and comprises 30,715 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;9,173. Pop. in 1851, 15,974; in 1861, 25,542. Houses, 4,989. Marriages in 1863, 180; births, 976,-of which 30 were illegitimate; deaths, 468,-of which 148 were at ages under 5 years, and 10 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,187; births, 6,353; deaths, 3,529. The places of worship, in 1851, were 14 of the Church of England, with 5,773 sittings; 6 of Independents, with 693 s.; 2 of Baptists, with 170 s.; 3 of Wesleyans, with 644 s.; 2 of Bible Christians, with 12-s.; and 1 of Latter Day Saints, with 18 s. The schools were 17 public day-schools, with 1,635 scholars; 35 private day schools, with 587 s.; 24 Sunday schools, with 1,882 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 15 s. The workhouse is in Shamblehurst tything. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/SouthStoneham/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/SouthStoneham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637315</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42035</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10026118</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>SOUTH STONEHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10033901</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH STONEHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10096030</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>SOUTH STONEHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10167589</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>SOUTH STONEHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10180892</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SOUTH STONEHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10497188</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOUTH STONEHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543680</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOUTH STONEHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5701</id>
   <name>WEST END</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
