<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4777</id>
<name>STRATFIELD SAYE</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.346424820018</lat>
<lon>-1.02244817958796</lon>
<gazetteerText>STRATFIELDSAYE, a parish in Basingstoke district; containing S. village and S. House in Hants, Beech-Hill tything in Berks; and lying on the Roman road to Silchester, 2&#189; miles SE of Mortimer r. station, and 7 NE by N of Basingstoke. It has a post-office under Winchfield. Acres, 3,532. Real property, &#163;5,279. Pop., 827. Houses, 162. The manor, with S. House, belonged, soon after the Norman conquest, to the Says; passed in the time of Richard II. to the D&apos;Abridge-courts, and in that of Charles I. to the Pitts; and was purchased, in 1815, for the Duke of Wellington. The present house dates chiefly from the time of Queen Anne, and has a comparatively plain appearance. A monument to the first Duke of Wellington, 82 feet high, terminating in a statue of the Duke 8&#190; feet high, was erected in 1866, on a spot adjacent to the road from Basingstoke to Reading. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester-Value, &#163;669.* Patron, the Duke of Wellington. The church was built in 1756, and is of the most inelegant type. The p. curacy of Beech-Hill is a separate benefice. There are an endowed school with &#163;22 a year, and charities &#163;13. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stratfield_Saye</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/Stratfieldsaye/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636715</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56746</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10077412</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STRATFIELD SAYE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143585</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STRATFIELD SAYE WITH HARTLEY WESPALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10162233</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>STRATFIELD SAYE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10497206</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STRATFIELD SAYE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
