<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3529</id>
<name>HARTLEY WINTNEY</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.3053112337329</lat>
<lon>-0.893795922189645</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARTLEY-WINTNEY, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a district in Hants. The village stands 2&#189; miles NW of Winchfield r. station, and 3&#188; NE by N of Odiham. The parish contains also the hamlet of HartfordBridge, which has a post office under Winchfield. Acres, 2, 405. Real property, &#163;5, 554. Pop. in 1851, 1, 582; in 1861, 1, 746. Houses, 346. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;108. * Patron, Lady St. John Mildmay. The old church is ancient, of various dates; and the new one, in the decorated style, was founded in 1869. There are a Baptist chapel, a workhouse, and charities &#163;11. A Cistertian nunnery was at HartleyBridge.&#151;The sub-district contains also the parishes of Winchfield, Elvetham, Eversley, Heckfield, and Rotherwick. Acres, 19, 993. Pop., 4, 965. Houses, 1, 035. -The district comprehends also the sub-district of Odiham, containing the parishes of Odiham, Dogmersfield, Crondall, South Warnborongh, and Greywell. Acres of the district, 42, 051. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;6, 883. Pop. in 1851, 11, 223; in 1861, 11, 480. Houses, 2, 386. Marriages in 1862, 48; births, 385, -of which 27 were illegitimate; deaths, 207, -of which 54 were at ages under 5 years, and 9 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 695. births, 3, 710; deaths, 2, 187. The places of worship, in 1851, were 14 of the Church of England, with 3, 074 sittings; 5 of Independents, with 824 s.; 6 of Baptists, with 836 s.; and 1 of Bible Christians, with 130 s. The schools were 23 public day schools, with 1, 493 scholars; 15 private day schools, with 318 s; and 15 Sunday schools, with 880 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartley_Wintney</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/HartleyWintney/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/HartleyWintney</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647395</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56753</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10002023</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>HARTLEY WINTNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10004020</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>HARTLEY WINTNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10057942</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARTLEY WINTNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10095554</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARTLEY WINTNEY AND ELVETHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10105961</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HARTLEY WINTNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10155150</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>HARTLEY WINTNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10512920</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HARTLEY WINTNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543708</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HARTLEY WINTNEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2241</id>
   <name>WINCHFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2629</id>
   <name>MATTINGLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2664</id>
   <name>ROTHERWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3033</id>
   <name>ELVETHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17333</id>
   <name>HART</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
