<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4758</id>
<name>ELING</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>50.910676630455</lat>
<lon>-1.51197008014404</lon>
<gazetteerText>ELING, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in New Forest district, Hants. The village stands on the north-west horn of Southampton-water, near the mouth of the river Anton, and near Totton r. station, 4 miles W of Southampton; was known at Domesday as Edlinges; is said to have then had a church, two mills, a fishery, and a saltern; has now a fair on 5 July; has also granaries, storehouses, and several docks; and carries on a considerable trade in corn, timber, and coal. The parish includes South Eling, North Eling, Bartley-Regis, Bauld-oxfee, Bistern and Bartley, Colebury, Durley, Langley, Lopperwood, Marchwood, Rumbridge, Tatchbury, Testwood, Wade, Ower, and Wigley; and has post offices of Bartley, Marchwood, and Totton under Southampton, and Ower under Romsey. Acres, 18, 459; of which 730 are water. Real property, of South Eling, &#163;1, 899; of North Eling, &#163;3, 984; of Bartley-Regis, &#163;1, 725; of Bauldoxfee, &#163;2, 610; of Bistern and Bartley, &#163;719; of Colebury, &#163;1, 847; of Durley, &#163;1, 217; of Langley, &#163;1, 045; of Lopperwood, &#163;545; of Marchwood, &#163;497; of Rumbridge, &#163;1, 358; of Tatchbury, &#163;550; of Testwood, &#163;2, 364; of Wade and Ower, &#163;2, 413; of Wigley, &#163;507. Pop. of the parish, 5, 947. Houses, 1, 179. The limits include 740 acres of New Forest. The property is much sub-divided. The manor, in the time of Edward the Confessor, was under obligation to give half-a-day&apos;s entertainment to the king whenever he should pass it; and it belongs now to the Rev. Sir J. B. Mill, Bart. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;630. Patrons, the Trustees of the Rev. W. J. G. Phillips. The church is of various dates, from the 11th century; and contains many interesting monuments. The vicarages of North Eling., Marchwood, and Netley, are separate benefices. Value of North Eling, &#163;260. Patrons, the Trustees of the Rev. W. J. G. Phillips. A new church, in the early decorated style, and a new school, - were founded in 1869. The charities include an alms-house for four persons, and a share in Nowes&apos; school. The parish contains the New Forest workhouse. -The sub-district includes 7, 920 acres of the New Forest. Pop., 5, 952. Houses, 1, 180. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/Eling/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650115</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56879</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10143834</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ELING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10162002</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ELING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10169240</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTH ELING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10493717</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ELING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543356</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ELING</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1725</id>
   <name>LYNDHURST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2327</id>
   <name>MINSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2656</id>
   <name>BRAMSHAW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2783</id>
   <name>COLBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3116</id>
   <name>BROCKENHURST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3257</id>
   <name>COPYTHORNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5184</id>
   <name>DENNY LODGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5702</id>
   <name>ASHLEY WALK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6125</id>
   <name>NETLEY MARSH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
