<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5165</id>
<name>CALBOURNE</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>50.6973409568392</lat>
<lon>-1.39023526579791</lon>
<gazetteerText>CALBOURNE, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict in the Isle of Wight. The village stands 5 miles WSW of Newport; and has a post office under Newport. The parish includes also Newtown borough; and extends from Brixton Down to the Solent. Acres, 6,397; of which 265 are water. Real property, &#163;4,471. Pop., 728. Houses, 145. The property is divided among a few. Westover manor belonged to the Esturs; passed to the Lisles and the Holmeses; and belongs now to the eldest son of Lord Heytesbury, in right of his wife, the daughter of the late Sir Leonard W. Holmes. The house on it is modern; and the grounds are tasteful. Calbourne Bottom, 1&#188; mile SSW of the village, is a depression between Brixton and Moltestone downs. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Newtown, in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;675.* Patron, the Bishop of Winchester. The church is early English, much modernized; and has a brass of 1480.-The subdistrict contains eight parishes. Acres, 25,050. Pop., 5,417. Houses, 1,071. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calbourne</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654036</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42080</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10077515</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CALBOURNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10180752</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CALBOURNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10499616</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WESTOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10543654</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CALBOURNE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
