<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3163</id>
<name>SILCHESTER</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.3488500992722</lat>
<lon>-1.0852105579548</lon>
<gazetteerText>SILCHESTER, a village and a parish in Basingstoke district, Hants. The village stands adjacent to the ancient Caer-Segont, 2&#188; miles SW of Mortimer r. station, and 7 N of Basingstoke; has a post-office under Basingstoke; and gives the title of Baron to the Earl of Longford. Caer-Segont was the chief town of the ancient British Segontiaci; became the Roman city, Calleva, long but erroneously regarded as the Roman Vindonis or Vindonum; was called by the Saxons Selceastre or Silchester, signifying &quot;the castle in the wood;&apos;&apos; seems to have been, in the Saxon and earlier times, surrounded by a region of thick forest; stood on the Roman road from London to Bath, at the junction of Roman roads from Salisbury and Winchester; was the place of the usurper Constantine&apos;s assumption of the purple in 407; was taken and destroyed by the Saxon Ella in 493; retains vestiges of its Roman streets, and portions of its Roman walls enclosing an area of about 120 acres; has remains of a Roman amphitheatre, 150 feet by 120; was found, by a discovery in 1833, to retain some large Roman baths; and has, at varions times, yielded large numbers of smaller Roman relics, including inscriptions, weapons, seals, rings, personal ornaments, and a profusion of coins. The parish comprises 1,881 acres. Real property, &#163;1,799. Pop., 480. Houses, 101. The manor belongs to the Duke of Wellington. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, the Duke of Wellington. The church is ancient. There are a national school, and charities &#163;15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/Silchester/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silchester</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637846</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56744</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10092590</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SILCHESTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10497012</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SILCHESTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10579855</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SILCHESTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10589605</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SILCHESTER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
