<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6008</id>
<name>HURSTBOURNE PRIORS</name>
<container>HAMPSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.2226147002649</lat>
<lon>-1.36629322414214</lon>
<gazetteerText>HURSTBOURNE-PRIORS, a village and a parish in Whitchurch district, Hants. The village stands near the Southwestern railway, 2 miles WSW of Whitchurch; and has a post office under Mitcheldever-Station. The parish comprises 3, 132 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 553. Pop., 437. Houses, 87. The manor belonged to the Winchester Benedictines; passed to the family of Wallop; and belongs now to their descendant, the Earl of Portsmouth. Hurstbourne Park is the Earl&apos;s seat. The mansion was designed by Wyatt; looks ill as a building, but occupies a fine site, in a large thickly wooded park; and contains some good pictures, and the manuscripts of Sir Isaac Newton, brought into the family by Sir Isaac&apos;s niece, Lady Lymington, and used by Sir David Brewster in his life of Newton. There is a paper mill. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of St. Mary-Bourne, in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;202. * Patron, the Bishop of Winchester. The church is Norman and early English; has a low tower; and was recently restored. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HAM/HurstbournePriors/index.shtml</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646359</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56810</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10131170</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HURSTBOURNE PRIORS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10184381</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HURSTBOURNE PRIORS WITH TUFTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10214208</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HURSTBOURNE PRIORS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10512943</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HURSTBOURNE PRIORS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10589484</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HURSTBOURNE PRIORS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
