<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4357</id>
<name>BENINGTON</name>
<container>HERTFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8895109743432</lat>
<lon>-0.112159945206088</lon>
<gazetteerText>BENNINGTON, a village and a parish in the district and county of Hertford. The village stands near the river Beane, and near a branch Roman way, 5 miles ESE of Stevenage, and 6 from Stevenage r. station. It has a post office under Stevenage; and was formerly a market-town; and has still a fair on 10 July. The parish comprises 2,908 acres. Real property, &#163;4,784. Pop., 637. Houses, 133. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged to the Benstedes, the C&#230;sars, and the Earl of Essex; and belongs now to the Proctors. An ancient palace of the kings of Mercia stood here; and either that, or a castle which succeeded it, is now indicated by an intrenched eminence. Bennington Place, to the east, is a fine seat. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;635.* Patron, the Rev. J. E. Pryor. The church contains some ancient monuments, and is good. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655898</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benington</link>
<link>http://www.pjoiner.demon.co.uk/genuki/HRT/Benington/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43583</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10088148</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BENINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10147827</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BENINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10569588</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BENNINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10569590</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BENNINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10569606</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BENNINGTON AND BUNTINGFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
