<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4400</id>
<name>WHEATHAMPSTEAD</name>
<container>HERTFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8187701663707</lat>
<lon>-0.30574946950253</lon>
<gazetteerText>WHEATHAMPSTEAD, a village and a parish in St. Albans district, Herts. The village stands on the river Lee and on the Hertford and Dunstable railway, 5 miles NNW of St. Albans; was known, at Domesday, as Watamestede; was the meeting-place of the barons, in 1312, against Edward II.; and has a post-office under St. Albans, and a r. station. The parish includes two hamlets, and comprises 5,033 acres. Real property, &#163;9,848. Pop., 1,960. Houses, 395. The manor was given, by Edward the Confessor, to Westminster Abbey. Mackrey-End, Delaport, and Lamer are chief residences. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;730.* Patron, the Bishop of Peterborough. The church is cruciform, with central tower and spire, and was restored in 1866. There are Independent and Wesleyan chapels, handsome national schools of 1862, and charities &#163;195. Abbot Bostock, who died in 1440, was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wheathampstead</link>
<link>http://www.pjoiner.demon.co.uk/genuki/HRT/Wheathampstead/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634172</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43281</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43283</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43282</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10085457</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHEATHAMPSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10149307</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WHEATHAMPSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582520</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WHEATHAMPSTEAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
