<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7152</id>
<name>BLUNTISHAM</name>
<container>HUNTINGDONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3516865310663</lat>
<lon>0.00794210407575253</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLUNTISHAM, a township and a parish in St. Ives district, Huntingdon. The township lies on the river Ouse, 3 miles SE of Somersham r. station, and 4&#189; NE of St. Ives; and has a post office under St. Ives. Real property, &#163;4,961. The parish includes also the hamlet of Earith. Acres, 3,423. Real property, &#163;9,747. Pop., 1,351. Houses, 314. The property is much subdivided. The manor was given, in 1015, to Ely Abbey. Bluntisham House is the seat of the Tebbuts. Part of the land is fen. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;1,010.* Patron, the Bishop of Peterborough. The church is early English; terminates, in the east, in a half hexagon; and has a screen, a piscina, and an octagonal font. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Wesleyan Methodists, Primitive Methodists, and Quakers. An endowed school has &#163;88 a year; other charities &#163;138. Dr. Knight, author of Lives of Erasmus and Dean Colet, was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655320</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/HUN/Bluntisham-cum-Earith/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluntisham</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42472</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10254012</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BLUNTISHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10254048</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLUNTISHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10254073</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BLUNTISHAM CUM EARITH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7168</id>
   <name>COLNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7353</id>
   <name>PIDLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
