<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>17319</id>
<name>THANET</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.3533851840119</lat>
<lon>1.34013815000055</lon>
<gazetteerText>THANET, an island and a district in the NE of Kent-The island projects to the North Foreland, at the month of the Thames; is bounded, on the N and the E, by the sea,-on the SE, by Pegwell bay,-on the S, by the river Stour,-on the W, by the rivulet Nethergong; was anciently separated from the land by the Wantsome channel, about a mile wide, along the course of the Stour and the Nethergong, and used as a short cut, in the ordinary passage between London and France; became nearly connected with the land by the silting up of that channel progressively till about the year 1500; appears to have extended much further seaward in the Saxon times than now; measures at present about 10 miles from E to W, and from 2&#189; to 7&#188; from N to S; was known to the ancient Britons as Ruim or Inis-Ruochim, to the Saxons as Tenet or Tanet-lond, to the old geographers as Thanatos; retains, or has furnished, many relics of Roman, Saxon, and Jutish inhabitation; lay, till about the beginning of last century, in nearly as wild a condition as the remotest parts of Cornwall: is now distinguished by rich cultivation and high progress; has generally a light fertile soil on a chalky bottom; includes some rich marshes on the sides of the streams; and gave, from 1628 till 1849, the title of Earl to the family of Tufton.&#151;The district is conterminate with the island and its foreshores; comprises 27,371 acres of land, and 3,712 of water or foreshore; contains ten parishes and a ville; and is divided into the sub-districts of Minster, Margate, and Ramsgate. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;13,250. Pop. in 1851, 31,798; in 1861, 31,862. Houses, 6,254. Marriages in 1863, 304; births, 970,-of which 60 were illegitimate; deaths, 818,-of which 248 were at ages under 5 years, and 35 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1 851-60, 2,208; births, 8,972; deaths, 6,711. The places of worship, in 1851, were 13 of the Church of England, with 12,333 sittings; 3 of Independents, with 1,675 s.; 8 of Baptists, with 2,660 s.; 2 of Quakers, with 145 s.; 13 of Wesleyans, with 3,075 s.; 3 of Primitive Methodists, with 280 s.; 1 of Lady Huntingdon&apos;s Connexion, with 650 s.; 3 undefined, with 1,000 s.; 2 of Roman Catholics, with 650 s.; and 1 of Jews, with 100 s. The schools were 24 public day-schools, with 3,879 scholars; 79 private day-schools, with 1,978 s.; 29 Sunday schools, with 3,430 s.; and 2 evening schools for adults, with 66 s. The workhouse is in Minster. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Thanet</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636056</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10003714</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>THANET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10102728</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>THANET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10108007</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>ISLE OF THANET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10112552</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>RINGSLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10167395</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>THANET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581151</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>THANET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739140</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>KENT ISLE OF THANET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739217</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>THANET EAST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739229</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>SOUTH THANET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12747317</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>THANET WEST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12753135</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>ISLE OF THANET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12755879</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>NORTH THANET</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
