<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>548</id>
<name>LYDD</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>50.9423605893842</lat>
<lon>0.924008700355037</lon>
<gazetteerText>LYDD, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Romney-Marsh district, Kent. The town stands near the coast, 3&#189; miles SW by S of New Romney, 4 NW of Dungeness, and 7&#189; SW of Appledore r. station; is a member of Romney cinque-port, and a borough by prescription; is governed by a bailiff, jurats, and freemen, -the bailiff and jurats elected annually; is a seat of petty sessions; had, till recently, a weekly market; and has a post office&#8225; under Folkestone, a neat market-house, a church, a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, breweries, and a fair on the last Monday of July. The church is later English, and large; has a lofty handsome tower, supposed to have been erected by Cardinal Wolsey, who held the benefice in right of the abbey of Tintern; contains an altar-tomb to Sir W. Meynell of the time of Edward III., and a number of brasses; and was given, by one of the De Clares, to Tintern abbey. The parish comprises 11,788 acres of land, and 1,715 of water. Real property, &#163;16,889. Pop. in 1851,1,605; in 1861, 1,667. Houses, 360. The land is of varions character; a great portion appears to be of more recent formation than the adjacent marshes; and parts, called the Rype and Midrips, run out in narrow tongues; yet reaches of the beach are suffering inroads by the sea, and are cut by it into pits or water-holes. A long tract, called the Holmstone, was once covered with sea-holly, locally termed holm, and of an unusual size. A heap of stones, at Stone-end on the shore to the E of the town, was long traditionally regarded as the tomb of Sts. Crispin and Crispianus, who were alleged to have been shipwrecked and buried here. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;1,450.* Patron, the Archbishop of Cauterbury. Charities, about &#163;130. See DUNGENESS.&#151;The sub-district contains also seven other parishes. Acres, 26,114. Pop., 2,826. Houses, 593. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lydd</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643327</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10028334</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>LYDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10106680</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>LYDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10225243</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LYDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10225346</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>LYDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10537101</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LYDD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10594339</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LYDD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>385</id>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2037</id>
   <name>BROOKLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2038</id>
   <name>BROOMHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2080</id>
   <name>IVYCHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3017</id>
   <name>HOPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3324</id>
   <name>DYMCHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6073</id>
   <name>BRENZETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6291</id>
   <name>NEWCHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6334</id>
   <name>OLD ROMNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6343</id>
   <name>ST MARY IN THE MARSH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>6267</id>
<name>LYDDEN</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1608238379211</lat>
<lon>1.2253116906421</lon>
<gazetteerText>LYDDEN, a village and a parish in Dover district, Kent. The village stands on Watling-street, adjacent to the London, Chatham, and Dover railway, in a valley between high chalk hills, 2 miles NW of Ewell r. station, and 5 NW of Dover. The parish comprises 1,422 acres; and its Post town is Dover. Real property, &#163;1,453. Pop., 198. Houses, 40. The property is diVided among a few. Considerable springs rise here; and streamlets, flowing from them, have a subterranean course and fall into the sea, under the name of Lydden spouts, from the cliffs at Hougham, about 4 miles distant. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;130.* Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church was rebuilt in 1833; and consists of nave and chancel, with a tower. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lydden</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643326</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10222333</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LYDDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10222345</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LYDDEN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6499</id>
   <name>WOOTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
