<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4950</id>
<name>BOUGHTON MALHERBE</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1997260796134</lat>
<lon>0.688065628101635</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOUGHTON-MALHERBE, a parish in Hollingbourne district, Kent; on the verge of the Weald, 5 miles NNW of Pluckley r. station, and 10 ESE of Maidstone. Post Town, Lenham, under Maidstone. Acres, 2,699. Real property, &#163;2,945. Pop., 408. Houses. 79. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged, in the time of Henry III., to the Malherbe family; passed to the Wottons, of whom was Sir Henry Wotton, whose life was written by Isaac Walton; passed again to Sir Horace Mann, the correspondent of Walpole; and belongs now to the heirs of Earl Cornwallis. The manor-house bears the name of Boughton Place; was built by Sir Edward Wotton in the time of Henry VIII., and visited by Queen Elizabeth; and is now a farmhouse, retaining some of the ancient rooms. The materials of it are said to have been Colbridge Castle, the baronial fortalice of the Peyferers, some traces of which still exist near the church. Chilstone Park is the seat of J. S. Douglas, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;176.* Patrons, the Heirs of Earl Cornwallis. The church is decorated English, in good condition. There are a Baptist chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;8. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boughton_Malherbe</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655115</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10080435</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOUGHTON MALHERBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10171696</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BOUGHTON MALHERBE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
