<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2071</id>
<name>GOUDHURST</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.0998044465176</lat>
<lon>0.457830590848686</lon>
<gazetteerText>GOUDHURST, a village and a parish in Cranbrook district, Kent. The village stands on a hill, near the river Tees, 4 miles WNW of Cranbrook, and 5 S by W of Marden r. station; was formerly a seat of the clothing trade, and a market-town; and has now a post office&#8225; under Staplehurst, a news-room, and fairs on 26 Ang., and 5 Nov. The parish comprises 9, 685 acres. Real property, &#163;13, 322. Pop., 2, 778. Houses, 535. The property is considerably divided. Goudhurst hill has an altitude of 491 feet; forms part of a range, about 3 miles long; and is skirted, on the W, by the river Tees. Bedgebury Park was long the residence of the Bedgeburys; passed to the Colepepers, the Stephensons, the Cartiers, and the Beresfords; and is now the seat of A. J. B. Hope, Esq. Combwell was once a priory, and afterwards the residence of the Campions. Finchcocks belonged to the Finchcock family in the time of Henry III.; and the present mansion was built by the Bathursts in 1725. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;432.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Rochester. The church stands on a lofty site; commands, from its tower, an extensive and noble view; is itself a fine old edifice; was about to be restored in June, 1865; and contains many monuments of the Colepepers and the Campions. The vicarage of Kilndown is a separate benefice. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a Primitive Methodist chapel, a national school, an endowment of &#163; 40 for a grammar school, and other charities with &#163;75. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goudhurst</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648263</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10040723</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GOUDHURST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10193552</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GOUDHURST</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
