<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6293</id>
<name>NEWINGTON</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1004324290986</lat>
<lon>1.10950503336698</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWINGTON-NEXT-HYTHE, a village and a parish in Elham district, Kent. The village stands near the Southeastern railway, 2&#189; miles N E of Hythe, and 3&#189; W by N of Folkestone r. station; is a scattered place, amid romantic environs; and has a post-office, of the name of Newington, under Hythe. The parish extendsto the coast; and comprises 3, 134 acres of land, and 60 of water. Real property, &#163;3, 150. Pop., 523. Houses, 94. Beachborough is the seat of T. Brockman, Esq. Asummer-house is on a hill adjoining Beachborough; isaccessible to strangers; and commands very fine and extensive views over land and sea. A vantage-ground on the Downs, about a mile from the village, likewise commands a magnificent view over the marshes to Hastings. There are remains of ancient entrenchments; and Romancoins and pottery have been found The living is a vicarage, annexed to the rectory of Cheriton, in the diocese of Canterbury. The church is ancient; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a lofty tower; and contains a font cased in carved oak, two brasses of 1501, and a brass of a man and three wives of 1522. There are aninfant school, and charities &#163;4. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7295897</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10223271</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NEWINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10223301</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWINGTON NEXT HYTHE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>6294</id>
<name>NEWINGTON</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.3484489608105</lat>
<lon>0.669519291186611</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWINGTON, a village and a parish in Wilton district, Kent. The village stands on Watling-street, and on the London, Chatham, and Dover railway; 3&#188; miles W N W of Sittingbourne; occupies the site of the Romanstation Durolevum; was known to the Saxons, and at Domesday, as Neweton; is now, in contra-distinction to other Newingtons, sometimes called Newington-juxta-Sittingbourne; was once a market-town; and has a railway station with telegraph, a post-office under Sittingbourne, and a floral and horticultural society. The parish contains also the hamlet of Breach, and comprises 2, 103 acres. Real property, &#163;6, 410. Pop. in 1851, 731; in 1861, 854. Houses, 172. The manor belonged, at Domesday, to Queen Editha; was given to a nunneryfounded, soon after Domesday, on a site 1&#188; mile W of the parish church; passed, in the time of Henry II., toa secular canonry of seven priests on the same spot; went, soon afterwards, to Sir Richard de Lucy; took then the name of Newington-Lucies; was exchanged in 1278, by Almericus de Lucy, with the monks of St. Augustine in Canterbury for other lands; went, at the Reformation, to the Crown; and passed in 1680, to Roger Jackson, in the end of Queen Anne&apos;s time, to the Pembertons, in 1771, to H. Mills, Esq., and in 1831, to Edward Leigh, Esq. The transference of it from the nunnery arose from the prioress having been found strangled in a bed; and that from the secular canonry arose from the murder of one of the canons by four of his brethren. The manor-house was, some years ago, taken down; and a new street, called Legh-street, was formed over its site to the railway station. Many entrenchments of Romanorigin, very numerous Roman coins and other Roman relics, and distinct vestiges of a Roman burying-place, have been found in and near the village; and many lines of ancient earthwork, and very numerous Roman urns, have been found at Keycol Hill, about 1 mile from the village, and supposed by some writers, though with little evidence, to have acquired its name by corruption of Caii Collis, signifying &quot; Caius Julius C&#230;sar&apos;s Hill.&quot; About 130 acres are disposed in hops; and a considerablearea is occupied with orchards. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;350.* Patron, Eton College. The church stands &#189; a mile from the centre of the village; is partly decorated English, partlymodern; consists of nave, aisles, and two chancels, with fine W embattled tower; and contains a remarkable octagonal font, an ancient tomb, three brasses, and other monuments. There are a national school, and charities &#163;13. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641629</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10223283</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NEWINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10223325</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWINGTON NEXT SITTINGBOURNE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2030</id>
   <name>BORDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4974</id>
   <name>LOWER HALSTOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4975</id>
   <name>HARTLIP</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6415</id>
   <name>STOCKBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
