<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6503</id>
<name>WYE</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1828600506592</lat>
<lon>0.940468670959504</lon>
<gazetteerText>WYE, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Kent. The village stands on the river Stour, adjacent to the Canterbury and Ramsgate railway, under W. Downs, 4 miles NNE of Ashford; was once a market-town; consists of two parallel streets, crossed by two others; and has a post-office&#8225; under Ashford, a r. station with telegraph, and fairs on 29 May and 11 Oct.&#151;The parish comprises 7,282 acres. Real property, &#163;10,216. Pop., 1,594. Houses, 322. The manor belonged to the Saxon kings; was given, by William the Conqueror, to Battle abbey; went, after the dissolution of monasteries, to the Hunsdons; and passed, in 1628, to the Finches. W. Downs command a fine view. A mineral spring is at Withersdane. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;70.* Patron, the Earl of Winchelsea. The church is large and handsome, and has a nave of the time of Henry VI., and a chancel and a tower of 1706. A college was founded in 1447; and is now partly a grammar-school, with &#163;16 a year from endowment, and partly a charity school for about 50 boys and 60 girls. There are general charities &#163;200. Archbishop Kempe and Mrs. Macaulay were natives.-- The sub-district contains 11 parishes, and is in East Ashford district. Acres, 27,336. Pop., 5,767. Houses, 1,141.-The hundred contains 4 parishes and a part, and is in Shepway lathe. Acres, 12,763. Pop. in 1851, 2,733. Houses, 489. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wye</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wye_with_Hinxhill</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633460</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10030444</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>WYE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10229479</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WYE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10229480</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WYE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10537083</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WYE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2075</id>
   <name>HINXHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3519</id>
   <name>CRUNDALE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5405</id>
   <name>GODMERSHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6026</id>
   <name>BROOK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
