<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2058</id>
<name>CHILHAM</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.244277824205</lat>
<lon>0.96020700365968</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHILHAM, a village and a parish in East Ashford district, Kent. The village stands near the river Stour and the Ramsgate and Hastings railway, 6&#189; miles SW by S of Canterbury; is the Cilleham of the Saxons; was once a market-town; and has a station on the railway, a post office under Canterbury, and a fair on 8 Nov. The parish comprises 4, 332 acres. Real property &#163;7, 502. Pop., 1, 319. Houses, 256. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged to the Saxon kings of Kent; was given by the Conqueror to Fulbert, who assumed the name of De Dover; passed to the Badlesmeres and others; went, in the time of Edward VI., to Sir Thomas Cheney; went again, at the beginning of the 17th century, to Sir Dudley Digges; passed to the Colebrooks, the Herons, and the Wildmans; and was bought, in 1862, byHardy, Esq. A Roman castrum was here, and is said to have been the residence of Lucius, the Brito-Roman king; a castle of the Saxon kings succeeded the castrum, was renovated after the Conquest, and underwent demolition by Sir Thomas Cheney; and a mansion, in lieu of this, was built by Sir W. Digges, is still standing, and forms a fine specimen of Jacobean architecture. The castle was surrounded by a deep fosse, enclosing about 8 acres; and the remains of it include a late Norman octagonal, three-storey keep. Many Roman relics, of various kinds, have been found here; and a great barrow or artificial mound, popularly called Julaber&apos;s Grave, the subject of much dispute among antiquaries, is immediately above the railway station. the living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Molash, in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;698.* Patron, Charles Hardy, Esq. The church is decorated English, with a later clerestory; was rebuilt, in the E part, in 1863; belonged anciently to Throwleigh priory, afterwards to Sion monastery; and contains monuments of the Diggeses, the Colebrooks, and the Wildmans. There are a national school, and charities &#163;37. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chilham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653167</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10040231</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CHILHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10080940</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHILHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
