<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6273</id>
<name>MARDEN</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1789648018255</lat>
<lon>0.495511625739533</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARDEN, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Kent. The village stands near an affluent of the river Medway, and on the Reigate, Tunbridge, and Ashford railway, 3 miles WNW of Staplehurst; is a picturesque place; was formerly a market town; and has a post office &#8225; under Staplehurst, a railway station with telegraph, and a fair on 11 Oct.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlet of Stile-Bridge. Acres, 7,607. Real property, &#163;11,652. Pop., 2,295. Houses, 452. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to R. Springett, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;828. * Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church is ancient but good; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and contains a very curious font of 1652. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, parochial schools, a Church of England school, and charities &#163;55. The parochial schools were built in 1859, at a cost of about &#163;1,600; and are a handsome structure, in the Tudor style. Amhurst, the author of the &quot;Craftsman, &apos;&apos;was a native.&#151;The sub-district contains also two other parishes, and part of another; and is in Maidstone district. Acres, 15,317. Pop. in 1861,4,905. Houses, 906.-The hundred excludes one of the parishes and the part-parish of the subdistrict, but includes another and larger parish; and is in the lathe of Scray. Acres, 23,029. Pop. in 1851, 6,550. Houses, 1,227. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marden,_Kent</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643060</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10099602</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>MARDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10222692</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10222709</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10561360</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MARDEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
