<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2872</id>
<name>HIGHAM</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.4302309918841</lat>
<lon>0.467611014160968</lon>
<gazetteerText>HIGHAM, a village and a parish in North Aylesford district, Kent. The village stands near the Thames and Medway canal and the North Kent railway, 1&#189; mile from the Thames, and 4 NNW of Rochester; was known, at Domesday, as Heckham; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Rochcster. The parish includes also Lillechurch, Oakley, Mockbeggar, and Gads Hill. Acres, 3, 155; of which 190 are water. Real property, &#163;7, 630. Pop. in 1851, 843; in 1861, 1, 064. Houses, 208. The increase in pop. arose from the extension of market gardening, and the erection of small houses for the workers. The property is much subdivided. A Benedictine nunnery was founded at Lillechurch, by King Stephen; had, for its first abbess, King Stephen&apos;s daughter, Mary; was soon removed to Higham village; was given, at the dissolution, to St. John&apos;s college, Cambridge; and is now represented by some fragments of masonry there, in a house called the Abbey. An ancient causeway, probably of Roman origin, leads from the village, across the marshes, to the Thames at a point where formerly there was a ferry to a road direct toward Colchester. An ancient barrow is about 1&#189; mile from the railway station. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of St. John, in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;598. Patron, St. John&apos;s College, Cambridge. The parish church is ancient, with slight Norman traces; was recently restored; and contains a font, a piscina, and a large ancient altar tomb. Roman bricks are in its masonry; and many Roman urns, pieces of pottery, and other relics were found in the near neighbourhood, in what is supposed to have been a potter&apos;s field. The church of St. John was built, in 1861, at a cost of &#163;3, 600; is in the early decorated English style; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with W porch and circular tower. There are national schools, and charities &#163;16. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Higham,_Kent</link>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/HIGH_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646988</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10040863</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HIGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10060795</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HIGHAM WITH MERSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10081294</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HIGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
