<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6029</id>
<name>HORTON KIRBY</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.3903499124979</lat>
<lon>0.256882024873501</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORTON-KIRBY, a village and a parish in Dartford district, Kent. The village stands on the river Darent, &#189; a mile SSE of Farningham r. station, and 4&#189; SSE of Dartford; and has a post office under Dartford. The parish contains also the hamlets of Pinden and DeanBottom, and part of South Darenth. Acres, 2, 813. Real property, &#163;6, 638. Pop. in 1851, 747; in 1861, 867. Houses, 1 56. The property is divided among a few. The manor was held, at Domesday, by Anschitill de Ros, under Bishop Odo: remained with the family of De Ros till the time of Lora, called the &quot;Lady of Horton;&quot; and went, by marriage with her, to the family of Kirkby, who previously owned adjacent lands. Horton Castle was founded, soon after the Conquest, by the De Ros; was rebuilt, in the time of Edward I., by Roger De Kirkby; seems to have been either rebuilt again or largely restored and altered, at a subsequent period; and is now represented by very considerable remains. Franks is a fine Tudor edifice; was built, in the time of Elizabeth, by Alderman Bathurst; is now the residence of R. Bradford, Esq.; and was recently restored at great expense. Extensive paper mills are at South Darenth. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;214.* Patron, the Rev. G. Rashleigh. The church is mainly early English, but has a modern tower; is cruciform, with the tower rising from the intersection; has arcades round the interior of the transepts; and contains some remains of Roman pavement. A refuge home for boys, at a cost of &#163;12, 000, was built in 1867. There are a national school, and charities &#163;30. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horton_Kirby_and_South_Darenth</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horton_Kirby</link>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/HORT_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646543</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10098373</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORTON KIRBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10215420</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HORTON KIRBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
