<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20089</id>
<name>LEE</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.4552829242692</lat>
<lon>0.0137964327800631</lon>
<gazetteerText>LEE, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Lewisham district, Kent. The village stands on the rivulet Lee, near Lewisham and Blackheath r. stations, 1&#189; mile SSE of Greenwich; is a pleasant, salubrious, and picturesque place; and has a metropolitan police station, and a post office, &#8225; under Lewisham, London SE. Both itself and its environs, within the parish, are a resort of merchants and wealthy families from the metropolis; and many handsome residences have been erected, since 1860, in Lee Park, Manor Park, and Lee Road. The parish comprises 1, 273 acres. Real property, &#163;37, 952. Pop., in 1851, 3, 552; in 1861, 6, 162. Houses, 953. Lee Manor House, Lee House, Lee Grove, Lee Place, Lee Villa, and others are old mansions; a continuous line of new villas connects the village with Blackheath Park; and so very many other new villas and ornate cottages are disposed in terraces or lines that a large proportion of the parish may be pronounced a metropolitan suburb. The living is a rectory in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;464.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The old church went to ruin; but the cemetery of it continues to be interesting, for containing several handsome monuments, one of which is to the Dacre family, and another to the astronomer Dr. E. Halley. A new church was built in 1842; but this was found, in a few years, to be too small for the increasing population, and was then taken down. The present church stands near the old one, in a beautiful situation with an extensive prospect; was erected at a cost of &#163;8, 000; and is a handsome structure with a lofty spire. Two other churches, Christ Church and Holy Trinity, are within the parish; and serve for chapelries constituted in 1840 and 1863, and containing a pop. of respectively 2, 333 and 1, 100. The livings of them are p. curacies; the former in the patronage of the Rector, the latter in that of L. Glenton, Esq. Value of the former, &#163;300;* of the latter, not reported * Christ Church stands in Lee Park; and is a neat structure, in the pointed style. Holy Trinity church was completed in 1864; is cruciform, in the early English style, of Kentish rag with Bath stone dressings; has an external staircase turret, surmounted by an openwork oak bell turret and shingled spire; and presents a somewhat novel yet heavy appearance. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans; a well conducted proprietary school; national and infant schools; thirty good alms houses, for the wives of freemen of the Merchant Tailors&apos; company; alms houses, with endowed income of &#163;71, founded by and T. Boone; and other charities &#163;62.&#151;The sub-district contains Kidbrook liberty, and the part of Lewisham parish lying N, NE, and NW of Plough-Bridge. Acres, 2, 399. Pop. in 1851, 8, 478; in 1861, 11, 807. Houses, 1,876. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee,_London</link>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/LEE__plc.htm</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10055477</id>
   <status>Lon_SDist</status>
   <name>LEE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221900</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LEE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221912</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221924</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEE THE GOOD SHEPHERD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221936</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEE THE GOOD SHEPHERD WITH ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221948</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEE HOLY TRINITY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221961</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEE ST MILDRED BURNT ASH HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221973</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEE PARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10539377</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LEE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>6255</id>
<name>LEEDS</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.2481209758769</lat>
<lon>0.607371854938032</lon>
<gazetteerText>Leeds, par. and vil., Kent, 5 miles SE. of Maidstone, 1653 ac., pop. 727; P.O.; a little to N. is Leeds Castle (13th cent.), one of the finest seats in Kent. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leeds,_Kent</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644689</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10221985</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LEEDS</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5383</id>
<name>BROOMFIELD</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.235516479158</lat>
<lon>0.629220162215892</lon>
<gazetteerText>BROOMFIELD, a parish in Hollingbourn district, Kent; on an affluent of the Medway, 6 miles ESE of Maidstone r. station. Post Town, Leeds, under Maidstone. Acres, 1,430. Real property, &#163;1,431. Pop., 150. Houses, 25. The property is divided among a few. The living is a vicarage, annexed to the vicarage of Leeds, in the diocese of Canterbury. The church is good. A fair is held on 16th May. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broomfield,_Kent</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10192845</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>BROOMFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10222000</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEEDS WITH BROOMFIELD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23343</id>
<name>GROVE PARK</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.4307700964261</lat>
<lon>0.0271063280062458</lon>
<gazetteerText>Grove Park, ry. sta., 2&#188; miles NW. of Chislehurst, W. Kent. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647833</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10221950</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEE ST AUGUSTINE GROVE PARK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
