<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4475</id>
<name>EASTWELL</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1863854129515</lat>
<lon>0.876808361370027</lon>
<gazetteerText>EASTWELL, a parish in East Ashford district, Kent; 2&#189; miles W by N of Wye r. station, and 3 N by E of Ashford. Post town, Westwell, under Ashford. Acres, 894. Real property, &#163;1, 079. Pop., 126. Houses, 17. The property is not much divided. The manor belonged anciently to a family of its own name, but passed to successively the families of Hales, Moyle, Finch, Heneage, and Hatton. Eastwell Park is the seat of the Earl of Winchelsea; has a modern mansion, by Bononi, on the site of one built by Sir Thomas Moyle in the time of Henry VIII.; extends beyond the parish so far as to include about 2, 500 acres; and both presents fine scenery within itself, and commands very brilliant exterior views. Richard, the last of the Plantagenets, a natural son of Richard III., took refuge in Eastwell after the battle of Bosworth; worked here as a mason till identified and relieved by Sir Thomas Moyle; and then built a small house, in which he lived and died, and which was demolished towards the end of the 17th century. A modern building marks the site of the house; and a spring near this is called Plantagenet&apos;s well. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;196.* Patron, the Earl of Winchelsea. The church is ancient but good; consists of nave, aisle, and two chancels, with square embattled tower; and contains a massive table monument to Sir Moyle Finch, and his wife the Countess of Winchelsea, and also a worn ancient tomb, without inscription, supposed by some to be the tomb of Richard Plantagenet, but appearing to others to be of earlier date. There is a free school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eastwell_Park</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296478</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10081129</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EASTWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10151521</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EASTWELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
