<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6475</id>
<name>WESTERHAM</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.2543304606569</lat>
<lon>0.0729952782790202</lon>
<gazetteerText>WESTERHAM, a small town, a parish, and a hundred, in Kent. The town stands on a gentle acclivity, 4&#188; miles N of Edenbridge r. station, and 5&#189; W of Sevenoaks; was the birthplace of the martyr Frith, Bishop Hoadley, and General Wolfe; is a pleasant place; and has a post-office&#8225; under Edenbridge, a hotel, a public hall and cornmarket built in 1866, a fine large later English church, an Independent chapel, a literary institution and reading room, a national school, charities &#163;30, a weekly market on Wednesday, and a fair on 3 May. Pop., 1,651. The parish includes Crockham hamlet, is in Sevenoaks district, and comprises 5,676 acres. Real property, &#163;11,303. Pop., 2,196. Houses, 431. The manor was given by Edward I., to Westminster abbey; passed to the Greshams and the Wardes; and, with Squerryes Court, belongs now to Colonel G. Warde. Dunsdale is the seat of J. Kitchin, Esq. Landslips occurred in greensand hills here in 1596 and 1756. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;450.* Patron, J. Board, Esq. The p. curacy of Crockham is a separate benefice.-The hundred consists of W. and Edenbridge parishes. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Westerham</link>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/WEST_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634434</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10031436</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>WESTERHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10228566</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WESTERHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10228580</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WESTERHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835449</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WESTERHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
