<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>385</id>
<name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>50.9859996634834</lat>
<lon>0.960481846142462</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROMNEY (New), a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Romney-Marsh district, Kent. The town stands 1&#189; mile from the coast, 7 S E of Ham-street r. station, and 9 S W of Hythe; was known to the Saxons as Rumenea, and to the Normans as Romenel; had, at Domesday, five parish churches, an hospital, twelve wards, and 156 burgesses; ranked, for some time, as an important one of the cinque ports; lost its harbour, in the time of Edward I., by a great storm which changed thecourse of the river Rother; is a borough by prescription, and was chartered by Edward III.; sent two members toparliament, till disfranchised by the reform act of 1832; is a seat of county courts, and a polling-place; gives the title of Earl to the family of Marsham; and has a post-office&#8224; under Folkestone, a good inn, a market house, an assembly-room, a church, a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, a work-house, alms-houses with &#163;112 a year, other charities &#163;11, and a large stock fair on 21 Aug. The church is mainly Norman, partly early English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a loftytower, seen all over the surrounding level; contains apiscina, two brasses, and some ancient monuments; and belonged once to Pontignac abbey in France. A cell of that abbey was once here; a lepers&apos; hospital, or chantry, of the time of Henry II., also was here; but both have been entirely effaced. The parish comprises 2, 276 acres of land, and 643 of water. Rated property, &#163;5, 619. Pop., 1,062. Houses, 205. The property is subdivided. There is a coast-guard station. The living is a vicarage, united with the sinecure rectory of Hope-All Saints, in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;430. Patron, All Souls College, Oxford.&#151;The sub-district contains alsoten other parishes. Acres, 20, 671. Pop., 2, 882. Houses, 585. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Romney</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641582</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10061635</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109978</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10134511</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10148303</id>
   <status>CnqPt</status>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224615</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY WITH HOPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224627</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>ST MARTINS NEW ROMNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10229911</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10229923</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10537113</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758960</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>NEW ROMNEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
