<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6182</id>
<name>EYNSFORD</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.3655739524257</lat>
<lon>0.198702107086863</lon>
<gazetteerText>EYNESFORD, a village and a parish in Dartford district, Kent. The village stands on the river Darent, adjacent to the Seven Oaks branch of the London and Dover railway, 5&#189; miles S of Dartford; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Dartford. The parish includes also the hamlet of Crockenhill. Acres, 3, 503. Real property, &#163;6, 682. Pop. in 1851, 1, 323; in 1861, 1, 738. Houses, 261. The increase of population arose from house-extension at Crockenhill, and from the carrying on of railway works. The manor belonged anciently to the archbishops of Canterbury; was held, under them, till the time of Edward I., by the family of Eynesford, or Ainsford; passed then to the great family of Criol; and went afterwards to numerous proprietors. A castle was built on it, by the Eynesfords; seems early to have fallen into decay; and is now represented by little more than the walls. These enclosed nearly an acre of ground; are of Norman architecture; consist of flints from the chalk, with intermixture of many Roman bricks; and include fragments of the keep. The moat has been converted into an orchard. There are large paper-mills, amid orchards and cherry-gardens. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;410.* Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church is chiefly early English; has a rich Norman W door: is cruciform; and has a later English N transept. The vicarage of Crockenhill is separate. There are a Baptist chapel, two public schools, and charities &#163;48. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/EYNS_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eynsford</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649775</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10040607</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EYNSFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10219292</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EYNSFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
