<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>440</id>
<name>DOVER</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.1266522405277</lat>
<lon>1.29577615352622</lon>
<gazetteerText>Dover, parl. and mun. bor., market town, and the chief of the Cinque Ports, E. Kent, on the Strait of Dover, 76 miles SE. of London by rail -- bor., 1317 ac., pop. 30,270; C. P. (with Corporate and Non-Corporate Members), 14,063 ac., pop. 76,478; 2 Banks, 4 newspapers. Market-days. Wednesday and Saturday. D. is the terminus of the London, Chatham, and Dover and the South-Eastern Ry. systems, and is also a port for the mail and packet service to the Continent, Calais being distant 22 miles and Ostend 68 miles. On the Continental service its trade chiefly depends, but it has also attractions as a seaside resort; and it has shipbuilding, rope and sailmaking, fisheries, and coast traffic, besides the supply of ships&apos; stores. The harbour has been greatly improved in recent years. The Admiralty Pier (commenced in 1848) runs more than one-third of a mile into the sea; it forms the W. arm of a harbour of refuge which, when completed, will enclose the whole bay. On the extremity of the Admiralty Pier is a flashing light seen 6 to 7 miles, and on the North Pier is a fixed light seen 3 miles. (For shipping statistics, see Appendix.) As the nearest landing-place from the Continent, D. has from the earliest times been a place of considerable importance; it contains many antiquities, the chief of which is Dover Castle, situated on NE. side, on a chalk cliff nearly 350 ft. high. Within its walls are the Roman pharos, the Romano-British fortress church, some remains of the Saxon fort, and the Norman keep. Dover returns 1 member to Parliament; it returned 2 members until 1885. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651048</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10027720</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10030304</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10037890</id>
   <status>CnqPt</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10040528</id>
   <status>CP/ExP</status>
   <name>DOVER CASTLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10040530</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10056792</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10060620</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST JAMES THE APOSTLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10060631</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DOVER TRINITY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10074101</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10081105</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST MARTIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10081592</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10134237</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135497</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10151466</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10151478</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST JAMES THE APOSTLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10151480</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST MARTIN THE LESS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10151491</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10172238</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST MARTIN THE GREATER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10193450</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST NICHOLAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10198227</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10218834</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>DOVER ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10536583</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10572587</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12737580</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>KENT DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12750006</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12756124</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>DOVER AND DEAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12757347</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12757876</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12780540</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833696</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DOVER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2078</id>
   <name>HOUGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2493</id>
   <name>GUSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4943</id>
   <name>ALKHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5526</id>
   <name>EYTHORNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5673</id>
   <name>TEMPLE EWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6267</id>
   <name>LYDDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6329</id>
   <name>RIVER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6342</id>
   <name>ST MARGARETS AT CLIFFE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6369</id>
   <name>SHEPHERDSWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6479</id>
   <name>WHITFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>2867</id>
<name>ISLE OF GRAIN</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.4533779157948</lat>
<lon>0.705887468427623</lon>
<gazetteerText>GRAIN (Isle of), or St. James, a parish in Hoo district, Kent; between the Thames and the Medway, 2 miles W by N of Sheerness r. station. It has a post office under Rochester. Acres, 9, 431; of which 6, 150 are water. Real property, &#163;4, 987. Pop., 255. Houses, 49. The property is divided among a few. The land was an island; bounded, on the W, by Yantlet creek, -on the other sides, by the Thames and the Medway; but it is now connected with the mainland westward by a good road. The site of the village, on the E, is high ground; but the rest of the parish is low and flat, mostly pasture and marsh; and is protected from sea-inundation by embankments. The Nore-light is off the E end. A large fort for the defence of the Medway was nearly completed in June 1865. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;360.* Patron, G. Henderson, Esq. The church belonged, before the time of Edward I., to Minster nunnery in Sheppey; has a brass of 1494; and is good. There is an Independent chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isle_of_Grain</link>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/GRAI_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648236</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10081208</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ISLE OF GRAIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10215419</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GRAIN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
