<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1259</id>
<name>SWANSCOMBE</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.4464685102877</lat>
<lon>0.301926649292249</lon>
<gazetteerText>SWANSCOMBE, a parish in Dartford district, Kent; on the river Thames, and on the North Kent railway, between Greenhithe and Northfleet r. stations, 5 miles E of Dartford. It contains Greenhithe, and has a post-office under Dartford. Acres, 2,593; of which 405 are water. Real property, &#163;11,122. Pop. in 1851, 1,763; in 1861, 2,323. houses, 414. The manor was known at Domesday, as Swene&apos;s Camp; took that name from a winter-camp, formed by Sweyne the Dane, to protect his fleet; passed to W. de Valence, and the Mortimers; was given, by Queen Elizabeth, to the Weldons; went afterwards to the Childs; and passed to the Earl of Jersey. The manor-house is an ancient building, now occupied by J. Coveney, Esq. S. Wood is a famous rural retreat, frequented by gipsying parties; and contains a cavern, called Clappernappers Hole, associated with much curious legend. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Rochester. Value, &#163;600.* Patron, Sidney-Sussex College, Cambridge. The church is partly transition Norman, and claims to be Saxon. There are alms- house s, and other charities &#163;23. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swanscombe_and_Greenhithe</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swanscombe</link>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/SWNS_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636433</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10135527</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SWANSCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227343</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SWANSCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227367</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWANSCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10227380</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWANSCOMBE ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
