<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6317</id>
<name>PLUMSTEAD</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.4871471348083</lat>
<lon>0.094433285736447</lon>
<gazetteerText>PLUMSTEAD, a suburban town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Lewisham district, Kent. The town issuburban to Woolwich on the E; stands on the North Kent railway, near the river Thames, 10 miles E by S of St. Paul&apos;s, London; was once a market-town; and has a station with telegraph on the railway, a post-office&#8225; in Sussex-place under London S E, and receiving post-offices in Agues-place and Burrage-Town. The parish comprises 3, 71 8 acres of land, and 344 of water. Real property, &#163;47, 403. Pop. in 1851, 8, 373; in 1861, 24, 502. Houses, 3, 195. The increase of pop. arose chiefly fromcontiguity to Woolwich, and from large extension thereof government employment. The manor was given, in960, by King Edgar, to Canterbury abbey; went, for atime, to Earl Godwin&apos;s son Tostan, and to Bishop Odo; passed, in the time of Henry VIII., to the Boughtons; and was given, in 1736, to Queen&apos;s College, Oxford. Lesnes or Lessness abbey estate, with interesting ruins1&#189; mile E of the parish church, belongs to Christ&apos;s hospital, London. Burrage-Town estate, forming the Wsection of the parish, belongs to the Pattison family. Genteel residences and elegant villas are very numerous. A committee was formed in Aug. 1866 to test the rightover Plumstead common. The S portions of the parishare hilly, and have good views; but the N portions arechiefly marsh. Shooter&apos;s Hill is in the same range as Plumstead common. About 2,000 acres of the Plumstead and Erith marshes were inundated in the time of Henry VIII., and were not recovered till the time of James I. Powder magazines are on the P. marshes; brickfields, tile-kilns, sand-pits, and chalk-pits, arenear P. common; market-gardening is carried on; and sugar moulds are made. The living is a vicarage, united with Arsenal chapel, in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;873.* Patron, the Rev. J. A. M&apos; Allister. The p. curacy of St. Nicholas is a separate benefice, of the value of &#163;300, in the patronage of the Vicar. St. James&apos; chapel, on the Burrage-Town estate, forms another charge, and is in the patronage of Mr. Pattison. St. Margaret&apos;schurch, on P. common, is a recent and handsome edifice. St. Nicholas&apos; church is an old building, and has beenmuch improved. St. James&apos; chapel is neat and modern. There are also neat and commodious dissenting chapels, national schools, and charities &#163;106. The sub-district includes also Charlton-next-Woolwich parish, and comprises 5,057 acres. Pop., 32, 974. Houses, 4, 312. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/PLUM_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plumstead</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640201</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10137457</id>
   <status>Lon_SDist</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224007</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Vest</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224019</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224032</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD THE ASCENSION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224056</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD ST JAMES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224068</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD ST JAMES WITH ST JOHN THE BAPTIST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224070</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD ST JOHN THE BAPTIST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224081</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD ST JOHN WITH ST JAMES AND ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224093</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD ST MARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224100</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD ST MARK AND ST MARGARET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224111</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD ST NICHOLAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224123</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10539444</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD EAST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10539456</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD WEST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12823435</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>21068</id>
<name>SHOOTERS HILL</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.4687604990316</lat>
<lon>0.0662305127379496</lon>
<gazetteerText>SHOOTERS-HILL, an eminence, a hamlet, and a chapelry, in Eltham parish, Kent. The eminence rises 1 mile S of Woolwich; is an insulated mass of London clay, 446 feet high; was thickly wooded, and called Sheters-Held, in the time of Richard II.; took its present name from bands of outlaws, who anciently haunted its woods to assail wayfarers on a great road crossing it; was the scene of archery and other sports, in the presence of Henry VIII. and his queen Catherine; is traversed by both an ancient Roman road and a great modern one; bears aloft a triangular tower, erected to commemorate the taking of Severndroog in India; and commands a panoramic view, very fine on all sides, and finest on the side toward London.-The hamlet adjoins the eminence; and has a post-office under London SE, and a R. police station.&#151;The chapelry was constituted in 1866. Pop., 423. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of London. Value, not reported. Patron, the Rev. J. S. Masters. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637920</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10224020</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD ALL SAINTS SHOOTERS HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10224044</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD CHRIST CHURCH SHOOTERS HILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>22968</id>
<name>ABBEY WOOD</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.4875279270898</lat>
<lon>0.123263174844033</lon>
<gazetteerText>ABBEY-WOOD, a hamlet in Erith parish, Kent; on the North Kent railway, 2&#190; miles E of Woolwich. It is named from the Abbey of Lessness, about a mile distant; it has become a sort of metropolitan suburb; and it has a r. station with telegraph, and a postal pillar box. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7302135</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10129450</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ABBEY WOOD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
