<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6279</id>
<name>MILTON</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.4353305517502</lat>
<lon>0.378776452713014</lon>
<gazetteerText>MILTON-NEXT-GRAVESEND, a parish in Gravesend district, Kent; on the river Thames and the North Kent railway, within Gravesend borough. It adjoins Gravesend parish on the E; was incorporated with Gravesend borough in the time of Elizabeth; includes a larger and finer portion of Gravesend town than the portion within Gravesend parish; contains many of the best houses, the custom-house, the fort, the literary institution, the Royal Terrace pier, and other objects of main interest; commands, from its higher thoroughfares, a rich view over the circumjacent portions of Kent, and a view of about 40 miles in reach along the N shore of the Thames; and, as to all its principal features, has already been noticed in our article GRAVESEND. Post town, Gravesend. Acres, 858; of which 155 are water. Real property, &#163;54,581; of which &#163;1,000 are in quarries, and &#163;.1,300 in gas-works. Pop. in 1851,9,927; in 1861, 10,897. Houses, 1,842. Two sections of the parish form the chapelries of Holy Trinity and Christchurch, constituted in 1845 and 1856. Pop. of H. T., 3,642; of C., 5,631. The head living is a rectory, and the other two livings are p. curacies, in the diocese of Rochester. Value of the rectoIy, &#163;270; * of H. T., &#163;150; of C., &#163;.300. Patron of the rectory, the Lord Chancellor two turns, and the Bishop of Rochester one turn; of H. T., alternately the Crown and the Bishop; of C., the Rector of Milton. The churches are noticed in the article GRAVESEND. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.nwkfhs.org.uk/MILT_plc.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milton-next-Gravesend</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10222904</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MILTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10222928</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MILTON CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10222930</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MILTON HOLY TRINITY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10222953</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MILTON NEXT GRAVESEND</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
