<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4942</id>
<name>ALDINGTON</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.0867024088805</lat>
<lon>0.963068205500453</lon>
<gazetteerText>ALDINGTON, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict in the district of East Ashford, Kent. The village stands near the Grand Military canal, 1&#189; mile S of Smeeth r. station, and 6 SE of Ashford. It has a post office under Hythe; and is in the lib. of Romney Marsh.&#151;The parish comprises 3,576 acres. Real property, &#163;5,357. Pop., 658. Houses, 144. The property is not much divided. The Roman road from Lymne to Pevensey went through the parish. Court-of-Street, on the line of that road, about a mile E of the village, was the scene of the imposture of Elizabeth Barton, the nun of Kent, who made so great a figure in the political party of Queen Catherine. the living is a rectory in the diocese of Canterbury; and till 1868 was united with Smeeth. Value, &#163;850.* Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church is early English, with a tower in late perpendicular; and formerly had a brass of 1475. Charities, &#163;9. The celebrated Erasmus of Rotterdam, and Richard Moster, who suffered death for aiding the imposture of Elizabeth Barton, were rectors of Aldington.-The subdistrict comprises seven parishes. Acres, 16,127. Pop., 2,487. Houses, 509. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657531</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aldington,_Kent</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10038881</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ALDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10171489</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ALDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10561887</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ALDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4488</id>
   <name>HURST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5379</id>
   <name>BONNINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5850</id>
   <name>EASTBRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
