<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6257</id>
<name>LENHAM</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.2375713231247</lat>
<lon>0.722499343113419</lon>
<gazetteerText>LENHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Hollingbourne district, Kent. The village stands near the source of the rivulet Len, 6 miles N by W of Pluckley r. station, and 9&#189; E by S of Maidstone; was once a market-town; and has a post office, &#8225; under Maidstone, and fairs on 6 June and 23 Oct. The parish contains also the hamlets of Lenham-Heath and Sandway. Acres, 6,963. Real property, &#163;10,096. Pop., 2,016. Houses, 411. The property is subdivided. The manor was given, by Kenulf, King of Mercia, and Cudred, King of Kent, to Canterbury abbey; continued in possession of the abbey till the dissolution; and belongs now to James S. Douglas, Esq. Chilston Park is the seat of Mr. Douglas; Torre-Hill is the seat of Lord Kingsdown; and Swadelands is the seat of J. Fermor, Esq. The surface extends across a valley between chalk hills and sand hills; contains the sources of the rivulet Len and a head-stream of the Stour; and is salubrious and of average fertility. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;670.* Patron, A. Akers, Esq. The church is partly early English with alterations, partly decorated; consists of nave, aisles, and two chancels, with a tower; and contains sixteen ancient oaken stalls, which were used by the monks of Canterbury when visiting the manor,-a stone chair, or sedile, with solid arms and a cinquefoil-headed canopy, a pis cina, under a very wide arch,-a richly-carved pulpit, of the 17th century,-the effigies of a priest, probably of the time of Edward III.,-monuments of the Colepepers,- and a brass of a grandson of Mary Honywood, who lived to see 367 of her descendants. There are an Independent chapel, national schools, an endowed school, with &#163;12 a year, and alms houses with &#163;70.&#151;The sub-district contains also five other parishes. Acres, 16,142. Pop., 3,608. Houses, 748. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lenham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644624</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10222035</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10222047</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10537149</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LENHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4950</id>
   <name>BOUGHTON MALHERBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6482</id>
   <name>WICHLING</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
