<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5912</id>
<name>BOUGHTON UNDER BLEAN</name>
<container>KENT</container>
<lat>51.2930757275544</lat>
<lon>0.938587638830457</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOUGHTON-UNDER-BLEAN, a village, a parish, and a hundred in Faversham district, Kent. The village stands on the edge of Blean forest, 3 &#189; miles SE of Faversham r. station; and has a post office,&#8225; of the name of Broughton, under Faversham, and a fair on the Monday after 29 June.&#151;The parish comprises 2,353 acres. Real property, &#163;8,904. Pop., 1,624. Houses, 323. The property is subdivided. Nash Court, then held by the Hawkinses, who were Roman Catholics, was demolished by a mob in 1715, and rebuilt in 1766. Boughton House is the seat of the Laggs. Boughton Hill, adjacent to the village, commands an extensive and brilliant view. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Canterbury. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church comprises nave, aisle, three chancels, and a tower. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;74.-The hundred is in the lathe of Scray; and comprises four parishes. Acres, 11,354. Pop., 2,930. Houses. 581. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boughton_under_Blean</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7294902</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10060096</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOUGHTON UNDER BLEAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10095750</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>BOUGHTON UNDER BLEAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10211086</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BOUGHTON UNDER BLEAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10536947</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BOUGHTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
