<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20875</id>
<name>CHORLTON UPON MEDLOCK</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4629755707873</lat>
<lon>-2.22746507396787</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHORLTON-UPON-MEDLOCK, a township, five chapelries, and a sub-district in Chorlton district, Manchester parish, Lancashire. The township lies within Manchester borough, and includes the south-eastern part of Manchester city. Acres, 700. Real property, &#163;178, 750. Pop., in 1841, 28, 336; in 1861, 44, 795. Houses, 8, 584. -The chapelries are All Saints, St. Luke, St. Saviour, St. Stephen, and St. Paul, and all are rectories in the diocese of Manchester. Value of All Saints, &#163;488; of St. Luke, &#163;300;* of St. Saviour, &#163;543;* of St. Stephen, &#163;356;* of St. Paul, &#163;248.* Patrons of All Saints, the Representatives of the Rev. Dr. Burton; of St. Luke, the Repr. of R. Gardner, Esq.; of St. Saviour, the Rev. E. Birch; of St. Stephen and St. Paul, Trustees. All Saints church was built in 1820, and has a tower and dome. St. Luke&apos;s was built in 1865, and is in the decorated English style. St. Paul&apos;s was built in 1862, and is in the later English style. An Armenian church, the earliest in England, was founded in Sept., 1869. A free library was built in 1866, at a cost of &#163;4, 000; and had 6, 000 volumes at its opening. A medical hospital was built in 1865. Land for a public park was purchased in 1868.-The sub-d. is co-terminate with the township. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653083</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41411</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10344979</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>CHORLTON UPON MEDLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10344980</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHORLTON ON MEDLOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10344992</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHORLTON ON MEDLOCK ST LUKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10345005</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHORLTON ON MEDLOCK ST PAUL WITH ST LUKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10345017</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHORLTON ON MEDLOCK ST STEPHEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10345029</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHORLTON UPON MEDLOCK ST AMBROSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10345030</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHORLTON UPON MEDLOCK ST SAVIOUR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10345042</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHORLTON UPON MEDLOCK ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10373001</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHORLTON UPON MEDLOCK ST SAVIOUR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545572</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHORLTON UPON MEDLOCK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
