<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>147</id>
<name>DENTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4512808430884</lat>
<lon>-2.11426398885456</lon>
<gazetteerText>DENTON, a township, two chapelries, and a sub-district in Manchester parish, Ashton-under-Lyne district, Lancashire. The township lies on the river Tame, and on the Staleybridge and Stockport railway, at the boundary with Cheshire, 3&#189; miles NNE of Stockport; and has a station on the railway, and a post office&#8225; under Manchester. Acres, 1, 647. Real property, &#163;8, 997; of which &#163;2, 000 are in mines. Pop., 3, 335. Houses, 675-Coal is worked, and hat-making carried on. Denton Hall, now a farm-house, was the seat of the Hollands. The chapelries are St. Lawrence and Christ-Church; the former constituted in 1854, the latter in 1846. Rated property, &#163;5, 209 and &#163;7, 683. Pop., 3, 127 and 3, 579. Houses, 623 and 739. The property of St. Lawrence is divided among a few; that of Christ-Church, much sub-divided. Both livings are rectories in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;203 * and &#163;221.* Patrons of St. L., the Earl of Wilton; ofC., alternately the Crown and the Bishop. The church ofwas built in 1856. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a mechanics&apos; institute, and two national schools. -The sub-district comprises the townships of Denton and Haughton. Acres, 2, 777. Pop., 6, 706. Houses, 1, 762. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Denton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denton,_Greater_Manchester</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651357</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41432</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10005190</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>DENTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10025424</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>DENTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347385</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>DENTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347439</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DENTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347452</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DENTON CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546394</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DENTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12745527</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>DENTON AND REDDISH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833283</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DENTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
