<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10578</id>
<name>KNOWSLEY</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4476492038485</lat>
<lon>-2.83886531576601</lon>
<gazetteerText>KNOWSLEY, a township-chapelry in Huyton parish, Lancashire; 2&#189; miles N by W of Huyton r. station, and 3 NW by W of Prescot. Post town, Prescot. Acres, 4, 750. Real property, &#163;12, 549; of which &#163;1, 367 are in mines, and &#163;330 in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 1, 486; in 1861, 1, 349. Houses, 243. The property all belongs to the Earl of Derby. Knowsley Hall is the Earl&apos;s seat; has been enlarged from time to time: includes portions of the period of Henry VII.; was fully restored, by the tenth earl, before 1735; presents imposing fronts, surmounted by round towers; contains portraits of all the Stanleys, and a large and valuable collection of paintings by the old masters; and was visited, in November 1865, by the Prince and Princess of Wales. The grounds around it comprise upwards of 2, 000 acres; are enclosed by a stone wall upwards of 8 feet high, pierced by thirteen entrances; and contain tasteful gardens, many ancient oaks, and ornamental waters nearly a mile long. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Chester. Valne, &#163;300.* Patron, the Earl of Derby. The church is recent, cruciform, and handsome; and has a W broach spire. There are national schools. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Knowsley/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645097</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41314</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10168582</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KNOWSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10369204</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>KNOWSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10369230</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KNOWSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12746179</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>KNOWSLEY NORTH AND SEFTON EAST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12748012</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>KNOWSLEY SOUTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12754267</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>KNOWSLEY NORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
