<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>638</id>
<name>KIRKHAM</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.7810496349768</lat>
<lon>-2.87968125530073</lon>
<gazetteerText>KIRKHAM, a small town, a township, and a sub-district, in Fylde district, and a parish partly also in Preston and Garstang districts, Lancashire. The town stands near the Preston and Wyre railway, 3 miles N of Naze Point on the Ribble estuary, and 8 WNW of Preston; has been regarded as the capital of the Fylde country; comprises several well built streets; has a good supply of water, and fair sanitary arrangements under a local board of health; is a seat of petty sessions and county courts; and has a post office&#8224; under Preston, a railway station, a magistrates&apos; office, a church, Independent and Wesleyan chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a reading room and library, a free grammar school, a girls&apos; charity school, a national school, a workhouse, and some charities. The church succeeded a Norman one, which was given by Roger de Poitiers to Shrewsbury Abbey, and by Edward I. to Vale-Royal abbey; comprises a nave of 1822, a tower and spire of 1844, and a chancel of 1853, together with a N transept; and is convenient and spacious. The Roman Catholic chapel is at the Willows, &#189; a mile from the town; was built in 1845, after designs by Pugin; is in the early English style; and consists of nave, aisles, chancel, and porch, with tower and octagonal spire. The grammar school was founded in 1658; affords both an English and a classical education; and has &#163;596 a year from endowment, and two exhibitions of &#163;60 a year to Cambridge. The workhouse is that of the Fylde district; has attached to it large garden ground; and, at the census of 1861, had 110 inmates. Fairs are held on 4 and 5 Feb., 28 and 29 April, and 18 and 19 Oct.; and there are flax mills in the town, and cotton mills in the adjoining township of Medlar-with-Wesham. -The town and the township are regarded as conterminate. Acres, 840. Real property, &#163;7, 450; of which &#163;162 are in gas works. Pop. in 1851, 2, 799; in 1861, 3, 380. Houses, 616.&#151;The sub-district contains also the townships of Freckleton, Warton, Bryning-with-Kellamergh, Ribby-with-Wrea, Westby-with-Plumpton, Weeton-with-Preese, Greenalgh-with-Thistleton, Cliftonwith-Salwick, Newton-with-Scales, Medlar-with-Wesham, Little Eccleston-with-Larbreck, Treals, Roseacre, and Wharles, and Elswick. Acres, 31, 464. Pop. in 1851, 8, 464; in 1861, 9, 141. Houses, 1, 740. -The parish contains all the sub-district, except Elswick township; and contains also the townships of Whittingham, Goosnargh-with-Newsham, Great and Little Singleton, and the chapelry of Hambleton. Acres, 48, 530. Real property, &#163;73, 737. Pop. in 1851, 10, 926; in 1861, 11, 445. Houses, 2, 191. The living is a vicarage in the diocese o Manchester. Value, &#163;1, 080.* Patron, Christ Church, Oxford-The p. curacies of Goosnargh, Great Singleton, Hambleton Lund, Ribby-with-Wrea, Treales, Weeton, White chapel, and Warton-with-Freckleton, are separate benefices. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Kirkham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kirkham,_Lancashire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645280</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53205</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53206</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53217</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53209</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53216</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53203</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53210</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53211</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53213</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53214</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53215</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53219</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53220</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53204</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53208</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53212</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53218</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53207</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10107179</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>KIRKHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109115</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>KIRKHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10216424</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>KIRKHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10369071</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>KIRKHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10369113</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KIRKHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544993</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KIRKHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12836727</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KIRKHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10032</id>
   <name>BRYNING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10685</id>
   <name>MEDLAR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10772</id>
   <name>RIBBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11022</id>
   <name>WESTBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17221</id>
   <name>FYLDE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
