<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10349</id>
<name>HORNBY</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>54.1058293783048</lat>
<lon>-2.63431910725654</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORNBY, a village, a township, and a chapelry, in Melling parish, Lancashire. The village stands at the confluence of the Wenning and the Lune rivers, adjacent to the Little Northwestern railway, 8&#189; miles NE by E of Lancaster; is neatly built; commands beautiful scenery along the valleys; is sometimes visited by tourists; has a station on the railway, a post office under Lancaster, and an inn; is a seat of petty sessions; was formerly a market town; and has still cattle fairs on every alternate Tuesday of the summer months.-The township comprises 2, 115 acres. Real property, &#163;4, 066. Pop., 317. Houses, 75. The manor belonged, in the 12th century, to Nicholas de Montbegon; passed to the Stanleys, Lords Monteagle; and belongs now to John Foster, Esq. Hornby Castle, the manorial seat, was founded by N. de Montbegon; retains two towers built by one of the Lords Monteagle and by Lord Wemyss; has undergone recent extensive renovations and improvements; and stands on an eminence, overlooking the rich surrounding scenery. The estate was the subject of a famous litigation, called &quot;the Great Will Cause, &quot; begun in 1826. Hornby Hall is the seat of John Murray, Esq. A Roman mound is near the Lune. A Premonstratensian priory, a cell to Croxton abbey, was anciently here; and was given, at the dissolution, to the Stanleys; and the remains of it are now a farm-house.&#151;The chapelry was constituted a parish in 1859, and is larger than the township. Pop., 455. Houses, 98. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;130. * Patron, John Foster, Esq. The church is ancient; has a chancel, and an octagonal tower, built by the first Lord Monteagle, after the battle of Flodden; and contains a tablet to Dr. Lingard, the historian. The shaft of an ancient cross is in the churchyard. A small Roman Catholic chapel, to the W of the church, was served by Dr. Lingard. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646598</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Hornby/</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53296</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10355977</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>HORNBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10355989</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORNBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10355990</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORNBY WITH CLAUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10356003</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HORNBY WITH FARLETON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
