<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9847</id>
<name>AUGHTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5491145877177</lat>
<lon>-2.91124337386281</lon>
<gazetteerText>AUGHTON, a parish and a subdistrict in the district of Ormskirk, Lancashire. The parish lies on a branch of the river Alt, and on the Liverpool and Preston railway, at Town-Green station, near the Liverpool and Leeds canal, 2&#189; miles SSW of Ormskirk. It has a post office under Ormskirk. Acres, 4,462. Real property, &#163;13,804. Pop., 1,870. Houses, 360. The property is much sub-divided. Aughton Hall is a chief residence. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;830. Patron, J. P. Tempest, Esq. The church was rebuilt in 1867, at a cost of &#163;6,000. There is a Roman Catholic chapel.-The subdistrict includes also two chapelries. Acres, 8,530. Pop., 3,862. Houses, 708. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Aughton/</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/AughtonH/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aughton,_Lancashire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656786</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41336</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41335</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10332448</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>AUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332450</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>AUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332461</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>AUGHTON CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545638</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AUGHTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25184</id>
<name>AUGHTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>54.1021423994626</lat>
<lon>-2.68826120659777</lon>
<gazetteerText>AUGHTON, a chapelry in Halton parish, Lancashire; on the river Lune, 2 miles N of Caton r. station, and 7 NE of Lancaster. Post Town, Caton, under Lancaster. Acres, 1,900. Pop., 132. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;140.* Patron, the Rector of Halton. The church was rebuilt in 1864. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
</results>
