<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10316</id>
<name>HAWKSHEAD</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>54.3758204200702</lat>
<lon>-3.00464322899014</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAWKSHEAD, a small town, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Ulverston district, Lancashire. The town stands in a sheltered valley, at the head of Esthwaite water, 2 miles W of Windermere lake, 4 E by N of Coniston r. station, and 5 SW by S of Ambleside; is surrounded by a picturesque country, with many of the finest features of the Lake region; dates from very ancient times; was long the capital of Furness, and a seat of the courts of justice of Furness abbey; has a compact form, with a rather spacious market place; contains a number of old, quaint, picturesque houses; is a seat of petty sessions, and a polling place; and has a post office&#8225; under Windermere, a good inn, a modern town hall, a church, a Baptist chapel, a grammar school, a national school, and some charities. The church was founded about the time of the Conquest; retains the piers and arches of its original masonry; was rebuilt, in the time of Elizabeth, by Archbishop Sandys; has a massive square tower; contains effigies of Archbishop Sandys&apos; parents; and stands on an elevation, with a fine view. The churchyard contains the grave of the distinguished Miss Elizabeth Smith. The grammar school was founded by Archbishop Sandys; has an endowed income of &#163;210, and a good library; and numbers, among its pupils, Dr. Walker, Dr. Wordsworth, the poet Wordsworth, Lord Abinger, Sir Frederick Pollock, and Dr. King. A weekly market is held on Monday; and fairs, on Easter Monday, the Monday before Holy Thursday, and 2 Oct.-The township bears the name of Hawkshead-with-Monk-Coniston and Skelwith; and includes the hamlets of Borwick, Henakin, and Gallowbarrow. Acres, 9, 152. Real property, &#163;6, 720. Pop., 1, 144. Houses, 234. The manor belonged formerly to Furness abbey; and belongs now to the Duke of Buccleuch.&#151;The parish contains also the townships of Claife and Satterthwaite, and comprises 19, 252 acres. Real property, &#163;13, 219. Pop. in 1851, 2, 283; in 1861, 2, 081. Houses, 415. The property, in many parts, is subdivided. Much of the land is hilly pasture. Slate and building stone are quarried; copper ore is worked; and iron ore and other useful minerals occur. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Carlisle. Value, &#163;150. * Patron, the Duchy of Lancaster. The chapelries of Satterthwaite, Brathay, and Low Wray are separate benefices. There are chapels of ease in Skelwith and Claife, and a Quakers&apos; chapel at Colthouse.&#151;The sub-district contains also part of Ulverston parish. Acres, 30, 132. Pop., 3, 599. Houses, 717. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hawkshead</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647285</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Hawkshead/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10354560</id>
   <status>Ch/CP/AP</status>
   <name>HAWKSHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10354572</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAWKSHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10354584</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HAWKSHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10354596</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAWKSHEAD AND LOW WRAY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10354602</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HAWKSHEAD AND MONK CONISTON WITH SKELWITH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546096</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAWKSHEAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
