<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>356</id>
<name>WORSLEY</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5065329000145</lat>
<lon>-2.39599963230032</lon>
<gazetteerText>WORSLEY, a village, a township, a chapelry, and a sub-district, in Eccles parish, Barton-upon-Irwell district, Lancashire. The village stands on the Bridgewater canal, and on the Manchester, Tyldesley, and Wigan railway, 6&#189; miles WNW of Manchester; and has a post-office&#8225; under Manchester, a r. station, a modern court-house for petty sessions, a literary institution, and nine schools. The township includes four other villages or hamlets; contains W., Ellenbrook, and Swinton chapelries; carries on cotton manufacture, iron-working, brick-making, and extensive coal mining; and has three churches, a school-church, several dissenting chapels, the Manchester industrial schools, a national school, and charities &#163;16. Acres, 6,240. Real property, &#163;36,315; of which &#163;5,200 are in mines, &#163;23 in iron-works, and &#163;48 in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 10,189; in 1861, 11,875. Houses, 2,232. The manor was known, at the Norman conquest, as Workedesly; belonged then to Elias de Workedesly; came to the Duke of Bridgewater; and , with W. Hall, belongs now to the Earl of Ellesmere. The Hall was built in 1840-6, after designs by Blore; is in a florid variety of the Tudor style; was visited, by Queen Victoria and Prince Albert in 1851, by the Queen again, in 1857,-by the Prince of Wales, in 1869; and commands an extensive view A memorial column to the first Earl of Ellesmere crowns an adjacent height. A splendid system of tunnel navigation, connected with the Bridgewater canal, commences in the village; had the effect, when completed, of reducing the cost of conveying coals and other heavy goods 100 per cent.; and possesses great interest to geologists, for examining the strata which it traverses.-W. chapelry was made ecclesiastically parochial in 1863. Pop., about 2,300. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;250.* Patron, the Earl of Ellesmere. The church is recent, and in the decorated English style; and has a lofty spire. There are three small dissenting chapels.&#151;The sub-district consists of W., and Clifton townships, and comprises 7,060 acres. Pop., 14,015. Houses, 2,597. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Worsley/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Worsley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633529</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41442</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10055295</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10385660</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>WORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10385702</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546503</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12747767</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>WORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>94</id>
   <name>KEARSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>96</id>
   <name>LITTLE HULTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>539</id>
   <name>TYLDESLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1005</id>
   <name>FARNWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
