<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10687</id>
<name>MELLING</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>54.1378743998036</lat>
<lon>-2.60447430254757</lon>
<gazetteerText>MELLING, a village, a township, and a parish in the district and county of Lancaster. The village stands near the Furness and Midland railway, 2 miles NNE of Hornby; and has a r. station. The township bears the name of Melling and Wrayton, and comprises 1,120 acres. Real property, &#163;1,618. Polp., 169. Houses, 35. The parish contains also the township of Hornby, which has a post office under Lancaster, and the townships of Farleton, Roeburndale, Wennington, Wray-with-Botton, and Arkholme-with-Cawood. Acres, 23,474. Real property, &#163;18,046; of which &#163;40 are in mines, and &#163;60 in quarries. Pop. in 1851,2,204; in 1861,2,013. Houses, 393. The property is subdivided. Much of the land, with Hornby Castle, belongs to John Foster, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Mauchester. Value, &#163;145.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is early perpendicular English; includes a chantry at the E end of the S aisle; has ten stained-glass windows; and was repaired in 1855. The chapelries of Hornby, Arkholme, and Wray are separate benefices. Chapels for Wesleyans and United Free Methodists are in Wray; a Roman Catholic chapel is in Hornby; and a slightly endowed school and charities &#163;67 are in Melling. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melling,_Lancashire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/MellinginLonsdale/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642781</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53298</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53301</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53295</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53302</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53299</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53296</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53297</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53300</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10373141</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MELLING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10373153</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MELLING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10373189</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>MELLING WITH WRAYTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10036</id>
   <name>CANTSFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>10686</id>
<name>MELLING</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5010140610915</lat>
<lon>-2.91096641875476</lon>
<gazetteerText>MELLING, a township-chapelry in Halsall parish, Lancashire; on the Leeds and Liverpool canal, adjacent to the river Alt, and to the East Lancashire railway, 1 mile SE of Maghull r. station, and 7 NNE of Liverpool. It has a postal letter-box under Liverpool. Acres, 2,120. Real property, &#163;5,430; of which &#163;100 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851,662; in 1861,728. Houses, 126. The chief landowners are Lord Skelmersdale, the Earl of Derby, and T. W. Blundell, Esq. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;120.* Patron, the Rector of Halsall. The church was rebuilt in 1834; is in the pointed style; and contains several handsome tablets. There are a national school, with &#163;25 a year from endowment, and a Roman Catholic school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/MellinginHalsall/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melling,_Merseyside</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642782</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41322</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10373165</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>MELLING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10373177</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MELLING</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
