<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10348</id>
<name>MUCH HOOLE</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6959531462088</lat>
<lon>-2.79581085172075</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOOLE, a village, two townships, and a parish in Preston district, Lancashire. The village is Much Hoole; stands near the river Douglas, 2&#190; miles NW of Croston r. station, and 7 SW of Preston; and has a post office under Preston.-The townships are Much Hoole and Little Hoole; the latter N of the former, and on the estnary of the Ribble. Acres of Much Hoole, 1, 701. Real property, &#163;3, 511. Pop., 708. Houses, 136. The chief landowners are Lord Lilford and the Marquis de Rothwell. Acres of Little Hoole, 1, 222; of which 70 are water. Real property, &#163;2, 533. Pop., 424. Houses, 72. A large cotton factory is here.&#151;The parish consists of the two townships. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;280. Patron, T. B. Addison, Esq. The church was originally a chapel of ease to Croston; is a plain edifice, with a low tower; and was enlarged in 1864. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and some small charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Hoole/</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/MuchHoole/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Much_Hoole</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642056</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53086</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53087</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53088</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10355904</id>
   <status>CP/Ch/AP</status>
   <name>HOOLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10355916</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HOOLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10355930</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>MUCH HOOLE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24592</id>
<name>HOOLEY HILL</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4676334055624</lat>
<lon>-2.11299164430397</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOOLEY-HILL, a village in Audenshaw division of Ashton-under-Lyne parish, Lancashire; near the boundary with Cheshire and the Ashton and Stockport railway, 2 miles SSW of Ashton-under-Lyne. It has a post office under Manchester. Pop., 1, 772. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hooley_Hill_railway_station</link>
</links>
</place>
<place>
<id>10347</id>
<name>LITTLE HOOLE</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.7079015612695</lat>
<lon>-2.79002921334307</lon>
<gazetteerText>Hoole, Little, and Hoole, Much, 2 townships, Hoole par., N. Lancashire - L. H., 1223 ac. (22 water), pop. 440; M. H., 1776 ac. (30 water), pop. 581. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/LittleHoole/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7295954</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53088</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10355928</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>LITTLE HOOLE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
