<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1274</id>
<name>ASTLEY BRIDGE</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6008539565288</lat>
<lon>-2.43071915272528</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASTLEY-BRIDGE, a village and a chapelry in Bolton-le-Moors parish, Lancashire. The village is partly in the township of Sharples; stands near the Bolton and Blackburn railway, 3 miles N of Bolton; and has a post office&#8224; under Bolton. The chapelry was constituted in 1844. Rated property, &#163;9,729. Pop., 3,210. Houses, 670. The property is subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;150. Patrons, the Crown and the Bishop alternately. The church was built in 1848. There are Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, and national and British schools. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10043050</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>ASTLEY BRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10136969</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>ASTLEY BRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332357</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASTLEY BRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332369</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>ASTLEY BRIDGE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>9845</id>
<name>ASTLEY</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.486310056249</lat>
<lon>-2.45376152008101</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASTLEY, or East Leigh, a township-chapelry in Leigh parish, Lancashire; near the Bridgewater canal and the Manchester and Liverpool railway, 8&#189; miles W of Manchester. It has a station on the railway, and a post office under Manchester. Acres, 2,628. Real property, &#163;11,967,-of which &#163;5,000 are in mines. Pop., 2,109. Houses, 437. There are collieries and a large cotton mill. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;250.* Patron, the Vicar of Leigh. The church is modern, and has been thrice enlarged There are a Wesleyan chapel, a free grammar school, a national school, and some small charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656876</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Astley/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Astley,_Greater_Manchester</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41365</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10332333</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>ASTLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332345</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASTLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
