<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>991</id>
<name>OLDHAM</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5409692411618</lat>
<lon>-2.09695038596462</lon>
<gazetteerText>Oldham, parl. and mun. bor., market town, and township, Prestwich par., SE. Lancashire, on river Medlock, 6 miles NE. of Manchester and 190 miles from London by rail - mun. bor. and township, 4730 ac., pop. 111,343; parl. bor. (partly in Ashton under Lyne par.), 12,310 ac., pop. 152,513; 5 Banks, 7 newspapers. Market-day, Saturday. Oldham is one of England&apos;s great modern centres of manufacture. In 1760 it contained only about 60 dwellings, mostly thatched huts. Its rapid progress is due chiefly to its proximity to the Lancashire coal fields. These coal fields give employment to a considerable section of the population. The great majority of the people, however, are engaged in the staple mfrs. with which the name of Oldham is familiarly associated. The factories are said to number 250, and it is estimated that there are about 1,000,000 spinning spindles and 650,000 twining spindles in the town and its neighbourhood. The goods produced are principally fustians, velveteens, velvets, silks, cotton cords and yarns, sheetings, shirtings, drills, sateens, &amp;C. Works for the mfr. of weaving machinery are very extensive, one especially employing between 6000 and 7000 hands. Foundries and engine works show great industrial activity, and during recent years a considerable and increasing trade has been done in the mfr. of gas metres. There are about 70 churches and chapels, and numerous institutions and charities, but the public buildings as a rule do not call for special remark. Oldham was enfranchised by the Reform Bill of 1832, and received its charter of incorporation in 1849. It returns 2 members to Parliament. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Oldham/</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Oldham</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oldham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641022</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53007</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10004846</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374200</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ST BARNABAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12746714</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>OLDHAM WEST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12780734</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374169</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545274</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM CENTRAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545250</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM EAST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186778</id>
   <status>MB/CB</status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374194</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374261</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10344669</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ST JOHN WERNETH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12834240</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374250</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ST MARY WITH ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374157</id>
   <status>Tn/Ch/CP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12744304</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12746702</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>OLDHAM EAST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10216163</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10043827</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739904</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>OLDHAM EAST AND SADDLEWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545262</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM SOUTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10566230</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM ABOVE TOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10566241</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM BELOW TOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578085</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374170</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374285</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374182</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ST AMBROSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578073</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371892</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LOWER MOOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374224</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ST CHAD LIMESIDE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10374248</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLDHAM ST JAMES</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>501</id>
   <name>ROYTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>501</id>
<name>ROYTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5685577373544</lat>
<lon>-2.12228417036304</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROYTON, a large village, a township-chapelry, and a sub-district, in Oldham district, Lancashire. The village stands at the terminus of the Manchester, Oldham, and Royton railway, near the junction with it of the Oldham and Rochdale railway, 2 miles N N W of Oldham; is a place of some antiquity and note; numbers among its natives the mathematicians Butterworth and Kay, and the botanist Mellor; carries on industry inlarge cotton factories; and has a post-office under Oldham, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, another r. station at R. r. junction, a police station, a public-bath, a church, three dissenting chapels, a national school, and several libraries, improvement societies, and other insituations. The chapelry comprises 1, 352 acres, and is in Prestwich parish, and within Oldham borough. Real property, &#163;20, 566; of which &#163;628 are in mines, and &#163;220 in gas-works. Pop. in 1851, 6, 974; in 1861, 7, 493. Houses, 1, 562. The property is not much divided. R. Hall was given, by Edward II., to Sir John de by ron; belongs now, to Sir J. Radcliffe, Bart., the chief landed proprietor; and has been divided into tenements. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Rector of Prestwich.&#151;The sub-district contains also the township of Thornham, and comprises 3, 350 acres. Pop. in 1851, 8, 484; in 1861, 9, 520. Houses, 1, 941. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Royton/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639015</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53009</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075233</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>ROYTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10088641</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>ROYTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377353</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>ROYTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377365</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROYTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377377</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROYTON ST ANNE LONGSIGHT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545213</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ROYTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739011</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>LANCASHIRE ROYTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739590</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>OLDHAM WEST AND ROYTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739606</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>OLDHAM CENTRAL AND ROYTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741169</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>HEYWOOD AND ROYTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>26551</id>
<name>OLDHAMS</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6061964018634</lat>
<lon>-2.44437684210063</lon>
<gazetteerText>OLDHAMS, a village in Sharples township, Bolton-le-Moors parish, Lancashire; 4&#188; miles E of Chorley. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
<place>
<id>461</id>
<name>PRESTWICH</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5322121833484</lat>
<lon>-2.27079469905653</lon>
<gazetteerText>PRESTWICH, a small town, a township, and a sub-district, in Manchester district, and a parish partly alsoin Oldham and Bury districts, Lancashire. The town stands 1&#188; mile E N E of the river Irwell, 1&#189; E by N of Clifton-Junction r. station, and 4 N N W of Manchester; contains numerous good residences; and has a post-office &amp; under Manchester, two churches, two Wesleyan chapels, a Jewish cemetery, a national school, a British school, a workhouse, the Lancashire lunatic asylum, and charities &#163;164. St. Bartholomew&apos;s church is later English; consists of nave, aisles, two terminal chapels, and a chancel, with a tower 85 feethigh; and contains a fine reredos erected in 1865, and several handsome monuments. St. Margaret&apos;s church was founded in 1848, by the Duchess of Cambridge. One of the Wesleyan chapels was built in 1867 The national school was built in 1866, at a cost of about &#163;2, 800; and is in the early English style, with high-pitched roof and brick tower. The lunatic asylum stands in the centre of extensive grounds; is a range of structures in brick, with stone facings; underwent enlargement about 1862; and has accommodation for about 1,000 patients. The workhouse is one of three for Manchester district; and, at the census of 1861, had 66 in-mates. The township comprises 1, 906 acres. Real property, &#163;21, 725. Pop. in 1851, 4,096; in 1861, 5, 288. Houses, 973.&#151;The sub-district contains also Great Heaton and Little Heaton townships, and comprises 3, 281acres. Pop. in 1851, 5,046; in 1861, 6, 285. Houses, 1, 168. The parish contains also the townships of Pilkington, Oldham, Chadderton, Tonge, Alkrington, Royton, and Crompton; and is ecclesiastically cut into thesections of Prestwich, Hollinwood, Ringley, Prestolee, Oldham, St. Mary, O., St. Peter, O., St. James, Chadderton, St. John, C., St. Matthew, Coldhurst, East Crompton, Glodwick, Werneth, Waterhead, Royton, Shaw, Unsworth, and Tonge-with-Alkrington. Acres, 21, 625. Pop. in 1851, 94, 470; in 1861, 117, 961. Houses, 23,039. The living of Prestwich is a rectory united with the chapelry of St. Margaret, and all the other livings are p.curacies, in the diocese of Manchester. Value of therectory, &#163;1, 230.* Patron, the Earl of Wilton. The other livings are noticed in the articles on their own several localities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Prestwich/</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Prestwich</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53002</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prestwich</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639897</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53009</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53005</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53001</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53003</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53007</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53006</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53008</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53010</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53004</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10005528</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10029107</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10062937</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10074496</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376520</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376531</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376543</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PRESTWICH ST GABRIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376555</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PRESTWICH ST HILDA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376567</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PRESTWICH ST MARGARET HOLYROOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546035</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578802</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578814</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PRESTWICH AND MIDDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12751916</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>SOUTH EAST LANCASHIRE PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12832813</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
