<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20380</id>
<name>NEWCHURCH IN ROSSENDALE</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6975500305729</lat>
<lon>-2.25144917069646</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWCHURCH-IN-ROSSENDALE, a village and a chapelry in Whalley parish, Lancashire. The village stands on an eminence, adjacent to the Manchester, Bury, and Bacup railway, 2&#189; miles W S W of Bacup; and has a station on the railway and a post-office&#8225; under Manchester, both of the name of Newchurch, and a fair on the last Monday of June. The chapelry contains also the villages of Clough-Fold, Tunstead, Waterfoot, Booth-Fold, and Whitwell-Vale. Acres, 9, 650. Rated property, &#163;33, 374. Pop., 24, 413. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to the Duke of Buccleuch. Thistle-Mount, Springfield, Ashlands, Clough-fold, Edgeside, and Leabank, are chief residences. Coal, freestone, and slate abound; stone is quarried; and thecotton and woollen manufactures are largely carried on. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;500.* Patron, the Vicar of Whalley. The church was rebuilt in 1826, on the site of a previous church of1512; is in the Tudor style; consists of nave and aisles, with an embattled tower; has very old pews, and a carved Caen stone pulpit of 1854; and contains 1, 200 sittings. The rectory house was built in 1852; and is a handsome edifice, in the Tudor style. Two other churches are in Tunstead and Waterfoot; chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, Primitive Methodists, and Unitarians, national schools, and an endowed grammar-school, are in Newchurch; a Baptist chapel is in Clough-Fold; and a mechanics&apos; institution is in Whitwell-Vale The Wesleyan chapel was built in 1804, and contains nearly 500sittings. The Unitarian chapel was rebuilt in 1865, at a cost of &#163;2, 200; and is in the pointed style. The grammar-school was built and endowed in 1711, by Mr. John Kershaw. The Baptist chapel in Clough-Folddates from 1700; had Dr. Isaac Watts, at one time, as itsminister; and was enlarged in 1838, and re-enlarged in 1853 (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641664</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53151</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10373918</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>NEWCHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10373931</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWCHURCH IN ROSSENDALE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10373943</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWCHURCH ST NICHOLAS WITH ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
