<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>21086</id>
<name>SPOTLAND</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6221669196678</lat>
<lon>-2.18144636569365</lon>
<gazetteerText>SPOTLAND, a township and a chapelry in Rochdale parish, Lancashire. The township is partly within Rochdale borough; comprises parts of the valleys of the Roach, the Spodden, the Nadin, and the Irwell; is cut into three divisions,-S.-Nearer-Side, containing 2 hamlets,-S.-Further-Side, containing 6 hamlets,-and Whitworth, containing 4 hamlets; exhibits much picturesque scenery; carries on coal mining, slate and freestone quarrying, and extensive cotton, baize, and flannel manufacture; and has several post-offices under Rochdale, a literary institution, two churches, five dissenting chapels, the Rochdale workhouse, and some charities. Acres, 4,518. Real property, &#163;118,074; of which &#163;18,099 are in mines, &#163;2,501 in quarries, and &#163;93 in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 23,476; in 1861, 30,378. Houses, 5,994. The chief villages are Whitworth, Bridge-Mill, Shawforth, Facit, Bagslate, Blackpits, and Shawclough; and the old-seats are Oakenrod, Chadwick, Greave, and Wolstenholm,- the last now a farmhouse.&#151;The chapelry comprises the tract around Spotland-Bridge; was constituted in 1844, and curtailed prior to 1868; and has a post-office, of the name of S.-Bridge, under Rochdale. Pop. in 1861, within the original limits, 11,016; within the curtailed limits, 8,354. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;500.* Patron, the Vicar of Rochdale. The church is ancient. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Spotland/</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53029</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10380595</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>SPOTLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10380601</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SPOTLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545742</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SPOTLAND AND NORDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10565388</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SPOTLAND NEARER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
