<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>659</id>
<name>BLACKROD</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5910145086727</lat>
<lon>-2.58067649003227</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLACKROD, a village and a township-chapelry in Bolton-le-Moors parish, Lancashire. The village stands on elevated ground near the river Douglas and the Bolton and Preston railway, 4&#189; miles SSE of Chorley: and it has a joint station with Horwich on the railway, and a post office of its own under Chorley. Its site is supposed to have been occupied by the Roman station Coccium, on Watling-street; and many Roman relics have been found. The chapelry comprises 2,367 acres. Real property, &#163;14,264; of which &#163;7,711 are in mines. Pop., 2,911. Houses, 546. The property is not much divided. The inhabitants are chiefly cotton-spinners and colliers. A fire in a colliery here was extinguished by drawing into it the river Douglas. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, the Vicar of Bolton. The church is good; and there is a Wesleyan chapel. A free grammar school has &#163;140 a year, besides sums for three exhibitions at Pembroke college, Cambridge; and other charities have &#163;104. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Blackrod/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655454</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blackrod</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53053</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10029478</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BLACKROD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109462</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BLACKROD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10342272</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>BLACKROD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10342284</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLACKROD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
