<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>660</id>
<name>FORMBY</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5668535553482</lat>
<lon>-3.07791677031485</lon>
<gazetteerText>FORMBY, a village, a township, and two chapelries in Walton-on-the-Hill parish, and a sub-district in Ormskirk district, Lancashire. The village stands on the coast, adjacent to the Liverpool and Southport railway, near the river Alt, 7&#189; miles W of Ormskirk; was formerly a market-town; and has a station with telegraph on the railway, and a post office under Liverpool. -The township includes also the hamlets of Ainsdale and Raven-Meols. Acres, 15, 264; of which 8, 560 are water. Real property, &#163;7, 531. Pop. in 1851, 1, 594; in 1861, 1, 780. Houses, 328. The increase of pop. arose from the erection of houses for persons from Liverpool. The property is divided among a few. Formby Hall is the seat of the Rev. L. Formby. A headland or projection, 3 miles SW by W of the village, bears the name of Form-by Point. Two beacons and a red tower are on the coast, and the floating light put up in 1834, at the Victoria or New Formby channel, on a line with the Crossby or main channel into the Mersey, is 3 miles WSW of the red tower. The Old Formby channel is nearer the shore, and not much used.-The two chapelries are St. Peter and St. Luke; and are jointly conterminate with the township. The livings are p. curacies in the diocese of Chester. Value of St. Peter, &#163;124;* of St. Luke, &#163;50.* Patron of the former, the Rector of Walton; of the latter, Dr. R. Formby. St. Peter&apos;s church is a plain brick building, with cupola. St. Luke&apos;s is neat and recent. A Roman Catholic chapel, in the Romanesque style, after designs by Mr. Clutton, of brick, with stone dressings, was built in 1864, at a cost of &#163;3, 000. Marsh&apos;s schools have &#163;34 from endowment; and other charities &#163;11.&#151;The sub-district contains also Birkdale township and Altcar parish. Acres, 25, 218. Pop., 3, 606. Houses, 647. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Formby/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formby</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649198</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41288</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10109486</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>FORMBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351900</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>FORMBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351911</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FORMBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351935</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FORMBY HOLY TRINITY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351947</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FORMBY ST LUKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545614</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FORMBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
