<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20823</id>
<name>CHEETHAM HILL</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5123845851394</lat>
<lon>-2.24431916867028</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHEETHAM, a village, a township, a sub-district, and two chapelries in Manchester parish, Lancashire. The village bears the name of Cheetham Hill; stands within Manchester borough, 2&#189; miles NNW of the centre of Manchester; and has a post office&#8225; under Manchester. The township includes the village; is all suburban to Manchester; contains numerous villas of Manchester merchants and manufacturers; and was long the residence of the ancient family of Chetham. Acres, 919. Real property, &#163;77, 917. Pop., 17, 446. Houses, 3, 168. -The sub-district contains also the township of Crumpsall. Acres, 1, 652. Pop., 21, 731. Houses, 3, 882. The chapelries are St. Luke-Cheetham and St. Mark-Cheetham; and were constituted in 1840 and 1846. Pop., 4, 719 and 2, 377. Houses, 843 and 478. The livings are rectories in the diocese of Manchester. Value of St. Luke, &#163;790; of St. Mark, &#163;351. Patrons of St. Luke, Trustees; of St. Mark, the Dean and Chapter of Manchester. The churches of both are good. There are two chapels for Independents and two for Wesleyans; and one of the latter, in Waterloo-road, is an edifice in the early English style, built in 1862. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Cheetham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6691216</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41413</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10344761</id>
   <status>CP/Ch/Tn</status>
   <name>CHEETHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10344773</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHEETHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10344785</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHEETHAM ST JOHN THE EVANGELIST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10344797</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHEETHAM ST SAVIOUR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10344803</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHEETHAM HILL ST LUKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10344815</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHEETHAM HILL ST MARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546023</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHEETHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10571339</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHEETHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12755351</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>MANCHESTER CHEETHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
