<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>243</id>
<name>LIVERPOOL</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4060811623629</lat>
<lon>-2.92301510796264</lon>
<gazetteerText>Liverpool, parl. and mun. bor., city, seaport, and par., SW. Lancashire, on estuary of river Mersey, 31 m. W. of Manchester and 201 m. NW. of London by rail - par., 1715 ac. land and 755 water, pop. 210,164; mun. bor., 5210 ac., pop. 552,508; parl. bor., pop. 601,050. Markets, daily. Lyrpoole and Litherpoole were ancient names ef this celebrated seaport, these designations being supposed to be derived from the Celtic Llerpwll, the &quot;place on the pool.&quot; It is very doubtful whether the town existed at the time of the Conquest. Camden (1551-1623) refers to it as being more famous for its beauty and populousness than for its antiquity. In 1172 the military operations in Ireland gave it great importance as a convenient point of embarkation for troops. With this exception the early history of Liverpool contains little that is interesting or important. The first charter was granted in 1173 by Henry II.; in 1207 the charter was confirmed by King John, and 20 years later the town was constituted a free borough by Henry III. During the reign of Elizabeth a quay and breakwater were erected, the latter being intended to act as a winter protection for shipping. In 1561 the merchants of the port had only 12 ships. The ship-money levied by Charles I. amounted to &#163;25. At the time of the Civil War Liverpool was held by the Parliamentarians, and in 1644 was besieged and taken by Prince Rupert; but in a brief time it again fell into the hands of the Parliament. It is modern enterprise, however, that has literally created and expanded the historical distinction of the city. From the latter part of the 18th century its progress in mercantile and maritime affairs is without a parallel, and justly entitles it to its position in the first rank of British seaports. Commercial intercourse is maintained with every part of the world. Several lines of splendid steamships keep up regular communication with New York; others with Boston, Philadelphia, New Orleans, Halifax, the Canadian ports, and the East and West Indies. (For shipping statistics, see Appendix.) Extending along both shores of the Mersey are immense lines of docks, which form the principal feature of the city. On the Liverpool shore they cover fully 6 miles, and on the Cheshire shore, at Birkenhead, 2 miles; the water area of the docks on the Liverpool side being 333&#189; ac., with nearly 23 miles of quay space; on the Cheshire side the water area is 164&#189; ac., with 9&#189; miles of quay space; total water area 498 ac., quay space 30&#189; miles. There are also 22 graving docks, and in connection with the docks generally there is a double line of railway over 5 miles in length N. to S. The famous landing stage of Liverpool is an immense structure, 2063 ft. long and 80 ft. broad, supported by floating pontoons, which rise and fall with the tide. Large vessels may proceed up the Mersey as far as the mouth of the Irwell, 35 miles above Liverpool; 5 great lines of railway now enter the city; but by the completion of the Mersey Tunnel, a formidable undertaking, begun in 1872, these facilities have been very materially increased. Inland water communication is kept up with Yorkshire and all parts of Lancashire, chiefly by the Leeds and Liverpool Canal. The city is justly celebrated for its fine buildings. The Town Hall (1754) is the oldest and the most interesting; but the finest building, from an architectural point of view, is St George&apos;s Hall (1854), a superb edifice, which cost &#163;250,000. The Exchange and the Free Library and Museum are likewise worthy of notice. Of the public parks the largest is Sefton Park (400 ac.), the others being Princess Park, Wavertree Park, Newsham Park, Sheil Park, and Stanley Park. There are 11 cemeteries. At the head of the educational institutions stands University College (affiliated to the Victoria University), opened by Lord Derby in 1882; and among middle-class schools are the Royal Institution School, Collegiate Institution, and Liverpool Institute High School. Cotton is the staple of the imports of Liverpool, which otherwise include goods from all parts of the world. Recently an enormous trade has arisen through the importation of provisions, including live stock, from America and the colonies. The port, too, is the principal place in the kingdom for the departure of emigrants. Mfrs. are not extensive. Shipbuilding has fallen off greatly owing to the competition at the Clyde and in the north of England. The mfrs. of engines for marine navigation, however, have a worldwide renown. Sugar refining, iron and brass founding, ropemaking, brewing, chemical works, iron chain cable and anchor making, and the distilling of tar and turpentine, form other leading industries. A large source of trade exists in the produce of neighbouring collieries. Liverpool was created a diocese in 1880, at which time it was transformed into a city by royal charter. Liverpool returns 9 members to Parliament (9 divisions - viz., Kirkdale, Walton, Everton, West Derby, Scotland, Exchange, Abercromby, East Toxteth, and West Toxteth, 1 member for each division); its representation was I increased from 3 to 9 members in 1885, when its i parliamentary limits were extended so as to include the &apos; remainder of Toxteth Park par., additional parts of Walton on the Hill and West Derby pars., and part of Wavertree township, Childwall par. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Liverpool/</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Liverpool</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liverpool</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644210</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41369</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41372</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41374</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41376</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41377</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41375</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41378</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41370</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41371</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41373</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10370840</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL EDGE LANE ST MARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370863</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL HOLY TRINITY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371466</id>
   <status>EExP/EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10004822</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371272</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST LUKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10027317</id>
   <status>MB/CB</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12755508</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL SCOTLAND EXCHANGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10134420</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370802</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ALL SOULS SPRINGWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371510</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST SILAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371442</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST MATTHIAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371235</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST JAMES THE LESS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370887</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL NORRIS GREEN ST CHRISTOPHER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545936</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EXCHANGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12743610</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12832771</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371533</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST SIMON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10576428</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL NORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371417</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST MARY MAGDALENE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371454</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371284</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST MARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371478</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST PETER WITH ST AMBROSE AND ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371090</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST BARTHOLOMEW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371570</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST TITUS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12757116</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL WAVERTREE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371053</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST ANNE WITH ST STEPHEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12738020</id>
   <status>PBDivCon/BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL EXCHANGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12746313</id>
   <status>BCon/PBDivCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL SCOTLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12746301</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL RIVERSIDE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12746283</id>
   <status>PBDivCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL EAST TOXTETH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370656</id>
   <status>CP/Ch/AP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10567385</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371247</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370875</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL NORRIS GREEN CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10105821</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12752386</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL TOXTETH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12756057</id>
   <status>PBDivCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL WEST TOXTETH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12749557</id>
   <status>PBDivCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ABERCROMBIE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371193</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST DAVID</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371491</id>
   <status>EP/EExP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST PHILIP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371181</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST COLUMBA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10067169</id>
   <status>RegD/PLPar</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371508</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST SAVIOUR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371521</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST SILAS WITH ST COLUMBA AND ST SIMON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12749570</id>
   <status>PBDivCon/BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL KIRKDALE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12411364</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371545</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST STEPHEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370772</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370796</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10576416</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370942</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371132</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST BRIDE WITH ST SAVIOUR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371120</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST BRIDE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370917</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL PRINCES PARK ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10576430</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL SOUTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10567002</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371612</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL STANLEY ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371430</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST MATTHEW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370899</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL OUR LADY AND ST NICHOLAS WITH ST ANNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370978</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST ANNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371557</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST STEPHEN WITH ST CATHERINE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370851</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL HOLY INNOCENTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371144</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST CATHERINE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371259</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST JOHN THE EVANGELIST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12780710</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370930</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST ALBAN BEVINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371429</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST MARTIN IN THE FIELDS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371065</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST BARNABAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370929</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST AIDAN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>354</id>
   <name>PRESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>363</id>
   <name>CHESTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>645</id>
   <name>WIGAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>658</id>
   <name>WARRINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>823</id>
   <name>BARROW IN FURNESS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>916</id>
   <name>SOUTHPORT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>990</id>
   <name>BLACKPOOL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1051</id>
   <name>LANCASTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1137</id>
   <name>WREXHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1201</id>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>21277</id>
<name>VAUXHALL</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.419520832849</lat>
<lon>-2.99171298338632</lon>
<gazetteerText>VAUXHALL, a chapelry in Liverpool parish, Lancashire; within Liverpool borough. It was constituted in 1847: and its Post town is Liverpool. Pop. in 1861, 8,512. Houses, 1,346. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, alternately the Crown and the Bishop. See Liverpool. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10370826</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ALL SOULS</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>10206</id>
<name>EVERTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4243098058564</lat>
<lon>-2.95950107891903</lon>
<gazetteerText>EVERTON, a suburban township, seven chapelries, and a sub-district, in Walton-on-the-Hill parish, West Derby district, Lancashire. The township is suburban to Liverpool; lies within Liverpool borough, on the NE side of the town, contiguous to Kirkdale; and has a post office&#8225; under Liverpool, 1&#189; mile distant from the Liverpool head-office. It had a village older than Liverpool, situated on an eminence, commanding an extensive view over the Mersey to Wales and the Irish channel; but it takes its present character from the growth and prosperity of Liverpool; has long been a favourite residence of many merchants; and comprises numerous airy streets and numerous elegant villas. It contains the cottage occupied by Prince Rupert in 1644; a mansion, called St. Domingo, built with money accruing from a French prize ship; the workhouse of West Derby district; the Liverpol hospital for infections diseases, about to be rebuilt in 186 9; the Liverpool collegiate institution; several national or other public schools; a public cemetery, formed in 1825; St. George&apos;s church, built in 1814, at a cost of &#163;12, 000; four churches built between 1829 and 1857; St. Saviour&apos;s church, in the Lombardic style, at a cost of &#163;5, 400, built in 1866; Emmanuel church, of very costly character, built in 1867; two Scotch Presbyterian chapels, built in 1863 and 1866; several English dissenting chapels; and a Roman Catholic church, designated St. Edward&apos;s college church, built in 1859 to the extent of three eastern chapels, measuring internally 280 feet in length, possessing fine features of the medi&#230;val style of architecture, and designed as part of an intended cathedral. Acres of the township, 700. Real property, &#163;162, 758; of which &#163;742 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 25, 883; in 1861, 54, 848. Houses, 9, 288. -The chapelries are St. George, St. Augustine, St. Chrysostom, St. Peter, Christchurch, St. Saviour, and Emmanuel. The living of St. Chrysostom is a vicarage, and the other livings are p. curacies, in the diocese of Chester. Value of St. George and St. Augustine, each &#163;300; of St. Chrysostom, &#163;400; of the others, not reported. Patron of Christchurch, T. B. Horsfall, Esq.; of Emmanuel, I - D. Anderson, Esq.; of St. Peter, not reported; of the others, Trustees. -The sub-district includes also the township of Kirkdale. Acres, 1,832. Pop., 70, 983. Houses, 11, 830. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Everton/</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41282</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10350920</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>EVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10350955</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10350979</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10350980</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON EMMANUEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10350992</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST AMBROSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351005</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST AMBROSE WITH ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351017</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST AMBROSE WITH ST TIMOTHY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351030</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST AUGUSTINE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351042</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST BENEDICT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351066</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST CHAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351080</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST CHAD WITH CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351091</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST CHRYSOSTOM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351108</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST CUTHBERT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351121</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST JOHN THE EVANGELIST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351157</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351169</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST POLYCARP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351170</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST SAVIOUR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351182</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST SAVIOUR WITH ST CUTHBERT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10351224</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERTON ST TIMOTHY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546310</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NORTH EVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546321</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOUTH EVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10562776</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12749569</id>
   <status>PBDivCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL EVERTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>21406</id>
<name>EDGE HILL</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4054579113325</lat>
<lon>-2.95227096442306</lon>
<gazetteerText>EDGE-HILL, a suburb and five chapelries in West Derby district, Lancashire. The suburb adjoins the E side of Liverpool; lies on the Liverpool and Manchester railway; includes a pleasant eminence near the road to Prescot; and has a station on the railway, and a post office&#8224; under Liverpool. The chapelries are St. Mary, St. Stephen, St. Jude, St. Timothy, and St. Catherine: the two last constituted in 1862 and 1863. The first four are p. curacies, and St.is a vicarage, in the diocese of Chester. Value of St. M. and St. J., each &#163;300; of St. S., &#163;300;* of St. T., &#163;200; of St. C., &#163;230. Patron of St. M., J. Stewart, Esq.; of St. S., St. J., and St. C., Trustees; of St. T., not reported. The five churches are modern; the newest built in 1863. See Liverpool. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10348936</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EDGE HILL ST CATHERINE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10348948</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EDGE HILL ST CYPRIAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10348961</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EDGE HILL ST DUNSTAN EARLE ROAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10349000</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EDGE HILL ST JUDE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10349023</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EDGE HILL ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10349059</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EDGE HILL ST NATHANIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10349060</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL ST STEPHEN AND GROVE STREET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12754024</id>
   <status>PBDivCon/BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL EDGE HILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1316</id>
<name>GARSTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3609316697989</lat>
<lon>-2.90873592296335</lon>
<gazetteerText>GARSTON, a small town, a township, and a chapelry, in Childwall parish, Lancashire. The town stands on the Mersey, and on the Warrington, Garston, and Liverpool railway, 6 miles SE of Liverpool; was once noted for extensive salt-works; is now a sub-port to Liverpool, with new docks; and has a railway station with telegraph, and a post office&#8225; under Liverpool. -The township includes also Aigburth, a suburb of Liverpool. Acres, 3, 293; of which 1, 665 are water. Real property, &#163;31, 643. Pop. in 1851, 2, 756; in 1861, 4, 720. Houses, 763.&#151;The chapelry includes only the eastern part of the township; excludes Aigburth; and was constituted in 1828. Pop., 2, 016. Houses, 356. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;138.* Patron, Richard Watt, Esq. The church is very good; and there are two dissenting chapels, Church schools, and charities &#163;12. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Garston/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648827</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41308</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10167360</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>GARSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221377</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>GARSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10352400</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>GARSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10352460</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GARSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12755340</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL GARSTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25129</id>
<name>STANLEY</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4146708303118</lat>
<lon>-2.92388669150267</lon>
<gazetteerText>STANLEY, a chapelry in West Derby parish, Lancashire; suburban to Liverpool, and 1&#189; mile NNE of Edgehill r. station. It contains Liverpool cattle-market and Old Swan; the latter of which has a post-office under Liverpool. The statistics are returned with the parish. The manor belongs to the Marquis of Salisbury. There are extensive borax works. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;150. Patron, the Rev. T. Gardner. The church is in plain Grecian style. There are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Roman Catholics. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10371624</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STANLEY ST ANN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>11018</id>
<name>WAVERTREE</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3975806610845</lat>
<lon>-2.90690293655814</lon>
<gazetteerText>WAVERTREE, a village, a township, two chapelries, and a sub-district, in Childwall parish and West Derby district, Lancashire. The village stands 1&#189; mile SE of Edgehill r. station, and 3 ESE of Liverpool; has been much improved under a local board of health; is a place of resort for invalids; and has a post-office&#8225; under Liverpool, a police station, public baths, and a reading room. -The township comprises 1,796 acres. Real property, &#163;36,743; of which &#163;66 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 4,011; in 1861, 5,392. Houses, 910. The manor belongs to the Marquis of Salisbury. There are numerous good residences, two churches, a free church of 1869, two dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, two national schools, two large breweries, and an extensive ropery. -The two chapelries are Holy Trinity and St. Mary; and the former is a p. curacy, the latter a rectory, in the diocese of Chester. Value of each, &#163;300. Patron of the former, the Vicar of Childwall; of the latter, the Bishop of Chester.&#151;The sub-district contains 4 townships. Acres, 7,448. Pop. in 1851, 7,415; in 1861, 10,845. Houses, 1,792. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Wavertree/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634646</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41304</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10136672</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WAVERTREE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10179130</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WAVERTREE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384588</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>WAVERTREE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384590</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WAVERTREE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384606</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WAVERTREE ST BRIDGET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384618</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WAVERTREE ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10384620</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WAVERTREE ST THOMAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546280</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WAVERTREE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12746337</id>
   <status>PBDivCon/BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL WAVERTREE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1201</id>
<name>WEST DERBY</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4237515227517</lat>
<lon>-2.91590902965515</lon>
<gazetteerText>West Derby.-- par. and local government district, SW. Lancashire - par. (partly within the bor. of Liverpool), 6203 ac., pop. 101,162; dist., 5561 ac., pop. 33,614; the sta. is 4 miles NW. of Central Station, Liverpool; the par. was, until 1847, part of Walton on the Hill par. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/WestDerby</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Derby</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/WestDerby/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634455</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41281</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41279</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10027408</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10043785</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10081713</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10112606</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10185609</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347464</id>
   <status>AP/CP/Ch</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347555</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347622</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347646</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY THE GOOD SHEPHERD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347658</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY RURAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347701</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY ST JAMES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347774</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY ST LUKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347798</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST DERBY ST NATHANIEL WINDSOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546333</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEST DERBY EASTERN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546345</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEST DERBY WESTERN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10582313</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12749582</id>
   <status>PBDivCon/BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12823617</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEST DERBY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3280</id>
   <name>LISCARD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1292</id>
   <name>TOXTETH PARK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>249</id>
   <name>BIRKENHEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1215</id>
   <name>WIRRAL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1230</id>
   <name>WALTON ON THE HILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1157</id>
   <name>HOYLAKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10147</id>
   <name>ECCLESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>362</id>
   <name>GREAT CROSBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1165</id>
   <name>BEBINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>93</id>
   <name>HUYTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>21279</id>
<name>KENSINGTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4117377553448</lat>
<lon>-2.95391587422629</lon>
<gazetteerText>Kensington, eccl. dist., West Derby par., SW. Lancashire, on NE. side of Liverpool, pop. 6406. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10370838</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL CHRIST CHURCH KENSINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25193</id>
<name>BROADGREEN</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4067649887526</lat>
<lon>-2.89964404388258</lon>
<gazetteerText>BROADGREEN, a village on the Liverpool and St. Helen&apos;s railway, Lancashire; 4&#189; miles E by N of Liverpool. It has a station on the railway, and a post office under Liverpool. It is wholly modern, and includes several villas. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadgreen</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>12748050</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>LIVERPOOL BROADGREEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
