<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10749</id>
<name>PENDLETON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4912253120305</lat>
<lon>-2.2977569860404</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENDLETON, a suburban town, a township, a chapelry, and a sub-district, in Salford district, Lancashire. The town is suburban to Manchester; lies on the Manchester and Bolton railway, near Peel Park, contiguousto the W side of Salford, 2 miles W N W of Manchester:contains very many genteel residences; carries on industry in cotton and flax mills, and in dye and print-works; and has a railway-station with telegraph, a post-office, &#8225;under Manchester, a townhall, and numerous places of worship, and public schools. The townhall was built in 1866, at a cost of about &#163;9,000; is in the Italian style, with assimilation to French; and contains an assembly-room, 85 feet long, 39&#189; feet wide, and 30 feet high. The churches are St. Thomas&apos;, rebuilt in 1831, and Sts. Paul, George, James, Anne, and Luke, built in 1856-65 atcosts of &#163;5,000, &#163;5,000, &#163;, 8, 500, &#163;1, 500, and &#163;6, 500. A New Connexion Methodist chapel was built in 1863, at a cost of &#163;2, 500; and has a Corinthian portico. Independent school-rooms were erected in 1865, at a cost of &#163;2, 400; are in the geometric pointed style; and includea central hall, 60 feet long and 40 feet wide. Very handsome Wesleyan schools were erected in 1863, at a cost of &#163;3, 500. The township comprises 1, 720 acres; and is in the parish of Eccles, and the borough of Salford. Real property, &#163;85,080; of which &#163;2, 186 are in mines, and &#163;1,024 in ironworks. Pop. in 1851, 14, 244; in 1861, 20, 900. Houses, 3, 906. Coal exists in seams of 7 feetthick and under, and is largely worked. The chapelryincludes but a portion of the township, and was constituted in 1860. Pop. in 1861, 5, 361. Houses, 984. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;344. Patron, the Vicar of Eccles. The sub-districtcomprises the townships of Pendleton and Pendlebury. Acres, 2, 650. Pop., 24, 448. Houses, 4, 578. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/PendletonS/</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41443</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10375680</id>
   <status>Tn/CP/Ch</status>
   <name>PENDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10375691</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PENDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10375745</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PENDLETON ST AMBROSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10375757</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PENDLETON ST BARNABAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545523</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PENDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12780746</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PENDLETON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>461</id>
   <name>PRESTWICH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>480</id>
   <name>SWINTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10026</id>
   <name>BROUGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10748</id>
   <name>PENDLEBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>10750</id>
<name>PENDLETON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.8496922221921</lat>
<lon>-2.37010896118585</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENDLETON, a township in Whalley parish, Lancashire; under Pendle hill, 2&#189; miles S S E of Clitheroe r.station. Acres, 2, 800. Real property, &#163;4, 585. Pop.in 1851, 1, 308; in 1861, 1, 446. Houses, 298. The bulk of the population is at Sabden-Bridge. Standen Hallis the seat of J. T. W. Aspinall, Esq. There are a chapel of ease, an Independent chapel, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Pendleton/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640474</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53139</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10375708</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>PENDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10375710</id>
   <status>EExP</status>
   <name>PENDLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10375721</id>
   <status>EExP</status>
   <name>PENDLETON HALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10375733</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PENDLETON IN WHALLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25205</id>
<name>CLAREMONT</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4951586430955</lat>
<lon>-2.30753663382178</lon>
<unit>
   <id>10345091</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CLAREMONT</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
