<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10046</id>
<name>CLAUGHTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.8812509802661</lat>
<lon>-2.71748601888786</lon>
<gazetteerText>CLAUGHTON, a township in Garstang parish, Lancashire; on the Lancaster canal and the Lancaster and Preston railway, 2&#189; miles S of Garstang. Acres, 3, 700. Real property, &#163;4, 690. Pop., 608. Houses, 110.Hall is the seat of the Brockholes family. There are a Preshyterian chapel of 1866, a Roman Catholic chapel, modern and in the Grecian style, a large Roman Catholic school, and the Garstang workhouse. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7293852</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10345121</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>CLAUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10345145</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CLAUGHTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>10045</id>
<name>CLAUGHTON</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>54.0851512407875</lat>
<lon>-2.66007237184665</lon>
<gazetteerText>CLAUGHTON, a parish in the district and county of Lancaster; on the river Lune, and on the Skipton and Lancaster railway, 1&#189; mile WSW of Hornby r. station, and 7 NE by E of Lancaster. Post town, Hornby, under Lancaster. Acres, 1, 550. Real property, &#163;1, 493. Pop., 94. Houses, 19. The property is subdivided. Claughton Hall, built as a manor-house in the time of James I., has two embattled towers and numerous transomed windows. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;150.* Patrons, the Trustees of T. Fenwick, Esq. The church is good; and there is a Roman Catholic chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Claughton/</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/ClaughtonG/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652921</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10345108</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CLAUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10345110</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CLAUGHTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
