<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20430</id>
<name>ST MICHAEL ON WYRE</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.8622111597577</lat>
<lon>-2.81966247762168</lon>
<gazetteerText>MICHAEL-ON-WYRE (ST.), a village and sub-district in Garstang district, and a parish partly also in Fylde and Preston districts, Lancashire. The village stands on the river Wyre, 3 miles W by N of Brock r. station, and 3&#189; SW of Garstang; is in the township of Upper Rawcliffewith-Tarnacre; and has a n eat stone bridge over the river.&#151;The sub-district comprises the St. Michael townships of Out-Rawcliffe, Upper-Rawcliffe-with-Tarnacre, Great Eccleston, and In skip-with-Sowerby, the Lancaster township of Myerscough, and the Garstang township of Bilsborrow. Acres, 1 5,965. Pop., 3,359. Houses, 638.-The parish, in addition to its four townships in the sub-district, contains the townships of Elswick and Wood-Plumpton. Post town, Garstang, Lancashire. Acres, 18,114; of which 180 are water. Real property, &#163;29,570. Pop. in 1851,4,680; in 1861,4,509. Houses, 879. The property is much subdivided. The manors of Upper Rawcliffe and Inskip belong to the Earl of Derby; that of Out-Rawcliffe belongs to the representatives of the late R. W. France, Esq.; and that of Wood-Plumpton belongs to Birley, Esq. Rushcutting is largely carried on in Great Eccleston; and tiles and drain-pipes are extensively made in Wood-Plumpton. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Manchester. Value, &#163;580.* Patron, the Rev. W. Hornby. The church is of the time of Henry VIII.; succeeded an ancient one, supposed to have been built about 640; comprises nave and aisles, with battlemented tower; and includes a N oratory, formerly the mortuary chapel of the Butler family. The chapelries of Cop or Great Eccleston, Out-Rawcliffe, Inskip, and Wood-Plumpton are separate benefices. There are, in the several townships, a Baptist chapel, three Wesleyan chapels, two Primitive Methodist chapels, two Roman Catholic chapels, two endowed schools and three national schools. There are also, in Wood-Plumpton, a police station and a small workhouse. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10378977</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST MICHAEL ON WYRE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545602</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
