<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20646</id>
<name>ARDWICK</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.470189463537</lat>
<lon>-2.21545045216471</lon>
<gazetteerText>ARDWICK, a township, three chapelries, and a subdistrict in Manchester parish, Lancashire. The township is suburban to Manchester city, on the SE; and lies within the borough boundaries. Acres, 470. Real pro perty, &#163;57,895. Pop., 21,757. Houses, 4,414. The Manchester and Sheffield railway has a station here, &#190; of a mile from the terminus; joins here the Manchester and Birmingham railway near Chancery lane; and is carried here on a succession of immense viaducts.-The chapel ries are Ardwick-St. Thomas, Ardwick-St. Silas, and Ardwick-St. Matthew; and were constituted in respec tively 1838, 1844, and 1868. Pop. of A. St. T., 10,147. Houses, 2,029. Pop. of A. St. S., 10,375. Houses, 2,143. The livings are rectories in the diocese of Manchester. Value of St. E. and St. S., each &#163;300; of St. M., not reported. Patrons of St. T., the Dean and Chapter of Manchester, of St. S. and St. M., Trustees.-The subdistrict includes also four other townships, and is in Chorlton district. Acres, 4,031. Pop., 47,752. Houses, 9,322. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ardwick</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Ardwick/</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41421</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10332023</id>
   <status>CP/Ch/Tn</status>
   <name>ARDWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332035</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ARDWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332047</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ARDWICK ST BENEDICT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332059</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ARDWICK ST JEROME</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332060</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ARDWICK ST JEROME AND ST SILAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332072</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ARDWICK ST MATTHEW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332084</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ARDWICK ST SILAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545559</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ARDWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10568869</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ARDWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12754036</id>
   <status>PBDivCon/BCon</status>
   <name>MANCHESTER ARDWICK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
