<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>560</id>
<name>RAINFORD</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4964329671959</lat>
<lon>-2.78214724264753</lon>
<gazetteerText>RAINFORD, a village, a township-chapelry, and a sub-district, in Prescot parish and district, Lancashire. The village stands on the Ormskirk and St. Helens railway, 1 mile S S E of that railway &apos;s intersection by the Liverpool and Wigan railway, and 4&#188; miles N W by N of St. Helens; and has a station on the railway, and a post-office under St. Helens. The chapelry comprises 5, 803 acres. Real property, &#163;12, 623; of which &#163;3, 280 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 2, 333; in 1861, 2, 784. Houses, 478. The increase of pop. arose from the opening of new collieries. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Earl of Derby. R. Hall, Mount Pleasant, and the Rookery are chief residences. Much of the land is reclaimed morass. Tobacco-pipemaking is largely carried on. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Chester. Value, &#163;135.* Patron, the Vicar of Prescot. The church is a plain building, with abelfry. There are an Independent chapel, an endowed school for boys, and a national school for girls. The sub-district is conterminate with the chapelry. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Rainford/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rainford</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639693</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=41351</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10107593</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>RAINFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154583</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>RAINFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376828</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>RAINFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10376830</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RAINFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10545420</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RAINFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
