<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>412</id>
<name>BACUP</name>
<container>LANCASHIRE</container>
<lat>53.7028818465035</lat>
<lon>-2.20433393775566</lon>
<gazetteerText>BACOP, or Bacup, a town and three chapelries in Whalley and Rochdale parishes, Lancashire. The town stands on the river Irwell, at the terminus of a branch of the Lancashire and Yorkshire railway, 7 miles NNW of Rochdale; is a seat of petty sessions and county courts; and carries on industry in cotton factories, woollen print works, Turkey-red dye-works, iron foundries, corn mills, and coal mining; has been much improved, by a local board, since 1864; and has a post office&#8225; under Manchester, a r. station with telegraph, a banking office, a police station, waterworks, a market-hall of 1867 built at a cost of &#163;6,000, a plain church of 1788, two churches of 1854 and 1865 in the early English style, two recent handsome Wesleyan chapels, seven other dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a mechanics institution, with public hall and reading rooms, several public schools, a weekly market on Saturday, and two annual pleasure fairs. Pop. in 1851, 6,981; in 1861, 10,935. Houses, 2,085. The chapelries are St. John, Christchurch, and St. Saviour. Pop., 6,981,5,730, and 2,350. The livings of St. J. andare vicarages, and that of St. S. is a p. curacy, in the dio. of Manchester. Value of St. J. and C., each &#163;300; of St. S., &#163;159.* Patrons of St. J., Hulme&apos;s Trustees; of C., Five Trustees; of St. S., J. M. Holt, Esq. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LAN/Bacup/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656666</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bacup,_Lancashire</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10062172</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>BACUP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10111523</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BACUP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332485</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BACUP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332503</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BACUP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332515</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BACUP CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10332527</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BACUP ST SAVIOUR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10546126</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BACUP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833623</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BACUP</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>100</id>
   <name>WHITWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17295</id>
   <name>ROSSENDALE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
