<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10853</id>
<name>HALLATON</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5667890745241</lat>
<lon>-0.839586578504718</lon>
<gazetteerText>HALLATON, a village and a parish in the district of Uppingham and county of Leicester. The village stands on a slope, 3 miles NNW of Medbourne r. station, and 6 WSW of Uppingham; was once a market town; and has now a post office under Uppingham, and fairs on Holy Thursday and on the third Thursday after. The parish Comprises 2, 360 acres. Real property, &#163;, 581. Pop., 696. Houses, 167. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Calverly Bewicke, Esq. Remains of an ancient encampment, called Hallatoncastle hill, of considerable extent, and comprising a conical eminence 118 feet high, once surmounted by a keep and engirt with ramparts and ditches, are about a mile W of the village; and vestiges of another are near it. The living is a rectory, united with the chapelry of Blaston-St. Michael, in the diocese of Peterborongh. Value, &#163;741.* Patrons,Bewicke, Esq., and the Rev. G. O. Fenwicke. The church consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with tower and spire; and contains an old font, sedilia, and monuments to the Vowes, the Bewickes, the Fenwickes, and the Dents. There are an Independent chapel, a national school, endowed with &#163;25, alms houses with &#163;50, and other charities with &#163;444. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LEI/Hallaton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hallaton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647624</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22052</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10173656</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>HALLATON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10378928</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HALLATON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10378930</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HALLATON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10712</id>
   <name>CRANOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10842</id>
   <name>GLOOSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10844</id>
   <name>GOADBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10871</id>
   <name>HORNINGHOLD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11195</id>
   <name>NOSELEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11304</id>
   <name>STONTON WYVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11347</id>
   <name>TUGBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
