<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10646</id>
<name>BREEDON ON THE HILL</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7950860025473</lat>
<lon>-1.39477009404682</lon>
<gazetteerText>BREEDON-ON-THE-HILL, a village and a township in the district of Shardlow, and county of Leicester, and a parish in the districts of Shardlow and Ashby-de-la-Zouch, and counties of Leicester and Derby. The village stands at the base of a high limestone rock, near the verge of the county, 4 miles N of Swannington r. station, and 5 NE by N of Ashby-de-la-Zouch; and has a post office, of the name of Breedon, under Ashby-de-la-Zouch. A small monastery of black canons, subject to the priory of St. Oswald in Yorkshire, was founded here in 1144 by Ferrers, Earl of Nottingham; and given, at the dissolution, to the Shirleys. -The township includes also the hamlets of Wilson and Tonge. Acres, 3,010. Real property, &#163;3,499. Pop., 893. Houses, 222.&#151;The parish contains also the townships of Staunton-Harrold and Worthington, and the liberty of Newbold. Acres, 6,410. Real property, &#163;11,797. Pop., 2,417. Houses, 542. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Earl of Stamford. Limestone is worked. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;205. Patron, the Earl of Stamford. The church surmounts the limestone rock at the village; contains tombs of the Shirleys; and is good. The p. curacy of Worthington is a separate benefice. There are two Wesleyan chapels, an endowed school with &#163;41 a year, and a vicarage augmentation charity &#163;244. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breedon_on_the_Hill</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654805</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10371843</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BREEDON ON THE HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371909</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BREEDON ON THE HILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
