<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20183</id>
<name>BELGRAVE</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6598054743722</lat>
<lon>-1.12020570355745</lon>
<gazetteerText>BELGRAVE, a township and a parish in Barrow-upon-Soar district, Leicester. The township lies on the river Soar, the Foss&#233; way, and the Midland railway, 1&#189; mile NNE of Leicester; and has a post office under Leicester. It gives the title of Viscount to the Marquis of Westminster. Real property, &#163;9,333. Pop., 1,510. Houses, 341. The parish includes also the township of South Thurmaston and the chapelry of Birstall. Acres, 3,450. Real property, with North Thurmaston, &#163;18,943. Pop., 2,808. Houses, 625. Belgrave House and a half-share of the manor belong to Isaac Harrison, Esq. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Birstall, in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;146.* Patron, the Bishop of Lichfield. The church is later English, but has a Norman door; and contains monuments and a curious font. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, a national school, town-lands worth &#163;90 a year, and other charities &#163;36. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655980</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belgrave,_Leicestershire</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10111249</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BELGRAVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370358</id>
   <status>CP/Tn/AP</status>
   <name>BELGRAVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370360</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BELGRAVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10370371</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BELGRAVE ST MICHAEL AND ALL ANGELS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
