<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11358</id>
<name>WALTON ON THE WOLDS</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7725840925654</lat>
<lon>-1.11166841094524</lon>
<gazetteerText>WALTON-ON-THE-WOLDS, a parish in Barrow-upon-Soar district, Leicester; 2 miles NE of Barrow-upon-Soar r. station. Post town, Loughborough. Acres, 1,720. Real property, &#163;2,087. Pop., 221. Houses, 57. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;450.* Patron, Mrs. Packe. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walton_on_the_Wolds</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634829</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10393036</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WALTON LE WOLDS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10393048</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WALTON ON THE WOLDS</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>11357</id>
<name>WALTHAM ON THE WOLDS</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8131682915124</lat>
<lon>-0.814461599455621</lon>
<gazetteerText>WALTHAM-ON-THE-WOLDS, a village and a parish in Melton-Mowbray district, Leicester. The village stands 3&#190; miles N by W of Saxby r. station, and 5 NE of Melton-Mowbray; was once a market-town; and has a post-office&#8225; under Melton-Mowbray, and a cattle and horse fair on 18 and 19 Sept. The parish comprises 2,870 acres. Real property, &#163;3,943. Pop, 672. Houses, 136. The manor belongs to the Duke of Rutland. Lime is calcined. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;520.* Patron, the Duke of Rutland. The church is cruciform, with central tower and spire; is chiefly decorated English; and has been restored. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;30. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waltham_on_the_Wolds</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634840</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10392883</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WALTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10392950</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WALTHAM ON THE WOLDS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10392962</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WALTHAM ON THE WOLDS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551523</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WALTHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10613</id>
   <name>BESCABY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
