<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11380</id>
<name>WOODHOUSE</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7279294746145</lat>
<lon>-1.22570354796499</lon>
<gazetteerText>WOODHOUSE, a township and a chapelry in Barrow-upon-Soar parish Leicester. The township lies 3&#190; miles S of Loughborough r. s ion, and contains a village of its own name. Post town, Loughborough. Acres, 2,770. Real property, &#163;5,402. Pop., 1,205. Houses, 283. The manor belongs to W. P. Herrick, Esq. The chapelry is less extensive than the township. Pop., 1,163. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;140. Patron, the Vicar of Barrow-upon-Soar. The church was built in 1338, and restored in 1858. There are an endowed school with &#163;239 a year, and charities &#163;10. See Woodhouse-Eaves. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woodhouse,_Leicestershire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633641</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10393498</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>WOODHOUSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10393504</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WOODHOUSE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>21691</id>
<name>WOODHOUSE EAVES</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.722500057924</lat>
<lon>-1.21371516688601</lon>
<gazetteerText>WOODHOUSE-EAVES, a chapelry, with a village, in Barrow-upon-Soar parish, Leicester; 4&#188; miles S by W of Loughborough r. station. It takes its name from including part of Wood house township, and from lying on the eaves or edge of Charnwood forest; it was constituted in 1844; and it has a post-office under Loughborough. Pop. in 1861, 1,163. Houses, 264. The surface is picturesque, and includes bold high grounds, commanding exquisite views. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;118.* Patrons, the Lords of the Manor of Charnwood Forest. The church was built in 1837; and is in the early English style, with a pinnacled tower. There are Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, and an endowed school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10393516</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WOODHOUSE EAVES</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
