<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>987</id>
<name>QUORNDON</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7429872387599</lat>
<lon>-1.16939748818418</lon>
<gazetteerText>QUORNDON, a village, a township-chapelry, and a sub-district, in Barrow-upon-Soar district, Leicester. The village stands on the river Soar, 1 mile W S W of Barrow r. station, and 2&#189; S E of Loughborough; is commonly called Quorn; and has a post-office under Loughborough. The chapelry is in Barrow-upon-Soar parish, and comprises 1, 990 acres. Real property, &#163;6, 591. Pop. in 1851, 1,876; in 1861, 1, 622. Houses, 378. Q. House is the seat of E. B. Farnham, Esq.; Q. Hall, of E. Warner, Esq.; and Q. Lodge, of R. Hole, Esq. There are gas-works for Quorndon, Mountsorrel, and Barrow-upon-Soar. There are also the kennels and stables of the Quorn hunt; and framework-knitting and lace-glove-making are carried on. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;122. Patron, the Vicar of Barrow. The church is old, was restored in 1866, and has a tower. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and charities &#163;60.&#151;The sub-district contains also three other sections of Barrow parish, a township of Rothley parish, two other parishes, and an extra-parochial tract. Pop., 5,089. Houses, 1, 152. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quorn,_Leicestershire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639755</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10138681</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>QUORNDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186705</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>QUORNDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10389574</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>QUORNDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10389604</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>QUORN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551584</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>QUORNDON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
