<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>776</id>
<name>WIGSTON</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5794966898631</lat>
<lon>-1.10664499042348</lon>
<gazetteerText>WIGSTON-MAGNA, a large village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Blaby district, Leicestershire. The village stands near the Leicester and Market-Harborough and the Leicester and Rugby railways, 4 miles SSE of Leicester; has recently undergone much improvement; carries on considerable trade, in framework-knitting and in other departments; and has a post-office&#8225; under Leicester, two r. stations, a mortuary old church with restored tower and spire, a handsome parochial church with lofty spire, an ornate Independent chapel of 1841, three other dissenting chapels, national and British schools, alms houses with &#163;151 a year, and other charities &#163;66. The parish comprises 2,780 acres. Real property, &#163;9,863. Pop. in 1851, 2,441; in 1861, 2,521. Houses, 556. The property is much subdivided. W. Hall is the seat of M. Turner, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;220.* Patron, alternately the Haberdashers&apos; Company and Christ&apos;s Hospital, London.&#151;The sub-district contains 5 parishes and 2 parts. Acres, 13,210. Pop., 7,314. Houses, 1,630. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633936</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10136714</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WIGSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10393334</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>EAST WIGSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10393358</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GREAT WIGSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10393360</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WIGSTON MAGNA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551419</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WIGSTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1284</id>
   <name>OADBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10625</id>
   <name>BLABY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10657</id>
   <name>BRUNTINGTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10670</id>
   <name>BURTON OVERY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10705</id>
   <name>COSBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10726</id>
   <name>DUNTON BASSETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10735</id>
   <name>FLECKNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10837</id>
   <name>GREAT GLEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10838</id>
   <name>GLEN PARVA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10965</id>
   <name>KIBWORTH HARCOURT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
