<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11158</id>
<name>MOUNTSORREL</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7281621430257</lat>
<lon>-1.14530217417675</lon>
<gazetteerText>MOUNTSORREL, a small town and two township-chapelries, in Barrow-upon-Soar district, Leicester. The town stands on rising-ground, on the W side of the river Soar, 1&#189; mile W of Sileby r. station, 1&#189; S by W of Barrow r. station, and 4 S E of Loughborough; is nearly overhung by a boldly precipitous height, called Castle-hill, about 100 feet in altitude; takes its name thence, by corruption, of &quot; Mount-Soar-Hill; &quot; had anciently, on the hill, a strong castle of Robert le Bossu, which was occupied by the rebel barons against Henry III., and razed to the ground by that king s command; had formerly also, near its own centre, an old market-cross, which was removed by Sir John Danvers, at the end of last century, to his grounds at Swithland; is built and paved with a remarkably hard and durable syenite, found in the neighbourhood; is a seat of petty-sessions, and of a court-leet and court-baron; and has a post-office&#8225;under Loughborough, two chief inns, an old four-arched-bridge, a market house, two churches, four dissenting chapels, a free school for 12 poor boys, a national school, and charities &#163;146. The market house was built by Sir John Danvers, on the site of the old cross; and is a small round structure, with an octostyle portico, and a cupola. St Peter&apos;s church, or the church of M.-North-End, is an old building, with a tower. Christ church, or the church of M.-South-End, was erected in 1844, at the expense of Miss Brinton; is a small building, in the pointed style; and has a tower and spire. One of the dissenting chapels is for General Baptists; was formerly occupied by Presbyterians; and is noted for occasional.ministrations in it of the famous Dr. Watts. A weekly market is held on Monday; a fair of 9 days duration begins on 10 July; stocking weaving is carried on; and considerable trade is done in connexion with the Mount-sorrel quarries and granite works. The quarries are in the near neighbourhood; give employment to upwards of600 men and boys; produce millstones, building-stones, paving-stones, and road-metal; were connected by railway, in 1861, with the Midland railway at the Barrow station; and send off vast quantities of material daily to many parts of the kingdom. The two township-chapelries are M.-North-End and M.-South-End; and the former is in Barrow-upon-Soar parish.the latter in Rothley parish. Acres of the two, 680. Real property in 1860, prior to the extension of the quarries, &#163;3, 626; of which &#163;102 were in the quarries. Pop. of M.-North-End, in 1851, 802; in 1861, 857. Houses, 197. Pop. of M.-South-End, in 1851, 795; in 1861, 897. Houses, 200. The manor belongs to the Earl of Lanesborough. The livings are p. curacies in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, of M.-North-End, &#163;260; of M.-South-End, &#163;130.* Patron, of the former, the Vicar of Barrow; of the latter, the Rev.Kemble. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mountsorrel</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642096</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10024705</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>MOUNTSORREL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10388065</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>MOUNTSORREL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10388089</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MOUNTSORREL CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10388090</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>MOUNTSORREL NORTH END</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10388107</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>MOUNTSORREL SOUTH END</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10388132</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MOUNTSORREL ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17279</id>
   <name>CHARNWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
