<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10957</id>
<name>HUNGERTON</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6520418541973</lat>
<lon>-0.975179526166524</lon>
<gazetteerText>HUNGERTON, a village, a township, and a parish in Billesdon district, Leicestershire. The village stands between the two branches of the river Wreak, 6 miles SE by E of Syston Junction r. station, and 7 NE by E of Leicester; and has a post office under Leicester. The township includes the village. Real property, &#163;1,565. Pop., 196. Houses, 48. The parish contains also the liberty of Baggrave, and the hamlets of Ingarsby and Quenby. Acres, 2,910. Real property, &#163;5, 945. Pop., 302. Houses, 64. The property is divided among a few. Baggrave Hall is the seat of E. A. Burnaby, Esq. Quenby Hall has, for upwards of seven centuries, belonged to the Ashbys. Ingarsby Hall, an old moated building, is now a farm house. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Twyford and the p. curacy of Thorpe-Satchville, in the diocese of Peterborongh. Value, &#163;320.* Patron, the Rev. E. Q. Ashby. The church is ancient; was restored in 1851; and consists of nave, chancel, and S aisle, with porch and lofty spire. There are a Wesleyan chapel and some charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646409</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10382427</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HUNGARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10382439</id>
   <status>EP/EP</status>
   <name>HUNGARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10382440</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HUNGARTON WITH TWYFORD AND THORPE SATCHVILLE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10701</id>
   <name>COLD NEWTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10963</id>
   <name>KEYHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11138</id>
   <name>LOWESBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
