<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11243</id>
<name>ROTHLEY</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7225821960128</lat>
<lon>-1.08168729805898</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROTHLEY, a village, a township, and a sub-district, in Barrow-upon-Soar district, and a parish partly also in Billelon and Melton-Mowbray districts, Leicester. The village stands on an affluent of the river Soar, 1&#189; mile S of Mountsorrel, and 2&#190; N W of Syston r. station; and has a post-office under Loughborough, and an ancient manorial court-house. The township comprises, with Rothley-Temple extra-parochial tract, 2, 170 acres. Real property, without that tract, &#163;4, 224. Pop., 939. Houses, 202.&#151;The sub-district contains also seven extra-parochial tracts, two parishes, and part of another. Acres, 14, 657. Pop., 4, 796. Houses, 1,067. The parish contains the townships of Rothley, Mountsorrel-South End, and Keyham, and the chapelries of Wartnaby and Wycomb-with-Chad-well. Acres, 5, 480. Pop., 2, 213. Houses, 486. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to H. R. Parker, Esq. The Barrow-upon-Soar workhouse is in R.township; and is a commodious structure, with a Tudorfront. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelries of Keyham, Wartnaby, Wycomb-with-Chadwell, and Gaddesby, in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;500.* Patrons, the Executors of the lateC. Macaulay, Esq. The church is ancient but good. The p. curacy of Mount-sorrel-Christchurch, is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, an endowed school with &#163;15 a year, a national school, and charities &#163;20. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LEI/Rothley.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rothley,_Leicestershire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639076</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10390096</id>
   <status>Tn/CP/AP</status>
   <name>ROTHLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10390102</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROTHLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10390151</id>
   <status>CP/ExP</status>
   <name>ROTHLEY TEMPLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551572</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ROTHLEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10706</id>
   <name>COSSINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11235</id>
   <name>RATCLIFFE ON THE WREAKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
