<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10633</id>
<name>BOTTESFORD</name>
<container>LEICESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9408084376641</lat>
<lon>-0.799194509455229</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOTTESFORD, or Botsworth, a village and a parish in the district of Grantham and county of Leicester. The village stands in the vale of Belvoir. near the Grantham canal and the Nottingham and Grantham railway, 7 miles WNW of Grantham; and it has a station on the railway, and a post office&#8225; under Nottingham. The parish includes also the hamlets of Easthorpe and Normanton. Acres, 5,010. Real property, &#163;9,386. Pop., 1,415. Houses, 317. The property is much subdivided. The manor was given at the Conquest to R. de Todeni, and belongs now to the Duke of Rutland. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;993.* Patron, the Duke of Rutland. The church is large, cruciform, and very good, with a tower at the west end; and contains monuments to many of the Earls and Dukes of Rutland. There are four dissenting chapels, two endowed hospitals for poor men and poor widows, with &#163;479 and &#163;133 a year, and a school with &#163;36. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655125</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bottesford,_Leicestershire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LEI/Bottesford.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10371107</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BOTTESFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10371119</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOTTESFORD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7511</id>
   <name>LANGAR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10560</id>
   <name>AB KETTLEBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10678</id>
   <name>LONG CLAWSON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10716</id>
   <name>CROXTON KERRIAL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10730</id>
   <name>EATON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10856</id>
   <name>HARBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11238</id>
   <name>REDMILE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11253</id>
   <name>SCALFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11357</id>
   <name>WALTHAM ON THE WOLDS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14092</id>
   <name>WOOLSTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
