<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13001</id>
<name>MESSINGHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.5286173574854</lat>
<lon>-0.675008208789935</lon>
<gazetteerText>MESSINGHAM, a village, a township, and a parish in Glanford-Brigg district, Lincoln. The village stands 3&#189; miles E of the river Trent, 4 NW by N of Kirton-inLindsey r. station, and 7&#189; W by S of Glanford-Brigg; is large and well built; and has a post office under KirtonLindsey, and a fair on Trinity Monday.-The township comprises 5,450 acres. Real property, &#163;7,922. Pop., 1,086. Houses, 247.&#151;The parish contains also the larger portion of East Butterwick township. Acres, with the rest of East Butterwick, 6,130. Real property, with the rest of E. B., &#163;10,319. Pop., exclusive of the rest of E. B., 1,362. Houses, 301. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to W. Smith, Esq. About 1,000 acres were formerly a low, sandy, barren tract upon the Trent; but have been highly improved by warping. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Bottesford, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;650. * Patron, alternately the Bishop of Lincoln and the Dean and Chapter of Lincoln. The church is a neat structure, with a tower; and was partly rebuilt in 1818, at a cost of nearly &#163;2,000. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Wethodists, a reading-room and library, and a recently erected national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Messingham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642697</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10435717</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MESSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10435730</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MESSINGHAM WITH EAST BUTTERWICK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11410</id>
   <name>ASHBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11744</id>
   <name>BOTTESFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11828</id>
   <name>EAST BUTTERWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12621</id>
   <name>HOLME</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13545</id>
   <name>SCOTTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13551</id>
   <name>SCOTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
