<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12183</id>
<name>EDENHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7821117137301</lat>
<lon>-0.44353325874677</lon>
<gazetteerText>EDENHAM, a parish in Bourn district, Lincoln; on the river Glen, at the terminus of a branch railway from the Great Northern, 2&#189; miles NW of Bourn. It includes the hamlets of Grimsthorpe, Ellsthorpe, and Scottlethorpe; and has a post office under Bourn, and a railway station; the branch railway from it going south-westward into junction with the Great Northern at Little Bytham. Acres, 6, 844. Real property, &#163;10, 398. Pop., 644. Houses, 128. The property is all in one estate. Grimsthorpe Castle is the seat of Lord Willoughby d&apos;Eresby, and is a very handsome edifice, in a park of about 6 miles in circuit. A Cistertian abbey formerly stood in the park, about a mile from the mansion; was founded, about the year 1451, by William, Earl of Albemarle; bore the name of Vallis Dei, vulgarly corrupted into Vaudey; and is now represented by only three or four large sculptured stones. A mineral well in the parish was, at one time, much frequented by invalids, but went into disrepute. The living is a donative in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;100. Patron, Lord Willoughby d&apos;Eresby. The church is early and later English. There are a public school, a library and reading room , and charities &#163;17. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Edenham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edenham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650242</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10414544</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EDENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10414570</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EDENHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
