<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12272</id>
<name>FOLKINGHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8837791821933</lat>
<lon>-0.406118099324739</lon>
<gazetteerText>FALKINGHAM, or Folkingham, a small town and a parish in Bourn district, Lincoln. The town stands on an eminence, commanding extensive views, 8 miles NE of Corby r. station, and 10&#189; E by S of Grantham; is a seat of sessions; and has a head post office, &#8225; a banking office, a prison, a church, a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;15. The prison occupies the site of a castle, which was built about 1280, by Henry de Bellomonte, and destroyed by Cromwell; serves as a county house of correction for the parts of Kesteven; and has capacity for 31 males and 4 females. The church has a good tower, with eight crocketted pinnacles; and was repaired in 1859. A weekly market is held on Thursday; and fairs on Ash-Wednesday, Palm-Monday, 13 May, 14 and 15 June, 3 and 4 July, the Thursday after Old Michaelmas, and 22 Nov. The parish comprises 1,861 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 649. Pop., 650. Houses, 134. The manor was given, by William the Conqueror, to Gilbert de Gaunt; and passed to the De Bellomontes or Beaumonts. A large ancient camp, with deep fosse and lofty vallum, lies to the SE of the town. The living is a rectory, united with the vicarage of Laughton, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;511. Patron, Lord Aveland. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Folkingham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649256</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10416528</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FOLKINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10416530</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FOLKINGHAM WITH LOUGHTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
