<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11956</id>
<name>COLSTERWORTH</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8028849277254</lat>
<lon>-0.616909519649442</lon>
<gazetteerText>COLSTERWORTH, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Grantham district, Lincoln. The township bears the name of Colsterworth-with-Woolsthorpe; lies on the river Witham, and on the High Lyke Roman way, 4 miles W of Corby r. station, and 8 S of Grantham; and has a post office, &#8225; of the name of Colsterworth, under Grantham. The parish includes also the hamlet of Twyford. Acres, 3, 300. Real property, &#163;4, 084. Pop., 1, 163. Houses, 274. The manor of Woolsthorpe belonged to the father of Sir Isaac Newton; and the manor-house, now a farm-house, still standing, was Sir Isaac&apos;s birthplace. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;585.* Patron, the Prebendary of South Grantham. The church is chiefly early English; has a tower; and was recently restored. There are two Methodist chapels. A school has &#163;30 from endowment. Walker, the author of the &quot;English Particles, &quot; was rector.&#151;The sub-district contains seventeen parishes, Acres, 35, 320. Pop., 5, 391. Houses, 1, 163. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Colsterworth/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colsterworth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652528</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10408386</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>COLSTERWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10408398</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>COLSTERWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10562600</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>COLSTERWORTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12171</id>
   <name>EASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13572</id>
   <name>SKILLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13659</id>
   <name>STAINBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
