<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13904</id>
<name>SWINESHEAD</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9505947586306</lat>
<lon>-0.163397835479644</lon>
<gazetteerText>SWINESHEAD, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Boston district, Lincoln. The town stands 2 miles S of the Boston and Sleaford railway, and 6 WSW of Boston; was known to the Saxons as Swinesaefed; had a Cistertian abbey, founded in 1134, by R. de Greslei; was the first resting-place of King John, after his narrow escape from destruction in the Wash; stood long in navigable communication with the sea; was, till recently, a market-town; and has a post-office&#8225; under Spalding, a r. station, and a fair on 2 Oct. The parish comprises 6,100 acres. Real property, &#163;20,289; of which &#163;50 are in gasworks. Pop., 1,903. houses, 438. A Danish camp is about &#188; of a mile NW of the town. Many ancient coins have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;240.* Patron, Trinity College, Cambridge. The church is decorated and later English, with a chancel of 1847; and has a tower and lofty spire. The p. curacy of Chapel hill is a separate benefice. There are Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, an endowed school with &#163;172 a year, and charities &#163;365.&#151;The sub-district contains three parishes, parts of two other s, and eight extra-parochial tracts. Pop., 5,583. houses, 1,146. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Swineshead/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swineshead,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636384</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10429663</id>
   <status>PA/CP</status>
   <name>LANDS COMMON TO SWINESHEAD AND WIGTOFT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10459473</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SWINESHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10459497</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWINESHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10563835</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWINESHEAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
