<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11417</id>
<name>ASLACKBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8543067639275</lat>
<lon>-0.368166981512614</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASLACKBY, a parish and a subdistrict in the district of Bourn, Lincoln. The parish lies 2 miles S of Folkingham, and 7 N by W of Bourn r. station; includes the hamlets of Graby and Millthorpe; and has a fen allotment. Post Town, Folkingham. Acres, 3,934. Real property, &#163;5,944. Pop., 534. Houses, 100. A commandery of the Knights Templars was founded here, in the time of Richard I., by John le Mareschal; belonged afterwards to the Knights Hospitallers; and passed, at the dissolution, to Edward, Lord Clinton. A farmhouse, called the Temple, now stands on the site of its church; and includes remains of a square embattled tower. A castle also was founded here before 1062; and can still be traced in fosse and mounds. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;453.* Patron, R. F. Barstow, Esq. The church is a handsome edifice, with an embattled tower.-The subdistrict comprises ten parishes. Acres, 23,635. Pop., 4,730. Houses, 982. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Aslackby/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aslackby</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656898</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10394417</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ASLACKBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10394429</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASLACKBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10394430</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>ASLACKBY AND LAUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547726</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ASLACKBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
