<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11401</id>
<name>ANCASTER</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.986096245189</lat>
<lon>-0.550072904761687</lon>
<gazetteerText>ANCASTER a village and a parish in Grantham district, Lincoln The village adjoins the Grantham and Boston railway, on the line of Ermine-street, 8 miles NE of Grantham. It has a station on the railway, and a post office under Grantham. It gave the title of Duke, now extant, to the Berties of Uffington. A Roman station either Cansenn&#230; or Crocolana, occupied its site; and many Roman coins, bricks, and other relics have been found. A spot in the neighbourhood was the scene of a victory, in 1643, over the Parliamentarians. The parish contains also the hamlets of Sudbrooke and West Willoughby. Acres, 2,800. Real property, &#163;4,241. Pop., 682. Houses, 139. The property is much subdivided. The chief residences are Ancaster Hall, Sudbrooke Hall, and West Willoughby Hall. A tract which formerly was a common, wild and barren, is now enclosed and fertile. A fine oolitic building-stone is extensively quarried; has been used for Belvoir Castle, Wollaton Hall, and other great edifices; and is well exemplified in the parsonage, which was built in 1842. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;160.* Patron, the Rev. Z. S. Warren. The church is a mixture of Norman and early English. There are two Methodist chapels, and charities &#163;7. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657332</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancaster,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Ancaster/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10394053</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ANCASTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10394065</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ANCASTER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
