<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11951</id>
<name>NORTH COCKERINGTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3965485645423</lat>
<lon>0.0749901256241942</lon>
<gazetteerText>COCKERINGTON (North), a parish in Louth district, Lincoln; near the East Lincoln railway, 3&#190; miles NE of Louth. Post town, Louth. Acres, 1, 750. Real property, &#163;2, 640. Pop., 265. Houses, 58. The manor belonged to the Scropes; three of whom were Adrian the regicide, Sir Adrian the royalist, and Sir Carr the poet. The living is a vicarage, annexed to the vicarage of Alvingham, in the diocese of Lincoln. There are three Methodist chapels, a diocesan school, and an alms-house. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/NorthCockerington/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Cockerington</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299097</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10408271</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NORTH COCKERINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10408283</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTH COCKERINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>11952</id>
<name>SOUTH COCKERINGTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3864439426955</lat>
<lon>0.0932385125098747</lon>
<gazetteerText>COCKERINGTON (South), a parish in Louth district, Lincoln; near the East Lincoln railway, 3&#188; miles NE of Louth. Post town, Louth. Acres, 1,880. Real property, &#163;2, 920. Pop., 300. Houses, 71. The property is divided among a few. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;163. Patron, the Bishop of Lincoln. The chur. ch is late perpendicular English, and contains an effigies of Sir A. Scrope, who died in 1623. There are three Methodist chapels. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637451</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/SouthCockerington/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10408295</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SOUTH COCKERINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10408313</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH COCKERINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
