<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11807</id>
<name>BURGH LE MARSH</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1603234521594</lat>
<lon>0.266285696772391</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURGH-IN-THE-MARSH, a small town, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Spilsby district, Lincoln. The town stands 1&#188; mile E of the East Lincoln railway, 4 W of the sea, and 6&#188; E by S of Spilsby; and has a station, of the name of Burgh, on the railway, a post office&#8225; of the same name under Boston, and a banking office. A weekly market is held on Thursday; and fairs on the second Thursday of May and Aug., and on 26 Sept. A Roman station was here; and remains of a Roman castrum still exist, on high ground, partly natural, partly artificial. Roman coins also have been found; and there are two tumuli, one of them very high, called Cockhill. There were formerly two churches, but one of them was long ago demolished. The other, now the parish church, is later English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel; has a fine embattled, turreted, western tower, the battlements adorned with quarter foils; and contains a richly carved oaken pulpit and an octagonal font. There are chapels for Baptists and Methodists, a free school, with &#163;60, and other charities, with &#163;71. The parish comprises 4,233 acres. Real property, &#163;10,071. Pop., 1,223. Houses, 254. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Winthorpe, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;120.* Patron, the Bishop of Lincoln. The subdistrict contains twelve parishes. Acres, 25,282. Pop., 4,941. Houses, 1,024. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/BurghleMarsh/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burgh_le_Marsh</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654298</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10404915</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BURGH LE MARSH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10404940</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BURGH LE MARSH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547799</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURGH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11756</id>
   <name>BRATOFT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
