<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13387</id>
<name>SOUTH ORMESBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2576148567131</lat>
<lon>0.0539810819851584</lon>
<gazetteerText>ORMSBY (South), a village and a parish in Spilsby district, Lincoln. The village stands on an acclivity of the Wolds, 4 miles S W of Anthorpe r. station, and 5&#189; W of Alford; and has a post-office under Alford. The parish contains also the hamlet or quondam parish of Ketsby, and comprises 2, 377 acres. Real property, &#163;4,064. Pop., 261. Houses. 51. The property of Ormsby-proper belongs to the Massingberd family; and that of Ketsby, to Capt. D. Yorke. Ormsby Hall is the seat of the Massingberds, and stands in a well-wooded park. A Roman camp of 3 acres is on the brow of asteep hill; and several Roman coins have been found on and near it. An ancient water-mill, mentioned in Domesday book, is in Ketsby. The living is a rectory, united with the rectories of Ketsby and Driby, and with the vicarage of Calceby, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;800.* Patrons, the Massingberd family. The church is transition Norman, in good condition; consists of nave, aisles, chancel, and mortuary chapel, with a tower; and contains brasses of 1430 and 1495, and severalneat monnments of the Massingberds. National schools were erected in 1858. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/SouthOrmsby/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Ormsby</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301684</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10445917</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>SOUTH ORMESBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10445980</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH ORMESBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10445991</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SOUTH ORMESBY CUM KETSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446030</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH ORMESBY WITH KETSBY CALCEBY AND DRIBY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17322</id>
   <name>EAST LINDSEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
