<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>778</id>
<name>LONG SUTTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7697292841363</lat>
<lon>0.113966889543138</lon>
<gazetteerText>SUTTON (Long), or Sutton-St. Mary, a town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Holbeach district, Lincoln. The town stands on the Sutton-Bridge and Spalding railway, 5 miles ESE of Holbeach; is a seat of petty-sessions; consists of streets recently much improved and well drained; and has a post-office under Wisbeach, a r. station, two banking offices, two chief inns, a corn exchange of 1856, an ancient church restored in 1866, with a loftyspire serving as a sea-mark, four dissenting chapels, a literary institute, an agricultural association, an endowed school with &#163;56 a year, alms houses with &#163;24, and other charities &#163;825. A weekly market is held on Friday; fairs are held on 13 and 14 May, and the Friday after 25 Sept.; and there are two breweries and some corn mills.&#151;The parish includes Sutton-Bridge town, and S.-St. Edmunds, S.-St. James, and S.-St. Nicholas hamlets; extends to the coast; and comprises 21,636 acres of land, and 3,510 of water. Real property, &#163;57,252; of which &#163;150 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 6,591; in 1861, 6,124. Houses, 1,320. The property is much subdivided. Sutton-Holland, Gwanock, and Cranwell are separate manors. The site of a large mansion, said to have been a residence of John of Gaunt, is near the church. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;1,973.* Patrons, the Representatives of the late Rev. T. S. Bennett. The p. curacies of S.-St. Edmund, S.-St. James, S.-St. Nicholas, and S.-Bridge, are separate benefices.&#151;The sub-district excludes part of Long Sutton parish, but includes all Tydd-St. Mary, part of Gedney, and two extra-parochial tracts. Pop., 7,999. Houses, 1,689. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/LongSutton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_Sutton,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643624</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10043608</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>LONG SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10136738</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>LONG SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10458390</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LONG SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10459102</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SUTTON ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10459140</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SUTTON ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547880</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LONG SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12960</id>
   <name>LUTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13864</id>
   <name>LITTLE SUTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
