<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14058</id>
<name>WHAPLODE</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.765761423375</lat>
<lon>-0.0352602266461264</lon>
<gazetteerText>WHAPLODE, a village and a parish in Holbeach district, Lincoln. The village stands on the Spalding and Lynn railway, 2&#188; miles W by S of Holbeach; is large and scattered; and has a post-office under Spalding, and a r. station. The parish includes W.-Drove chapelry, and comprises 10,164 acres. Real property, &#163;23,300. Pop. in 1851, 2,564; in 1861, 2,462. Houses, 509. The property is much subdivided; and there are seven manors. Irby Hall was anciently a seat of the Irbys, and is now a farmhouse. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;605.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is Norman and good. There are two Wesleyan chapels, a free school, and alms houses. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Whaplode/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whaplode</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634187</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463233</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WHAPLODE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10463245</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHAPLODE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24051</id>
<name>WHAPLODE DROVE</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7027138675477</lat>
<lon>-0.0461936761696018</lon>
<gazetteerText>WHAPLODE-DROVE, a chapelry, with a village, in Whaplode parish, Lincoln; 1 mile NE of Crowland r. station. It has a post-office under Peterborough. Acres, 2,135. Real property, &#163;5,439. Pop., 8844. Houses, 152. The manor belongs to the Duke of Somerset. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;400.* Patrons, Trustees. The church is modern. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whaplode_Drove</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10463269</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHAPLODE DROVE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
