<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13650</id>
<name>SPILSBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1735605419206</lat>
<lon>0.0990980522299421</lon>
<gazetteerText>SPILSBY, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Lincoln. The town stands on an acclivity, at the terminus of the Spilsby and Firsby railway, 16 miles NNE of Boston; overlooks a vast tract of marsh and fen land; is a seat of quarter sessions, petty sessions, and county courts, and a polling place; had the late Sir John Franklin as a native, to whom a bronze statue has been erected; consists chiefly of four streets diverging from a market place; and has a head post-office,&#8225; three banking offices, two chief inns, an ancient market-cross, a town hall and corn-market, a news-room and library, a county house of correction, built in 1824 at a cost of &#163;30,000, a later English church, internally repaired in 1852, an Independent chapel of 1866, Wesleyan and Primitive Methodist chapels, an endowed grammar-school with &#163;82 a year, a national school, an agricultural association, charities &#163;95, a weekly market on Monday, and four annual fairs.&#151;The parish includes the hamlet of Eresby, and comprises 2,340 acres. Real property, &#163;7,007; of which &#163;150 are in gasworks. Pop., 1,467. Houses, 310. The manor belongs to Lord Willonghby D&apos;Eresby. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;105. Patron, Lord Willoughby D&apos;Eresby.&#151;The sub-district contains 22 parishes. Acres, 32,834. Pop., 8,421. Houses, 1,748.&#151;The district comprehends also the sub-districts of Burgh, Alford, Wainfleet, and Stickney; and comprises 140,269 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;17,614. Pop. in 1851, 28,937; in 1861, 28,799. Houses, 6,000. Marriages in 1863, 201; births, 1,023, -of which 123 were illegitimate; deaths, 639,-of which 204 were at ages under 5 years, and 21 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,947; births, 9,818; deaths, 5,482. The places of worship, in 1851, were 64 of the Church of England, with 12,264 sittings; 4 of Independents, with 414 s.; 4 of Baptists, with 752 s.; 54 of Wesleyans, with 8,168 s.; and 13 of Primitive Methodists, with 1,566 s. The schools were 41 public day-schools, with 2,630 scholars; 56 private day-schools, with 1,007 s.; and 75 Sunday schools, with 4,667 s. The workhouse is in Hundleby, and has accommodation for 280 inmates. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Spilsby/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spilsby</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Spilsby</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637224</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10074538</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>SPILSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10139247</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>SPILSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10198501</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>SPILSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10452776</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>SPILSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10452790</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SPILSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547817</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SPILSBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
