<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13430</id>
<name>PINCHBECK</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8091579952983</lat>
<lon>-0.199096027531125</lon>
<gazetteerText>PINCHBECK, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Spalding district, Lincoln. The village stands near the river Glen and the Peterborough and Boston railway, 2 miles N by E of Spalding r. station; and has a post-office under Spalding. The parish contains also the hamlets of Pinchbeck-Bars, Mill-Green, Guthram-Cote, Crossgate, Matthews, and others; and includes part of Cowbit-Wash. Acres, 11, 640. Real property, &#163;29, 653. Pop., 2, 933. Houses, 608. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to M. Johnson andF. Bonness, Esqs. Grove House and Bridge House are chief residences. There is a large scutching mill. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;700.* Patron, the Rev. W. Wayet. The church is early and later English; was restored in 1864; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower. The p. curacy of West Pinchbeck is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, two national schools, and charities &#163;96. The sub-district excludes the part of Cowbit-Wash, but includes smallparts of two other parishes. Pop., 3,052. Houses, 632. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Pinchbeck/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640279</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10447021</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PINCHBECK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10447069</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PINCHBECK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547957</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PINCHBECK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12326</id>
   <name>GOSBERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12631</id>
   <name>HORBLING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13460</id>
   <name>QUADRING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13857</id>
   <name>SURFLEET</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13900</id>
   <name>SWATON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>24050</id>
<name>WEST PINCHBECK</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8069626758268</lat>
<lon>-0.213646350862646</lon>
<gazetteerText>PINCHBECK (West), a chapelry in Pinchbeck parish, Lincoln; 4&#189; miles N W of Spalding r. station. It was constituted in 1851; and it has a post-office under Spalding. Pop., 1, 415. Houses, 281. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;210.* Patron, the Vicar of Pinchbeck. The church was built in 1849. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7290842</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10447100</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST PINCHBECK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
