<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13917</id>
<name>TATTERSHALL</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1135765618082</lat>
<lon>-0.190371576348767</lon>
<gazetteerText>TATTERSHALL, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Horncastle district, Lincoln. The town stands on the river Bain, the Witham navigation, and the Lincoln and Boston railway, 9 miles SSW of Horncastle; is partly in T. parish, but mostly in Coningsby parish; contains a pop. of about 2,000; and has a r. station, an inn, an ancient cruciform church, four dissenting chapels, an endowed school with &#163;20 a year, alms houses with &#163;30, other charities &#163;39, a weekly market on Thursday, stock-markets on the Thursday before and the two Thursdays after Easter, and cattle fairs on 15 May and 25 Sept.&#151;The parish consists of the townships of Tatter shalland Tattershall-Thorpe, and comprises 4,580 acres. Post town, Coningsby, under Boston. Real property, &#163;6,481. Pop. in 1851, 987; in 1861, 848. Houses, 180. The manor was given, by William the Conqueror, to Eudo; passed to the Cromwells, the mother of Henry VII., the Brandons, and the Clintons: and belongs now to Earl Fortescue. T. Cast1e was built by Eudo, and rebuilt about 1440 by the Cromwells; suffered much injury in the civil wars of Charles I.; and has left an interesting four-storied tower, 100 feet high, with octangular corner turrets. Two Roman camps are at T. Park. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;110. Patron, Earl Fortescue.-- The sub-district contains 9 parishes, 4 extra-parochial tracts, and 15 fen-allotments. Pop., 6,609. Houses 1,389. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Tattershall/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tattershall</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636180</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10459783</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TATTERSHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10459801</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TATTERSHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10459813</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>TATTERSHALL THORPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548019</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TATTERSHALL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
