<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13016</id>
<name>MOULTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7945373904262</lat>
<lon>-0.0577340746702903</lon>
<gazetteerText>MOULTON, a village, a parish, and a sun-district, in Spalding district, Lincoln. The village stands adjacent to the Spalding and Lynn railway, 4 miles E by N of Spalding; is a large and pretty place; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Spalding. The parish contains also the chapelry of Moulton-Chapel, and the hamlets of Austindyke, Eaugate, and Seasend; and extends to the coast. Acres, 13,785; of which 335 are water. Real property, &#163;26,384. Pop. in 1851,2,058; in 1861,2,143. Houses, 457. The manor belongs to Lord Boston. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;456.* Patron, M. Johnson, Esq. The church is partly early English, partly perpendicular; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with beautiful tower and finely-proportioned octagonal spire; and contains a water-drain, an ambry, and a font of 1683, resembling that of St. James&apos;, Westminster. The p. curacy of Moulton-Chapel is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists, a free grammar school, and charities &#163;150. The grammar school was founded in 1560, by John Harrox; has &#163;500 a year from endowment; and is divided into upper school and lower school, with residences for two masters.&#151;The sub-district contains also Weston parish. Acres, 19,171. Pop., 2,893. Houses, 618. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Moulton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moulton,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642123</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10436060</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MOULTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10436072</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MOULTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10436084</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MOULTON ST JAMES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547910</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MOULTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24662</id>
<name>MOULTON CHAPEL</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7455739682577</lat>
<lon>-0.0828021774335733</lon>
<gazetteerText>MOULTON-CHAPEL, a chapelry in Moulton parish, Lincoln; 3&#188; miles S by W of Moulton r. station, and 4&#188; SE of Spalding. It has a post office under Spalding. Pop. in 1851,450. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;90. Patron, the Vicar of Moulton. The church was built in 1722, and is an octagonal structure. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642121</link>
</links>
</place>
</results>
