<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12793</id>
<name>LEASINGHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0249695426815</lat>
<lon>-0.415840295666657</lon>
<gazetteerText>LEASINGHAM, a township and a parish in Sleaford district, Lincoln. The township lies 2&#188; miles NNW of Sleaford r. station, and 4 E of Ermine street; and has a post office under Sleaford. Pop., 381. Houses, 84.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlet of Roxholme, and comprises 2, 959 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 127. Pop., 473. Houses, 99. The property is divided among a few. The present parish is a consolidation of two quondam parishes, North L. and South L. The living is a double rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;924.* Patron, Sir John H. Thorold, Bart. The N church has disappeared. The S church has a tower, with a tall spire; and was recently restored. The parsonage was built in 1840, at a cost of &#163;2, 300. There are a United Free Methodist chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Leasingham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leasingham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644731</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10429900</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LEASINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429924</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>LEASINGHAM ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429936</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEASINGHAM ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429948</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>LEASINGHAM ST JOHN THE BAPTIST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429950</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEASINGHAM ST JOHN THE BAPTIST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429961</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEASINGHAM WITH ROXHOLME</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12790</id>
<name>LEADENHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0602300999553</lat>
<lon>-0.589463863987781</lon>
<gazetteerText>LEADENHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Sleaford district, Lincoln. The village stands on the Lincoln and Grantham railway, 2&#190; miles W of Erminestreet, and 8&#190; NW of Sleaford; is a pleasant place, and a seat of petty sessions; and has a station on the railway, a post office under Grantham, and a fair in May.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlet of Lowfield, and a recently annexed place called Maiden House. Acres, with Beyards-Leap extra-parochial tract, 2, 260. Real property, &#163;6, 645. Pop., 688. Houses, 141. The property is divided among a few. The manor, with Leadenham House and much of the land, belongs to Colonel John Reeve. A spring called St. Ann&apos;s Well, and a barrow, are near the village. A cliff, commanding a very extensive view, is near Leadenham House. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;800.* Patron, the Rev. O. Smith. The church is decorated English; was restored in 1861; and has a pinnacled tower and a crocketted spire. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a school with &#163;20 a year from endowment, and charities &#163;84.&#151;The sub-district contains seven parishes and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 19, 202. Pop., 3, 940. Houses, 793. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Leadenham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leadenham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644752</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10429845</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LEADENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429857</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEADENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10565080</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LEADENHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12792</id>
<name>OLD LEAKE</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0311235413773</lat>
<lon>0.0998790051218575</lon>
<gazetteerText>LEAKE, a parish in Boston district, Lincoln; on the East Lincoln railway, the Hobhole drain, and the coast, 7 miles NE of Boston. It contains Old Leake r. station and New Leake village, and has a post office under Boston. Acres, 7, 655; of which 1, 775 are fen. Real property, &#163;15, 312. Pop. in 1811, 922; in 1851, 2, 062; in 1861, 1, 912. Houses, 376. The increase of pop. from 1811 to 1851 arose chiefly from the enclosure of 1, 537 acres in the East Fen. The property is much subdivided, but is largely held by four. Moat House, about 1&#189; mile E of the church, occupies the site of an ancient chantry; was rebuilt, in 1835, by the Hon.B. Percy; and contains wainscotted rooms, and some curious carving. Derby Hall, at a short distance, is a large ancient mansion. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;200. * Patrons, the Governors of Oakham and Uppingham schools. The church has a clerestoried nave, partly later English, but chiefly decorated, and a tower built in 1490-1547; and contains three sedilia, an octagonal font, and an alabaster effigies of a knight. There are two Wesleyan chapels, a Primitive Methodist chapel, a British school, and charities &#163;150. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Leake/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Leake</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641012</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10429869</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LEAKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429870</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEAKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429894</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>OLD LEAKE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12789</id>
<name>LEA</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3696495170442</lat>
<lon>-0.75470571539629</lon>
<gazetteerText>LEA, a parish in Gainsborough district, Lincoln; on the Gainsborough and Lincoln railway, adjacent to the river Trent, at the boundary with Notts, 2&#188; miles SSE of Gainsborough. It has a post office under Gainsborough. Acres, 2, 149. Real property, &#163;3, 396. Pop., 194. Houses, 39. The property, with the manor and Lea Hall, belongs to Sir Charles H. J. Anderson, Bart. A Cistertian nunnery was founded in 1180, at Hevening or Heyning, by Reyner Evermere; and has left some traces. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;450. * Patron, SirH. J. Anderson, Bart. The church is early English, was recently restored, has a tower, and contains an altar tomb to Sir Ralph de Trehampton, and some other monuments. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Lea/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644765</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10429821</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429833</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEA</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7537</id>
   <name>LITTLEBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11812</id>
   <name>GATE BURTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12772</id>
   <name>KNAITH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12998</id>
   <name>MARTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>12791</id>
<name>NEW LEAKE</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0915796802128</lat>
<lon>0.0878854968399393</lon>
<gazetteerText>Leake.-- coast par., Lincolnshire, partly within the parl. limits of Boston, 9514 ac. (1775 water), pop. 2120; contains Old Leake, vil. with ry. sta., 7 miles NE. of Boston; P.O., T.O.; and New Leake, vil., 3 miles NE. of Old Leake sta.; P.O. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301736</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10429882</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>NEW LEAKE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12175</id>
   <name>EASTVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13007</id>
   <name>MIDVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
