<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13403</id>
<name>OWSTON FERRY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4930419534015</lat>
<lon>-0.788675875646212</lon>
<gazetteerText>OWSTON, a village, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Gainsborough district, Lincoln. &apos; The village stands in the Isle of Axholme, near the river Trent, 3&#189; miles S E of Epworth, 3&#189; E of Haxey r. station, and 7 N of Gainsborough; and is a pleasant place. The township contains also the small market-town and port of West Ferry, Kinnards-Ferry, or Owston-Ferry; which has a post-office, of the name of Owston-Ferry, &#8225; under Bawtry. Real property, &#163;8, 957. Pop. in 1851, 1, 693; in 1861, 1, 585. Houses, 382. The parish contains also the township of West Butterwick-with-Kelfield, and part of the township of East Ferry; and extends 9 miles along the Trent, from the boundary with Notts to the parish of Althorpe. Acres, exclusive of the part of East Ferry, 5, 350. Real property, exc. of the part of East Ferry, &#163;13, 952. Pop. of the whole, in 1851, 2, 613; in 1861, 2, 520. Houses, 592. The property is much subdivided. Owston Place is the seat of J. Walker, Esq. Owston Wood is a meet for the Cottesmore hounds. A brewery, a ropery, a boat-building yard, a brick and tile yard, an oil-cake mill, several corn mills, and packing and sail-cloth manufactories are at West Ferry; and the Trent iscrossed there by means of ferry-boats. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Chester. The church is a handsome stone building, in pointed architecture; has, of late years, been considerably improved; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; has a rich stained-glass E window, put up in 1836; and is approached through a beautiful arch, recently erected, and through a fine avenue. The p. curacy of West Butterwick is a separate benefice. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a Wesleyan day-school, and endowed alms-houses at Owston; a Primitive Methodist chapel, a United Free Methodist chapel, and two well-attended schools, at West Ferry; and a national school adjoining West Ferry. The sub-district excludes the part of East Ferry township, but includes the parish of Haxey. Acres, 13, 820 Pop., 4, 649. Houses, 1,094. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Owston/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640740</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10446405</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>OWSTON FERRY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446430</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OWSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10563719</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OWSTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11738</id>
   <name>BLYTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11830</id>
   <name>WEST BUTTERWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12218</id>
   <name>EAST FERRY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12352</id>
   <name>GREENHILL AND REDHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12788</id>
   <name>LAUGHTON BY GAINSBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13951</id>
   <name>THONOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14073</id>
   <name>WILDSWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
