<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13501</id>
<name>REVESBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1146847061398</lat>
<lon>-0.0651720281832673</lon>
<gazetteerText>REVESBY, a village and a parish in Horncastle district, Lincoln. The village stands 6 miles S by E of Horncastle r. station, and has a post-office under Boston The parish contains also the hamlets of Medlam, Moor-houses, and Tumby-Wood. Acres, 4, 660. Real property, &#163;7, 315. Pop., 614. Houses, 125. The property is divided among a few. The manor, with R. Abbey, belongs to J. B. Stanhope, Esq. A Cistertianabbey was founded here, in 1142, by William de Romara; was given, at the dissolution, to the Duke of Suffolk; and passed to the Bankses and the Stanhopes. The abbot&apos;shouse was the seat of Sir Joseph Banks. The presentmansion, called the Abbey, is an edifice in the Tudor style, after designs by Burns. There is an ancient camp, engirt with a wide fosse, and measuring 300 feet by 100; and at each end of it is a tumulus 100 feet in diameter. A navigation goes from the parish to Boston. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;200.* Patron, J. B. Stanhope, Esq. The church was rebuilt in 1730. There are a national school, alms-houses with &#163;50 a year, and other charities &#163;4. The school was built in 1858, at a cost of about &#163;1,000; and is in the Tudor style. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Revesby/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639475</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10448815</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>REVESBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10448827</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>REVESBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
