<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12688</id>
<name>SOUTH KELSEY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4744503707521</lat>
<lon>-0.417294166855266</lon>
<gazetteerText>KELSEY (SOUTH), a village and a parish in Caistor district, Lincoln. The village stands near the head of the Ancholme navigation, 2 miles W by S of Moortown r. station, and 6 WSW of Caistor; and has a post office under Caistor. The parish contains also the hamlet of Moortown, and comprises 4, 980 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 921. Pop., 633. Houses, 127. The property is all in one estate. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;600. Patron, alternately the Crown and G. B. Skipworth, Esq. There formerly were two churches and two parishes, St. Mary and St. Nicholas. St. Nicholas&apos; church has gone to ruin. St. Mary&apos;s church is a neat modern edifice, with an ancient tower, and has been extensively repaired. There are two chapels for Wesleyans, one for Primitive Methodists, and a national school. Bishop Ayscough, the confessor of Henry VI., and Anne Askew, the martyr, were natives. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Kelsey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637396</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/SouthKelsey/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10427198</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SOUTH KELSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427216</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH KELSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427241</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>SOUTH KELSEY ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427253</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH KELSEY ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427265</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>SOUTH KELSEY ST NICHOLAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427277</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOUTH KELSEY ST NICHOLAS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
