<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12479</id>
<name>GUNBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7802410823681</lat>
<lon>-0.655930985390444</lon>
<gazetteerText>GUNBY ST. NICHOLAS, a parish in Grantham district, Lincoln; on the SW verge of the county, 6 miles SW of Corby r. station, and 10 S of Grantham. Posttown, Colsterworth, under Grantham. Acres, 66s. Real property, &#163;1, 669. Pop., 164. Houses, 34. The manor belongs to the Earl of Dysart. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Stainby, in the diocese of Lincoln. The church comprises nave and chancel, with later English tower. Charities, &#163;6. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/GunbyStNicholas</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7295526</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10422243</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GUNBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10422255</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GUNBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10422280</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>GUNBY AND STAINBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12480</id>
<name>GUNBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1713303046063</lat>
<lon>0.203740088092704</lon>
<gazetteerText>GUNBY ST. PETER, a parish in Spilsby district Lincoln; adjacent to the Burgh station of the East Lincoln railway, 5 miles E by N of Spilsby. Post town, Burgh, under Boston. Acres, 606. Real property, &#163;1.187. Pop., 82. Houses, 18. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Algernon Massingberd, Esq. Gunby Park is the seat of John H. Holloway, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;170. Patron, the Rev. H. Windsor. The church was rebuilt in the beginning of last century; consists of nave and chancel, with a tower; has a brass of Sir Thomas Massingberd and his lady; and was recently in disrepair. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/GunbyStPeter/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10422267</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GUNBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10422279</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GUNBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
