<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12949</id>
<name>LUDBOROUGH</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4444480020423</lat>
<lon>-0.0486012665952505</lon>
<gazetteerText>LUDBOROUGH, a village, a parish, and a wapentake, in Lincoln. The village stands near the East Lincoln railway, 5&#189; miles NNW of Louth; occupies the site of a Roman settlement; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Louth. The parish is in Louth district, and comprises 2,250 acres. Real property, &#163;3,190. Pop., 401. Houses, 85. The manor belongs to the trustees of J. Livesey, Esq. The manor-house is very ancient, but has been modernized, and is now occupied by a farmer. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;590. Patron, R. Thorold, Esq. The church is a very fine early English structure; was well restored in 1860; comprises nave, aisles, and chancel, with a three-storied tower; contains a double piscina, foliated water-drains, and a circular-arched old aumbrie; and was found, while being restored, to contain a sepulchral slab of the 14th century, bearing an incised cross. There are chapels for Wesleyans, Primitive Methodists, and United Free Methodists, and a new Church of England school.-The wapentake contains also nine other parishes. Acres, 12,931. Pop., 1,892. Houses, 407. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Ludborough/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643440</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10030810</id>
   <status>Wap</status>
   <name>LUDBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10434373</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LUDBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10434397</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LUDBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10576581</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LUDBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12539</id>
   <name>HAWERBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14107</id>
   <name>WYHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
