<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11573</id>
<name>BINBROOK</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4196736556688</lat>
<lon>-0.160657468939423</lon>
<gazetteerText>BINBROOK, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict in the district of Louth, Lincoln. The village stands on the river Ancholme, at the foot of the Wolds, 8 miles ENE of Market-Raisen r. station; and has a post office&#8225; under Market-Raisen. It was formerly a market-town, and a place of some note; but has considerably decayed. The parish consists of two quondam parishes, Binbrook St. Gabriel and Binbrook St. Mary, united by act of parliament; and is held by some to include the hamlet of Orford, which others regard as extra-parochial. Acres, 6,070. Real property, &#163;8,092. Pop., 1,334. Houses, 277. The property is divided among a few. The manor Belongs toTurnor, Esq. There are extensive rabbit warrens. The living is a rectory and a vicarage-St. Mary a rectory, St. Gabriel a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;291. Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church of St. M. is bad; and that of St. G. is in ruins. There are three Methodist chapels, a temperance hall, a national school, a reading room, a police station, and a church estate &#163;83.-The subdistrict contains fourteen parishes and two extra-parochial tracts. Pop., 4,468. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Binbrook/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binbrook</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655650</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10398423</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BINBROOK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10398460</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BINBROOK ST GABRIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10398472</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BINBROOK ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10398496</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BINBROOK ST MARY AND ST GABRIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547647</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BINBROOK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12845844</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>BINBROOK ST GABRIEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12845856</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>BINBROOK ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13343</id>
   <name>WOLD NEWTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13908</id>
   <name>SWINHOPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
