<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12523</id>
<name>HARLAXTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8878257673891</lat>
<lon>-0.684520886874842</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARLAXTON, a village and a parish in Grantham district, Lincoln. The village stands near the Nottingham and Grantham canal, 3 miles SW by S of Grantham; and has a post-office under Grantham. The parish comprises 2,530 acres. Real property, &#163;5,242; of which &#163;22 are in the canal. Pop., 488. Houses, 98. The manor belonged to John of Gaunt, who had a hunting-seat on it; and passed to the Blewitts, the De Lignes, the Listers, and the Gregorys. The old manor-house was built by the Blewitts, in the time of Henry VII.; was considerably enlarged by the De Lignes, in the time of James I.; was a fine specimen of Tudor architecture; was defended by a moat: had many stained windows and interesting portraits; and was taken down in 1858. The new manor-house, Harlaxton Hal, is a recent edifice, after designs by Salvin, in the style of the time of James I.; and belongs to T. Sherwin Gregory, Esq. A helmet of gold, set with jewels, and supposed to have belonged to John of Gaunt, was found in a field near the village, and is now in the Madrid museum. An urn, containing Roman coins, and burnt bones, was found in 1740. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;760. * Patron, the Prebendary of South Grantham. The church is ancient; consists of nave, chancel, and aisles, with tower and spire; underwent recent restoration in the chancel, with addition of a porch; and contains a later English font, and a canopied monument, with two alabaster effigies. There are a national school, and charities &#163;6. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Harlaxton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harlaxton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647472</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10423259</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HARLAXTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10423260</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARLAXTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13781</id>
   <name>STROXTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
