<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12790</id>
<name>LEADENHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0602300999553</lat>
<lon>-0.589463863987781</lon>
<gazetteerText>LEADENHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Sleaford district, Lincoln. The village stands on the Lincoln and Grantham railway, 2&#190; miles W of Erminestreet, and 8&#190; NW of Sleaford; is a pleasant place, and a seat of petty sessions; and has a station on the railway, a post office under Grantham, and a fair in May.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlet of Lowfield, and a recently annexed place called Maiden House. Acres, with Beyards-Leap extra-parochial tract, 2, 260. Real property, &#163;6, 645. Pop., 688. Houses, 141. The property is divided among a few. The manor, with Leadenham House and much of the land, belongs to Colonel John Reeve. A spring called St. Ann&apos;s Well, and a barrow, are near the village. A cliff, commanding a very extensive view, is near Leadenham House. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;800.* Patron, the Rev. O. Smith. The church is decorated English; was restored in 1861; and has a pinnacled tower and a crocketted spire. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a school with &#163;20 a year from endowment, and charities &#163;84.&#151;The sub-district contains seven parishes and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 19, 202. Pop., 3, 940. Houses, 793. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Leadenham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leadenham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644752</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10429845</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LEADENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429857</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LEADENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10565080</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LEADENHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
