<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12224</id>
<name>EAST FIRSBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3581716350772</lat>
<lon>-0.473592570394522</lon>
<gazetteerText>FIRSBY (East), a township and a parish in the district and county of Lincoln. The township lies on the Wolds, 5 miles W of Market-Rasen r. station. Real property, &#163;746. Pop., 47. Houses, 7. The parish contains also the township of West Firsby; and its post town is Glentham, under Market-Rasen. Acres, 2, 292. Real property, &#163;2, 086. Pop., 108. Houses, 17. The living is a rectory, annexed to the vicarage of Saxby, in the diocese of Lincoln. The church is in ruins. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/EastFirsby/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10415433</id>
   <status>Ch/AP/CP</status>
   <name>EAST FIRSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10415445</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EAST FIRSBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12223</id>
<name>FIRSBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1448278140994</lat>
<lon>0.177207936470376</lon>
<gazetteerText>FIRSBY, a parish in Spilsby district, Lincoln; on the river Steeping and the Great Northern railway, 2 miles SSW of Burgh, and 4 SE of Spilsby. It has a station with telegraph on the railway; at the junction of the Spilsby branch. Post town, Burgh, under Boston. Acres, 910. Real property, &#163;2, 201. Pop., 237. Houses, 53. The living is a rectory, united with the vicarage of Great Steeping, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;242. Patron, the Rev. Joseph Walls. The church was recently restored. There are a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;13. Bishop Warburton was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Firsby/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firsby</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649384</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10415410</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FIRSBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10415421</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FIRSBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12225</id>
<name>WEST FIRSBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3545284394485</lat>
<lon>-0.505845370535868</lon>
<gazetteerText>FIRSBY (West), a township in East Firsby parish, Lincoln. Real property, &#163;1, 340. Pop., 61. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7295581</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10415457</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>WEST FIRSBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
