<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12286</id>
<name>FRISKNEY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0617424511371</lat>
<lon>0.206251988533709</lon>
<gazetteerText>FRISKNEY, a village and a parish in Spilsby district, Lincoln. The village stands near the coast, 3 miles ESE of East Ville r. station, and 4 SW of Wainfleet; and has a post office under Boston. The parish comprises 7, 003 acres of land, and 6, 080 of water. Real property, &#163;14, 177. Pop., 1, 604. Houses, 344. The property is divided among a few. A large tract of the land was drained, inclosed, and embanked, under an act of 1809. So many as upwards of 30, 000 head of ducks, widgeon, and teal were annnally sent from decoys in this tract, previous to the reclamation; but the number afterwards scarcely amounted to 5, 000. From 2, 000 to 4, 000 pecks of cranberries also were annually gathered from Cranberry fen; but, after the drainage of the tract, the gathering of them almost ceased. Friskney Flat is a long reach of sand, alternately covered and left bare by the tide. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;518.* Patron, John Booth, Esq. The church comprises a south porch, a nave of five bays, and a chancel; contains a carved oaken pulpit of 1659, a chancel-screen, and an octagonal font; and was recently in disrepair. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists. An endowed school has &#163;68; and other charities, &#163;10. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Friskney/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649045</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10416840</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FRISKNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10416863</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FRISKNEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
