<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11499</id>
<name>BARDNEY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2198423043308</lat>
<lon>-0.306638320984382</lon>
<gazetteerText>BARDNEY, a village and a parish in the district and county of Lincoln. The village stands on the river Witham, adjacent to the Lincoln and Boston railway, 5&#189; miles E by S of Lincoln; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Wragby. It dates from ancient times; and was called by the Saxons Bardanig or Bealthanig. The parish includes also the hamlet of Southrow. Acres, 5, 490. Real property, &#163;8, 653. Pop., l,425. Houses, 298. An abbey was founded, about &#189; a mile west of the village, in 697, by Ethelred, king of Mercia; who himself afterwards became abbot of it till his death. It is said to have had 300 monks; but was destroyed, in 870, by the Danes; lay in ruins upwards of 200 years; was re-edified, in the time of William the Conqueror, for Benedictine monks, by Gilbert de Gaunt, Earl of Lincoln; and passed, at the dissolution, to Sir Robert Tirwhit. The later abbots were styled Lords of Lindsey, and were peers in parliament. Not a vestige of the edifice now exists. A large barrow occurs in theneighbourhood, said to have been the grave of King Ethelred; and is surmounted by a modern cross, erected to his memory. The parish is a meet for the Burton hounds. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Lincoln. The church consists of nave, aisle, chancel, and tower. There are three Wesleyan chapels. A free school has &#163;136, and other charities &#163;70. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Bardney/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bardney</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656359</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10396463</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BARDNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10396475</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARDNEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11523</id>
   <name>BAUMBER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12188</id>
   <name>EDLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12328</id>
   <name>GOULCEBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12552</id>
   <name>HENINGBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12639</id>
   <name>HORSINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12786</id>
   <name>LANGTON BY WRAGBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13010</id>
   <name>MINTING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13645</id>
   <name>SOTBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13661</id>
   <name>STAINFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14103</id>
   <name>WRAGBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
