<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13329</id>
<name>NAVENBY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1101181006901</lat>
<lon>-0.531695411237934</lon>
<gazetteerText>NAVENBY, a village and parish in the district and county of Lincoln. The village stands near Ermine-street, and near the Bourn and Lincoln railway, whichwas in course of formation in 1867, 2&#190; miles E of the river Brant, and 9 S of Lincoln; is a polling-place for the parts of Kesteven; was formerly a market-town, with an ancient cross; and has a post-office under Grantham, a pleasure fair on the Thursday before Easter, and abusiness fair on 17 Oct. The parish comprises 2, 110 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 622; of which &#163;20 are in gas-works. Pop. in 1851, 1,057; in 1861, 1, 170. Houses, 241. The manor belongs to the Dean and Chapter of Lincoln. The area extends to the river Brant; and isdiversified by the South Cliff hills, which command an extensive view. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;588.* Patron, Christ College, Cambridge. The church is partly early English, partly decorated; is large and handsome; and has a tower. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a parochial school with &#163;133 a year from endowment, and charities &#163;68. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Navenby/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641861</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10444305</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NAVENBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10444317</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NAVANBY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11742</id>
   <name>BOOTHBY GRAFFOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11955</id>
   <name>COLEBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12525</id>
   <name>HARMSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13914</id>
   <name>TEMPLE BRUER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14054</id>
   <name>WELLINGORE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
