<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>903</id>
<name>BARTON UPON HUMBER</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6761475801512</lat>
<lon>-0.44426144660091</lon>
<gazetteerText>BARTON-UPON-HUMBER, a town and two parishes in Glanford-Brigg district, Lincoln. The town stands on a rising-ground, about &#190; of a mile from the Humber, at the terminus of a branch of the Lincolnshire railway, 5 miles westward from New Holland, and 6 WSW of Hull. It occupies the site of a Roman station; and was a place of considerable commerce in the time of the Conqueror; but suffered much when Edward I. made Hull a free borough. It consists principally of spacious but irregularly built streets, and contains some good modern houses.-St. Peter&apos;s church is a large edifice, of nave, aisles, and chancel, chiefly in decorated English, with a tower partly Saxon, partly early Norman; and was renovated in 1859 at a cost of about &#163;1,400. St. Mary&apos;s church is a structure of probably the 14th century. There are three dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a national school, charities &#163;250, a newspaper, a head post office, &#8225; a banking office, and two chief inns. A weekly market is held on Monday; and a fair on Trinity Thursday. A good trade exists in corn and flour; manufactures are carried on in ropes, sacking, bricks, tiles, pottery, and malt; and quarrying is done in chalk and oolite. The town is a coastguard station, a seat of petty sessions, and a polling-place. The two parishes are St. Peter and St. Mary. They are regarded politically as conterminate with the town, yet comprise 6,710 acres of land and 1,430 of water. Real property, &#163;16,799. Pop. of St. Peter, 1,672. Houses, 384. Pop. of St. Mary, 2,185. Houses, 504. The property in both is much subdivided. The manor belonged at one time to Lord Beaumont, and afterwards to the Crown. Remains of ramparts and other works, raised for defence in the Saxon times, occur at Castle Dykes. The livings are jointly a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;250.* Patron, G.Uppleby, Esq. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656206</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barton-upon-Humber</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Barton/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10111262</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BARTON UPON HUMBER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10167050</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BARTON UPON HUMBER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173061</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>BARTON UPON HUMBER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10396761</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BARTON UPON HUMBER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10396815</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARTON ON HUMBER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10396827</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BARTON UPON HUMBER ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10396840</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARTON UPON HUMBER ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10396852</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BARTON UPON HUMBER ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10396876</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARTON UPON HUMBER ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548070</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12831961</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BARTON UPON HUMBER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12216</id>
   <name>SOUTH FERRIBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
