<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>865</id>
<name>MARKET RASEN</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3818880029071</lat>
<lon>-0.328847316385711</lon>
<gazetteerText>RASEN, or Market-Rasen, a town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Caistor district, Lincoln. The town stands on the river Rasen, and on the Hull and Lincoln railway, 15 miles N E by N of Lincoln; consists chiefly of one long street, intersected at right angles by smaller streets; is a seat of petty sessions, and a polling-place; and has a head post-office, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, two banking offices, three chief inns, a police station, a public-hall, a corn exchange, a church, three dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a new cemetery with chapels, a national school, an endowed school with &#163;17 a year, alms-houses with &#163;40, and other charities &#163;53. The church is later English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and contains several monuments. The Roman Catholic chapel was built in 1824, and is a neat edifice. A corn and provision market is held on every Tuesday; a cattle-market, on every alternate Tuesday from Palm Sunday till Michaelmas; fairs for cattle, sheep, and horses, on thefourth Tuesday in Lent, and on 25 Sept.; and races, on the Monday after 25 Sept. There are breweries, maltings, a steam saw-mill, an iron foundry, and brickfields. Pop. in 1861, 2, 468. Houses, 536. The parish comprises 1, 220 acres. Real property, &#163;7, 348; of which &#163;92are in gas-works. Pop. in 1851, 2, 110; in 1861, 2, 563. Houses, 554. The manor belongs to Capt. W.Gordon. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;223.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor.&#151;The sub-district contains also 25 other parishes. Acres, 56, 138. Pop. in 1851, 9, 658; in 1861, 10, 224. Houses, 2, 138. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/MarketRasen/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Market_Rasen</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643023</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10029211</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>MARKET RASEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10153827</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MARKET RASEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10448190</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MARKET RASEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10448207</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARKET RASEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547740</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MARKET RASEN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11502</id>
   <name>EAST BARKWITH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11566</id>
   <name>BENNIWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12207</id>
   <name>FALDINGWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12751</id>
   <name>KIRKBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12795</id>
   <name>LEGSBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12917</id>
   <name>LINWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12920</id>
   <name>LISSINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13473</id>
   <name>MIDDLE RASEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13475</id>
   <name>WEST RASEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14071</id>
   <name>WICKENBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
