<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12326</id>
<name>GOSBERTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8570223117166</lat>
<lon>-0.184709661772512</lon>
<gazetteerText>GOSBERTON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Spalding district, Lincoln. The village stands near Risegate drain, 2&#189; miles WNW of Surfleet and Gosberton r. station, and 6 N by W of Spalding; and has a post office&#8225; under Spalding. The parish includes also the hamlets of Cheal, Rightbolt, Westhorpe, and part of Risegate. Acres, 8, 820. Real property, &#163;19, 826. Pop., 2, 107. Houses, 453. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;150.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Lincoln. The church is cruciform and interesting; includes a chapel of the Blessed Sacrament on the S side of the . chancel; has a tower, with fine groined roof, and a beautiful octagonal spire; contains sedilia, rood stairs, and effigies of a knight and lady; and was recently in disrepair. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Free Methodists, a school with &#163;28 from endowments, and other charities with &#163;74.&#151;The sub-district includes also Surfleet parish. Acres, 12, 320. Pop., 3, 060. Houses, 662. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Gosberton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gosberton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648279</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10418045</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GOSBERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418069</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GOSBERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547945</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>GOSBERTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24043</id>
<name>GOSBERTON CLOUGH</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8510838699449</lat>
<lon>-0.217776353087999</lon>
<unit>
   <id>10418070</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GOSBERTON CLOUGH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
