<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14028</id>
<name>ULCEBY BY ALFORD</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2319642366463</lat>
<lon>0.132175934634562</lon>
<gazetteerText>ULCEBY, a parish in Spilsby district, Lincoln; 2&#189; miles SW of Alford r. station. Post town, Alford. Acres, 2,220. Real property, &#163;1,622. Pop., 212. Houses, 38. The manor belongs to Capt. Mansell. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;650.* Patron, the Rev. W. A. Peacock. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635206</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10462540</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ULCEBY WITH FORDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10462575</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ULCEBY WITH FORDINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>14027</id>
<name>ULCEBY BY BARTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.6178350655781</lat>
<lon>-0.329283272521419</lon>
<gazetteerText>ULCEBY, a parish in Glanford-Brigg district, Lincoln; on the Manchester and Lincolnshire railway, at the forking of the lines toward New Holland and Great Grimsby, 7 miles S by E of New Holland. It contains U.-Skilter, and has there a head post-office&#8225; of the name of Ulceby, and a r. station with telegraph; and contains also Ulceby village, 1&#188; mile from the r. station, and has there a post-office, of the name of Ulceby Village, under Ulceby. Acres, 3,790. Real property, &#163;5,954. Pop., 1,048. Houses, 228. The property is much sub-divided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;316.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church was recently restored, and has a lofty spire. There are two Methodist chapels, and an endowed school with &#163;29 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Ulceby/</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/UlcebyBarton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ulceby</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635205</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10462514</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ULCEBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10462538</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ULCEBY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
