<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12535</id>
<name>HAUGHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3125410514396</lat>
<lon>0.00999872647865393</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAUGHAM, a parish in Louth district, Lincoln; 3 miles Sw of Legbourne r. station, and 4 S of Louth. Post town, Louth. Acres, 1, 907. Real property, &#163;1, 848. Pop., 115. Houses, 23. The property is all in one estate, and belongs to Henry Chaplin, Esq. An alien priory, a cell to the Benedictine abbey of St. Mary San Chester; was transferred, in the time of Richard II., to the Carthusian priory of St. Ann, near Coventry; and was given, at the dissolution, to J. Bellow and J. Broxholme. A rivulet, called Skirbeck, issues from a hill in this parish; has the capacity of a torrent for several weeks after heavy rain; and ceases to flow in dry weather. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;176.* Patron, H. Chaplin, Esq. The church was rebuilt in 1840, at a cost of &#163;2, 500; is in the pointed style; and consists of nave and chancel, with tower and crocketted spire. A neat parsonage was erected in 1861. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Haugham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647330</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10423521</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HAUGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10423557</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAUGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12534</id>
<name>HAUGH</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2599922806707</lat>
<lon>0.123651077091934</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAUGH, an extra-parochial tract, but in some respects a parish, in Louth district, Lincoln; 2&#189; miles W by S of Alford r. station. Post town, Alford. Acres, 640. Real property, &#163;672. Pop., 17. Houses, 2. One of the houses is a spacions red brick edifice, of the time of Henry VII.; was long the seat of the Haugh family, afterwards the seat of the Bolles; and is now a farmhouse. The living is a vicarage in tlie diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;72. Patrons, Misses Horsefall. Tha church contains several ancient monuineuts. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Haugh/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301723</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10423508</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HAUGH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
