<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11571</id>
<name>BILLINGHAY</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0859686512192</lat>
<lon>-0.257114878233726</lon>
<gazetteerText>BILLINGHAY, a parish in Sleaford and Boston districts, and a subdistrict in Sleaford district, Lincoln. The parish lies on Billinghay Skirt, 3&#189; miles WSW of Tattershall r. station, and 8&#189; NE of Sleaford. It includes the township of Dogdyke, and the hamlet of Walcott; and has a post office&#8225; under Sleaford. Acres, 7,630. Real property, &#163;17,794. Pop., 2,247. Houses, 477. The property is much subdivided. Billinghay Skirt is a cut 5 miles long, from the Sleaford canal to the river Witham. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Walcott, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;280.* Patron, Earl Fitzwilliam. The church has Norman arches, and is good. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists.-The subdistrict comprises five parishes, parts of two other parishes, and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, returned with Sleaford subdistrict. Pop., 5,423. Houses, 1,100. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655663</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Billinghay</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Billinghay/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10398381</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BILLINGHAY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10398393</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BILLINGHAY WITH WALCOT AND DOGDYKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547908</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BILLINGHAY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12043</id>
   <name>DOGDYKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13969</id>
   <name>THORPE TILNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14049</id>
   <name>WALCOT NEAR BILLINGHAY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
