<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>647</id>
<name>SUTTON BRIDGE</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7943902562512</lat>
<lon>0.200370201458719</lon>
<gazetteerText>SUTTON-BRIDGE, a small town and a chapelry in Long Sutton parish, Lincoln. The town stands on the river Nen, 3 miles above its influx to the Wash, and on the Wisbeach and Lynn railway, 7&#189; miles N by E of Wisbeach; originated in the construction of a bridge in 1831; is a sub-port, with a good quay and warehouses; consists chiefly of a long one-sided street, with one or two short streets, and several genteel detached residences; carries on commerce in corn, coal, timber, and other goods; and has a post-office&#8225; under Wisbeach, a r. station with telegraph, a hotel, a custom-house, and a coastguard station. The original bridge was superseded, in 1850, at a cost of more than &#163;20,000, by a large iron swing bridge. The depth of water, at full tide, close to the bridge, is sufficient to float a man-of-war. A lofty embanked road goes from the bridge along the Cross-Keys Wash; and occasioned the reclamation of many thousand acres of land from the sea.&#151;The chapelry was constituted in 1845. Pop. in 1861, 1,565. Houses, 319. About two-thirds of the houses, and nearly all the land, belong to Guy&apos;s Hospital, London. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;200 Patron, the Bishop of L. The church was built in 1843, and is in the early English style. There are three dissenting chapels and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/SuttonBridge/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sutton_Bridge</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636487</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075282</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SUTTON BRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109255</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SUTTON BRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10458419</id>
   <status>CP/PA</status>
   <name>SUTTON BRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10458444</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SUTTON BRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3368</id>
   <name>WALPOLE ST ANDREW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14087</id>
   <name>CENTRAL WINGLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
