<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12281</id>
<name>FREISTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.968201011312</lat>
<lon>0.0648861089313453</lon>
<gazetteerText>FRIESTON, a hamlet and a parish in Boston district, Lincoln. The hamlet lies on the coast, 3&#188; miles E of Boston town and r. station; and has a post office under Boston. The parish includes also the hamlets of Frieston-Shore and Crane-End, and a fen allotment. Acres, 7, 410; of which 3, 430 are water. Real property, &#163;12, 998. Pop., 1, 239. Houses, 243. Pop. of the fen allotment, 180. Houses, 32. The property is much subdivided. Frieston-Shore lies 2&#189; miles S of Frieston hamlet; is a watering-place; and was designed, by a resolution of the shareholders of the Boston, Sleaford, and Midland Counties railway, in August 1862, to be put into communication, by a branch railway, with the port and railway station of Boston. The water there has a depth of 29 feet at ebb tide; and vessels trading to Boston could lie there at all times for loading and discharging. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Butterwick, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;380. Patron, L. Hitchon, Esq. The church belonged to a Benedictine cell of Crowland, founded here in 1114; was originally cruciform, but has lost its choir and transepts; is early perpendicular English in the clerestory of its nave; has a western tower, with stepped battlements; has also a Tudor tower, of brick, with groined crypts and octagonal turret, called the Kime or Richmond tower, after an ancient family who resided in the parish; contains an octagonal font, with rich carved cover, and a chancel-screen; and was recently in disrepair. A Wesleyan chapel was built in 1867. A school has &#163;9 from endowment: and other charities have &#163;121. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Freiston/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frieston</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649078</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10416681</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FREISTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10416693</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FREISTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
