<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14041</id>
<name>WAINFLEET</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1059353584354</lat>
<lon>0.237999204128682</lon>
<gazetteerText>WAINFLEET-ALL SAINTS, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Spilsby district, Lincoln. The town stands on the river Steeping, 3&#190; miles W by N of the river&apos;s month, 3&#190; SE of Firsby r. station, and 7&#190; SE of Spilsby: has been supposed, by some antiquaries, to occupy the site of a Roman station; sent a member to parliament in the time of Edward III.; was the birth-place of Bishop Patten, William of Waynflete, founder of Magdalen college, Oxford; was once a considerable sea-port, but suffered decline of its commerce by the partial silting-up of the reach of river between it and the sea; consists chiefly of one street, with a central market place; has undergone considerable recent improvement; and has a post-office&#8225; under Boston, a banking office, a church of 1820, two Methodist chapels, a grammar-school founded by Bishop Patten in 1484, national schools of 1857, a literary institution, charities &#163;15, a weekly market on Saturday, and four annual fairs. The parish comprises 1,598 acres. Real property, &#163;6,490; of which &#163;100 are in gasworks. Pop., 1,392. Houses, 302. The manor is held, under the Duchy of Lancaster, byB. Reynardson, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;322. Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The old church stood about 1&#189; mile from the town; and a national school of 1859, used as a chapel of ease, is now there.&#151;The sub-district contains 7 parishes. Acres, 37,673. Pop., 5,502. Houses, 1,172. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/WainfleetAllSaints/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wainfleet,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634914</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10210320</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WAINFLEET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10445516</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WAINFLEET ST THOMAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10462850</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WAINFLEET ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10462885</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WAINFLEET ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10462897</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WAINFLEET ALL SAINTS AND ST THOMAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547830</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WAINFLEET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12759400</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>WAINFLEET</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12675</id>
   <name>IRBY IN THE MARSH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13736</id>
   <name>LITTLE STEEPING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13968</id>
   <name>THORPE ST PETER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
