<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12546</id>
<name>HECKINGTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9891516392233</lat>
<lon>-0.255170891222225</lon>
<gazetteerText>HECKINGTON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Sleaford district, Lincoln. The village stands adjacent to the Boston and Grantham railway, 5 miles ESE of Sleaford; and has a station on the railway, a postoffice&#8225; under Sleaford, a police station, a temperance hall, a hotel, and fairs on the Wednesday before the Lincoln April fair and 10 Oct. The parish contains also the hamlets of Garwick and Oatsheaf, and the tract called Six Hundreds. Acres, 5, 720. Real property, &#163;11, 908. Pop. in 1851, 1, 581; in 1861, 1, 725. Houses, 383. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to Benjamin West Smith &apos;The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;340.* Patron, W. G. Allison, Esq. The church is decorated English, cruciform, and 172 feet long; has a W tower 98 feet high, surmounted by a spire 86 feet high; and contains ancient stall work, a fine hexagonal font, a double piscina, a rich Easter tomb, and an altar tomb and effigies of R. Potsgrove, who was vicar in 1307. An ancient market cross, formerly in the village, is now in the churchyard. There are a chapel of ease in the Fen, a Baptist chapel, two Wesleyan chapels, two national schools, and charities &#163;120.&#151;The sub-district contains eight parishes and part of another. Acres, 26, 189. Pop., 4, 366. Houses, 922. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Heckington/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heckington</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647200</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10423790</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HECKINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10423806</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HECKINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10423831</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HECKINGTON WITH HOWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10562582</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HECKINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
