<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12768</id>
<name>KIRTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9563466433856</lat>
<lon>-0.0899726317211027</lon>
<gazetteerText>KIRTON, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a wapentake in the parts of Holland, Lincoln. The village stands near the Peterborough and Boston railway, 4 miles SSW of Boston; is a large place; was once a market town; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Boston.&#151;The parish contains also Kirton-Fen, and the township of Brothertoft. Acres, 5, 820. Real property, &#163;22, 177. Pop., 2, 255. Houses, 484. The property is much subdivided. Kirton House is the seat of S. Smeeton, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;304. * Patrons, the Mercers&apos; Company, London. The church was founded, in 1311, by Alexander de Blois; was a superb cruciform structnre, in decorated English; became much dilapidated toward the end of last century; was shorn of its transepts, and its Lady chapel in 1809; was, at the same time, partially rebuilt on a smaller scale; has a fine early English W arch, and a later English clerestory of twelve three light windows on each side; and contains an octagonal font of 1405. The donative of Brotherstoft is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Independents and Methodists, a free grammar school, alms houses, and some other charities. The grammar school was originally a free school, founded and endowed in 1624 by Sir Thomas Middlecott; and was recently remodelled and rebuilt.&#151;The sub-district includes only 4, 920 acres of the parish, but contains two other parishes, parts of three more, and an extra-parochial tract; and is in the district of Boston. Acres, 31, 412. Pop., 5, 028. Houses, 1, 085.-The wapen take comprises sixteen parishes and part of another. Acres, 74, 892. Pop. in 1851, 16, 770: in 1861, 18, 938. Houses, 4, 075. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kirton,_Lincolnshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645181</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10177959</id>
   <status>Wap</status>
   <name>KIRTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429377</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>KIRTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429420</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KIRTON IN HOLLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547672</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KIRTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11399</id>
   <name>AMBER HILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11567</id>
   <name>BICKER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11768</id>
   <name>BROTHERTOFT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12045</id>
   <name>DONINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12279</id>
   <name>FRAMPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12492</id>
   <name>GREAT HALE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12782</id>
   <name>LANGRIVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13863</id>
   <name>SUTTERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13904</id>
   <name>SWINESHEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
