<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11562</id>
<name>BENINGTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.999173997694</lat>
<lon>0.0937767369413515</lon>
<gazetteerText>BENNINGTON, a parish and a subdistrict in Boston district, Lincoln. The parish lies on the Wash, 3 miles SSE of Sibsey r. station, and 5 ENE of Boston. It includes an allotment in the East Fen; and has a post office under Boston. Acres, 7,495; of which 4,405 are water. Real property, &#163;7,025. Pop., 588. Houses, 138. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;805.* Patron, the Earl of Ripon. The church has a perpendicular clerestoried nave, a fine tower, and a sculptured octagonal font. There are a Primitive Methodist chapel, an endowed school with &#163;90 a year, five alms-houses, and some other charities.-The subdistrict comprises four parishes, parts of three others, and the East Fen allotment of Boston. Acres, 50,285. Pop., 6,572. Houses, 1,340. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Benington/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655897</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10398101</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BENINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10398125</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BENINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547684</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BENINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>11563</id>
<name>LONG BENNINGTON</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.991925557474</lat>
<lon>-0.7674627161122</lon>
<gazetteerText>BENNINGTON (Long), a village and a parish in the district of Newark and county of Lincoln. The village stands on the river Witham, 3&#190; miles W by S of Hougham r. station, and 8 NW by N of Grantham; consists of one long street; and has a post office under Grantham. The parish, inclusive of Bennington Grange, comprises 4,420 acres. Real property, &#163;8,142. Pop., 1,066. Houses, 255. The property is subdivided. Freestone and lime are worked. A Cistertian priory, with local endowment, was founded here, before 1175, by Ralph de Filgeriis; given to the Abbey of Savigney in Normandy; transferred, by Richard II., to the Carthusians of St Ann, near Coventry; conveyed by Henry V. to the priory of Mountgrace; and given, at the dissolution, to the dean and chapter of Westminster. Remains of a moat, which surrounded its farmhouse, are in Bennington Grange. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Foston, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;463.* Patron, the Duchy of Lancaster. The church is good; and there are two Wesleyan chapels, a national school, and charities &#163;21. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/LongBennington/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_Bennington</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643720</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10398137</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LONG BENNINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10398162</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONG BENNINGTON WITH FOSTEN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7219</id>
   <name>ALVERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7354</id>
   <name>COTHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7394</id>
   <name>FLAWBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7484</id>
   <name>KILVINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7720</id>
   <name>ORSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7764</id>
   <name>STAUNTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12042</id>
   <name>DRY DODDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14055</id>
   <name>WESTBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>11564</id>
<name>BENNINGTON GRANGE</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9574736216664</lat>
<lon>-0.758654290257283</lon>
<gazetteerText>BENNINGTON GRANGE, an extra-parochial tract in the district of Newark and county of Lincoln; adjacent on the south to the parish of Long Bennington. Pop., 13. Houses, 3. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/BenningtonGrange/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10398174</id>
   <status>CP/ExP</status>
   <name>BENNINGTON GRANGE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
