<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11962</id>
<name>CORRINGHAM</name>
<container>LINCOLNSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4132253533276</lat>
<lon>-0.690618015626266</lon>
<gazetteerText>CORRINGHAM, two hamlets, a parish, and a wapentake in Lincoln. The hamlets are Great and Little Corringham, and lie about 2&#188; miles S by E of Blyton r. station, and 4 E by N of Gainsborough. The parish includes also the hamlets or villages of Aisby, Dunstall, Yawthorpe, and Somerby; and is in the district of Gainsborough. Post town, Blyton, under Gainsborough. Acres, 6, 189. Real property, &#163;7, 109. Pop., 717. Houses, 138. The property is divided among a few. Somerby Park is the seat of Sir Thomas Beckett, Bart. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;200.* Patron, the Bishop of Lincoln. The church belonged to the Templars; shows some Norman features; has stalls and a brass; and is good. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists. Charities, &#163;15. -The wapentake is in the parts of Lindsey; extends to the boundary with Notts; and contains fourteen parishes and parts of two others. Acres, 49, 209. Pop., 14, 190. Houses, 3, 139. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/LIN/Corringham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652331</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10187898</id>
   <status>Wap</status>
   <name>CORRINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10408489</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CORRINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10408490</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CORRINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10572034</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CORRINGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
