<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1807</id>
<name>HAREFIELD</name>
<container>MIDDLESEX</container>
<lat>51.6021309773377</lat>
<lon>-0.480843835235205</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAREFIELD, a village and a parish in Uxbridge district, Middlesex. The village stands near the Grand Junction canal, the river Colne, and the boundary with Bucks, 3&#190; miles N of Uxbridge r. station; was known at Domesday as Harefelle; and has a post-office under Uxbridge, and a police station. The parish comprises 4,513 acres. Real property, &#163;8,772. Pop., 1,567. Houses, 325. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged, in the time of Edward the Confessor, to the Countess Goda; at Domesday, to Richard, son of Earl Brion; in 1284, to Roger de Bacheworth; in 1315, to Simon de Swanland; in next generation and till 1585, to the Newdegates; in 1585, to Sir Edmund Anderson; in 1601, to Sir Thomas Egerton, Lord keeper of the Great Seal, and his wife, the Countess Dowager of Derby; in the next generation, to their son, Lord Chandos; and from 1675 till the present time has belonged again to the Newdegates. Harefield Place, on a site near the church, was long the manorial seat; received a state visit from Queen Elizabeth; had associations or connexious with Milton&apos;s &quot;Arcades&quot; and &quot;Comus;&quot; was burned down, in 1660, in the time of Lady Chandos; was rebuilt, soon after 1675, by Sir Richard Newdegate; and was taken down early in the present century. Harefield Place is now the seat of the Newdegates. Breakspere House took name from the family of Breakspere; was the residence of Nicholas Breakspere, who became Pope Adrian IV.; and is now the seat of William W. Drake, Esq. A monastic house, a cell to Clerkenwell priory, was founded in the parish by Alice de Clare, who probably held the manor prior to Roger de Bacheworth. The living is a donative in the diocese of London. Value, &#163;64.* Patron, C. N. Newdegate, Esq. The church is very ancient; belonged originally to either the Knights Templars or the Knights of St. John; underwent recent restoration and enlargement, at a cost of upwards of &#163;3,000; and contains an elegant monument to the Countess of Derby, and several ancient monuments to the Newdegates. There are national schools, alms-houses for six widows, and other charities &#163;73. Chief Justice Anderson was a resident. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harefield</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647487</link>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/MDX/Harefield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22353</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22359</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22358</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22351</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22352</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22355</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22356</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22350</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22354</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22357</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10021273</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HAREFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10053183</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HAREFIELD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
