<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5803</id>
<name>LLANELTUD</name>
<container>MERIONETHSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7820515512346</lat>
<lon>-3.92261831670352</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANELLTYD, or LLANYLTID, a village and a parish in Dolgelly district, Merioneth. The village stands on the river Maw, at the influx of the Wnion, amid magnificent scene, overhung by Cader Idris, 1&#188; mile NW of Dolgelly r. station; and has a post office under Corwen. Mr. Pratt says respecting the scenery,-&apos; &apos; Its beauties are so manifold and extraordinary that they literally beggar description; now pastures of the most exuberant fertility; now woods rising in all the majesty of foliage; the road itself curving in numberless unexpected directions, -at one moment shut into a verdant recess, so contracted that there seems neither carriage nor bridle way out of it,-at another the azure expanse of the main ocean filling the eye; on one side, rocks glittering in all the colours of that beauty which constitutes the sublime, and of a height which diminishes the wild herds that browse or look down upon yon from the summit, where the largest animal appears insignificantly minute; on the other hand, plains, villas, cottages, or copses, with whatever belongs to that milder grace which belongs to the beautiful. &apos;&apos;A main group of features in this scenery is presented by the near mass of Cader Idris, rearing its mighty head to the clouds, and sending down numerous offshoots, clothed with wood, to the edge of the water. The parish comprises 6,673 acres. Real property, &#163;1,838; of which &#163;60 are in mines. Pop., 465. Houses, 103. The property is subdivided. Much of the surface is upland; and a considerable portion is barren. Copper ore is found; and supplies of peat are obtained. Cymmer Abbey, which we have noticed in its own alphabetical place, is near the village. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;62. Patron, Sir R. W. Vaughan, Bart. The church is dedicated to St. Illtyd, and is good. There is a Calvinistic Methodist chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llanelltyd</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MER/Llanelltyd/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644099</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10207538</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANELTUD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
