<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2771</id>
<name>LLANFOR</name>
<container>MERIONETHSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9272404051732</lat>
<lon>-3.5880298010008</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANFAWR, or LLANFOR, a village and a parish in Bala district, Merioneth. The village stands on the river Dee, n ea r its efflux from Bala lake, and adjacent to the Corwen, Bala, and Dolgelly railway,-which was in course of formation in 1867,-1 mile NE of Bala; and has fairs on 14 Aug. and 20 Sept.&#151;The parish is divided into the townships of Bettws, Ciltalgarth, Garn, Llan, Nantllerdiog, Penmaen, Rhiwaedog-Isafon, Rhiwaedog-Uwchafon, and Uchedre. Post town, Bala, under Corwen. Acres, 20,030. Real property, &#163;8,235. Pop. in 1851,1,719; in 1861,1,531. Houses, 308. Most of the property is in one estate. Rhiwlas, a fine old mansion, is the seat of the Price family; and stands amid grounds traversed by the rapid rivulet Tryweryn, running to the Dee. A battle was fought within the parish between the Saxons and Llywarch-Hen. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. Asaph. Valne, &#163;306. *as. Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church is early English, in very bad condition; and contains monuments of the Prices. A new church was in contemplation in 1867. The p. curacy of Trinity, or of Rhos-y-Gwalia, is a separate benefice; and serves for a chapelry which was constituted in 1856, and had a pop. of 356 in 1861. Value, &#163;158. Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. A part of the chapelry of St. Mark, or of Fron-Goch, also is within the parish, and, in 1861, had a pop. of 413. A part of the chapelry of St. James, or Llawr-y-Bettws, constituted in 1863, likewise is within the parish. Charities, &#163;73. Llywerch-Hen, the poet and warrior, w ho lost 24 sons in battle, and died at the age of 150, is said to have been buried in the parish church. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MER/Llanfawr/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644056</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10077667</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANFOR</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
