<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1135</id>
<name>TYWYN</name>
<container>MERIONETHSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5872100698708</lat>
<lon>-4.08301847559895</lon>
<gazetteerText>TOWYN, a village and a parish in the district of Machynlleth and county of Merioneth The village stands on the coast, near the mouth of the river Dysyni, and on the Welsh Coast railway, 10&#188; miles S by W of Barmouth; is a sea-bathing resort and a polling place; presents a cleanly and pleasant appearance; and has a post-office,&#8225; designated Towyn, Merionethshire, a r. station, a hotel, baths, a cruciform ancient church, with fine early Norman nave, a very remarkable inscribed stone lying against the S wall of the church, four dissenting chapels, endowed schools with &#163;17 a year, alms houses with &#163;20, and four annual fairs. The parish contains several other villages; and includes seven townships and a part. Acres, 26,372; of which 2,230 are water. Real property, about &#163;10,927; of which &#163;130 are in mines, and &#163;13 in fisheries. Pop., 2,859. Houses, 634. Ynys-maengwyn and Craig-y-Deryn are chief residences. Trebeni Castle stood on a hill, and has been reduced to mere vestiges. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;224.* Patron, the Bishop of B. The p. curacy of Aberdovey is a separate benefice. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tywyn</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MER/Tywyn/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6559494</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10197569</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ABERDYFI</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10315451</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TYWYN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10315487</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>TYWYN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553489</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TOWYN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828160</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>TOWYN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
