<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6641</id>
<name>LLANUWCHLLYN</name>
<container>MERIONETHSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.845067720391</lat>
<lon>-3.70095468563099</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANUWCHYLLYN, a village and a parish in Bala district, Merioneth. The village stands on the rivulet Dwfrdwy, near the head of Bala lake, and near a railway which was in course of formation in 1866 from Corwen to Barmouth, amid a wild country under the Arrenig and Berwyn mountains, 5 miles SSW of Bala; and has a post office under Corwen, and fairs on 25 April, 20 June, 22 September, 16 October, and 22 November.&#151;The parish comprises the townships of Castell, Cynllwyd, Penanlliw, and Penarran. Acres, 12,000. Real property, &#163;4,692. Pop. in 1851, 1,264; in 1861,1,145. Houses, 263. The property is divided among a few. Slate is quarried; and a gold-mine was worked ion 1866-7. A waterfall is on the river Twrch, at Bwlchy-Grols pass. A Roman fortalice is supposed to have been at Caer-Gai; and Roman coins have been found there. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;200. Patron, Sir W. W. Wynn, Bart. The church is dedicated to St. Deiniol, contains the effigies of a knight, and was reported in 1859 as wretchedly uncomfortable. The name Llanuwychyllyn alludes to the church&apos;s situation in reference to Bala lake, and signifies &apos; &apos; the church above the lake. &apos;&apos;There are a Calvinistic Methodist chapel, an endowed school with &#163;25 a year, alms houses with &#163;42, and other charities &#163;29. R. Vaughan, the translator of the &apos; &apos; Practice of Piety, &apos;&apos;resided at Caer-Gai. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MER/Llanuwchllyn/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643930</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10237774</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANUWCHLLYN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
