<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5523</id>
<name>LLANABER</name>
<container>MERIONETHSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7578424550746</lat>
<lon>-4.01515240557512</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANABER, a parish in Dolgelly district, Merioneth; on the river Maw, Cardigan bay, and the Barmouth railways, around the town of Barmouth. It contains Barmouth town, with its head post office and railway station; and contains also the hamlets of Isymynydd and Uchmynydd. Acres, 12,679; of which 760 are water. Real property, &#163;6,354. Pop., 1,600. Houses, 382. The surface is hilly; and the rocks include lead and copper ores. Egyrn was once a friary, and is now a farm-house. The living is a rectory, united with the chapelry of Barmonth, in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;213. Patron, the Prince of Wales. The church stands 1&#190; mile N of Barmouth; is early English, with plain exterior; was, for many years, so greatly dilapidated as to be unfit for use; has been beautifully restored, after designs by Boyce; comprises clerestoried nave, aisles, and chancel; has a very fine interior, and an exquisite S doorway; and contains a curious chest which was used for receiving votive offerings. A church and three dissenting chapels are in Barmouth; and there are charities &#163;5. Four successive bards, of the name of Phillips, lived at Hendreo-Vechan. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MER/Llanaber/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644197</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10198100</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANABER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4948</id>
   <name>LLANBEDR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5569</id>
   <name>LLANDDWYWE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5625</id>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL Y PENNANT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11324</id>
   <name>LLANENDDWYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
