<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8229</id>
<name>MINFFRWD</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8135186333228</lat>
<lon>-3.34266948197837</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENNANT, or Pennant-Melangell, a township and a parish in Llanfyllin district, Montgomery. The township lies near the head of the river Tanat, under the Berwyn mountains, 9&#189; miles N W by W of Llanfyllin r.station. Real property, &#163;1, 418. The parish contains also the townships of Cornorion, Cwmllech, Dwyffrwd, Garthgelymen-fawr, Garthgelymenfechan, and Pangwern. Post-town, Llanfyllin. Acres, 5,000. Real property, &#163;3, 502. Pop., 712. Houses, 147. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Penybont, in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;185.* Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church is ancient but good; includes, in its S wall, four Norman capitals turned upside down; has a very primitive tower; and contains carved woodwork representing the legend of St. Monocella. Charities, &#163;7. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10282421</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Tn</status>
   <name>MINFFRWD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10290648</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>PENNANT MELANGELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23015</id>
<name>PENNANT</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5652268307036</lat>
<lon>-3.65256141589803</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENNANT, a township in Llanbrynmair parish, Montgomery; on the stream of the Ffrwd-y-Pennantwaterfall, 9&#189; miles N W of Llanidloes. Real property, &#163;1, 527; of which &#163;50 are in mines. Pop., 363. The waterfall here makes a descent of 130 feet. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/Pennant/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640441</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10290685</id>
   <status>Tn</status>
   <name>PENNANT</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
