<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2485</id>
<name>LLANFAIR CAEREINION</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.651085235957</lat>
<lon>-3.36669953614358</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANFAIR-CAEREINION, a small town and a parish in Llanfyllin district, Montgomery. The town stands on the river Einion, 8&#188; miles WSW of Welshpool r. station, and 11 NW of Montgomery; takes the latter part of its name from the ancient British camp of Castell-Caereinion, about 3 miles to the E; is neatly built and picturesquely situated; forms a good centre for anglers in the Banw, the Einion, and the Vyrnwy; is a seat of petty sessions and a polling-place; and has a post office,&#8225; under Welshpool, two good inns, a town hall, a church, five dissenting chapels, and charities &#163;6. The church is early English, contains the effigies of a knight, and was about to be restored in the early part of 1867. A weekly market is held on Saturday; and fairs are held on Shrove-Tuesday, the Saturday before Palm-Sunday, 18 May, 26 July, 3 Oct., 1 Nov., and the Friday before Christmas &apos;The parish contains the townships of Brynelen, Brynglas, Dolgead, Gelligasson, Gwaenynog, Heniarth, Kylyruclh Llanlodian-Isaf, Llanlodian-Uchaf, Penarth, Pentyrch, Rhewhirieth, and Rhosaflo. Acres, 16,157. Rated property, &#163;10,052. Pop. in 1851, 2,727; in 1861,2,584. Houses, 543. The property is subdivided. The surface is undulating, and rises toward the S into small hills. A Roman way traversed the parish; and numerous Roman coins and other relics were found in 1740. There are two woollen factories. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;358. * Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/LlanfairCaereinion/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Llanfair_Caereinion</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644084</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10060485</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANFAIR CAEREINION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10151030</id>
   <status>Tn</status>
   <name>LLANFAIR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553453</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANFAIR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2978</id>
   <name>ABERHAFESB</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4041</id>
   <name>LLANGADFAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5525</id>
   <name>LLANERFYL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6240</id>
   <name>GARTHBEIBIO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6467</id>
   <name>LLANGYNYW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6576</id>
   <name>LLANLLUGAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6658</id>
   <name>LLANWYDDELAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6739</id>
   <name>MANAFON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8998</id>
   <name>TREGYNON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17446</id>
   <name>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
