<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4641</id>
<name>CERI</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4883096584739</lat>
<lon>-3.24814695342699</lon>
<gazetteerText>KERRY, or CERI, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Newtown district, Montgomery. The village stands at the foot of the Kerry Hills, in a pleasant vale, at the terminus of a short branch of the Oswestry and Llanidloes railway, 3 miles E by S of Newtown; is a pretty place and a seat of petty sessions; and has a postoffice under Newtown, Montgomeryshire. The parish contains the townships of Trellan, Bahaithlon, Brynllywarch, Cefnyberen, Cloddie, Drevor, Garthillin, Goitrey, Graig, Gwenthrew, Gwernesgob, Gwernuggo, Kefnymonach, Keyliber-Issa, Keyliber-Ucha, Kilthriew, Manllwyd, Penygelli, and Weeg-Dolvor. Acres, 21, 430. Rated property, &#163;14, 660. Pop. in 1851, 1, 930; in 1861, 2, 075. Houses, 380. The property is not much divided. Dolforgan is the seat of R. P. Long, Esq.; and Brynllywarch, of John Naylor, Esq. Much of the land is moor or pasture, and was formerly under wood. The Kerry Hills form a considerable part of the area; but, at the same time, extend eastward into Salop, toward Clun and Bishops Castle; and they have a bleak and desolate appearance. An ancient castle stood in the palace, but was demolished in the time of Henry III. There are several ancient earthworks. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Dolvor, in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;550. * Patron, the Bishop of St. Davids. The church is ancient but good; and contains an old font, monuments of the Wilkinses, and a good marble monument of Richard Jones, who founded a school here. The p. curacy of Sarn is a separate benefice.&#151;The sub-district contains also Moughtrey parish, and comprises 26, 455 acres. Pop., 2, 601. Houses, (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/Ceri/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645771</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10159787</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CERI</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10192894</id>
   <status>Cmt</status>
   <name>CERI</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553404</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KERRY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
