<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4340</id>
<name>GUILSFIELD</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7006278227614</lat>
<lon>-3.16308846628883</lon>
<gazetteerText>GUILSFIELD, a village and a parish in Llanfyllin district, Montgomery. The village stands among wooded hills, 2&#189; miles W of Pool-Quay r. station and the river Severn, and 3 NNW of Welshpool; is a very pretty place; and has a post office under Welshpool. The parish includes the townships of Llan, Lower Broniarth, Upper Broniarth, Burgedin, Garth, Gungrog-fechan, Hendrehen, Llanerchrochwell, Rheteskin, Tirymynech. Trelydan, Trowscoed, and Varchoel. Llan contains the village; and several parts are within Welshpool borough. Acres, 14, 835. Real property, &#163;21, 816; of which &#163;264 are in gas works. Pop. in 1851, 2, 397; in 1861, 2, 634. Houses, 512. The property is much subdivided. Garth is the seat of the Mytton family; Trowscoed, of the Trevors; and Trelydan Hall, of Col. Pryce. Traces exist of a Roman way and an ancient camp; and the site is here of Strata Marcella abbey. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;360.* Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church is a fine old edifice; is in good condition; and was attached to Strata Marcella abbey. The vicarage of Pool Quay is a separate benefice. A school has &#163;15 from endowment; and other charities have &#163;41. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/Guilsfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647788</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10146800</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GUILSFIELD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2477</id>
   <name>LLANDRINIO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2853</id>
   <name>LLANDYSILIO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3190</id>
   <name>CARREGHOFA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4649</id>
   <name>CRUGION</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5022</id>
   <name>BAUSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6779</id>
   <name>MEIFOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14571</id>
   <name>LLANSANTFFRAID</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
