<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5076</id>
<name>CARNO</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5682158556288</lat>
<lon>-3.539794457026</lon>
<gazetteerText>CARNO, a river, a village, and a parish in Montgomeryshire. The river rises near the watershed with the Dyfi; and runs 9 miles south-eastward to the Severn, 2&#188; miles N of Llandinam. The village stands on the river, adjacent to the Newtown and Macliynlleth railway, 10 miles W by N of Newtown; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Shrewsbury. The parish comprises the townships of Derlwyn, Llysyn, and Trowscoed; and is in the district of Newtown. Acres, 10,982. Real property, &#163;3,168. Pop., 969. Houses, 166. The property is much subdivided. Great part of the surface is mountainous. Remains of a Roman fortress, called Caer-Noddfa, are contiguous to the village; and vestiges of two castles are on a bill above AvonCerniog and on a spur of Allt-Mawr, both within a mile of the village. A battle, decisive of the sovereignty of North Wales, was fought, in 946, at the village; and another, of fierce character, with similar result, was fought, in 1077, on Mynydd-Carn. The living is vicarage in the diocese of Bangor. Value, &#163;95. Patron, Sir W. W. Wynn, Bart. The church occupies the site of an old one of the Knights of St. John; and was built in 1807. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Calvinistic Methodists, and Wesleyans. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/Carno/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653707</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10178368</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CARNO</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
