<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6779</id>
<name>MEIFOD</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7238137366139</lat>
<lon>-3.24415468525759</lon>
<gazetteerText>MEIFOD, or MYFOD, a village and a parish in Llanfyllin district, Montgomery. The village stands on the river Vyrnwy, under Broniarth hills, 5&#189; miles NE of Llanfair, and 6 SW of Llansaintffraid r. station; contests with other places the claim of occupying the site of the Roman Mediolanum; was a place of considerable importance in the ecclesiastical affairs of Powisland; and has a post office&#8225; under Welshpool, and fairs on the last Friday of Feb., April, June, Aug., Oct., and Dec. The parish includes the townships of Cefullyfnog, Cwm, Deffryn, Keel, Main, Nan tymeichied, Peniarth, Teirtref, Trevedid, Trefnany, and Ystymcolwyn. Acres, 12,614. Rated property, &#163;12,209. Pop., 1,806. Houses, 359. The property is subdivided. There are several pleasant seats. There are also an ancient circular camp and several barrows. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, 490.* Patron, the Bishop of St. Asaph. The church belonged to Ystrad-Marchel abbey; was the burial-place of the prine of Powis; is large and interesting, with some Norman features: has a W battlemented tower of the 15th century; includes, in its wall near the font, a coffinlid of the 12th century; and contains some old monuments. The churchyard is remarkably large, occupying an area of about 5 acres. Parts of Pont-Robert and Penrhos. chapelries, with pop. in 1861 of respectively 250 and 217, are within the parish. Charities, &#163;55. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/Meifod/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642819</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10242824</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MEIFOD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
