<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1116</id>
<name>MONTGOMERY</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5629665032669</lat>
<lon>-3.15331495504809</lon>
<gazetteerText>Montgomery.-- parl. bor., par., and co. town of Montgomeryshire, 7 miles S. of Welshpool and 181 NW. of London by rail, 3323 ac., pop. 1194; P.O., T.O., 1 Bank. Market-day, Thursday. Montgomery is a very old place, having claims even to an ancient British origin. Of the castle, a fortress founded in the reign of William the Conqueror, very slight remains exist; it was reduced by the Parliamentarians. There are no mfrs. Montgomery is a corporate town, with charter of 1st Henry VII. The Montgomery District of Parliamentary Boroughs (including Montgomery, Llanfyllin, Llanidloes, Machynlleth, Newtown, and Welshpool) returns 1 member to Parliament. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/Montgomery/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Montgomery</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Forden</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642304</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075683</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>FORDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10239977</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10282858</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10282883</id>
   <status>Ldsp</status>
   <name>MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10282895</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553398</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10577196</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12735765</id>
   <status>DistBCon</status>
   <name>MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12827799</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>MONTGOMERY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2479</id>
   <name>LLANDYSUL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>4089</id>
<name>FORDEN</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6049578361722</lat>
<lon>-3.13182579945604</lon>
<gazetteerText>FORDEN, a village and a parish in the district and county of Montgomery. The village stands near Offa&apos;s dyke, the river Severn, and the Cambrian railway, 3 miles N of Montgomery; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a post office under Welshpool, and a r. station. The parish includes also the townships of Ackley, Edderton, Hem, Kilkewydd, Llettygynfarch, Munlyn, Thornbury, Woodlaston, and Wropton; and contains the Montgomery and Pool house of industry. Acres, 5, 270. Real property, &#163;6, 928. Pop., 926. Houses, 145. Cefn-Digoll here was the scene of the final discomfiture of the Welsh in 1294. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Hereford. Value, &#163;119.* Patrons, the Grocers. Company. A new church was built in 1867, at a cost of &#163;3, 000; and has a detached tower. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/Forden/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649232</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10114949</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>FORDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10128687</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FORDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10207150</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>FORDEN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4399</id>
   <name>HOPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4411</id>
   <name>LEIGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9004</id>
   <name>TRELYSTAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
