<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>127</id>
<name>WELSHPOOL</name>
<container>MONTGOMERYSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6625948433061</lat>
<lon>-3.14822835631048</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELSHPOOL, or Pool, a town, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Montgomeryshire. The town stands on the river Severn, the Montgomery or Ellesmere canal, and the Cambrian railway, near the junction of the Shrewsbury and Welshpool railway, 19&#190; miles WSW of Shrewsbury; takes its name from a neighbouring pool or lake; is called by the Welsh Tralliom, from its alder trees; grew to importance under the fostering influence of Powis Castle, situated 1 mile to the S; acquired parliamentary representation in the time of Henry VIII., lost it in 1728, re-acquired it in 1832, and unites with Montgomery and four other boroughs in sending a member to parliament; was first chartered by James I.; is governed, under the new act, by a mayor, 4 aldermen, and 12 councillors; is a seat of assizes, sessions, and county courts, and the headquarters of the county militia; was the meeting-place of an Eisteddfod in 1825; carries on malting, tanning, and flannel manufacture; presents a well built and thriving appearance; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a r. station, two banking offices, a hotel, a county-hall and market house, with a room 102 feet by 25, a church mainly rebuilt in 1774, a chapel of ease in the Norman style, seven dissenting chapels, a grammar-school, a national school, a school of industry, alms houses, a dispensary, some other charities, a weekly market on Monday, and twelve annual fairs. The parliamentary borough includes most of W. parish and a small part of Guilsfield; and the municipal borough includes also the rest of W. parish, some more of Guilsfield, all Buttington, and parts of Berriew and Castle-Caereinion. Corporation revenue, about &#163;290. Pop. of the p. borough in 1851, 4,434; in 1861, 5,004. Houses, 1,046. Pop. of the m. borough in 1851, 6,564; in 1861, 7,304. Houses, 1,431.&#151;The parish is divided into Upper Pool, Middle Pool, Lower Pool, and Cyfronydd; and comprises 6,801 acres. Real property, &#163;8,224; of which &#163;913 are in railways. Pop. in 1851, 4,391; in 1861, 4,844. Houses, 1,015. Powis Castle is a main feature, but has been separately noticed. An ancient small tower stood close to the town, and probably guarded the passage of the Severn. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Asaph. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of St. A. Bishop Morgan, the translator of the Welsh Bible, was vicar.&#151;The sub-district contains three parishes and two parts, and is in Montgomery district. Acres, 22,048. Pop., 7,220. Houses, 1,465.- The hundred excludes the borough, and contains one parish and three parts. Acres, 25,362. Pop., 2,895. Houses, 649. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/Welshpool/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welshpool</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634560</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10009390</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>WELSHPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10036677</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>POOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10128717</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WELSHPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10487419</id>
   <status>PA</status>
   <name>POOL LOWER DIVISION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10487420</id>
   <status>PA</status>
   <name>POOL MIDDLE DIVISION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10487432</id>
   <status>PA</status>
   <name>POOL UPPER DIVISION</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553386</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WELSHPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12783073</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WELSHPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12796341</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WELSHPOOL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828202</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WELSHPOOL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1620</id>
   <name>CLETTERWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6811</id>
   <name>MIDDLETOWN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9103</id>
   <name>TREWERN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9183</id>
   <name>UPPINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10533</id>
   <name>WOLLASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11285</id>
   <name>CASTLE CAEREINION</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
