<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10802</id>
<name>LLANWENARTH</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8462179933863</lat>
<lon>-3.06472740280773</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANWENARTH, a village and a parish in Abergavenny district, Monmouth. The village stands on the river Usk, under the Sugarloaf mountain, 1 mile E of the boundary with Brecon, and 2&#188; W by N of Abergavenny r. station; is a considerable place; and contains some curious houses. The parish is cut into two divisions, Citra and Ultra, and extends beyond the Brecon canal. Post town, Abergavenny. Acres of thediv., 2,860. Real property, &#163;2,463. Pop. in 1851,254; in 1861,230. Houses, 53. Acres of the U. div., 2,480. Real property, &#163;4,307; of which &#163;285 are in ironworks, and &#163;165 in the canal. Pop. in 1851,2,248; in 1861, 2,096. Houses, 421. The property is much subdivided. Graig Hill, a shoulder of the Sugarloaf mountain, is covered with wood; and ironstone rocks of it are extensively worked into what is called bastard lime. Other tracts yield ironstone and coal. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;267.* Patron, the Earl of Abergavenny. The church has a later English tower, and is good. A large portion of the Ultra div. was constituted a separate charge in 1865; and the living of it is a vicarage of the value of &#163;274, in the patronage of the Rector. Another portion, which had a pop. of 660 in 1861, is included in the chapelry of Blaenavon, which was constituted in 1860. Charities, &#163;4. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Llanwenarth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643918</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10238020</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LLANWENARTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377845</id>
   <status>CP/Hmlt</status>
   <name>LLANWENARTH CITRA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377857</id>
   <status>Hmlt/CP</status>
   <name>LLANWENARTH ULTRA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10488825</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>LLANWENARTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
