<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10800</id>
<name>LLANFIHANGEL CRUCORNAU</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8820064065957</lat>
<lon>-2.97029636201912</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANVIHANGEL-CRUCORNEY, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Abergavenny district, Monmouth. The village stands on the river Monnow, adjacent to the Abergavenny and Hereford railway, near the boundary with Hereford, and under Skirrid-fawr mountain, 1 mile NNE of Llanfihangel r. station, and 4&#189; NNE of Abergavenny; and has a post office under Abergavenny.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlet o Penbiddle, and comprises 3,264 acres. Real property, &#163;3,579; of which &#163;215 are on the railway. Pop., 479. Houses, 103. The property is much subdivided. Llanvihangel Court belonged to the Arnolds; passed, in the time of Queen Anne, to the Harleys; belongs now to the Hon. W. Rodney; is an ancient edifice; and has a remarkably grand avenue of firs. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;281. Patron, the Prince of Wales. The church is good. Charities, &#163;4.&#151;The sub-district contains also six other parishes. Acres, 20,510. Pop., 1,860. Houses, 402. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/LlanvihangelCrucorney/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643924</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10165179</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL CRUCORNAU</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10377780</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANFIHANGEL CRUCORNAU</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549322</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANVIHANGEL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4119</id>
   <name>WALTERSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6212</id>
   <name>BWLCH TRE WYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10793</id>
   <name>LLANGATWG LINGOED</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10804</id>
   <name>OLDCASTLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>14565</id>
   <name>CWMYOY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
