<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8231</id>
<name>MITCHELL TROY</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7861670572391</lat>
<lon>-2.73083057080934</lon>
<gazetteerText>MITCHEL-TROY, or ST. MICHAEL-TROY, a village and a parish in the district and county of Monmouth. The village stands on the river Trothy, adjacent to the Monmouth and Pontypool railway, 2 miles SW by S of Monmouth; takes the latter part of its name, by corruption, from the Trothy; and has a post office, called Mitchell-Troy, under Monmouth. The parish comprises 2,000 acres. Real property, 2,858. Pop., 385. Houses, 85. The property is much subdivided. Troy House belongs to the Duke of Beaufort; stands by the side of the Trothy, under the shelter of a hill; has a huge roof; is said to have been built by Inigo Jones; contains some family portraits of the Herberts, the Somersets, and others, including one of Lord Herbert of Cherbury when a boy; contains also a good specimen of Tudor ceiling, a panelling of the time of James I., an old oak chimney-piece curiously carved with Scripture subjects, and a suite of armour said to have been worn by Henry V. at Agincourt, but apparently of more recent date. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Cumcarvan, in the diocese of Llandaff. Valne, &#163;398.* Patron, the Duke of Beaufort. The church is ancient, with a tower; and was reported in 1859 as bad. The churchyard contains an ancient cross. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/MitchelTroy/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642410</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10282457</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MITCHELL TROY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10515634</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>MITCHELL TROY UNITED</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9504</id>
   <name>WONASTOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
