<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>679</id>
<name>TREDEGAR</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7797275891926</lat>
<lon>-3.25334624386501</lon>
<gazetteerText>TREDEGAR, a town, a chapelry, and a sub-district, in Bedwelty parish and district, Monmouth. The town stands on the river Sirhowy, and on the Vale of Sirhowy and the Merthyr and Abergavenny railways, 12&#189; miles WSW of Abergavenny; was merely an insignificant village so late as 1800; grew to importance around iron-works, established by the Homfrays; acquired a tram railway southward, for the conveyance of minerals, so early as 1802; carries on great industry in the working and exporting of coal and iron; presents an appearance repulsive to lovers of tidiness and good scenery; comprises a central square and radiating streets; and has a head post-office,&#8224; two r. stations with telegraph, a banking office, a town hall, a market house, a good modern church, eight dissenting chapels, a weekly market on Saturday, and three annual fairs. Pop. in 1851, 8,305; in 1861, 9,383. Houses, 1,720. The chapelry was constituted in 1840. Pop. in 1861, 20,318. Houses, 3,643. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;300. Patron, the Incumbent of Bedwelty. The sub-district comprises all the Manmoeland Ushlawrcoed sections of Bedwelty parish. Pop. in 1851, 24,544; in 1861, 28,548. Houses, 5,140. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tredegar</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635547</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10127178</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>TREDEGAR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10308781</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>TREDEGAR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10308811</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TREDEGAR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549220</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TREDEGAR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828172</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>TREDEGAR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12829528</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TREDEGAR</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
