<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10900</id>
<name>TRELLECK</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7439702243111</lat>
<lon>-2.72354248521178</lon>
<gazetteerText>TRELLECK, a township and a sub-district in Monmouth district, and a parish partly also in Chepstow district, Monmouthshire. The township lies 4&#189; miles S by W of Monmouth r. station; takes its name from a group of monoliths, locally associated with Harold; and has a post-office under Chepstow. Real property, &#163;979. Pop., 128. Houses, 29. The parts of the parish in Monmouth district comprise 5,287 acres. Real property, &#163;3,315. Pop., 991. Houses, 209. The property is divided among a few. A tumulus, 450 feet in circuit, is near the group of monoliths; and is said to have been the site of a castle of the Earls of Clare. The part of the parish in Chepstow district is Trelleck-Grange chapelry, Acres of the entire parish, 7,061. Pop., 1,128. Houses, 231. The living is a vicarage, united with Penalth, in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;430.* Patron, the Bishop of L. The church is good. The p. curacy of Trelleck-Grange is a separate benefice. There are an endowed school with &#163;43 a year, and charities &#163;24.&#151;The sub-district includes 10 other parishes, and comprises 26,444 acres. Pop., 4,797. Houses, 1,041. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Trelleck/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trelleck</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10282469</id>
   <status>Ldsp</status>
   <name>TRYLEG</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10314306</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TRYLEG</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10314318</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TRYLEG</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10380157</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>TRELLECK TOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10515610</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>TRELECH UNITED</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549206</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TRELLECK</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>10823</id>
<name>TRELLECK GRANGE</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7113472419961</lat>
<lon>-2.7389117981296</lon>
<gazetteerText>TRELLECK-GRANGE, a chapelry in Trelleck parish, Monmouth; 6 miles NNW of Chepstow r. station. Post town, Chepstow. Acres 1,774. Real property, &#163;1,788. Pop., 137. Houses, 22. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;74. Patron, the Duke of Beaufort. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/TrelleckGrange/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10378230</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TRELLECK GRANGE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
