<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3750</id>
<name>CALDICOT</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5877605964113</lat>
<lon>-2.75593482568412</lon>
<gazetteerText>CALDICOTT, a village, a parish, a stream, a level, and a hundred in Monmouth. The village stands on the stream, near the South Wales railway and the estuary of the Severn, 1&#189; mile W of Portskewet r. station, and 5 SW of Chepstow; and has a post office under Chepstow. The parish is in Chepstow district; and comprises 1,938 acres of land, and 1,220 of water. Real property, &#163;3,171. Pop., 579. Houses, 136. The property is subdivided. The land is part of the low flat tract of Caldicott level. A stately castle ruin, with round towers, remarkable for the excellence of its masonry, partly Norman, but mostly late decorated English, stands adjacent to the village. The castle belonged to the Bohuns; passed to the Duke of Gloucester; and was annexed, by Henry VIII., to the duchy of Lancaster. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;240. Patron, M. H. Noel, Esq. The church is ancient and good; consists of nave, chancel, and aisles, with a bold tower; and has decorated cinquefoils in the chancel. There are a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;17. The stream bears the name of Caldicott Pill; rises in Wentwood chase, within 2&#189; miles of the Usk; and runs 7 miles south-south-eastward to the estuary of the Severn at Portskewet. The level lies along the Severn estuary and the Bristol channel; extends about 11 miles to the mouth of the Usk; was at one time subject to continual inundation; was drained and brought into cultivation, by the monks of Goldcliff; and is now a rich grazing tract. The hundred is cut into two divisions, Higher and Lower. The Higher div. contains Caldicott parish, twelve other parishes, and part of another. Acres, 27,950. The Lower div. contains Goldcliff parish, and sixteen other parishes. Acres, 53,000. Pop. of both, 13,624. Houses, 2,741. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caldicot,_Monmouthshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654014</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Caldicott/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10010767</id>
   <status>Ldsp</status>
   <name>CALDICOT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10118013</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CALDICOT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10156865</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>CALDICOT</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2170</id>
   <name>CAER WENT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4402</id>
   <name>IFTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4463</id>
   <name>LLANFACHES</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6738</id>
   <name>MAGOR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8514</id>
   <name>PORTSKEWETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8618</id>
   <name>REDWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8627</id>
   <name>ROGGIET</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9178</id>
   <name>UNDY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10809</id>
   <name>LLANVAIR DISGOED</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10822</id>
   <name>ST BRIDES NETHERWENT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
