<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1151</id>
<name>LLANFRECHFA UPPER</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6662240110444</lat>
<lon>-3.03916285109385</lon>
<gazetteerText>Upper Llanfrechva, township, Llanfrechva par., Monmouthshire, 2&#189; miles NW. of Caerleon and 4 N. of Newport, 2656 ac., pop. 4177; P.O., called Llanfrechfa; is a local government district. See LLANVRECHVA. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Llanfrechfa/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10175215</id>
   <status>CP/PA</status>
   <name>LLANFRECHFA UPPER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10413163</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>LLANFRECHFA UPPER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12827623</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>LLANFRECHFA UPPER</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5529</id>
<name>LLANFRECHFA</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6365880047583</lat>
<lon>-2.98702833778683</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANVRECHVA, a parish of two divisions, lower and upper, in Pontypool district, Monmouth; on an affluent of the river Usk, 1&#190; mile NE of Llantarnam r. station, and 2&#189; NNW of Caerleon. Post town, Caerleon, under Newport, Monmouth. Acres, 4,320. Real property of the lower div., &#163;3,700. Pop. in 1851,985; in 1861,933. Houses, 207. Real property of the upper div., &#163;4,678; of which &#163;1,000 are in mines, &#163;62 in quarries, and &#163;250 in railways. Pop. in 1851,1,517; in 1861,1,621. Houses, 296. The property is much subdivided. Woollen manufacture is carried on. The living is a vicarage united with the chapelry of Cumbrane, in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;85.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Llandaff. The church was reported in 1859 as not good. A national school was built in 1862. Charities, &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Llanfrechfa/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10198264</id>
   <status>CP/PA</status>
   <name>LLANFRECHFA LOWER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10487250</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANVRECHVA</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10909</id>
   <name>LLANTHEWY VACH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
