<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1117</id>
<name>MYNYDDISLWYN</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6484507259379</lat>
<lon>-3.18051931065971</lon>
<gazetteerText>MYNYDDYSLWYN, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Newport district, Monmouth. The village stands 1&#189; mile E of the river Sirhowy, 2&#189; E by S of Tredegar-Junction r. station, and 9&#189; N W of Newport. The parish comprises the hamlets of Clawrplwyf, Mynydd-maen, and Penmaen; and contains the town of Abercarn, which has a post-office under Newport, Monmouth. Acres, 15, 938. Real property, &#163;29, 971; of which &#163;12, 970 are in mines, &#163;60 in quarries, &#163;220 in iron-works, and &#163;3, 446 in railway s. Pop. in 1851, 5, 994; in 1861, 6, 877. Houses, 1, 393. The property is sub-divided. The surface is hilly and boldly undulating; and descends to the rivers Sirhowy and Ebbw. Chemical works, iron and tin-plate works, and extensive collieries are at or near Abercarn. A large tumulus, supposed to have been a beacon or signal station, is near thechurch. The parish is a meet for the Tyisha harriers. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;160.* Patron, the Bishop of Llandaff. The church is large and good; and has a tower, rebuilt in 1821. The p. curacy of Penmaen is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Calvinistic Methodists, Wesleyans, and Roman Catholics. Ruins ofan ancient chapel of ease are in the vicinity of Abercarn.&#151;The sub-district contains also Machen parish, and twohamlets of Bedwas. Acres, 25, 311. Pop., 10, 596. Houses, 2, 147. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mynyddislwyn</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641927</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Mynyddyslwyn/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10284790</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MYNYDDISLWYN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10284818</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MYNYDDISLWYN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549152</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MYNYDDISLWYN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12746120</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>ISLWYN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
