<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8633</id>
<name>RHAGLAN</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7585739668934</lat>
<lon>-2.85607386111932</lon>
<gazetteerText>RAGLAN, or Ragland, a village, a parish, and a hundred, in Monmouthshire. The village stands on a smallaffluent of the river Usk, 1&#188; mile W S W of Raglan-Foot-path r. station, and 7 W S W of Monmouth; gives the title of Baron to the Duke of Beaufort; and has a post-office&#8225; under Newport, Monmouth. The parish is in Monmouth district, and comprises 4,083 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 796. Pop., 905. Houses, 195. The property is divided among a few. Raglan Castle stands on a rising ground, &#189; a mile N N E of the village; was built, in the time of Henry V., by the Herberts; occupies the site of a previous castle of the Morleys; passed to the Somersets; was the residence of the Earls of Worcester; was garrisoned in 1642, by the Marquis of Worcester, indefence of Charles I.; gave shelter, for some time, to thatmonarch; made successful resistance in his cause till verynear the end of the war; surrendered to Fairfax in Aug., 1646; was subsequently dismantled; is now one of thefinest baronial ruins in England; exhibits the latestforms of the feudal castle, passing into the modern style of fortification; covers a space of about one-third of a mile in circuit; includes a terrace 260 feet long, a greatmachicolated gateway with hexagonal towers, a stonecourt 100 feet by 60, a fountain court, a hall 62 feet by 28, a great kitchen, Charles I.&apos;s tower, the hexagonalyellow tower 193 feet in circuit, and other parts and features; belongs now to the Duke of Beaufort; and is the head-quarters of the Monmouthshire Archery club, and a favourite resort of picnic parties. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;270.* Patron, the Duke of Beaufort. The church is early perpendicular, with an embattled tower; was recently restoredat a cost of &#163;2, 500; and contains monuments of the Somersets. There are a Baptist chapel, and charities &#163;6. The hundred contains also 20 other parishes, and parts of 3 others; and is cut into two divisions, higher and lower. Acres, 27,090 and 16, 543. Pop. in 1851, 5,032 and 2, 751; in 1861, 8,024. Houses, 1, 718. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Ragland/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raglan,_Monmouthshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639700</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10120998</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>RHAGLAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10297783</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RHAGLAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10515622</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>RAGLAN UNITED</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2214</id>
   <name>CLEIDDA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4421</id>
   <name>LLAN ARTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4440</id>
   <name>LLANDENNY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6628</id>
   <name>LLAN SOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10783</id>
   <name>BRYNGWYN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10899</id>
   <name>TREGARE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17183</id>
   <name>MONMOUTHSHIRE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
