<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6442</id>
<name>LLANGYBI FAWR</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6678812184601</lat>
<lon>-2.93492347163821</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANGIBBY, a village, a parish, and a district-district, in Pontypool district, Monmouth. The village stands near the Roman way to Caerleon, 3&#188; miles SSW of Usk r. station. and has a post office under Newport, Monmouth. The parish comprises 4,443 acres. Real property, &#163;5,092; of which &#163;35 are in limestone quarries. Pop., 525. Houses, 95. The property is divided among a few. Llangibby House is the seat of W. A. Williams, Esq., and was built by Inigo Jones. Some remains exist of Llangibby Castle, which, in the time of Sir TreVor Williams, was besieged and taken by the Parliamentary forces. About &#189; a mile from the castle are some slight remains of an ecclesiastical building, called Tregrwg. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;526. Patron, W. A. Williams, Esq. The church is dedicated to St. Cybi, and is good. A small but neat church, for a separate charge, was built, in 1861, at Common, Coed-y-Paen. A well, arched over with very ancient masonry, is near the parish church. There are two schools.&#151;The sub-district contains also three other parishes and part of another. Acres, 12,635. Pop., 3,620. Houses, 696. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Llangibby/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10227628</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LLANGYBI FAWR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549267</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LLANGIBBY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10907</id>
   <name>LLANDEGVETH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
