<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1136</id>
<name>USK</name>
<container>MONMOUTHSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7034400634242</lat>
<lon>-2.89698343168233</lon>
<gazetteerText>USK, a town, a township, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Monmouth. The town stands on the river Usk, the Julian way, and the Monmouth and Pontypool railway, 12&#189; miles SW of Monmouth; occupies the site of the Roman Burrium or Bull&#230;um; was known to the ancient Britons as Brynbega; acquired a castle and a Benedictine nunnery, founded by the Clares, in the first half of the 13th century; was chartered by Roger Mortimer in 1398; is governed by a portreeve, a recorder, and other officials; unites with Monmouth and Newport in sending a member to parliament; is a seat of sessions, and a polling place; publishes a weekly newspaper; and has a post-office&#8225; under Newport, Monmouth, a r. station with telegraph, a good inn, a town hall and market house, a county-house of correction with capacity for 107 male and 39 female prisoners, an old five-arched bridge, an ancient church once cruciform and originally belonging to the Benedictine nunnery, Independent and Wesleyan chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, an endowed grammar-school with &#163;439 a year, charities &#163;39, a weekly market on Friday, and four annual fairs. The castle passed from the Clares to the Mortimers and to the Crown; was the birth-place of Edward IV. and Richard III.; went, after the time of Henry VII., to the Herberts; suffered much injury from Owen Glendower, and utter dismantling by the parliamentarian troops in the civil wars of Charles I.; and is now represented by ivy-clad ruins and a round tower within the grounds of Usk House, the seat of F. Macdonnell, Esq. Pop. of the town in 1861, 1,545 Houses, 311.-The township includes all the town, excepting a pendicle of Gwehellog hamlet. Acres, 404. Real property, &#163;7,623; of which &#163;2,582 are in the railway, and &#163;70 in gasworks. Pop., 1,528. Houses, 307.&#151;The parish includes also Gwehellog and Glascoed hamlets; comprises 4,956 acres; and is in Pontypool district. Pop., 2,112. Houses, 423. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Llandaff. Value, &#163;250. Patron, W. A. Williams, Esq.--The subdistrict excludes Glascoed hamlet, but includes 9 other parishes. Acres, 18,360. Pop., 4,035. Houses, 843.- The hundred contains 21 parishes; and is cut into two divisions, higher and lower. Acres, 16,761 and 30,770. Pop. in 1851, 3,274 and 9,730; in 1861, 13,859. Houses, 3,243. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usk</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MON/Usk/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635052</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10103642</id>
   <status>Ldsp</status>
   <name>USK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10120792</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>USK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10316297</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>USK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10316376</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>USK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549255</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>USK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828196</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>USK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10906</id>
   <name>GWERNESNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
