<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1091</id>
<name>NEWBIGGIN BY THE SEA</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.182752094036</lat>
<lon>-1.51963193253826</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWBIGGIN, a village and a township-chapelry in Woodhorn parish, Northumberland. The village stands on the coast, near North Seaton r. station, 1&#189; mile N of the mouth of the Wansbeck river, and 7&#188; E by N of Morpeth; is a fishing-station and a watering place; is sometimes called Newbiggin-by-the-Sea; and has a post-office, &#8225; of that name, under Morpeth, a good inn, a coast-guard station, a life-boat station, and -a roadsteadwith tolerably secure anchorage for small vessels. The chapelry comprises 400 acres. Real property, &#163;1, 586. Pop. in 1851, 717; in 1861, 948. Houses, 184. The increase of pop. arose from extension of fisheries and fromincreased accommodation for summer visitors. A beautiful small bay adjoins the village, and has firm, smooth, safe sands. Several collieries are in the neighbourhood. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the vicarage of Woodhorn, in the diocese of Durham. The church was rebuilt in 1846; has a low spire; contained the effigies of a knight, discovered in 1867; stands picturesquely on a point projecting into the sea on the N side of the bay; and serves as a landmark to mariners. There are chapels for Presbyterians and Wesleyans, a parochial school, and a subscription library and reading-rooms. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7297705</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10152823</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>NEWBIGGIN ON SEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173784</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>NEWBIGGIN BY THE SEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221158</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>NEWBIGGIN BY THE SEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10324002</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>NEWBIGGIN BY THE SEA</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9654</id>
   <name>NORTH SEATON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>9521</id>
<name>NEWBIGGIN</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.0117386352493</lat>
<lon>-1.68924199058788</lon>
<gazetteerText>Newbiggin, township, Newburn par., Northumberland, 1349 ac., pop. 60; Newbiggin Hall, seat, is 3 miles NE. of Newburn sta. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Newbiggin/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10323988</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>NEWBIGGIN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>22554</id>
<name>NEWBIGGIN</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.8429004259811</lat>
<lon>-2.07630973174982</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWBIGGIN, a township in Shotley parish, Northumberland; on the river Derwent at the boundary with Durham, 9&#189; miles S by E of Hexham. Acres, 2,056. Pop., 69. Houses, 10. The property belongs to the Rev. D. Capper. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10323990</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>NEWBIGGIN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
