<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>762</id>
<name>GOSFORTH</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.0111477384677</lat>
<lon>-1.62525259964769</lon>
<gazetteerText>GOSFORTH, two townships and a parish in Castle Ward district, Northumberland. The townships are South G. and North G.; and they lie 3 and 4 miles N of Newcastle-upon-Tyne, and have a station on the Newcastle and Blyth railway. Acres, 436 and 1, 066. Pop., 248 and 197. Houses, 50 and 40. The parish contains also the townships of East Brunton, West Brunton, Coxlodge, Fawdon, and Kenton; the last of which has a post office under Newcastle-upon-Tyne. Acres, 6, 355. Real property, &#163;26, 585; of which &#163;9, 981 are in mines and &#163;270 in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 2, 337; in 1861, 2, 943. Houses, 643. The manor belonged to the Surtees and the Lisles; and passed to the Brandlings. Gosforth House is a structure of last century; stands amid grounds pleasantly adorned with wood and water, and broadly engirdled with plantation; and was the scene of some of George Stephenson&apos;s displays of ingenuity, when he lived at Killingworth. Coal is extensively worked. The living of Gosforth is a vicarage, and that of North Gosforth, constituted in 1865, is a p. curacy, in the diocese of Durham. Value of the former, &#163;300; of the latter, &#163;150. Patron of the former, the Bishop of D.; of the latter, T. E. Smith, Esq. Gosforth church was not long ago rebuilt. There two charity schools. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gosforth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648273</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Gosforth/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10136428</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>GOSFORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10316285</id>
   <status>Ch/CP/CP</status>
   <name>GOSFORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10316388</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GOSFORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10316510</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GOSFORTH ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551997</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>GOSFORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1179</id>
<name>SOUTH GOSFORTH</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.010007848477</lat>
<lon>-1.62199378950884</lon>
<gazetteerText>South Gosforth, town with ry. sta. (Gosforth), Gosforth par., Northumberland, 2 miles N. of Newcastle, pop. 4126; P.O., T.O., called Gosforth; comprises the townships of South Gosforth and Coxlodge, and is a local government district. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Gosforth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648273</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10002692</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SOUTH GOSFORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10004573</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SOUTH GOSFORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10316431</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>SOUTH GOSFORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>9188</id>
<name>NORTH GOSFORTH</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.0311210757736</lat>
<lon>-1.61246657292113</lon>
<gazetteerText>North Gosforth, eccl. dist., Gosforth and Longbenton pars., Northumberland, pop. 1977. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296611</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10316390</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>NORTH GOSFORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10316418</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTH GOSFORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
