<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9262</id>
<name>HEBRON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.1971401946333</lat>
<lon>-1.70708804014475</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEBBURN, or Hebron, a township and a parish in Morpeth district, Northumberland. The township lies near the Northeastern railway, 2&#189; miles N of Morpeth; and includes a lofty eminence, called Hebburn-Shaw, which commands an extensive view, and was formerly used as an alarm beacon. Acres, 972. Pop., 125. Houses, 19. The parish contains also the townships of Cockle-Park, Tritlington, Earsdon, Earsdon-Forest, Fenrother, and Causey-Park. Post town, Morpeth. Acres, 7, 696. Real property, &#163;4, 320. Pop., 595. Houses, 108. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the rectory of Bothal, in the diocese of Durham. The church was rebuilt in 1793. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Hebburn/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647202</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10318063</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>HEBRON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8727</id>
   <name>BENRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8934</id>
   <name>COCKLE PARK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9302</id>
   <name>HIGH AND LOW HIGHLAWS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>9276</id>
<name>HEPBURN</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.5120507417338</lat>
<lon>-1.88383131109509</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEBBURN, or HEPBURN, a township in Chillingham parish, Northumberland; 5 miles SE of Wooler. Pop., 77. Houses, 19. Hebburn Wood is a maze of birches, ferns, and rock; Hebburn Crags are crowned with an ancient camp; and Hebburn Tower, within a gate of Chillingham Park, is a good old peel, with a fine pointed window. Limestone is quarried. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647082</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10318324</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>HEPBURN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
