<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9417</id>
<name>KIRKNEWTON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.5347722206429</lat>
<lon>-2.15362606510439</lon>
<gazetteerText>KIRKNEWTON, a township and a parish in Glendale district, Northumberland. The township lies on the river Glen, under the Cheviots, near the railway from Scots-Gap to the Tweed, 3&#190; miles E of the boundary with Scotland, and 5 WNW of Wooler. Acres, 2, 217. Pop., 79. Houses, 15.&#151;The parish contains also the townships of Howtell, Kilham, Paston, Coldsmouth-with-Thompsons-Walls, Greys-Forest, Heathpool, West Newton, Crookhouse, Lanton, .Yeavering, Coupland, Selbys-Forest, Akeld, and Milfield; the last of which has a post office under Alnwick. Acres, 37, 976Real property, &#163;21, 778-Pop. in 1851, 1, 732; in 1861, 1, 503. Houses, 291. The property is much divided. The surface includes much mountain pasture, and contains a fine variety of scenery. Coupland Castle is a Border tower, with additions of 1614; belonged to the ancient family of Coupland; passed to the Wallaces; and belongs now to M. T. Culley, Esq. Milfield was a residence of the Kings of Bernicia; was also the scene of a contest which preceded the battle of Flodden; and now has a handsome mansion, the seat of G. A. Grey, Esq. Yeavering was a residence of the Kings of Bernicia, prior to Milfield, or till the death of Edwin. Howtell has a fragment of an ancient Border tower, built into farmhouses. Lanton Hill is crowned with an obeliskal monument, erected by the late Sir W. Davidson. Vestiges of ancient camps and extensive earth works are on the hills; and various relics of the ancient Britons and the Romans have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;631.* Patrons, the Marquis of Bute&apos;s Trustees. The church is very ancient; shows traces of Norman architecture; and was recently restored. There are chapels for Presbyterians, Independents, and Primitive Methodists at Milfield, and a national school at Kirknewton, and denominational schools at Milfield and Howtel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Kirknewton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645242</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10321864</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>KIRKNEWTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10321890</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KIRKNEWTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329437</id>
   <status>PA</status>
   <name>UNDIVIDED MOOR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9283</id>
   <name>HETHPOOL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9656</id>
   <name>SELBYS FOREST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9768</id>
   <name>WESTNEWTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
