<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9453</id>
<name>LONGHOUGHTON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.4294689587812</lat>
<lon>-1.61355115379211</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOUGHTON (LONG), a township and a parish in Alnwick district, Northumberland. The township lies on the Northeastern railway and on the coast, 4 miles ENE of Alnwick; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Bilton, Northumberland. Acres, 2,847; of which 222 are water. Pop., 491. Houses, 104. The parish contains also the township of Little Houghton and that of Boulmer and Seaton-House. Acres, 4,113. Real property, &#163;5,976. Pop., 777. Houses, 154. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Duke of Northumberland. Coal, limestone, and lead ore are found. Boulmer bay and Ratcheugh crag are here; and the latter commands an extensive coast view. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;162.* Patron, the Duke of Northumberland. The church is ancient but good; and has a massive tower, with walls of great thickness, and with some early Norman windows. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/LongHoughton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643676</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10322583</id>
   <status>Ch/CP/AP</status>
   <name>LONGHOUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10322625</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONGHOUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8920</id>
   <name>SOUTH CHARLTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8947</id>
   <name>CRASTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9086</id>
   <name>DUNSTAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9110</id>
   <name>EMBLETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9318</id>
   <name>HOWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9447</id>
   <name>LITTLEHOUGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9622</id>
   <name>RENNINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9639</id>
   <name>ROCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9666</id>
   <name>SHIPLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9682</id>
   <name>STAMFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
