<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9436</id>
<name>LESBURY</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.3971561669772</lat>
<lon>-1.63453290069486</lon>
<gazetteerText>LESBURY, a village, a township, and a parish in Alnwick district, Northumberland. The village stands on the river Alne, &#189; a mile N of Bilton r. station, and 3&#189; E by S of Alnwick; and has a neat stone bridge over the Alne. The township contains also the hamlets of Bilton, Hawkhill, and Worden; the first of which has a head post office, designated Bilton, Northumberland. Acres, 2,045; of which 392 are water. Pop., 750. Houses, 153. The parish includes also the township of Alnmouth, which has a post office under Bilton. Acres of the parish, 2,624. Real property, &#163;7,271; of which &#163;18 are in fisheries. Pop., 1,202. Houses, 253. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to the Duke of Northumberland. There are a large corn-mill, a large timber-yard, and a slates-depot, from which considerable quantities of slates are shipped. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;269.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is ancient, was restored in 1846, and has a tower. There are an Established place of worship at Alnmouth, a Wesleyan chapel, and an endowed school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644604</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Lesbury/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10322285</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10322303</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LESBURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9076</id>
   <name>DENWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
