<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8940</id>
<name>CORBRIDGE</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.9788157520696</lat>
<lon>-2.01193777834743</lon>
<gazetteerText>CORBRIDGE, a small town, a township, and a parish in Hexham district, Northumberland. The town stands on Watling-street and the river Tyne, adjacent to the Newcastle and Carlisle railway, in the vicinity of the Roman Corstopitum, 2&#190; miles S of the Roman wall, and 3&#188; E of Hexham. It had a monastery in 771; was occupied by David I. in 1138; was burnt by the Scots in 1296 and 1311; sent members to parliament in the time of Edward I.; had, at one period, five churches; was long a market town; displays now an aspect of grey antiquity; and has a head post office, &#8225; a railway station, a market cross, an old tower, once a jail, a seven-arched bridge, a parish church, three dissenting chapels, and charities &#163;67. The church is old, of fortified structure, and in good condition. -The township includes the town, and comprises 4. 499 acres. Pop., 1, 340. Houses, 288. Corchester, about &#189; a mile west of the town, is the Roman Corstopitum; and there Roman coins and altars, two Greek inscriptions, a silver-votive tablet of 148 oz., and remains of an ancient bridge have been found. -The parish contains also the townships of Dilston, Thorn-brough, Aydon, Aydon-Castle, Halton, Halton-Shields, Clarewood, Great Whittington, and Little Whittington. Acres, 13, 130. Real property, &#163;10, 582. Pop., 2, 170. Houses, 444. The manor belonged to the Claverings and the Percys. Dilston was the seat of the Earls of Derwentwater. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Halton, in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;482.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Carlisle. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corbridge</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652382</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Corbridge/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10086632</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>CORBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10306670</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CORBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10306735</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CORBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10572010</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CORBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758261</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>CORBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8693</id>
   <name>AYDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8933</id>
   <name>COCKLAW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9409</id>
   <name>KIRKHARLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9419</id>
   <name>KIRKWHELPINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9475</id>
   <name>MATFEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9501</id>
   <name>MONKRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9652</id>
   <name>SANDHOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9773</id>
   <name>WEST WHELPINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9781</id>
   <name>GREAT WHITTINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
