<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>682</id>
<name>HEXHAM</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.9658600971992</lat>
<lon>-2.1270485661961</lon>
<gazetteerText>Hexham, market town, par., and township, with ry. sta., S. Northumberland, 23&#189; miles W. of Newcastle-on-Tyne - par., 24,032 ac., pop. 6924; township and town, 5136 ac., pop. 5919; P.O., T.O., 3 Banks, 3 news-papers. Market-day, Tuesday. The town, which occupies a pleasant situation on the S. bank of the river Tyne, is an ancient place, irregularly built, and having very narrow streets. The chief object of interest is the ruined Priory Church of St Wilfrid, built about 674, destroyed two centuries later by the Danes, renovated in 1113, and demolished by the Scots in 1296. The trade of Hexham is mainly agricultural; but there are some mfrs. of hats, gloves, and leather; and in the neighbourhood are large nurseries and market gardens. Near the town was fought (1463) the battle of Hexham, between the Yorkists and Lancastrians. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Hexham/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hexham</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Hexham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647007</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10004550</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10043888</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10061994</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10133555</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10174326</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318567</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318592</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318610</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>HEXHAM ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551742</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574950</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12739000</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>NORTHUMBERLAND HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740610</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833313</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8659</id>
   <name>ACOMB</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8721</id>
   <name>BELLINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8740</id>
   <name>BIRTLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8928</id>
   <name>CHOLLERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8944</id>
   <name>CORSENSIDE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9321</id>
   <name>HUMSHAUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9590</id>
   <name>OTTERBURN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9723</id>
   <name>TROUGHEND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9743</id>
   <name>WALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9751</id>
   <name>WARDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>9507</id>
<name>HEXHAMSHIRE</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.9362930032632</lat>
<lon>-2.15609486303271</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEXHAMSHIRE, a division of Hexham parish, and a quondam county palatine, in Northumberland. The division of Hexham parish comprises the townships of High Quarter, Low Quarter, Middle Quarter, and West Quarter. Acres, 23, 198. Real property, &#163;7, 356; of which &#163;20 are in mines. Pop., 1, 209. Houses, 240. Acres of High Quarter, 8, 783; of L. Q., 3, 608; of M. Q., 5, 700; of W. Q., 5, 117. Pop. of H. Q., 243; of L. Q., 454; of M. Q., 2, 555; of W. Q., 257. Houses, 44, 92, 54, and 50. H. Q. extends from 6 miles S by W of Hexham town to the borders of Durhamshire; is wild and mountainous; and contains the hamlet of Lillswood. L. Q. extends from 2 to 4 &#189; miles S of Hexham; includes the camping ground of the Lancastrians previous to the battle of Hexham, and a romantic ravine called Deepden, with the Queen&apos;s cave, where Margaret and her child lay concealed after the battle; and contains the hamlets of Dotland, Lee, Linnels, Ordley, and Steel. M. Q. extends from 3 to 6 miles S by W of Hexham; had a lead manufactory, which was recently removed to Allendale parish; and contains the hamlets of Dalton, Mollerstead, and Raw green. W. Q. extends from 1 to 4 miles W of Hexham; includes the access to the suspension bridge over the South Tyne; and contains the hamlets of Greenshaw plain, Nubbock, and Summerrods. The quondam county palatine comprised the parishes of Hexham, St. John-Lee, and Allendale; was governed, as a regality, by the bishops of Hexham; passed, as a barony, to the archbishops of York; and was annexed, in the time of Elizabeth, to Northumberland. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7300687</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10318634</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HEXHAMSHIRE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318658</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HEXHAMSHIRE HIGH QUARTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318701</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HEXHAMSHIRE LOW QUARTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318737</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HEXHAMSHIRE MIDDLE QUARTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318750</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HEXHAMSHIRE WEST QUARTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10323630</id>
   <status>ExP</status>
   <name>MOORLAND COMMON TO THE TOWNSHIPS OF HEXHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
