<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9101</id>
<name>ELSDON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.2649607702967</lat>
<lon>-2.2163744524837</lon>
<gazetteerText>ELSDON, a village, a township, and a sub-district in Rothbury district, and a parish in Rothbury and Bellingham districts, Northumberland. The village stands on an affluent of the river Reed, near the line of projected railway northward from Scots Gap, 8 miles NNW of Scots Gap r. station, and 9 &#189; SW of Rothbury; and has a post office under Newcastle-on-Tyne, and a fair on 26 Aug.; and is a polling-place. Its site is supposed to have been a Roman station, probably the first of a chain of forts between Watling-street and the Devil&apos;s causeway; and a conical moated entrenchment, at a short distance to the NE, is supposed to have been a Roman watch-hill and place of sepulture. The township includes the village, and bears the name of Elsdon-ward. Acres, 6, 404. Pop., 266. Houses, 56. -The parish includes also the townships of Monkridge-ward and Woodside-ward in Rothbury district, and the townships of Rochester-ward, Otterburn-ward, and Troughend-ward in Bellingham district. Acres, 74, 917. Real property, &#163;20, 195; of which &#163;55 are in mines. Pop., 1, 521. Houses, 277. The property is much subdivided. The area is about 23 miles in length, and 12 in greatest breadth; comprises a long vale, flanked by heathy hills; seems to have once been almost entirely covered with forest, some small remnants of which still exist in the vale; was, not long ago, little else than a desolate series of neglected heaths and morasses; but now exhibits cheering effects of extensive reclamation, enclosing, and improvement. Limestone and ironstone, of superior quality, abound; and some good seams of coal exist. Elsdon Castle was built in the time of Henry III., by David, king of Scotland; presents, on its front, the arms of the Umfravilles; is a strong tower, with circular stair-case at one corner; was once the residence of Dr. Dutens, the editor of Leibnitz; and is now the parsonage house. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacies of Horsley and Otterburn, in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;803.* Patron, the Duke of Northumberland. The church is ancient, cruciform, and good; and, at a clearing away of earth at its north transept, a few years ago, remains of upwards of one hundred human skeletons were found there, regularly deposited in double rows. The p. curacy of Byrness is a separate benefice. There is an United Presbyterian church. Tradition speaks of a giant of the name of Ella, who lived at Elsdon, and committed great devastations. -The sub-district, in addition to the three Rothbury townships of Elsdon parish, contains Kidland, Holystone, and twelve townships of Rothbury and Alwinton. Acres, 75, 981. Pop., 1,837. Houses, 344. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Elsdon/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elsdon,_Northumberland</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10313995</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ELSDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10314021</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ELSDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551882</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ELSDON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
