<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9673</id>
<name>SHOTLEY</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.8722748401881</lat>
<lon>-1.90597162720007</lon>
<gazetteerText>SHOTLEY, a village, two townships, and a parish, in Hexham district, Northumberland. The village stands 6 miles SSE of Riding-Mill r. station, and 9 SE of Hexham; and is in S. Low-Quarter township. That township comprises 6,676 acres. Pop., 637. Houses, 124. The other township is S. High-Quarter, or Blanchland; is noticed in the article Blanchland; and has a post-office,&#8225; of the name of Blanchland, formerly under Carlisle, now under Riding-Mill, Northumberland. The parish contains also the township of Newbiggin, and comprises 12,460 acres. Real property, &#163;2,516; of which &#163;25 are in mines. Pop., 1,180. Houses, 229. The manor belongs to H.Silvertop and T. Wilson, Esqs. Much of the land is moor and mountain. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;139* Patrons, the Trustees of Bishop Lord Crewe. The church was built in 1834. The p. curacy of Blanchland is a separate benefice. There are a Baptist chapel, built in 1856, and an endowed school with &#163;14 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Shotley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296768</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10328147</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>SHOTLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10328160</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHOTLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10328184</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>SHOTLEY LOW QUARTER</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>8744</id>
<name>BLANCHLAND</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.8641581632779</lat>
<lon>-2.07957433928846</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLANCHLAND, a village and a township-chapelry in Shotley parish, Northumberland. The village stands in a deep narrow green vale, flanked by heathy hills; on the N side of Derwent river, 6 miles SSW of Riding Mill r. station, and 9 SSE of Hexham: and has a post office&#8225; under Carlisle, and a fair on 24 Aug. A premonstratensian abbey was founded here, in 1165, by Walter de Balbeck; raised to the rank of a mitred abbey in the time of Edward I.; given, at the dissolution, to John Bellow and John Broxholm; passed, by purchase, to Bishop Crewe; and was bequeathed by him, along with other estates, for charitable purposes. The tower of it was formed, in 1752, into a chapel, which continues to be the church of the chapelry; and the gateway and some other parts also are still standing.&#151;The chapelry or township bears also the name of Shotley High Quarter; and comprises 3,728 acres. Rated property, &#163;835. Pop., 474. Houses, 95. Much of the surface is moor and morass. Lead ore occurs in considerable abundance; and has long been mined. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;198.* Patron, the Trustees of Bishop Lord Crewe. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blanchland</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Blanchland/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655379</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10301361</id>
   <status>Ch/CP/PA</status>
   <name>BLANCHLAND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10301415</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLANCHLAND</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
