<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1270</id>
<name>LONGBENTON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.0313696080413</lat>
<lon>-1.57388915878989</lon>
<gazetteerText>BENTON (Long), a township, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Tynemouth, Northumlberland. The township lies on the Northeastern railway, and on the Blyth and Tyne railway, near the Roman wall, 3 miles NNE of Newcastle-upon-Tyne; and has stations on the railways, and a post office under Newcastle-upon-Tyne. The village consists of one long street, and stands on rock, dry, healthy, and pleasant. Pop., 2,222. Houses, 472. The parish includes also the townships of Walker, Killingworth, and Weetslade: and lies partly on the Tyne. Acres, 9,040; of which 110 are water. Real property, &#163;39,372; of which &#163;12,541 are in mines, &#163;500 in quarries, and &#163;2,000 in iron-works. Pop. in 1841, 8,711; in 1861, 13,304. Houses, 2,415. The property is not much divided. The manor belonged formerly to the De Merlays; and passed partly to the Brandlings. The inhabitants are employed mainly in extensive collieries, quarries, foundries, copperas-works, and gunpowder-works, The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;353. Patron, Balliol College, Oxford. The church is very good. The vicarage of Walker and the p. curacy of Killingworth are separate benefices. There are several dissenting chapels, and a national school.-The subdistrict is conterminate with the parish. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Longbenton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Longbenton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643719</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10136430</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>LONGBENTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10300721</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONG BENTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10300733</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LONGBENTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10300745</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONG BENTON ST MARY MAGDALEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551948</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LONGBENTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>762</id>
   <name>GOSFORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1179</id>
   <name>SOUTH GOSFORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8695</id>
   <name>BACKWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8862</id>
   <name>BURRADON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8881</id>
   <name>CAMPERDOWN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9188</id>
   <name>NORTH GOSFORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9260</id>
   <name>HEATON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9398</id>
   <name>JESMOND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17219</id>
   <name>NORTH TYNESIDE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
