<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9318</id>
<name>HOWICK</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.450422852121</lat>
<lon>-1.61132099663718</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOWICK, a parish, with a village, in Alnwick district, Northumberland; on the coast, 1 mile NE of Long Houghton r. station, and 5 NE by E of Alnwick. Posttown, Bilton, Northumberland. Acres, 1, 692; of which 72 are water. Real property, &#163;2, 738. Pop., 265. Houses, 51. The property is divided between two. The manor belonged to the Muschamps; passed to the Vescies, afterwards to the Greys, who became Earls Grey; and gives to the latter the title of Viscount. Howick Hall, the seat of Earl Grey, occupies the site of an ancient tower, destroyed in 1780; is a fine Grecian edifice, built in 1782, and much enlarged and improved in 1812; and contains some valuable statues, paintings, and other works of art. A trout stream, called Howick burn, crossed by a stone bridge, winds through the park, and along a beautifully wooded dene, to the sea; and the shore, adjacent to its mouth, is broken into picturesque masses of jagged freestone rock. Traces exist of a camp variously regarded as British, Roman, and Danish; and ancient spears, swords, coins, and several gold rings, linked together in the form of a gorget, have been found. Coal was at one time worked, but proved unremunerative. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;318.* Patron, the Bishop of Durham. The church was rebuilt, in 1746, by Sir Henry Grey, Bart.; was remodelled, with insertion of Norman windows and floriated capitals, in 1849, by the third Earl Grey; and contains, under a rich Gothic canopy of Caen stone, the monument of the second Earl Grey, the distinguished prime minister. There are a national school, and charities &#163;40. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Howick/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Howick,_Northumberland</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646490</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10319213</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HOWICK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
