<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8751</id>
<name>BOLAM</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.1195424938873</lat>
<lon>-1.86845354601889</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOLAM, a township and a parish in Castle Ward district, Northumberland. The township lies between the rivers Blyth and Wansbeck, near the Devil&apos;s causeway, a branch of Watling-street, and on the Morpeth and Scots Gap railway, near Angerton station, 8 miles WSW of Morpeth. Acres, 1,119. Pop., 102. Houses, 21.&#151;The parish includes also the townships of Bolam vicarage, Trewick, Gallow Hill, Shortflatt, Harnham, Bradford, and Belsay; the last of which has a post office under Newcastle-on-Tyne. Acres, 7,336. Real property, &#163;7,682. Pop., 685. Houses, 136. The property is divided among a few. Bolam manor belonged anciently to the De Bolams; passed to the Horsleys; and went from them to Lord Decies. Harnham manor belonged, in the time of Charles II., to Colonel Philip Babbington, governor of Berwick. Belsay Castle belonged formerly to the Middletons; and belongs now to the baronet family of Monck. A stone coffin was found in a tumulus on Bolam moor. Coal and limestone occur. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;238.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is ancient, in good condition; and contains the effigies of a Knight Templar, supposed to be Sir Walter de Bolam, and a tomb of the Middletons. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Bolam/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655251</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bolam,_Northumberland</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10301567</id>
   <status>AP/CP/Tn</status>
   <name>BOLAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10301579</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOLAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10301580</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>BOLAM VICARAGE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
