<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9315</id>
<name>HORTON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.1027649708846</lat>
<lon>-1.55100668691896</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORTON, a township and a parish in Tynemouth district, Northumberland. The township lies on the river Blyth, 2 miles WNW of Newsham r. station, and 3 WSW of Blyth. Acres, 2, 365; of which 190 are water. Pop., 368. Houses, 82. The parish contains also the townships of East Hartford, West Hartford, Bebside, and Cowpen; the last of which has a head post office, designated Cowpen, Northumberland. Acres, 5, 550. Real property, &#163;43, 563; of which &#163;30, 000 are in mines and &#163;100 in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 4, 449; in 1861, 6, 787. Houses, 1, 349. The increase of pop. was caused by the extension of collieries. The property is not much divided. An old castle of the Delavals stood here: and the ruins of it were destroyed in 1809. Coal is very extensively worked. The parish originally formed part of Woodhorn, and afterwards became a parochial chapelry. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;150. Patron, the Vicar of Woodhorn. The church was rebuilt in 1827, and has a tower. There are chapels for Presbyterians, Independents, Wesleyans, Primitive Methodists, and Roman Catholics. There is also a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Horton/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10319158</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>HORTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10319160</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>9316</id>
<name>HORTON GRANGE</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.0780518849035</lat>
<lon>-1.6953272856057</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORTON-GRANGE, a township in Dinnington parish, Northumberland; 6&#189; miles S of Morpeth. Acres, 1, 222. Pop., 85. Houses, 16. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10319171</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HORTON GRANGE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
