<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9725</id>
<name>TWEEDMOUTH</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.7504446688569</lat>
<lon>-2.01918343163172</lon>
<gazetteerText>TWEEDMOUTH, a village, a township, and a parish, in Berwick district, Northumberland. The village stands on the Northeastern railway, at the junction of the branch to Kelso, 1 mile S of Berwick; had a castle, founded by King John, and destroyed by William of Scotland; is a seat of petty-sessions; carries on industry in iron foundries, a brewery, saw-mills, a paper mill, and engine works; and has a great r. station with telegraph, a church, two Presbyterian chapels, an ultra-mural cemetery, and a national school.-The township comprises 1,931 acres of land and 397 of water. Pop., 2,884. Houses, 394. -The parish contains also Spittal and Ord townships, and comprises 5,140 acres. Post town, Berwick-upon-Tweed. Real property, &#163;15,251; of which &#163;150 are in quarries, &#163;475 in mines, &#163;316 in fisheries, and &#163;500 in gasworks. Pop., 5,414. Houses, 789. The manor belongs to the corporation of Berwick. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;300. Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of D. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Tweedmouth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635314</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10329073</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>TWEEDMOUTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329127</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TWEEDMOUTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12780333</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TWEEDMOUTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9309</id>
   <name>HORNCLIFFE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9448</id>
   <name>LOANEND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9456</id>
   <name>LONGRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9588</id>
   <name>ORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9670</id>
   <name>SHORESWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9708</id>
   <name>THORNTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
