<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8673</id>
<name>ALLENDALE</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.8655647870055</lat>
<lon>-2.26815377404242</lon>
<gazetteerText>ALLENDALE, a small town, a parish, and a subdistrict in the district of Hexham, Northumberland. The town stands on the Allen rivulet, and on the Allendale railway, 9 miles SW of Hexham. It has a post office. under Carlisle; and is a polling place. A weekly market is held on Friday; and fairs on the Friday after 12 May, and 29 Oct., and 22 Aug.&#151;The parish is cut into eight divisions (some of them called grieveships), Allendale town, Catton, Keenty, Broadside, High Forest, Low Forest, Park, and West Allen; and it contains the townships or villages of West Allendale, Catton, Keenty, Broadside-with-Forest, and Allenheads. Acres, 37,267. Real property, &#163;64,716,-of which &#163;27,373 are in mines. Pop., 6,401. Houses, 1,155. Much of the surface is moorish, bleak, hilly, and mountainous. The property is much subdivided. Lead mines are worked to the extent of about 2,500 tons of metal in the year; and there are several smelting-houses, with very extensive flues. Coal also is worked; and some silver and rock crystal are found. Allenheads, at the sources of the Allen, 7 miles S of the town of Allendale, is in the neighbourhood of the lead mines, and has a post office of its own name under Carlisle. An ancient camp occurs at Old Town. The living of Allendale is a rectory in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;250.* Patron, W. B. Beaumont, Esq. The church was built in 1807. The p. curacies of St. Peter, Ninebanks, and West Allen are separate benefices. Values, &#163;120, &#163;150,* and &#163;100. Patron of all, W. B. Beaumont, Esq. There are Wesleyan and Primitive Methodist chapels and a free grammar school. The Allendale railway was authorized in 1865; joins the Newcastle and Carlisle near Hexham; was opened to Langley in 1867, to Catton-road in 1868; and was to be prolonged to Allenheads.-The subdistrict of Allendale comprises Allendale parish and Haydon chap elry. Acres, 50,955. Pop., 8,622. Houses, 1,589. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Allendale,_Northumberland</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Allendale/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7290889</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10298994</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>WEST ALLEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10299081</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>ALLENDALE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10299111</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ALLENDALE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10299123</id>
   <status>PA</status>
   <name>ALLENDALE COMMON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10299196</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ALLENDALE ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551754</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ALLENDALE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
