<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9313</id>
<name>HORSLEY MOOR</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.2264205082973</lat>
<lon>-1.75000614725506</lon>
<gazetteerText>Horsley Moor, tract, N. Northumberland, common to townships of Bigges Quarter, Freeholders Quarter, Riddells Quarter, and Fenrother, 192 ac. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10319092</id>
   <status>ExP</status>
   <name>HORSLEY MOOR</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>9310</id>
<name>HORSLEY</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>54.9922213265612</lat>
<lon>-1.86999873675658</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORSLEY, a township in Ovingham parish, Northumberland; near the Roman wall, the river Tyne, and the Newcastle and Carlisle railway, 2&#189; miles NW of Wylam. It has a post office under Wylam, and chapels for Independents and Wesleyans. Acres, 1, 478. Pop., 272. Houses, 58. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646553</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10319031</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10319055</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9680</id>
   <name>SPITAL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9784</id>
   <name>WHITTLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>24684</id>
<name>HORSLEY</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.2659750443878</lat>
<lon>-2.2439467666849</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORSLEY, a chapelry in Elsdon parish, Northumberland; on the river Reed, 3 miles NNW of Otterburn, and 7 N by W of Woodburn r. station. Post town, Otterburn, under Newcastle-upon-Tyne. The statistics are returned with the parish. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the rectory of Elsdon, in the diocese of Durham. The church is a modern edifice, in the Lombardic style, with an apse. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10319080</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10319109</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORSLEY WITH BYRNESS</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>20356</id>
<name>LONG HORSLEY</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.2462256677832</lat>
<lon>-1.76718568824305</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORSLEY (LONG), a village in Morpeth district, and a parish partly also in Rothbury district, Northumberland. The village stands on a branch of the river Coquet, 4&#190; miles W by S of Widdrington r. station, and 6 NW by N of Morpeth; and has a post office under Morpeth.&#151;The parish comprises the townships of WittonShields, Stanton, Longshaws, Bigges-Quarter, RiddellsQuarter, Freeholders-Quarter, Todburn, and Wingates. Acres, 12, 849. Real property, &#163;7, 463; of which &#163;38 are in mines. Pop., 964. Houses, 201. The manor belonged to Gospatrick, passed to the Merlays, and belongs now to Thomas Riddell and Henry J. Baker, Esqs. An old tower of the Riddells stands at the W end of the parish, and is used as a Roman Catholic chapel. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;336. * Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is modern, and has a bell turret. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643677</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Longhorsley/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10319134</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LONG HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10319146</id>
   <status>CP/PA</status>
   <name>LONG HORSLEY COMMON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10322571</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LONGHORSLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
