<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9222</id>
<name>HARTBURN</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.1812929071159</lat>
<lon>-1.91929199976528</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARTBURN, a township in Morpeth district, and a parish partly also in Castle-Ward and Rothbury districts, Northumberland. The township lies on the Hart burn stream, 1 mile N of Angerton r. station and 8 W of Morpeth; and it has a post office under Morpeth. Pop., 31. Houses, 7. The parish contains also the townships of Hartburn-Grange, Whitridge, Cambo, WallingtonDemesne, Deanham, Todridge, North Middleton, South Middleton, Highlaws, Corridge, Low Angerton, High Angerton, East Thornton, West Thornton, Long Witton, East Shaftoe, West Shaftoe, Greenleighton, Harwood, Hartington, Hartington-Hall, Rothley, and Fairnley. Acres, 25, 778. Real property, &#163;17, 090; of which &#163;10 are in mines. Pop., 1, 526. Houses, 276. The property is not much divided. Most of the land is in pasture. Coal, limestone, and lead ore are found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;650. * Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is ancient, but very good; has a square tower; and contains a monument to Hodgson, the historian of Northumberland, a monument by Chantrey to Lady Bradford, and a memorial window of 1853 to Sir Thomas Bradford. Hodgson and Archdeacon Sharp were vicars; and the latter built a quaint Gothic tower, now used as a school House. The vicarage of Cambo is a separate benefice. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Hartburn/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647416</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10317137</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Tn</status>
   <name>HARTBURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10317174</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARTBURN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10317198</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>HARTBURN GRANGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10317230</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARTBURN WITH MELDON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9779</id>
   <name>WHITRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
