<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9799</id>
<name>WOOLER</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.5617007532747</lat>
<lon>-2.03340829467044</lon>
<gazetteerText>WOOLER, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Glendale district, Northumberland. The town stands on a branch of the river Till, under the Cheviots, 9&#189; miles SW by W of Belford r. station; was anciently called Willover; was given, by Henry I., to R. de Muscamp; passed to the Scropes, the D&apos;Arcys, the Percys, the Greys, and the Earl of Tankerville; was much injured by fire in 1722 and in 1863; is a seat of petty-sessions and county courts, and a polling place; presents an appearance partly poor, and partly much improved: and has a post-office&#8225; under Alnwick, a banking office, a good inn, a mechanics&apos; institute, with library and reading-rooms, a church rebuilt in 1765 and enlarged in 1835, four dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a public school, a dispensary, the Glendale workhouse, a weekly market on Thursday, and fairs on 4 May and 17 Oct.&#151;The parish includes Fenton township and several hamlets, and comprises 4,852 acres-Real property, &#163;8,002. Pop. in 1851, 1,911; in 1861, 1,697. Houses, 322. Traces of an old castle of the Muscamps are on a round hill. Many ancient entrenchments are in the vicinity. Humbledon Heugh, connected with the battle of Humbledon, and about a mile NW of the town, is the most remarkable of the entrenchments; and a pillar, commemorative of Earl Percy&apos;s victory, is in the plain beneath. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;478.* Patron, the Bishop of Chester.&#151;The sub-district contains 6 parishes and 2 parts. Acres, 82,531. Pop., 6,378. Houses, 1,194. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wooler,_Northumberland</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Wooler/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633606</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10330660</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WOOLER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10330671</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WOOLER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551870</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WOOLER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8666</id>
   <name>AKELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8945</id>
   <name>COUPLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9083</id>
   <name>DODDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9122</id>
   <name>EWART</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9320</id>
   <name>HUMBLETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9322</id>
   <name>ILDERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9417</id>
   <name>KIRKNEWTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9488</id>
   <name>NORTH MIDDLETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9495</id>
   <name>MILFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9514</id>
   <name>NESBIT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
