<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8754</id>
<name>BOTHAL</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.1822003923318</lat>
<lon>-1.60604567358706</lon>
<gazetteerText>BOTHAL, a township and a parish in Morpeth district, Northumberland. The township is called Bothal Demesne; and lies on the Wansbeck river, near the Northeastern railway, 3 miles E of Morpeth. Acres, 3,027. Real property, &#163;6,895. Pop., 642. Houses, 122. The parish includes also the townships of Oldmoor, Pegsworth, Longhirst, and Ashington and Sheepwash; and its Post Town is Morpeth. Acres, 7,593. Real property, &#163;5,510; of which &#163;903 are in mines. Pop., 1,233. Houses, 241. The property is divided among a few &apos;The manor belonged, in the time of Henry II., to the Bertrams; passed by marriage first to the Ogles, then to the Cavendishes; and belongs now to the Duke of Portland. Remains of a castle of the Bertrams, and of an ancient chapel of the Virgin, still exist. Coal is worked. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Sheepwash, and the p. curacy of Hebburn, in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;1,357.* Patron, the Duke of Portland. The church contains tombs of the Ogles. A school is endowed with &#163;25 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bothal</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Bothal/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655133</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10301609</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BOTHAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10301622</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>BOTHAL DEMESNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10301646</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BOTHAL DEMESNE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8690</id>
   <name>SHEEPWASH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
