<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9393</id>
<name>INGRAM</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.4396594379927</lat>
<lon>-1.97470796353057</lon>
<gazetteerText>INGRAM, a township and a parish in Glendale district, Northumberland. The township lies on the river Breamish, 4&#189; miles NW of Whittingham, and 11 W of Alnwick r. station; and bears the name of Ingram, Linhope, and Greenshawhill. Acres, 6, 882. Pop., 72. Houses, 10. The parish contains also the township of Reaveley, and that of Fawdon, Clinch, and Hartside; and its post town is Eglingham, under Alnwick. Acres, 11, 304. Real property, &#163;3, 693. Pop., 200. Houses, 32. The property is divided among a few. Reaveley Manor is a chief residence. Much of the land is moor and mountain. Traces of an ancient British town are at Linhope; and many camps and foundations of habitations are on Ingram Hill or Brough Law. The pier of a Roman bridge, on the Breamish, near the church, was discovered in 1859, in consequence of a change in the course of the river. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;462. * Patron, L. I. H. Allgood, Esq. The church is ancient; comprises only part of the original edifice; was repaired in 1858; and has a tower. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Ingram/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ingram,_Northumberland</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646199</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10319304</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>INGRAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10319316</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>INGRAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10319328</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>INGRAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10321268</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>INGRAM LINHOPE AND GREENSHAWHILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10321359</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>INGRAM LINHOPE GREENSHAWHILL AND HARTSIDE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
