<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>761</id>
<name>BLYTH</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.1143190852445</lat>
<lon>-1.52658959804862</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLYTH (South), a seaport town, a township, and a chapelry in Earsdon parish, Northumberland. The town stands on the S side of the river Blyth, at its mouth, and on the Blyth and Tyne railway, 9 miles SE of Morpeth. It was formerly a disagreeable place, of poor appearance, with narrow, irregular streets; but it has been much improved; and it now contains many good houses. It has a post office,&#8225; of Blyth, Northumberland, a r. station with telegraph, a bank, a church of 1863, two Presbyterian chapels, a Wesleyan chapel of 1866, a P. Methodist chapel, and national schools. A weekly market is held on Wednesday; a large trade is carried on in coals and coasting; and much manufacturing industry is a foot in connexion with shipping. The harbour has undergone great improvement since 1854, and not yet completed, costing nearly &#163;50,000, and including docks, a quay of 1,400 feet, and a breakwater of about 3,000 yards. The depth of water over the bar, at full tides, was formerly 16 feet; and this has been increased. Two fixed lights, put up in 1788, are 445 feet apart, and 26 and 48 feet high.-The township comprises 1,180 acres. Pop., 1,953. Houses, 327. The manor belongs to Sir M. W. Ridley, Bart.&#151;The chapelry is conterminate with the township; and is a donative in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;93. Patron, Sir M. W. Ridley, Bart. The church was built in 1751. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blyth,_Northumberland</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655315</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10136416</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>BLYTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10168521</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BLYTH VALLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10209092</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SOUTH BLYTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10301506</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BLYTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10301520</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLYTH ST CUTHBERT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10301543</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLYTH ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551900</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BLYTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12744950</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>BLYTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12744961</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>BLYTH VALLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12836314</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BLYTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>311</id>
   <name>MORPETH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>312</id>
   <name>ALNWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>496</id>
   <name>ASHINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>625</id>
   <name>AMBLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>682</id>
   <name>HEXHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>981</id>
   <name>CRAMLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1257</id>
   <name>COWPEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8940</id>
   <name>CORBRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9607</id>
   <name>PONTELAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9684</id>
   <name>STANNINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
