<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9110</id>
<name>EMBLETON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.4865388692102</lat>
<lon>-1.65350682382515</lon>
<gazetteerText>EMBLETON, a village, a township, a parish, and a sub-district in Alnwick district, Northumberland. The village stands near the coast, 1&#189; mile ESE of Christon-Bank r. station, and 6&#189; NE by N of Alnwick; is irregularly built; and has a post office under Chathill The township includes the village, and comprises 1, 978 acres of land and 418 of water. Pop., 727. Houses, 155. The parish contains also the townships of Stamford, Craster, Dunston, Newton-by-the-Sea, Falloden, Rock, Rennington, Broxfield, and Brunton. Acres, 13, 228. Real property, &#163;16, 333; of which &#163;150 are in mines. Pop., 2, 302. Houses, 450. The property is not much divided. The manor belongs to the Earl of Tankerville. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;815.* Patron, Merton College, Oxford. The church is a fine old structure; has an embattled tower; and was restored in 1850. The parsonage was anciently fortified, and has still a machicolated tower. Charities, &#163;22. The p. curacies of Rock and Rennington are separate benefices.&#151;The sub-district contains also Edlingham, Howick, and Long Houghton parishes. and five townships of two other parishes. Acres, 50, 587. Pop., 6, 063. Houses, 1, 195. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embleton,_Northumberland</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650016</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Embleton/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10314367</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EMBLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10314392</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EMBLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10551780</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EMBLETON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
