<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9155</id>
<name>FELTON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.30296288141</lat>
<lon>-1.7403662519254</lon>
<gazetteerText>FELTON, a township in Alnwick district, and a parish partly also in Morpeth district, Northumberland. The township lies on the river Coquet, 3&#190; miles SW of Acklington r. station, and 9 S of Alnwick; has a post office&#8225; under Acklington, and a three-arched bridge over the Coquet; and enjoys picturesque scenery along that river&apos;s winding course. The parish contains also the townships of Elyhaugh, Swarland, Bockenfield, Eshott, Greens and Glantlees, Acton and Old Felton, and East and West Thirston-with-Shothaugh. Acres, 12, 830. Real property, &#163;12, 224; of which &#163;104 are in mines. Pop., 1, 591. Houses, 307. The property is not much divided. Felton Hall was built by the Widdringtons; and passed to the Riddells. The barons of Northumberland did homage at Old Felton, in 1216, to Alexander of Scotland; and King John was so enraged at their conduct as to devastate the place. An obelisk to the memory of Lord Nelson, erected by Sir W. Davison, is at Swarland. The living is a vicarage, united with the vicarage of Long Framlington, in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;275.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is good; . and there are chapels for Presbyterians and Roman Catholics and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Felton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649569</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10134286</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>FELTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10315578</id>
   <status>CP/Tn/AP</status>
   <name>FELTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10315621</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FELTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8662</id>
   <name>ACTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9108</id>
   <name>ELYHAUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>26728</id>
<name>OLD FELTON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.3144164636455</lat>
<lon>-1.71636171625488</lon>
<gazetteerText>Felton, Old, hamlet, Felton par., N. Northumberland. See ACTON AND OLD FELTON. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7291387</link>
</links>
</place>
</results>
