<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9496</id>
<name>MITFORD</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.1654503620429</lat>
<lon>-1.74818996361695</lon>
<gazetteerText>MITFORD, a village, a township, and a parish, in Morpeth district, Northumberland. The village stands at the confluence of the rivers Font and Wansbeck, near the Wansbeck Valley railway, 2&#189; miles W by S of Morpeth; was originally called Midford; was once a markettown; and has a post office under Morpeth.-The township includes the village, and extends into the country. Pop., 210. Houses, 35.&#151;The parish contains also the townships of Molesden, Spittal-Hill, Edington, Benridge, Newton-Underwood, Newton-Park, Throphill, Nunriding, Pigdon, and High and Low Highlaws. Acres, 9,595. Real property, &#163;7,252. Pop., 646. Houses, 118. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged, before the Norman conquest, to the Mitfords; passed by marriage, soon after the Conquest, to Sir Richard Bertram; was ravaged by the Flemish Rutars, in consequence of Roger Bertram having joined the barons against King John; was forfeited in 1264, in consequence of another Bertram having rebelled against Henry III.; passed to the Earls of Pembroke and Athole, and to the Percys; went back to the Mitfords in the time of Charles II.; belongs now to Admiral Mitford; and is associated with William Mitford, author of the &quot;History of Greece, &apos;&apos;and with Mary Russell Mitford, author of &quot;Our Village.&quot; A castle was built here in 1150-70, by W. Bertram; and is still represented by a ruined massive keep, with two posterns, and two waggonheaded vaults. The old manor house was built in 1637, out of materials of the castle; and is still represented by a turreted porch and some offices. The present mansion, the seat of Admiral Mitford, is a modern edifice after designs by Dobson. Spittal-Hill House is the seat of the Bullock family; and occupies the site of an hospital, founded by Sir William Bertram. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;100.* Patron, the Bishop of Durham. The church stands embosomed in trees; is cruciform, 109 feet long, with Norman nave, a good Norman door, and an early English chancel; has a picturesque W turret; and contains an effigies of a Bertram. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mitford</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642409</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Mitford/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10024699</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>MITFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10323381</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MITFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10323423</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MITFORD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9094</id>
   <name>EDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9568</id>
   <name>NEWTON PARK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9569</id>
   <name>NEWTON UNDERWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9603</id>
   <name>PIGDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
