<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9520</id>
<name>NETHERWITTON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.2095208496727</lat>
<lon>-1.83832408132249</lon>
<gazetteerText>WITTON (Nether), a township in Morpeth district, and a parish partly also in Rothbury district, Northumberland The township lies on the river Font, 4 miles N of Angerton r. station, and 8 WNW of Morpeth; contains a picturesque village of its own name; is sometimes called Witton-by-the-Waters; contained the residence of Roger Thornton, the distinguished merchant-prince of Newcastle, who died in 1429; and has a post-office under Morpeth. Acres, 3,914. Pop., 301. Houses, 53. N.-W. Hall is the seat of R.. Trevelyan, Esq.; and has, at the back, a curious tall tower, which was visited by Oliver Cromwell and the parliamentarian army. The parish includes, in its Rothbury section, six townships; and comprises altogether 7,723 acres. Real property, &#163;4,546; of which &#163;101 are in mines. Pop., 486. Houses, 86. There is a small woollen factory. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, the Vicar of Hartburn. There is a village school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.bpears.org.uk/NBL/Netherwitton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641769</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10323964</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>NETHERWITTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10323976</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NETHERWITTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9124</id>
   <name>EWESLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9259</id>
   <name>HEALEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9304</id>
   <name>HOLLINGHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9458</id>
   <name>LONGSHAWS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9461</id>
   <name>LONGWITTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9583</id>
   <name>NUNNYKIRK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9633</id>
   <name>RITTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9685</id>
   <name>STANTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9792</id>
   <name>WINGATES</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
