<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>313</id>
<name>EARSDON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.0466583714726</lat>
<lon>-1.51074356664507</lon>
<gazetteerText>EARSDON, a township, a parish, and a sub-district in Tynemouth district, Northumberland. The township lies on the coast, and on the North Shields and Blyth railway, 4 miles NNW of North Shields; and has a post office under Newcastle-upon-Tyne. Acres, 1, 769; of which 978 are water. Pop., 577. Houses, 152. The parish contains also the townships of Seghill, Burradon, Backworth, Holywell, Hartley, Seaton-Delaval, and South Blyth, and the lordship of Newsham; and it has railway stations for Hartley, Seaton-Delaval, Seghill, Newsham, and Blyth. Acres, 11, 646. Real property, &#163;71, 375; of which &#163;47, 900 are in mines, &#163;150 in quarries, &#163;40 in fisheries, and &#163;399 in gas-works. Pop., 12, 444. Houses, 2, 475. Two fearful colliery accidents occurred in this parish; the one in Burradon, in the beginning of 1860, with a loss of nearly 80 lives; the other in Hartley, in the beginning of 1862, with a loss of upwards of 200. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Durham. Value, &#163;119.* Patrons, the Proprietors of Land. The ancient church belonged, from the 11th century, to Tynemouth priory; and a new church, an elegant structure on an eminence, with a conspicuous and imposing tower, was built in 1837. The p. curacies of Seghill and Seaton-Delaval, and the donative of Blyth, are separate benefices. There are several dissenting chapels.&#151;The sub-district is less than the parish by South Blyth and Newsham. Acres, 10, 466. Pop., 9, 543. Houses, 1, 960. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Earsdon</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650531</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10042616</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>EARSDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10313685</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>EARSDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10313727</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EARSDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10566538</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EARSDON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>9089</id>
<name>EARSDON</name>
<container>NORTHUMBERLAND</container>
<lat>55.2366843329456</lat>
<lon>-1.69600719318824</lon>
<gazetteerText>EARSDON-FOREST, a township in Hebburn parish, Northumberland; on the river Wansbeck, adjacent to the Wansbeck railway, 6 miles W of Morpeth. Acres, 744. Pop., 24. Houses, 4. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10313740</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>EARSDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10313764</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>EARSDON FOREST</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
