<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5151</id>
<name>HOUGHTON ST GILES</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8842383218796</lat>
<lon>0.857248646340686</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOUGHTON-IN-THE-HOLE, or HOUGHTON-le-Dale, a parish in Walsingham district, Norfolk; on the river Stiffkey, and on the Norwich and Wells railway, 1 mile SSW of New Walsingham. Post town, New Walsingham, under Fakenham. Acres, 978. Real property, &#163;1, 615. Pop., 191. Houses, 46. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Henry L. Warner, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;148. Patron, H. L. Warner, Esq. The church is decorated English, and has a fine E window, and remains of a carved screen. A small ancient chapel, on the W side of the parish, is supposed to have belonged to Walsingham abbey; and was converted into.a barn.. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barsham,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/houghton_st_giles/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10180533</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HOUGHTON ST GILES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10212893</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HOUGHTON ST GILES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505549</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOUGHTON ST GILES</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3113</id>
<name>HOUGHTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8260507953618</lat>
<lon>0.660847608305731</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOUGHTON (NEW), HOUGHTON-IN-THE-BRAKE, or HOUGHTON-NEXT-HARPLEY, a village and a parish in Docking district, Norfolk. The village stands 9&#189; miles W by S of Fakenham r. station; and has a post office, of the name of Houghton, under Rougham. The parish comprises 1,495 acres. Real property, &#163;1,322. Pop., 227. Houses, 53. The property, with Houghton Hall, belongs to the Marquis of Cholmondeley. Houghton Hall was built by Sir Robert Walpole, after designs by Ripley; presents a principal front of 166 feet with a cupola and lantern at each angle; has wings connected by a Tuscan colonnade, making a total frontage of 450 feet; contains a staircase by Kent, a hall of 40 feet by 40, a saloon of 40 feet by 30, a library of 22 feet by 21, and other spacious apartments; is enriched with noble and costly works of art; had a collection of pictures which was sold, in 1779, for &#163;45,500, to the Empress Catherine of Russia; stands in rather a flat park, with many fine old beech and other trees, of Sir Robert&apos;s planting; was inhabited, for ten years, by Sir Robert Walpole; and was visited, in 1814 and 1818, by the Duke of Wellington. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;110. Patron, the Marquis of Cholmondeley. The church was repaired by Sir Robert Walpole; consists of nave, chancel, and aisles, with a small tower; and contains an effigies of a prior of Coxford, of the time of Edward I. The church vault contains the remains of fifteen generations of the Walpole family. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/houghton/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646527</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10090866</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HOUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505537</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOUGHTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>6006</id>
<name>HOUGHTON ON THE HILL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6105805552009</lat>
<lon>0.760206123022555</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOUGHTON-ON-THE-HILL, a parish in Swaffham district, Norfolk; on the river Wissey, 4&#190; miles SE of Swaffham r. station. Post town, Swaffham. Acres, 601. Real property, &#163;1, 001. Pop., 49. Houses, 10. The manor belongs to E. A. Applewaite, Esq. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of North Pickenham, in the diocese of Norwich. The church consists of nave and chancel, with a tower. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/houghton_on_hill/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10214166</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HOUGHTON ON THE HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505525</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOUGHTON ON THE HILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
