<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4725</id>
<name>HELLINGTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5741102217119</lat>
<lon>1.41796683591819</lon>
<gazetteerText>Hellington (or Hillington), par., S. Norfolk, 4 miles NW. of Loddon, 516 ac., pop. 100. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/hellington/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7295703</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10161551</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10504892</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5150</id>
<name>HILLINGTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7751813808502</lat>
<lon>0.654667829992597</lon>
<gazetteerText>HILLINGTON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Freebridge-Lynn district, Norfolk. The village stands near the river Babingley, 5&#189; miles ENE of Wootton r. station, and 7 NE of Lynn; is a pleasant place; has a post office&#8225; under Lynn, and a good inn; and is a seat of petty sessions.&#151;The parish comprises 2, 529 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 525. Pop., 330. Houses, 56. The manor belonged formerly to the Hovells; and belongs now to Sir W. H. B. Ffolkes, Bart. Hillington Hall was built in 1627; has been greatly enlarged and improved; and is a stately mansion. Four ancient crosses are in the village. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;450.* Patron, Sir W. H. B. Ffolkes, Bart. The church is partly old, but has a modern nave; is built of stone, flint, and brick; has a square embattled tower; and contains monuments of the Hovells, the Brownes, and the Ffolkeses. Handsome schools, of Carr stone and red brick, were built in 1855. -The sub-district contains ten parishes. Acres, 26, 155. Pop., 4, 543. Houses, 929. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/hillington/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10180510</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HILLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505148</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HILLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541451</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HILLINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
