<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4662</id>
<name>CAISTER ST EDMUND</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5845418013524</lat>
<lon>1.31025421102298</lon>
<gazetteerText>CAISTOR-ST. EDMUNDS, a small village and a parish in Henstead district, Norfolk. The village stands on the river Tees, near the Eastern Union railway, 3 miles south of Norwich. The Venta-Icenorum of the Romans, their principal station in the country of the Iceni, was here; and Roman roads went hence to Brancaster, Cromer, Burgh-Castle, Dunwich, Bury, Cambridge, Colchester, and London. Substructions or traces of Roman buildings occur over an area of 30 acres; and Roman urns, bronzes, numerous coins, and other relics have been found. Ancient Norwich is believed to have been built of materials from the Roman structures here; and hence the old rhyme,- Caistor was a city when Norwich was none, And Norwich was built of Caistor stone. The parish comprises 1,044 acres; and its Post Town is Norwich. Real property, &#163;2,384. Pop., 162. Houses, 37. The property is divided among a few. Caistor Hall is the seat of Mrs. H. Dashwood. The living is a rectory, united with the sinecure rectory of Markshall, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;447.* Patron, Mrs. H. Dashwood. The church stands within the old Roman enclosure, and has a few Roman bricks in its masonry. Charities, &#163;42. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caistor_St_Edmund</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/c/caistor_st_edmund/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10057772</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CAISTER ST EDMUND WITH MARKSHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10069026</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>CAISTOR ST EDMUND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143159</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CAISTER ST EDMUND</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10160686</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CAISTER ST EDMUND</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
