<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2289</id>
<name>HINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5728122759705</lat>
<lon>0.984978050479765</lon>
<gazetteerText>HINGHAM, a small town and a parish in Forehoe district, Norfolk. The town stands on a rising ground, near a lake which emits one of the headstreams of the river Yare, 3&#188; miles WSW of Kimberley r. station, and 6 W by N of Wymondham; was largely burnt in the middle of last century, and is now chiefly modern; had formerly a weekly market; has still fairs on 7 March, Whit-Tuesday, and 2 Oct.; has also a post office&#8225; under Attleborough; and is a seat of petty sessions. The parish comprises 3, 649 acres. Real property, &#163;11, 149. Pop., 1, 605. Houses, 373. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the Earls of Pembroke, and passed to the Morleys and the Wodehouses. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;1, 200. * Patron, Lord Wodehouse. The church was built by Remigius de Hethersete, the rector, in 1316; is a spacious structure with a lofty tower; had formerly several chapels; contains, in a still extant side chapel, a noble monument to Thomas Lord Morley, who died in 1435; has an E window of stained glass, 36 feet by 18, given in 1813 by Lord Wodehouse; and was recently in disrepair. There are chapels for Independents and Primitive Methodists. A free grammar school, founded in 1727 by William Parlett, has &#163;165 a year from endowment; and other charities have &#163;71. Sir Ralph de Hingham, a judge in the time of Edward I., was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/hingham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hingham,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646856</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050091</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505185</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575151</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575163</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HINGHAM AND MITFORD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1689</id>
   <name>SOUTHBURGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2282</id>
   <name>HACKFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3071</id>
   <name>HARDINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3951</id>
   <name>DEOPHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3966</id>
   <name>KIMBERLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4736</id>
   <name>MORLEY ST BOTOLPH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5129</id>
   <name>WICKLEWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5584</id>
   <name>LITTLE ELLINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5886</id>
   <name>CROWNTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6209</id>
   <name>REYMERSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
