<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3946</id>
<name>SNETTISHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.875614441449</lat>
<lon>0.493974703449342</lon>
<gazetteerText>SNETTISHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Docking district, Norfolk. The village stands adjacent to the Lynn and Hunstanton railway, 10&#190; miles N by E of Lynn; was once a market-town; is now a seat of petty sessions; and has a r. station with telegraph, a post-office&#8225; under Lynn, an ancient cross, and a fair on 12 Oct. The parish contains also Southgate hamlet, with a coastguard station; extends some distance along the Wash; and comprises 5,580 acres of land, and 9,660 of foreshore. Real property, &#163;8,115; of which &#163;30 are in quarries. Pop., 1,173. Houses, 251. The manor belongs to H. S. Le Strange, Esq. S. Halland Park House are chief residences. British celts and other antiquities have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;110.* Patron, H. S. Le Strange, Esq. The church comprises nave, aisles, and S transept, restored in 1856, at a cost of &#163;1,200; includes remains of a ruined chancel; and has an E tower, with lofty spire, serving as a landmark to mariners. There are two Methodist chapels, an endowed school with &#163;92 a year, and charities &#163;8.&#151;The sub-district contains ten parishes. Acres, 39,480. Pop., 5,702. Houses, 1,206. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Snettisham</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/s/snettisham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637580</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10123628</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SNETTISHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541062</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SNETTISHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5474</id>
   <name>INGOLDISTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
