<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3111</id>
<name>PULHAM ST MARY MAGDALENE</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4384618714698</lat>
<lon>1.23391824594874</lon>
<gazetteerText>PULHAM-ST. MARY MAGDALENE, or Pulham-Market, a village and a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk. The village stands adjacent to the Waveney Valley railway, 3&#189; miles W N W of Harleston; was formerly a market town; and has a station on the railway, a post-office under Harleston, and a cattle fair on thethird Thursday of May. The parish contains also Depwade workhouse, which had 244 inmates at the census of1861. Acres, 2, 957. Real property, &#163;5, 941; of which &#163;19 are in the railway . Pop. in 1851, 1, 414; in 1861, 1, 279. Houses, 239. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to G. Copeman, Esq. P.-M. Hallwas formerly the seat of the Percies, and is now the seat of the Leggetts. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;646.* Patron, the Crown. The church is old but good; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with N porch and embattled tower. There are chapels for Wesleyan and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and charities &#163;160. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/p/pulham_market/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pulham_Market</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639861</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6930001</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10049830</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>PULHAM MARKET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10090842</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>PULHAM ST MARY MAGDALENE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10097939</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PULHAM MARKET</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1678</id>
   <name>MOULTON ST MICHAEL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2283</id>
   <name>HARDWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2625</id>
   <name>TIVETSHALL ST MARGARET</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2991</id>
   <name>WACTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3947</id>
   <name>LONG STRATTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4710</id>
   <name>SHELTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4737</id>
   <name>ASLACTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>3196</id>
<name>PULHAM ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4240608400692</lat>
<lon>1.25703545060336</lon>
<gazetteerText>PULHAM-ST. MARY-THE-VIRGIN, a village and a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk. The village stands near the Waveney Valley railway, 2&#189; miles W N W of Harleston; and has a station on the railway, and a post-office under Harleston. The parish comprises 2, 998 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 464. Pop., 863. Houses, 196. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged anciently to Audrey abbey at Ely; wentto the Crown, by an exchange, in the time of Elizabeth; and belongs now to G. Copeman, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;662.* Patron, the Crown. The church consists of nave, aisle, and chancel, with very fine porch and lofty embattled tower. There are a Baptist chapel, a parochial school, partly free, and charities &#163;30. William of Wykeham and the poet Broome were rectors. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/p/pulham_st_mary/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639861</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093740</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PULHAM ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10101840</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>PULHAM ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5134</id>
   <name>NEEDHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
