<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5643</id>
<name>REEPHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7624748175135</lat>
<lon>1.11283007522338</lon>
<gazetteerText>REEPHAM, a small town and a parish in Aylsham district, Norfolk. The town stands on a branch of the river Wensum, 6&#189; miles S W by W of Aylsham, and 7 Eby N of Elmham r. station; extends into the parishes of Hackford, Whitwell, and Kerdiston; is a seat of petty sessions and a polling-place; and has a post-office&#8225; under Norwich, a hotel, a police station, two churches, Wesleyan and Primitive Methodist chapels, two cemeteries, a public library and reading-room, two national schools, and charities &#163;27. The two churches are those of Reepham and Whitwell; and they stand in one churchyard, where also stood formerly the church of Hackford. Reepham church is ancient but good; has an embattled tower; and contains ancient monuments of the Kerdistons. A weekly market is held on Wednesday; a stockfair is held on 29 June; and there are a brewery and twolarge tanneries. The parish comprises 570 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 454. Pop., 346. Houses, 86. The manor belonged once to the De Vauxs. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Kerdiston, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;699.* Patron, Trinity College, Cambridge. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/k/kerdiston/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reepham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639512</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/r/reepham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reepham,_Norfolk</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10057656</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>REEPHAM WITH KERDISTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143317</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>REEPHAM AND HACKFORD WITH WHITWELL AND KERDISTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10201986</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>REEPHAM WITH KERDISTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10203831</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>REEPHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23436</id>
<name>KERDISTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7776905638095</lat>
<lon>1.08128694395143</lon>
<gazetteerText>KERDISTONE, a parish in Aylsham district, Norfolk; 1&#189; mile NW of Reepham, and 7&#189; ENE of Elmham r. station. Post town, Reepham, under Norwich. Acres, 1, 680. Real property, &#163;2, 604. Pop., 207. Houses, 41. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Reepham, in the diocese of Norwich. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10505914</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KERDISTON REIFFHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
