<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3981</id>
<name>BUCKENHAM TOFTS</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.518406067534</lat>
<lon>0.704919320535224</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUCKENHAM-NEAR-TOFTS, or Buckenham-Parva, a parish in Swaffham district, Norfolk; on the river Wissey, 6 miles NE of Brandon r. station, and 6 SW by W of Watton. Post Town, Tottington, under Thetford. Acres, 931. Real property, &#163;300. Pop., 60. Houses, 12. The property is all in one estate. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, not reported. Patron, the Rev. T. Newman. There is no church. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/buckenham_tofts/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10057760</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BUCKENHAM TOFTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10096856</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>BUCKENHAM PARVA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10102820</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BUCKENHAM PARVA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10124128</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BUCKENHAM TOFTS</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5740</id>
<name>BUCKENHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5980244396367</lat>
<lon>1.48026964840988</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUCKENHAM, a parish in Blofield district, Norfolk; on the river Yare and the Yarmouth railway, 7&#190; miles ESE of Norwich. It has a station on the railway; and its Post Town is Cantley, under Norwich. Acres, 931. Real property, &#163;1,394. Pop., 49. Houses, 11. The property is all in one estate. A Roman station is supposed to have been here; and a ferry is here over the Yare. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Hassingham, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;280.* Patron, Sir J. B. Proctor Beauchamp, Bart. The church is ancient, has an octagonal tower, and was recently repaired. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/buckenham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buckenham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654417</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10033184</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BUCKENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10199578</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BUCKENHAM WITH HASSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10205414</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BUCKENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10501600</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BUCKENHAM FERRY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5698</id>
<name>OLD BUCKENHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4855627522685</lat>
<lon>1.04439919812042</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUCKENHAM (Old), a village and a parish in Guiltcross district, Norfolk. The village stands round a green of about 40 acres, 3 miles SSE of Attleborough r. station, and 7 SSW of Wymondham; and has a post office under Attleborough. Acres, 4,986. Real property, &#163;10,216. Pop., 1,214. Houses, 287. The property is divided among a few. The manor was given by the Conqueror to De Albini; passed to the Knevets and others; and belongs now to Lord Petre. A castle was built on it, soon after the Conquest; and gave place to the castle at New Buckenham. A priory of black canons was erected out of the materials of the castle; and given, in the time of Mary, to Sir Thomas Lovell. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;102. Patrons, the Inhabitants. The church belonged to the priory, and is plain and thatched. There are an endowed school and some charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/buckenham_old/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641037</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10203764</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>OLD BUCKENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10501660</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OLD BUCKENHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3332</id>
<name>NEW BUCKENHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4691619093943</lat>
<lon>1.08154265883501</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUCKENHAM (New), a village and a parish in Guiltcross district, Norfolk. The village stands 4 miles SE of Attleborough r. station, and 7&#189; S by W of Wymondham; and has a post office&#8225; under Attleborough. It consists chiefly of small narrow streets; and is irregularly built. A weekly market was formerly held on Saturday; and fairs are still held on the last Thursday of May and Sept., and 22 Nov. The parish comprises 324 acres. Real property, &#163;1,630. Pop., 656. Houses, 152. The property is subdivided. A castle was built here, in the time of Henry II., by William de Albini. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;115.* Patrons, the Inhabitants. The church is partly of 1479, partly earlier; has a square tower and a very beautiful screen; and contains a number of curious and interesting monuments. There are Wesleyan and Primitive Methodist chapels, a national school, an almshouse for six women, and other charities &#163;61. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Buckenham</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/buckenham_new/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641694</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10044170</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>NEW BUCKENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10098786</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>NEW BUCKENHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>4674</id>
<name>BUNWELL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.492682629099</lat>
<lon>1.13456076624735</lon>
<gazetteerText>BUNWELL, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; 3&#188; miles NE of New Buckenham, and 4&#189; WSW of Forncett r. station. It has a post office under Attleborough. Acres, 2,470. Real property, &#163;5,556. Pop., 907. Houses, 212. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;644.* Patron, Sir R. J. Buxton, Bart. The church is good. There are a P. Methodist chapel and a n. school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bunwell</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/bunwell/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654322</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10160844</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BUNWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10501696</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BUNWELL CARLTONS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1697</id>
   <name>FORNCETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2242</id>
   <name>FORNCETT ST MARY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3367</id>
   <name>TACOLNESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4753</id>
   <name>CARLETON RODE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5148</id>
   <name>FUNDENHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
