<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3947</id>
<name>LONG STRATTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4875330518036</lat>
<lon>1.23628860074149</lon>
<gazetteerText>STRATTON (Long), or S.-St. Mary, a village and a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk. The village stands 2 miles E of Forncett r. station, and 10&#188; SSW of Norwich; was the Estratnnas of the East Anglian kings; is a seat of petty-sessions, and a polling place; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a good inn, a restored ancient church, an Independent chapel, a national school, a weekly market on Tuesday, and fairs on Whit-Tuesday, and 12 Oct. The parish includes Wood-Green hamlet, and comprises 1,517 acres. Real property, &#163;3,751. Pop., 743. Houses, 159. S. House is the seat of R. R. Burroughs, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;424.* Patron, Cains College, Cambridge. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_Stratton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643628</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/l/long_stratton/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10123641</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>STRATTON ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10142866</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONG STRATTON ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10198963</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>LONG STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10509567</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541037</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10564104</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STRATTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2278</id>
<name>STRATTON ST MICHAEL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4975325196214</lat>
<lon>1.24646550440203</lon>
<gazetteerText>STRATTON-ST. MICHAEL, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; 1 mile NNE of Long Stratton, and 2&#189; ENE of Forncett r. station. Post town, Long Stratton. Acres, 1,050. Real property, &#163;2,342. Pop., 251 . Houses, 65. The property is subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;388.* Patron, New College, Oxford. The church is ancient. There are two Methodist chapels, a national school, and charities &#163;7. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10049982</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>STRATTON ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143330</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONG STRATTON ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10161460</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>LONG STRATTON ST PETER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
