<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5136</id>
<name>REEDHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5795890427645</lat>
<lon>1.60565947357879</lon>
<gazetteerText>REEDHAM, a village and a parish in Blofield district, Norfolk. The village stands adjacent to the Norwich and Yarmouth railway, at the junction of the branch to Lowestoft, near the river Yare, 8&#188; miles S E by E of Yarmouth; and has a station with telegraph at the railway junction, and a post-office under Norwich. The parish includes a detached tract of marsh, and comprises 3, 328acres. Real property, &#163;6,022; of which &#163;50 are inquarries. Pop., 836. Houses, 174. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to H. M. Leathes, Esq. A seat of the kings of East Anglia was here; and Lodbroc, or Lothbroch, the Dane, landed here in a storm. There are mills, lime-kilns, a foundry, a brick-field, and a ferry over the Yare. Foundations of a Roman pharo were discovered on a low cliff. The living is a rectory, united with the vicarage of Freethorpe, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;607.* Patron, H. M. Leathes, Esq. The church is ancient but good. There are a Primitive Methodist chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/r/reedham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reedham,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639519</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10180338</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>REEDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507935</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>REEDHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1670</id>
   <name>WICKHAMPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1704</id>
   <name>LIMPENHOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3267</id>
   <name>FREETHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4698</id>
   <name>SOUTHWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
