<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4682</id>
<name>TUNSTEAD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7505154224774</lat>
<lon>1.41436392079091</lon>
<gazetteerText>TUNSTEAD, a parish, a district, and a hundred, in Norfolk. The parish lies near the North Walsham railway, 3 miles NE of Coltishall. Post town, Coltishall, under Norwich-Acres, 2,291. Real property, &#163;4,684. Pop., 405. Houses, 95. The property is divided among three. The living is a vicarage, united with South Ruston, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;286.* Patron, Mrs. T. Mack. The church was recently restored.&#151;The district contains 42 parishes, and is divided into 4 sub-districts. Acres, 62,607. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;8,113. Pop. in 1851, 15,614; in 1861, 14,516. Houses, 3,344. Marriages in 1863, 89; births, 474,-of which 45 were illegitimate; deaths, 266,-of which 71 were at ages under 5 years, and 12 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,044; births, 4,672; deaths, 3,192. The places of worship, in 1851, were 42 of the Church of England, with 8,248 sittings; 1 of Independents, with 210 s.; 7 of Baptists, with 1,873 s.; 8 of Wesleyans, with 1,025 s.; 11 of Primitive Methodists, with 1,312 s.; and 1 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 100 attendants. The schools were 21 public day-schools, with 1,436 scholars; 20 private day-schools, with 387 s.; 35 Sunday schools, with 1,917 s.; and 3 evening schools for adults, with 16 s. The workhouse is in Smallburgh.-The hundred contains 27 parishes. Acres, 36,954. Pop. in 1851, 11,127; in 1861, 10,425. Houses, 2,426. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/t/tunstead/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299493</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10031370</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>TUNSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10161034</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TUNSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10510351</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TUNSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581485</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TUNSTEAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5119</id>
<name>SMALLBURGH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7630906829475</lat>
<lon>1.4630978568437</lon>
<gazetteerText>SMALLBURGH, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Tunstead district, Norfolk. The village stands 5&#188; miles SE of North Walsham r. station; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a post-office under Norwich. The parish comprises 1,247 acres. Real property, &#163;3,052. Pop. in 1861, 559; of whom 93 were in the Tunstead workhouse. Houses, 112. The manor belongs to Sir J. H. Preston, Bart. New-Halland Holly House are chief residences. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;430.* Patron, the Bishop of N. The church is old but good. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, a village school, church charities &#163;21, and a poors&apos; allotment.&#151;The sub-district contains 13 parishes. Acres, 16,999. Pop., 4,229. Houses, 1,002. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/s/smallburgh/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637621</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10085690</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD/Inc</status>
   <name>SMALLBURGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10095300</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>SMALLBURGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10153086</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>SMALLBURGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10179968</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SMALLBURGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10509038</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SMALLBURGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541396</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SMALLBURGH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
