<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5142</id>
<name>COSTESSEY</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6564080585922</lat>
<lon>1.21001066397241</lon>
<gazetteerText>COSSEY, or Costessey, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Forehoe district, Norfolk. The village stands on the river Wensum, 4&#189; miles NW of Norwich; consists chiefly of one long street; and has a post office, of the name of Cossey, under Norwich. The parish comprises 3, 040 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 509. Pop., 1, 047. Houses, 244. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged, after the Conquest, to Alan, Earl of Richmond; passed, in the time of Henry II., to the Crown; went back to the Earls of Richmond, and back again to the Crown; formed part of the dowry of Queen Anne of Cleves; was given, in 1557, to Sir Henry Jermingham; and has descended from him to Lord Stafford. Cossey Hall, Lord Stafford&apos;s seat, dates from the time of Sir Henry Jermingham; was rebuilt in pure Tudor style, after designs by Buckler; has an elegant chapel, in the pointed style, 90 feet long and 35 feet wide; contains a number of interesting portraits; and stands in a beautiful park of upwards of 900 acres. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, not reported. Patrons, the Corporation of Norwich. The church has a square tower, with wooden spire, and is good; and there are Baptist, Wesleyan, and Roman Catholic chapels.&#151;The sub-district contains fourteen parishes. Acres, 15, 618. Pop., 4, 116. Houses, 922. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Costessey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652289</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/c/costessey/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10180405</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>COSTESSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10502718</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>COSTESSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541104</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>COSTESSEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
