<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4718</id>
<name>FINCHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6245510810086</lat>
<lon>0.497967545994661</lon>
<gazetteerText>FINCHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Downham district, Norfolk. The village stands 5 miles E of Stow r. station, and 5 ENE of Downham-Market; consists of a long street, with several good houses; and has a post office under Downham. -The parish comprises 2, 968 acres. Real property, &#163;6, 145. - Pop., 886. Houses, 190. The property is divided among a few. An old seat here was built in the time of Edward IV., and became a farm-house. The present parish comprises two ancient ones, St. Martin and St. Michael; and the living is a conjoint one, consisting of the vicarage of St. Martin and the rectory of St. Michael, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;581.* Patron, alternately the Lord Chancellor and the Rev. W. Blyth. St. Martin&apos;s church is an ancient structure of flint and stone, with lofty square tower; has a square Norman font; and it in very good condition. St. Michael&apos;s church was taken down in 1745. There are a Methodist chapel, a partially endowed national school, and charities &#163;95.&#151;The sub-district contains nine parishes. Acres, 22, 849. Pop., 5, 215. Houses, 1, 104. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649446</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/f/fincham/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10161472</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FINCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10503700</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FINCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541086</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FINCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10573476</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FINCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10573488</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FINCHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
