<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5748</id>
<name>LYNG</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7103091304394</lat>
<lon>1.07279547697115</lon>
<gazetteerText>LING, or LYNG, a village and a parish in Mitford district, Norfolk. The village stands on the river Wensum, 6 miles NE by E of East Dereham r. station; and has a post office under Norwich, and a fair on 20 Nov. The parish contains also the hamlet of Ling-Easthaugh, and comprises 1,899 acres. Real property, &#163;3,516. Pop., 590. Houses, 141. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Rev. H. Lombe. A nunnery was early founded here; and was removed, in 1160, to Thetford. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;528. * Patron, the Rev. H. Lombe. The church comprises nave, aisle, and chancel, with S porch and tower; and was recently in disrepair. There are chapels for Primitive Methodists and United Free Methodists, a national school, and charities &#163;6. Jeffrey de Ling, a monkish historian, was probably a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/l/lyng/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lyng,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643293</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10205505</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LYNG</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10514010</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LYNG</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2626</id>
   <name>WHITWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3297</id>
   <name>HOCKERING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3333</id>
   <name>WESTON LONGVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3927</id>
   <name>NORTH TUDDENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5469</id>
   <name>SPARHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5694</id>
   <name>ELSING</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
