<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5161</id>
<name>BLAKENEY</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9563975604925</lat>
<lon>1.00875227610046</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLAKENEY, a small seaport and a parish in Walsingham district, Norfolk. The seaport stands on a natural harbour of its own name, 5&#189; miles NNW of Holt, and 7&#189; E of Wells r. station; and has a post office under Thetford. It was anciently called Snitterley; and it got the right to a market in the time of Henry III. A Carmelite monastery was founded at it about 1295; and given, at the dissolution, to William Rede; and some remains of the edifice, including several fine arches, are still standing. John de Baconsthorpe, who was styled &quot;the resolute and subtle doctor,&quot; held a place in the monastery, and rose to be head of the English Carmelites. The parish church, on an eminence a little S of the town, is a curious flint structure, in early and in later English; has a lofty embattled tower, which serves as a mark to mariners in taking the harbour; and contains a fine ancient font, three sedilia, and remains of a screen and stalls. There are chapels for Baptists and Methodists. The harbour has a dangerous shifting bar, yet serves well both for commerce and for shelter. About 60 vessels, aggregately nearly 4,000 tons, belong to the port. The chief export is corn; the chief imports are coal, timber, iron, hemp, tar, and tallow; and a considerable fishery is carried on.&#151;The parish comprises 1,865 acres; of which 235 are water. Real property, &#163;3,260. Pop., 961. Houses, 264. The property is not much divided. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Glandford and the rectory of Cockthorpe, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;506.* Patron, Lord Calthorpe. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655384</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/blakeney/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blakeney,_Norfolk</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10099365</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLAKENEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143469</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLAKENEY WITH LITTLE LANGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10180703</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BLAKENEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10500928</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BLAKENEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
