<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4734</id>
<name>LUDHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7098061921377</lat>
<lon>1.53418385923044</lon>
<gazetteerText>LUDHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Tunstead district, Norfolk. The village stands 1&#190; mile NE of the river Bure, 8 NE of Brundall r. station, and 12&#189; NE by E of Norwich; was once a market-town; and has a post office under Norwich, and a fair on the Thursday and Friday after Trinity Sunday. The parish comprises 2,977 acres. Real property, &#163;7,175. Pop. in 1851,982; in 1861,884. Houses, 199. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the abbey of St. Benet-at-the-Holme; and was given, by Henry VIII., to the Bishops of Norwich. A grange of the abbey on it was converted by the bishops into a palaceThe palace was, in great degree, burnt down in 1611; was restored and enlarged by Bishop Harsnet; and, after the bishops ceased to occupy it, was partly converted into a granary, and partly made a farm-house, now called Ludham Hall. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is later English; has an embattled tower; and contains a richly carved screen, and a beautifully carved font. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, a national school, a fuel allotment worth &#163;98 a year, and other charities &#163;14.&#151;The sub-district contains also six other parishes. Acres, 18,219. Pop.. 3,682. Houses, 815. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/l/ludham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ludham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643426</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10161654</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LUDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506372</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LUDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541372</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LUDHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2291</id>
   <name>HORNING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5324</id>
   <name>CATFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5551</id>
   <name>IRSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
