<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3025</id>
<name>BURGH ST PETER</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4854866284308</lat>
<lon>1.6581422778803</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURGH-ST. PETER, or Wheatacre-Burgh, a parish in Loddon district, Norfolk; on the river Waveney and on the Lowestoft railway, near Mutford station, 6 miles ENE of Beccles. Post Town, Mutford-Bridge, under Lowestoft. Acres, 2,041. Real property, &#163;3,486. Pop., 298. Houses, 73. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;330.* Patron, the Rev. W. Boycatt. The church is good; and there is a Wesleyan chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/burgh_st_peter/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10087442</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BURGH ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10512578</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURGH ST PETER</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2263</id>
<name>BURGH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7862817637892</lat>
<lon>1.29132522193896</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURGH-NEXT-AYLSHAM, or Burgh-St.-Peter, a parish in Aylsham district,.Norfolk; on the river Bure, 2 miles SE of Aylsham, near the line of the projected railway from Norwich to Cromer, and 11&#189; N of Norwich. Post Town, Aylsham, under Norwich. Acres, 789. Real property, &#163;1,857. Pop., 227. Houses, 54. The property is divided between three. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, not reported. Patron, J. H. Holly, Esq. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/burgh_next_aylsham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654297</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10049775</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BURGH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
