<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2248</id>
<name>GREAT WALSINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9012728611518</lat>
<lon>0.871431727347634</lon>
<gazetteerText>WALSINGHAM, a small town, a sub-district, and a district, in Norfolk. The town stands on the river Stiff-key, and on the Eastern Counties railway, 5 miles N by E of Fakenham; is in the parish of New Walsingham; was formerly famous for an Augustinian priory, founded in 1061 by Faverches; had also a grey friary founded in 1346 by the Clares, and a lepers&apos; hospital; drew to its shrines, for a long period, many distinguished pilgrims, one of the last of whom was Henry VIII. in the second year of his reign; gives the title of Baron to the family De Grey; is a seat of petty-sessions and county courts; and has a post-office&#8225; under Fakenham, a r. station, a police station formerly a bridewell, a parish church, Independent and Wesleyan chapels, an endowed grammar-school with &#163;110 a year, a national school, eight alms houses, charities &#163;180, and three annual fairs. The priory was preceded by a chantry, built in imitation of the Sancta Casa at Nazareth; contained a highly venerated image of the Virgin, which Henry VIII. eventually caused to be burnt at Chelsea; was devastated at the Reformation; and is now represented mainly by the W entrance-gateway, by a window-arch 60 feet high, and by part of the cloisters. The parish church is later English and cruciform; has a tower with slender spire; and has been partially restored. See Walsingham (Little).&#151;The sub-district contains 19 parishes. Acres, 28,251. Pop., 6,492. Houses, 1,437. -The district includes also Fakenham and Wells sub-districts, and comprises 87,342 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;13,438. Pop. in 1851, 21,883; in 1861, 21,118. Houses, 4,724. Marriages in 1863, 134; births, 601,- of which 74 were illegitimate; deaths, 440,-of which 134 were at ages under 5 years, and 26 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,447; births, 6,728; deaths, 4,402. The places of worship, in 1851, were 48 of the Church of England, with 10,705 sittings; 9 of Independents, with 993 s.; 4 of Baptists, with 754 s.; 1 of Quakers, with 160 s.; 14 of wesleyans, with 1,948 s.; 22 of Primitive Methodists, with 2,489 s.; and 6 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 712 s. The schools were 30 public day-schools, with 2,070 scholars; 58 private day-schools, with 1,205 s.; 52 Sunday schools, with 2,873 s.; and 7 evening schools for adults, with 97 s. The workhouse stands on the boundary with Great Snoring, about a mile S of Walsingham. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walsingham</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/w/walsingham_great/</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Walsingham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7295693</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10041995</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WALSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10049489</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GREAT WALSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173899</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WALSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10187552</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>WALSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10197405</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GREAT WALSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10510624</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WALSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541438</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WALSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581722</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WALSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
