<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6010</id>
<name>GILLINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4778063530655</lat>
<lon>1.55425401118197</lon>
<gazetteerText>GILLINGHAM, a village and a parish in Loddon district, Norfolk. The village stands near the river Waveney, the East Suffolk railway, and the boundary with Suffolk, 1&#189; mile NNW of Beccles; and is small. The parish includes also a small suburb of Beccles on the left side of the Waveney. Post town, Beccles. Acres, 2, 008. Real property, &#163;3, 768. Pop., 390. Houses, 90. The property is divided among a few. Gillingham Hall, near the village, was built by the father of Lord Bacon; became the seat of Mrs. Schultz; and has a picturesque cupola-tower. Much of the land was formerly marsh, and is now excellent grazing ground. There were formerly two parishes, -G-All-Saints. and G-St. Mary; but they were united in 1748. The livings remain nominally distinct, but are actually united; and both are rectories in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;523.* Patron, Lord G. Beresford. All-Saints church was taken down at the union of the parishes, and only the ivy-clad ruin of its tower remains. St. Mary&apos;s church is cruciform; has an apsidal Norman chancel, and an embattled tower; contains a brass of 1553; and was restored in 1858. Charities, &#163;51. Dean Moss, chaplain of Queen Anne, was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/g/gillingham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299503</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10089189</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>GILLINGHAM ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10092826</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GILLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10180491</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>GILLINGHAM ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10204719</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GILLINGHAM ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10214233</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>GILLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10216229</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GILLINGHAM ST MARY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
