<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3201</id>
<name>HORSTEAD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7196618589373</lat>
<lon>1.35241754695817</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORSTEAD, a village and a parish in St. Faith district, Norfolk. The village stands on the river Bure, &#189; a mile W of Coltishall, and 6 NNE of Norwich r. station; and took its name, which is a corruption of &quot;Hursted&quot; or wood place, from the former abundance of wood about it.&#151;The parish includes the quondam parish of Stanninghall, and bears the name of Horstead-with-Stanninghall. Post town, Coltishall, under Norwich. Acres, 2, 733. Real property, &#163;4, 181. Pop., 608. Houses, 121. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Dr. Thomas Blake. Horstead Hall, a mansion of 1835, in the Tudor style, is a seat of Lord Suffield. An ancient priory was here, a cell to Trinity abbey at Caen, in Normandy; and was given to King&apos;s College, Cambridge. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich.. Value, &#163;580.* Patron, King&apos;s College, Cambridge. The church is ancient, but very good; has a square tower; and contains an ancient font, and monuments of the Hornsells, the Wards, and the Townshends. Charities, &#163;11. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/horstead/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646551</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093806</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HORSTEAD WITH STANNINGHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10097927</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORSTEAD WITH STANNINGHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10180521</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HORSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2989</id>
   <name>CROSTWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3030</id>
   <name>GREAT HAUTBOIS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3961</id>
   <name>HAINFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4719</id>
   <name>FRETTENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5581</id>
   <name>LAMMAS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
