<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1684</id>
<name>EAST RAYNHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7963326586323</lat>
<lon>0.798155090431053</lon>
<gazetteerText>RAINHAM (East), a parish, with a village, in Walsingham district, Norfolk; on the river Wensum, 3&#190; miles S W of Fakenham r. station. Post-town, Brougham, under Brandon. Acres, 1, 635. Real property, &#163;2, 908. Pop., 139. Houses, 31. The property belongs to Marquis Townshend. R. Hall is the Marquis&apos;s seat; wasbuilt, in 1630, by Inigo Jones; contains some very valuable paintings; and stands on an eminence, with a charming view. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of West Rainham, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;717.* Patron, Marquis Townshend. The church was restored, or rather rebuilt, in 1868. Charities, &#163;6. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650348</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/r/raynham_east/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015418</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EAST RAYNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10077278</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EAST RAYNHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5467</id>
<name>WEST RAYNHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.788309148585</lat>
<lon>0.753611650538478</lon>
<gazetteerText>RAINHAM (West), a parish in Walsingham district, Norfolk; on the river Wensum, 4&#188; miles S W of Faken.ham r. station. Post-town, Rougham, under Brandon. Acres, 1, 370. Real property, &#163;2, 945. Pop. 369. Houses, 64. The property belongs to Marquis Townshend. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of East Rainham, in the diocese of Norwich. The church is in ruins. There are a girls&apos; school, and charities &#163;33. Whitakerthe antiquary was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/r/raynham_west/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634283</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050777</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>RAYNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10169010</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RAYNHAM WITH HELHOUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10175136</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST RAYNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10195597</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WEST RAYNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507893</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEST RAYNHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
