<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20263</id>
<name>ECCLES NEXT THE SEA</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8031559222921</lat>
<lon>1.58325209482204</lon>
<gazetteerText>ECCLES, or Eccles-next-the-Sea, a parish in Tunstead district, Norfolk; on the coast, 9 miles ESE of North Walsham r. station, and 18 NE of Norwich. Post town, Happisburgh, under Norwich. Acres, 397; of which 100 are water. Real property, with Hempstead, &#163;2, 204. Pop., 28. Houses, 7. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;75. Patron, the Rev. H. Lombe. The church was destroyed by the sea in 1605. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/e/eccles/</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/e/eccles_by_the_sea/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10123720</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ECCLES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143482</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ECCLES</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23435</id>
<name>ECCLES</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4647800925288</lat>
<lon>0.972487344829323</lon>
<gazetteerText>ECCLES, a parish in Guiltcross district Norfolk; adjacent to the Norfolk railway, at Eccles-Road station 2&#189; miles NE of Harling. It has a post office under Attleborough. Acres, 1, 685. Real property, &#163;1, 746. Pop., 194. Houses, 38. The property is divided among three. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;290. Patron, Sir T. Beevor, Bart. The church is ancient. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650279</link>
</links>
</place>
<place>
<id>5145</id>
<name>QUIDENHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4491825874247</lat>
<lon>0.984684983573331</lon>
<gazetteerText>QUIDDENHAM, a parish in Guiltcross district, Norfolk; on an affluent of the Little Ouse river, 1 mile S of Eccles-Road r. station, and 2&#189; E N E of East Harling. Post-town, Attleborough. Acres, 1, 126. Real property, &#163;1, 303. Pop., 111. Houses, 22. The property belongs to the Earl of Albemarle; and Q. Hall is the Earl&apos;s seat. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Snetterton, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;636.* Patron, the Earl of Albemarle. The church was restored in 1859; has a high Norman porch and a round tower with octangular lantern; and contains two monuments to the Hollands and one to Lady Sophia Macdonald. There is a free school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/q/quidenham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quidenham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639770</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10123549</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>QUIDENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10180454</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>QUIDENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507807</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>QUIDENHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
