<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6046</id>
<name>GREAT MASSINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7629705240092</lat>
<lon>0.659894874639955</lon>
<gazetteerText>MASSINGHAM (GREAT), a village and a parish in Freebridge-Lynn district, Norfolk. The village stands near the Peddar way, 7 miles NE of East Winch r. station, and 12 E by N of Lynn; was formerly a market town; and has a post office under Brandon, and fairs on Monday-Thursday and 8 Nov. The parish comprises 4,112 acres. Real property, &#163;5,191. Pop., 934. Houses, 191. The property is snbdivided. One manor belongs to the Marquis of Cholmondeley, and another to the Earl of Leicester. An Angustinian priory was founded here, before 1260, by Nicholas le Syre; became a cell to the priory of Westacre; and, at the dissolution, was given to Sir T. Gresham. About 1,000 acres are heath and sheepwalk. Traces of ancient British dwellings exist. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;900.* Patron, the Marquis of Cholmondeley. The church is later English; was repaired in 1865; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;26. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648061</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/massingham_great/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10215857</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GREAT MASSINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506554</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MASSINGHAM PRIORY AND DARTFORDS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1685</id>
   <name>ROUGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2800</id>
   <name>LITTLE MASSINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4663</id>
   <name>HARPLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4684</id>
   <name>WEASENHAM ST PETER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5150</id>
   <name>HILLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5814</id>
   <name>WEASENHAM ALL SAINTS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
