<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4727</id>
<name>HEYDON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8044108211587</lat>
<lon>1.14070171556688</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEYDON, a village and a parish in Aylsham district, Norfolk. The village stands on an affluent of the river Wensum, 5 miles W by N of Aylsham, and 9&#189; ENE of Elmham r. station; and has a post office under Norwich. The parish comprises 1, 942 acres. Real property, &#163;1, 799. Pop., 302. Houses, 60. The manor belonged formerly to the Earles, and belongs now to W. E. L. Bulwer, Esq. Heydon Hall is a Tudor mansion of 1584; was recently restored and improved; and stands in a wooded park of about 400 acres. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Irmingland, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;290.* Patron, W. E. L. Bulwer, Esq. The church has a lofty embattled tower, with pinnacles; is in good condition; and contains an altar tomb of Erasmus Earle, serjeant-at-law to Cromwell. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/heydon/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heydon</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647003</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10077175</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEYDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10161575</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HEYDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505057</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEYDON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2269</id>
<name>SAXLINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9151414553822</lat>
<lon>1.02319901783173</lon>
<gazetteerText>SAXLINGHAM, a parish in Walsingham district, Norfolk; 8 miles E N E of Walsingham r. station. Its post town is Holt. Acres, 1, 498 Real property, &#163;2, 285. Pop., 156. Houses, 30. The manor belongs to the Rev. Sir E. R. Jodrell, Bart. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;474.* Patron, the Rev. Sir E. R. Jodrell, Bart. The church is later English and cruciform. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saxlingham</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/s/saxlingham/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10049891</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SAXLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10508502</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SAXLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
