<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2304</id>
<name>BARTON BENDISH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6144491757403</lat>
<lon>0.546660149434008</lon>
<gazetteerText>BARTON-BENDISH, a village and a parish in Downham district, Norfolk. The village stands 5&#189; miles SSW of Narborough r. station, and 7&#189; ENE of Downham; and has a post office under Brandon. It took its distinctive name from a dyke, called Bendish, which the Saxons erected to mark the boundary of the hundred. The parish includes also the hamlet of Eastmore. Acres, 4,390. Real property, &#163;4,849. Pop., 484. Houses, 94. The property is divided among a few. Barton-Bendish Hall is the seat of Sir H. Berney, Bart. The living consists of the rectory of St. Mary-with-All Saints, and the rectory of St. Andrew; and is in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;569.* Patrons, Sir H. Berney, Bart. and the Lord Chancellor. The church of St. Mary-with-All Saints is good; and that of St. Andrew has a fine screen, with hagiological figures, and was repaired in 1859. There are a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;36. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barton_Bendish</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/barton_bendish/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301876</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050285</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10057723</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10142829</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10161800</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10169094</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10174880</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10180685</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10204707</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH ST MARY AND ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10209705</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
