<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5463</id>
<name>HILGAY</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5365207352446</lat>
<lon>0.354105717763282</lon>
<gazetteerText>HILGAY, a village and a parish in Downham district, Norfolk. The village stands on the river Wissey, 2 miles from the Ouse, 3 NE of Hilgay Fen r. station, and 4 SSE of Market-Downham; and has a post office under Downham. The parish comprises 7, 860 acres; of which 5, 908 are in the Fens. Real property, &#163;13, 492. Pop., 1, 624. Houses, 365. The property is much subdivided. The Hall, about &#189; a mile from the village, belonged to the abbots of Ramsey; went at the dissolution to James Howe; belongs now to the Jones family; and was rebuilt, in the Tudor style, in 1840. Modney priory, a cell to Ramsey abbey, stood at what is now a farm house 2 miles SW. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;1, 600.* Patron, the Rev. W. J. Parkes. The parish church is mainly decorated English, partly later English, with a modern tower; and has been restored. A chapel of ease is in a hamlet on the Tennule bank W of the Ouse; and an iron church is in an isolated tract 7 miles distant; but that tract, together with portions of Littleport and Feltwell parishes, was made a separate charge in 1866. There are Methodist chapels, national schools, church lands about &#163;150, and charities &#163;290. P. Fletcher, the poet, was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/hilgay/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646903</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10168855</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HILGAY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10195512</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HILGAY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505112</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HILGAY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6005</id>
   <name>FORDHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
