<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5479</id>
<name>BILLINGFORD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.3708359199532</lat>
<lon>1.19260789117509</lon>
<gazetteerText>BILLINGFORD, or Pirleston, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; on the river Waveney, 1 mile E of Scole, and 2 SE of Diss r. station. Post Town, Scole. Acres, 1,820. Real property, &#163;1,589. Pop., 199. Houses, 46. The property is not much divided. The manor Belonged to Sir S. Burley, the Black Prince&apos;s favourite, executed in 1388. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Little Thorpe, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;264. Patron, G. Wilson, Esq. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/8223947</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/billingford_nr_diss/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10195755</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BILLINGFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10500734</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BILLINGFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2308</id>
<name>BILLINGFORD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7506177945359</lat>
<lon>0.979627650718011</lon>
<gazetteerText>BILLINGFORD, a parish in Mitford district, Norfolk; on the river Wensum, 1&#189; mile ESE of Elmham r. station, and 3&#189; SSW of Foulsham. It has a post office under Thetford. Acres, 1,820. Real property, &#163;2,337. Pop., 354. Houses, 74. The manor belongs to the Earl of Leicester. An hospital for poor travellers was founded at Beckhall here, in the time of Henry III., by William Beck. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;360.* Patron, the Earl of Leicester. The church is good. There are a Primitive Methodist chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/billingford_nr_dereham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655665</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050327</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BILLINGFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10512554</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BILLINGFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>21110</id>
<name>THORPE PARVA</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.3678173391942</lat>
<lon>1.17315414565082</lon>
<gazetteerText>THORPE-PARVA, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; 1&#190; mile E of Diss r. station. Post town, Scole. Acres, 349. Real property, &#163;487. Pop., 21. Houses, 4. The manor belongs to G. H. Wilson, Esq. The living is a rectory, annexed to Billingford. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/t/thorpe_parva/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015169</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>THORPE PARVA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10509970</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>THORPE PARVA</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
