<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>148</id>
<name>SHERINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9390963787448</lat>
<lon>1.2089719938901</lon>
<gazetteerText>SHERINGHAM, two villages and a parish in Erpingham district, Norfolk. The villages are Lower S. and Upper S., and have each a post-office under Norfolk. Lower S. stands on cliffs of the coast, 4&#189; miles W by N of Cromer, and 12 NW of North Walsham r. station; is supplied with water from a reservoir formed in 1862; carries on a considerable fishery; and has a harbour excavated out of a cliff, curing-houses, about 173 boats, a coastguard station, a lifeboat, a mariners&apos; chapel, and a reading room. Upper S. stands 1&#189; mile SSW of Lower S., and contains the church. The parish comprises 2,181 acres of land, and 175 of water. Real property, &#163;3,337. Pop., 1,289. Houses, 299. The manor, with S. Hall, belongs to H. R. Upcher, Esq. A black priory, a cell to Nutley abbey, was founded here in the time of Henry II. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;70. Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is early and later English, and was repaired in 1851. There are a school, and charities &#163;21. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheringham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638019</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/s/sheringham/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10025450</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SHERINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10079226</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SHERINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10508770</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHERINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541335</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHERINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2293</id>
   <name>KELLING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2641</id>
   <name>EDGEFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3032</id>
   <name>BEESTON REGIS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3266</id>
   <name>WEYBOURNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3420</id>
   <name>GRESHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3474</id>
   <name>BODHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3964</id>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5132</id>
   <name>CLEY NEXT THE SEA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5161</id>
   <name>BLAKENEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5458</id>
   <name>THORNAGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
