<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20305</id>
<name>HEIGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6391972515394</lat>
<lon>1.28148904499902</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEIGHAM, or Higham, a parish Norwich district, Norfolk; in the W side of Norwich city. Real property, &#163;36, 799. Pop. in 1851, 7, 745; in 1861, 13, 894. Houses, 3, 181. The increase of pop. arose from the removal hither of families from other parts of the city, and of Norwich workhouse from St. Andrew&apos;s parish. Here also are the jail, a private lunatic asylum, and the girls&apos; home. There are three livings, St. Bartholomew, Holy Trinity, and St. Philip; the latter two constituted in 1867; thefirst two rectories, the last a p. curacy, in the diocese of Norwich. Value of St. B., &#163;300; * of H. T. &#163;420; * of St. P., &#163;200.* Patron of all, the Bishop of N. St. P. church was built in 1 868, and is in the early French style. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/heigham/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10033779</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEIGHAM ST THOMAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10057826</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEIGHAM ST PHILIP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10061350</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEIGHAM ST BARNABAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10084969</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEIGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10161540</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HEIGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10169203</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEIGHAM MOST HOLY TRINITY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3911</id>
<name>POTTER HEIGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7216506738977</lat>
<lon>1.58977260562992</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEIGHAM-POTTER, a parish in Tunstead district, Norfolk; near the rivers Bure and Thurne, 6&#190; miles N by E of Acle, and 10&#189; NE by N of Brundall r. station. Post town, Ludham, under Norwich. Acres, 2, 527. Real property, &#163;4, 350. Pop., 439. Houses, 92. Nearly half of the land is marsh or waste; and there are a lake of 100 acres, and a piece of water called Heigham-Ponds. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;263.* Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is ancient; has a tower, circular below, octagonal above; and contains the tomb of Bishop Hall. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/p/potter_heigham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Potter_Heigham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639973</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10123010</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>POTTER HEIGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507753</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>POTTER HEIGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
