<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3464</id>
<name>GREAT ELLINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5329102882046</lat>
<lon>0.975777043081198</lon>
<gazetteerText>ELLINGHAM (Great), a village and a parish in Wayland district, Norfolk. The village stands 2 miles NE of Attleborough r. station; and has a post office under A. The parish comprises 2, 670 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 676. Pop., 717. Houses, 182. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory, united with the vicarage of Little Ellingham, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;735.* Patron, Samuel Colby, Esq. The church is good; and has a tower and spire. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans. Rack, the collaborateur of Collinson in the &quot;History of Somerset, &quot; was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/e/ellingham_great/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648111</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10103691</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GREAT ELLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10503504</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>GREAT ELLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3470</id>
<name>ELLINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4789068190075</lat>
<lon>1.48409095330943</lon>
<gazetteerText>ELLINGHAM, a parish in Loddon district, Norfolk; at the verge of the county, on the river Waveney, adjacent to the Waveney Valley railway, 2&#189; miles NE by E of Bungay. It has a side station on the railway. Post town, Bungay. Acres, 1, 379. Real property, &#163;2, 928. Pop., 386. Houses, 80. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich Value, &#163;414.* Patrons, Trustees. The church is very good; and there are charities &#163;51. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/e/ellingham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650094</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10103757</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ELLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10503474</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ELLINGHAM BY BUNGAY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5584</id>
<name>LITTLE ELLINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5511795455669</lat>
<lon>0.951315472286402</lon>
<gazetteerText>ELLINGHAM (Little), a parish in Wayland district, Norfolk; 4 miles NW of Attleborough r. station. Post town, Great Ellingham, under Attleborough. Acres, 1, 540. Real property, &#163;2, 705. Pop., 382. Houses, 78. The property is divided among a few. A village here was of some importance at Domesday, but now is very inconsiderable. A steam corn and seed mill was recently erected. The living is a vicarage, annexed to Great Ellingham, in the dio. of Norwich. The church, soon after being restored, was destroyed by fire in 1867; and was re-restored in 1869. Charities, &#163;45. . (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/e/ellingham_little/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296646</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10200192</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LITTLE ELLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10503516</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LITTLE ELLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
