<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2909</id>
<name>ORMESBY ST MARGARET</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6701816805385</lat>
<lon>1.69517009026353</lon>
<gazetteerText>ORMSBY-ST. MARGARET, or Great Ormsby, a village and a parish in Flegg district, Norfolk. The village stands about a mile from the sea, and 4&#190; miles N by W of Yarmouth r. station; and has a post-office, of the name of Ormsby, under Great Yarmouth. The parish, together with Ormsby, St. Michael and Scratby, comprises 2, 761 acres; of which 75, in Ormsby, St. Michael, are fore-shore. Real property of O., St. Margaret and O., St. Michael, &#163;6, 214. Pop. of O., St. Margaret alone, 777. Houses, 169. The property is subdivided. Ormsby House is the seat of Sir. E. H. K. Lacon, Bart.; and is a handsomemansion, in the pointed style, amid well-wooded grounds. An old mansion, formerly the seat of the Cleres, is nowa farm-house. The living is a vicarage, united with thevicarages of Ormsby, St. Michael and Scratby, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;420. Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Norwich. The church is ancient; has a finetower, surmounted by four figures of monks in lieu ofpinnacles; and contains brasses and monuments of the Cleres, the Symondses, and the Earl of Home. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and charities &#163;60. Twochurches, dedicated to the Holy Trinity and to St. Peter, formerly stood between the two Ormsbys, but are nowextinct. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ormesby_St._Margaret_with_Scratby</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/o/ormesby_st_margaret/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ormesby_St_Margaret_with_Scratby</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10082912</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ORMESBY ST MARGARET WITH SCRATBY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5471</id>
   <name>FILBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
