<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2925</id>
<name>MATTISHALL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6577883460583</lat>
<lon>1.02643385156718</lon>
<gazetteerText>MATTISHALL, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Mitford district, Norfolk. The village stands 3&#189; miles E of Yaxham r. station, and 4&#189; ESE of East Dereham; and has a post. office under Dereham, and a fair on the Tuesday before Holy Thursday. The parish comprises 2,280 acres. Real property, &#163;6,220. Pop., 971. Houses, 222. The property is much subdivided. The chief landowners are W. B. Donne, Esq. and the Rev. J. Sparke. The living is a vicarage, united with the rectory of Pattesley, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;469.* Patron, Cains College, Cambridge. The church is later English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with N and S porches, and with embattled tower; and was restored in 1858. There are chapels for Independents and Primitive Methodists.&#151;The sub-district contains also nine other parishes. Acres, 16,664. Pop., 4,340. Houses, 941. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/mattishall_burgh/</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/mattishall/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642905</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10083163</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MATTISHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10095694</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MATTISHALL BURGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506580</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MATTISHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10514034</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MATTISHALL BURGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541153</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MATTISHALL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1686</id>
   <name>RUNHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2315</id>
   <name>CARLETON FOREHOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2808</id>
   <name>YAXHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2916</id>
   <name>GARVESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2935</id>
   <name>COLTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3386</id>
   <name>BRANDON PARVA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3909</id>
   <name>EAST TUDDENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4680</id>
   <name>THUXTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5743</id>
   <name>WELBORNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5960</id>
   <name>BARNHAM BROOM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>2294</id>
<name>MARKSHALL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.591553048138</lat>
<lon>1.28827316101822</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARKSHALL, or MATTISHALL-HEATH, a parish in Henstead district, Norfolk; on the river Tas, adjacent to the Great Eastern railway, 2&#189; miles S of Norwich. Posttown, Norwich. Acres, 2,280. Real property, &#163;713. Pop., 34. Houses, 4. The property belongs to R. K. Long, Esq. and Mrs. Dashwood. The living is a sinecure rectory, annexed to the rectory of Caistor, in the diocese of Norwich. The church was relinquished in 1695, and has left some remains. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/markshall/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050157</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARKSHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10077229</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARKSHALL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
