<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20483</id>
<name>UPWELL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5983309704546</lat>
<lon>0.21350732618975</lon>
<gazetteerText>UPWELL, a village and a sub-district in Wisbeach district, and a parish partly also in Downham district, Cambridge and Norfolk. The village stands on the river Nen, 4&#190; miles E of Pear-Tree r. station, and 6 SE by S of Wisbeach; was once a market-town; and has a post-office under Wisbeach. The parish includes Welney chapelry; and is ecclesiastically cut into the sections of St. Peter, Christchurch, and Welney. Acres, 21,746. Real property, &#163;42,703. Pop. in 1851, 5,377; in 1861, 4,783. Houses, 1,081. The property is much subdivided. Beaupre Hall manor belongs to W. Townley, Esq.; and Wisbeach-Barton manor, to the Ecclesiastical Commissioners. A Gilbertine monastery was founded at Mirmaud about the time of King John. The livings are rectories in the diocese of Norwich. Value of St. Peter, &#163;3,080;* of Christchurch, &#163;1,594;* of Welney, &#163;1,300.* Patron of St. P. and C., W. Townley, Esq.; of Welney, W. Townlee, Esq. St. Peter&apos;s church is mainly later English; Christchurch was built in 1865; and Welney church was built in 1850. There are five dissenting chapels, a parochial school, and charities &#163;346.&#151;The sub-district excludes Welney chapelry, but includes Outwell parish. Acres, 19,472. Pop. in 1851, 5,619; in 1861, 4,947. Houses, 1,133. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/u/upwell/</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Upwell/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635078</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10012880</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>UPWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10057425</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>UPWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10105419</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>UPWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10120329</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>UPWELL CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10200167</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>UPWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550786</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>UPWELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
