<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6038</id>
<name>ERPINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8335218670191</lat>
<lon>1.25778579770066</lon>
<gazetteerText>ERPINGHAM, a parish, a district, and two hundreds in Norfolk. The parish is in Aylsham district; and lies on the river Bure, 3 miles NNE of Aylsham, and 5 &#189; miles W by N of North Walsham railway station. Post town, Aylsham, under Norwich. Acres, 1, 381. Real property, &#163;2, 664. Pop., 423. Houses, 99. The property is much divided. The manor belonged to the Erpinghams or Hapurgans, one of whom fought at Agincourt. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Blickling, in the diocese of Norwich. The church is later English, with a tower; and contains a painted rood-screen, a brass effigies of the Erpinghams of date 1370, and three brasses of later dates.&#151;The district comprehends the sub-district of North Walsham, containing the parishes of North Walsham, Suffield, Antingham, Gunton, Thorpe-Market, South Repps, Gimingham, Trunch, Knapton, Mundsley, Trimingham, Sidestrand, and North Repps; the sub-district of Cromer, containing the parishes of Cromer, Overstrand, Felbrigg, Metton, Roughton, Hanworth, Aldborough, Thurgarton, Sustead, Bessingham, Gresham, Aylmerton, Runton, Beeston-Regis, Sheringham, East Beckham, West Beckham, Barningham-Norwood, Barningham-Winter, Matlask, Plumstead, and Baconsthorpe; and the sub-district of Holt, containing the parishes of Holt, Bodham, Weybourne, Kelling, Salthouse, Cley-next-the-Sea, Glandford, Bayfield, Letheringsett, Hempstead, Edgefield, Hunworth, Stody, Thornage, Brinton, Briston, and Melton-Constable-with-Burgh-Parva. It comprises Erpingham poor-law union and Brinton incorporation, the latter consisting of the parishes of Brinton and Melton-Constable-with-Burgh-Parva; and it has one workhouse in West Beckham and another in Melton-Constable. Acres, 72, 513. Poor-rates in 1862, &#163;11, 234. Pop. in 1851, 21, 722: in 1861 20, 874. Houses, 4, 891. Marriages in 1860, 143; births, 642, -of which 68 were illegitimate; deaths, 460, -of which 163 were at ages under 5 years, and 22 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1, 437; births, 6, 605; deaths, 4, 505. The places of worship in 1851 were 49 of the Church of England, with 11, 718 sit-tings; 2 of Independents, with 443 s.; 2 of Baptists, with 370 s.; 2 of Quakers, with 298 s.; 12 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 2, 514 s.; 18 of Primitive Methodists, with 2, 252 s.; 4 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 702 s.; 1 undefined, with 190 s.; and 1 of Latter Day Saints, with 16 s. The schools were 28 public day schools, with 1, 947 scholars; 20 private day schools, with 902 s.; 47 Sunday schools, with 2, 635 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 12 s.-The two hundreds are N and S; and they jointly are larger in extent than the district, yet exclude some portions of it. The N hundred contains thirty-one parishes. Acres, 40, 040. Pop., 10, 534. Houses, 2, 510. The S hundred contains forty parishes. Acres, 49, 078. Pop., 14, 979. Houses, 3, 326. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/e/erpingham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erpingham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649926</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Erpingham</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10030341</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>ERPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10044339</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>SOUTH ERPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10076006</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>NORTH ERPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10086711</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>ERPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10215766</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ERPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10220580</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>ERPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10503607</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ERPINGHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
