<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>22</id>
<name>SWAFFHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6438908867829</lat>
<lon>0.682157491437038</lon>
<gazetteerText>SWAFFHAM, a town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Norfolk. The town stands on a rising-ground, adjacent to the East Anglian railway, 14&#189; miles SE by E of Lynn; is a seat of quarter sessions, a polling place, and a place of election; consists of wide and well built streets, diverging from a spacious market place; carries on iron-founding and coach-making; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a r. station with telegraph, two banking offices, two chief inns, a shire-hall, a house of correction, a police station, a corn-hall of 1858, a market-cross of 1783, an assembly-room of 1817, a cruciform church of 1474, three dissenting chapels, an endowed grammar-school with &#163;24 a year, a national school, alms houses, a workhouse, charities &#163;36, a weekly market on Saturday, and fairs on the second Wednesday of May, the third Wednesday of July, and the first Wednesday of Nov. Pop. in 1861, 2,974. Houses, 675.&#151;The parish comprises 7,550 acres. Real property, &#163;17,344; of which &#163;250 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 3,858; in 1861, 3,559. Houses, 786. The manor belongs to A. Hamond, Esq. A common of 2,370 acres is on the NW side of the town. The living is a vicarage, united with Threxton, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;738.* Patron, the Bishop of N.-The Sub-district excludes a small part of the parish, but includes 14 other parishes. Pop., 6,516. Houses, 1,378. -The district contains also Saham-Toney sub-district, and comprises 81,200 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;8,332. Pop. in 1851, 14,320; in 1861, 13,747. Houses, 2,941. Marriages in 1863, 80; births, 424,-of which 59 were illegitimate; deaths, 274,-of which 97 were at ages under 5 years, and 16 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 963; births, 4,466; deaths, 2,646. The places of worship, in 1851, were 32 of the Church of England, with 5,439 sittings; 1 of Independents, with 20 attendants; 4 of Baptists, with 580 sittings; 7 of Wesleyans, with 953 s.; 8 of Primitive Methodists, with 667 s.; 1 of Bible Christians, with 132 s.; 1 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 80 s.; 1 undefined, with 17 attendants; and 1 of Roman Catholics, with 115 at. The schools were 21 public day-schools, with 1,497 scholars; 18 private day-schools, with 523 s.; 24 Sunday schools, with 1,711 s.; and 5 evening schools for adults, with 106 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Swaffham</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swaffham</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/s/swaffham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636464</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001500</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SWAFFHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10003799</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>SWAFFHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10025461</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>SWAFFHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10063127</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>SWAFFHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186985</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SWAFFHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10206728</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SWAFFHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10509671</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWAFFHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541268</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWAFFHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580950</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWAFFHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1688</id>
   <name>SHINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3906</id>
   <name>BEECHAMWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6165</id>
   <name>COCKLEY CLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
