<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3119</id>
<name>HOCKWOLD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4622856974194</lat>
<lon>0.539420875407066</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOCKWOLD, a village and a parish in Thetford district, Norfolk. The village stands near the Little Ouse river and the boundary with Suffolk, 1 mile N of Lakenheath r. station, and 4 W by N of Brandon; and has an ancient stone cross 15 feet high, a post office under Brandon, and a fair on the first Wednesday after 11 Oct. The parish includes also the village and quondam parish of Wilton; bears the name of Hockwold-cum-Wilton; and has sometimes, but erroneously, been returned as including the extra-parochial tract of Redmere. Acres, 7, 478. Real property, &#163;6, 667. Pop. in 1851, 1, 067; in 1861, 803. Houses, 203. The decrease of pop. was caused by emigration. The property is much subdivided. Great part of the surface is fen land. A new road was formed through the fens, and a suspension bridge constructed across the Little Ouse, in 1829. Hockwold Hall is a chief residence. The living is a rectory and a vicarage, -Hockwold a rectory, Wilton a vicarage, -in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;766.* Patron, Caius College, Cambridge. Hockwold church is a rude structure, with a tower; and contains stone stalls and a piscina. Wilton church is an edifice of stone and flint, with tower and spire; both churches have been thoroughly restored. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and charities &#163;45. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/hockwold/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646812</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10090945</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HOCKWOLD CUM WILTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143172</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HOCKWOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10161605</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HOCKWOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10189287</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HOCKWOLD WITH WILTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505252</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOCKWOLD WITH WILTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
