<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1679</id>
<name>MUNDESLEY</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8786417713293</lat>
<lon>1.42995777498344</lon>
<gazetteerText>MUNDSLEY, or Mundesley, a village and a parish in Erpingham district, Norfolk. The village stands on the coast, 5 miles N N E of North Walsham, and 19&#189; N N W of Norwich r. station; is a pleasant place. with a fine sea-view; ranks as a kind of sub-port, where vessels load and unload on the beach; is much frequented as a watering-place; has a post-office under Norwich, a goodinn, good lodging-houses, bathing-machines, and a coast-guard station; and carries on some fishing. The parish comprises 574 acres of land, and 100 of water. Real property, &#163;1, 979. Pop., 437. Houses, 106. The property is not much divided. The sea makes continualencroachments. A terrace built at the village, 90 feetabove the beach, was broken down by the tide in Feb.1836; was rebuilt in the same year; was again broken down in 1863; and has not been rebuilt. A deep ravinepierces lofty broken cliffs to the coast at the village; and is traversed by a rivulet called the Mun, which gives name to the parish. Bones of elephants and other inter-tropical animals have been found. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;170. Patron, the Duchy of Lancaster. The church stands on a cliff; has lost its tower and its chancel; and is available for use in only a part of the nave. There are a dissentingchapel and a church school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/mundesley/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641966</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015303</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MUNDESLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506979</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MUNDESLEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1708</id>
   <name>ANTINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2252</id>
   <name>TRUNCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2264</id>
   <name>PASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2281</id>
   <name>GIMINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3114</id>
   <name>KNAPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3157</id>
   <name>EDINGTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3416</id>
   <name>SWAFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4668</id>
   <name>BRADFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4739</id>
   <name>BACTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5472</id>
   <name>GUNTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
