<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3953</id>
<name>DOCKING</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.908239507589</lat>
<lon>0.631278954465567</lon>
<gazetteerText>DOCKING, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a district in Norfolk. The village stands near the West Norfolk Junction railway, 12&#188; miles S W by W of Wells; had anciently a priory, subordinate to Ivry abbey; and has now a post office&#8225; under Lynn, a railway station, a police station, a neat church in pointed architecture, two Methodist chapels, a national-school of 1860, a work-house built at a cost of &#163;9, 000, and a weekly Saturday market. The parish includes the ancient suppressed parish of Summerfield or Southmere, and comprises 5, 113 acres. Real property, &#163;9, 381 . Pop., 1, 625. Houses, 333. The property is divided among a few. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;459.* Patron, Eton College, on the nomination of the Bishop of Norwich.&#151;The sub-district contains the parishes of Docking, Great Bircham, Bircham-Tofts, Bircham-Newton, Fring, Stanhoe, Barwick, Barmer, Bagthorpe, Syderstone, East Rudham, West Rudham, and New Houghton. Acres, 28, 4 76. Pop., 5, 397. Houses, 1, 116. The district comprehends also the sub-district of Snettisham, containing the parishes of Snettisham, Ingoldisthorpe, Dersingham, Shernborne, Anmer, Holme-next-the-Sea, Hunstanton, Great Ringstead, Heacham, and Sedgeford; and the sub-district of Burnham, containing the parishes of Burnham-Westgate, Burnham-Overy, Burnham-Norton, Burnham-Deepdale, Burnham-Thorpe, Burnham-Sutton-cum-Burnham-Ulph, Waterden, South Creake, North Creake, Brancaster, Titchwell, and Thornham, and the extra-parochial tract of Choseley. Acres, 101, 136. Poor-rates, in 1862, &#163;10, 793. Pop. in 1841, 16, 927; in 1861, 17, 596. Houses, 3, 792. Marriages in 1860, 122; births, 529, -of which 61 were illegitimate; deaths, 381, -of which 149 were at ages under 5 years, and 17 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1, 208; births, 5, 641; deaths, 3, 672. The places of worship in 1851 were 33 of the Church of England, with 8, 978 sittings; 3 of Independents, with 761 s.; 21 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 2, 330 s.; 20 of Primitive Methodists, with 1, 497 s.; and 4 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 545 s. The schools were 29 public day schools, with 1, 564 scholars; 44 private day schools, with 964 s.; 42 Sunday schools, with 2, 148 s.; and 6 evening schools for adults, with 88 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Docking</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/d/docking/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Docking,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651188</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001481</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>DOCKING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10003775</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>DOCKING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10055933</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>DOCKING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10123707</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>DOCKING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10503220</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DOCKING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10562168</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DOCKING</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2246</id>
   <name>BIRCHAM TOFTS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2930</id>
   <name>BIRCHAM NEWTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3295</id>
   <name>STANHOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3982</id>
   <name>CHOSELEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
