<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2912</id>
<name>WATTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5685880358273</lat>
<lon>0.833634552698096</lon>
<gazetteerText>WATTON, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Wayland district, Norfolk. The town stands on the river Wissey, at the terminus of the Thetford and Watton railway, 9 miles NNE of Thetford; adjoins Wayland Wood, the scene of the old ballad of the &quot;Children in the Wood;&quot; is a seat of petty sessions; consists chiefly of one wide street; and has a post-office&#8225; under Thetford, a r. station, a banking office, a good inn, a police station, a town hall of 1853, an ancient market-cross with a quaint rebus, a restored ancient church, a large national school, an agricultural society, alms houses, other charities &#163;127, a weekly market on Wednesday, and five annual fairs. The parish comprises 1,807 acres. Real property, &#163;6,860. Pop., 1,365. Houses, 303. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;190.* Patron, the Rev. W. H. Hicks.&#151;The sub-district contains 14 parishes. Acres, 28,178. Pop., 6,056. Houses, 1,330. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/w/watton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watton,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634662</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10082973</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10510831</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541207</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WATTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3467</id>
   <name>THOMPSON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3924</id>
   <name>THREXTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3970</id>
   <name>MERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
