<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5854</id>
<name>OXBOROUGH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5835431930773</lat>
<lon>0.569654449578226</lon>
<gazetteerText>OXBOROUGH, a village and a parish in Swaffham district, Norfolk. The village stands on an affluent of the river Wissey, 3 miles N E by E of Stoke-Ferry, and 7 S W of Swaffham r. station; occupies the site of a Roman station, supposed by some to have been Iciani; is mentioned in Domesday book; was once a markettown; and has still a fair on Easter Tuesday. The parish comprises 2, 518 acres; and its post town is Stoke-Ferry, under Brandon. Real property, &#163;2, 721. Pop.in 1851, 293; in 1861, 225. Houses, 51. The decrease of pop. was caused by the removal of cottages. The manor belonged once to Torchil the Dane; and, with Oxborough Hall and most of the land, belongs now to Sir Henry G. Bedingfeld, Bart. O. Hall is a castellated brick quadrangle of the 15th century; measures 118feet by 92; has towers 80 feet high, and a fine old gate-way; is surrounded by a moat; was visited by Henry VII.; and contains some curious old tapestry, and a number of paintings by old masters. An ancient camp and tumuli are at Warren Hill; and ancient coins have been found there. The living is a rectory, united with the vicarage of Foulden, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;516.* Patron, Cains College, Cambridge. The church comprises nave, aisles, and chancel; has a squaretower, with a very lofty octagonal spire; and contains aterra cotta screen, and monuments of the Bedingfelds. There are a Roman Catholic chapel, a handsome endowed school, and charities &#163;100. The R. Catholic chapel was built in 1835, and is a neat edifice. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/o/oxborough/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oxborough</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640737</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10106023</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OXBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10208749</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>OXBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10212273</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OXBOROUGH WITH CALDECOTE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507406</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OXBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
