<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2291</id>
<name>HORNING</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6968533418786</lat>
<lon>1.50132180096611</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORNING, a village and a parish in Tunstead district, Norfolk. The village stands on the river Bure, 5&#189; miles NNE of Brundall r. station, and 9&#189; NE by E of Norwich; consists of two long straggling streets, with many good houses; and has a post office under Norwich, and a fair on the third Thursday of July.&#151;The parish comprises 2, 567 acres. Real property, &#163;4, 493. Pop., 441. Houses, 97. The property is all in one estate. Much of the land is marsh, inundated after rains and freshets, and much haunted by ignis fatuus. Holme abbey, noticed in our article HOLME or COWHOLME, was here. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;250. * Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church stands on a rising ground, about 1 mile SE of the village; is an ancient edifice, with a lofty tower; and was reported in 1859 as very bad and unsafe. Charities, &#163;15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/horning/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horning</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646588</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050110</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HORNING</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505458</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HORNING</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5932</id>
<name>HORNINGTOFT</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7731442845874</lat>
<lon>0.870957000246217</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORNINGTOFT, a parish in Mitford district, Norfolk; 3 miles NW of Elmham r. station, and 5 S of Fakenham. Post town, Litcham, under Swaffham. Acres, 1, 405. Real property, &#163;2, 389. Pop., 248. Houses, 59. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to Mrs. Talbot. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Whissonsett, in the diocese of Norwich. The church is ancient but good; and the tower of it fell in 1796. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/horningtoft/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horningtoft</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296644</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10211633</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HORNINGTOFT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10515038</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HORNINGTOFT</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
