<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2914</id>
<name>NORTHWOLD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5467509783793</lat>
<lon>0.556905639011532</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTHWOLD, a village and a parish in Thetford district, Norfolk. The village stands on the river Wissey, 4 miles S E by E of Stoke Ferry, and 6&#189; N by W of Brandon r. station; and has a post-office&#8225; under Brandon, and a fair on 30 Nov. The parish contains also the hamlet of Whittington. Acres, 5, 232. Real property, &#163;8, 274. Pop., 1, 370. Houses, 298. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged once to Burhill, the friend of Raleigh; and belongs now to H. S. Partridge, Esq. There are several fine residences, a large chalk-pit, and an extensive malt-house. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;950.* Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is large and handsome; comprises nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower of the 14th century, surmounted by ten spirelets; has anornate oak roof in the nave; and contains remains of ashrine. There are a handsome recent Wesleyan chapel, a Primitive Methodist chapel, an endowed school with &#163;18 a year, and charities &#163;132. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/n/northwold/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Northwold</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641218</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10083035</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>NORTHWOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10212029</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTHWOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507261</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NORTHWOLD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
