<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2618</id>
<name>REDENHALL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4103363676391</lat>
<lon>1.32770832347072</lon>
<gazetteerText>REDENHALL, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; on the river Waveney, and on the Waveney Valley railway, at the boundary with Suffolk, 1&#190; mile E N E of Harleston r. station. It contains the town of Harleston, which has a head post-office. Acres, with Wortwell, 3, 714. Real property of R. alone, &#163;7, 543. Pop., 1, 736. Houses, 399. Pop., exclusive of Harleston, 434. Houses, 84. The manors of Redenhall, Hawkers, Holbrook, and Coldham belong to Mrs. Holmes; and that of Harleston belongs to the Duke of Norfolk. Gawdy Hall was the seat of the Gawdy family; passed to the Wogans; and is now the seat of Mrs. Holmes. The living is a rectory, united with the chapelry of Harleston, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;1,005.* Patron, the Duke of Norfolk at the nomination of the Bishop of Norwich. The church was rebuilt by Thomas of Brotherton, Duke of Norfolk; was restored in 1858; has a fine tower; and contains monuments of the Gawdy family. See Harleston. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/harleston/</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/r/redenhall/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299512</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10068137</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>REDENHALL WITH HARLESTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578930</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>REDENHALL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2649</id>
   <name>MENDHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2672</id>
   <name>WORTWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2920</id>
   <name>STARSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5157</id>
   <name>ALBURGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
