<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5132</id>
<name>CLEY NEXT THE SEA</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9484792625701</lat>
<lon>1.05674458270469</lon>
<gazetteerText>CLEY-NEXT-THE-SEA, or Clay, a village and a parish in Erpingham district, Norfolk. The village stands on the river Glaven, about a mile from the beach, 4&#189; NNW of Holt, and 8 E of Wells r. station. It has a post office, &#8225; of the name of Cley, under Thetford; had formerly a weekly market; still has a fair on the last Friday in July; carries on a small coasting trade; and is frequented as a watering-place. Prince James, afterwards James I. of Scotland, was forced hither by stress of weather on his passage to France; made a prisoner by the villagers; and given up to Henry IV., who sent him prisoner to the Tower of London. The parish comprises 2, 198 acres of land, and 165 of water. Real property, &#163;3, 857. Pop., 791. Houses, 216. The property is divided among a few. Part of the land has recently been re-claimed by embanking and draining. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;400. Patron, W. Bishop, Esq. The church is cruciform, curious, chiefly early decorated English; has a clerestory over the nave; contains a figured font and three brasses; and was recently restored. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/c/cley/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652856</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10180223</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CLEY NEXT THE SEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10512311</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CLEY NEXT THE SEA</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2258</id>
   <name>WIVETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3112</id>
   <name>GLANDFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5924</id>
   <name>SALTHOUSE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
