<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5475</id>
<name>MARTHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7077097796987</lat>
<lon>1.63133620760122</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARTHAM, a village and a parish in Flegg district, Norfolk. The village stands on rising-ground above marshes, 3&#188; miles from the coaSt, and 9 NW by. N of Yarmonth r. station; is a large place, with several handsome houses and some good shops; and has a post office&#8225; under Yarmouth, Norfolk, and a fair on the last Tuesday of July and the following day. The parish comprises 2,644 acres. Real property, &#163;7,020. Pop., 1,092. Houses, 255. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to J. F. Grove, Esq. Martham Hall is the seat of W. Rising, Esq. Theliving is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;364.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Norwich. The church comprises nave, aisles, S porch, and lofty fine tower, in early perpendicular English; includes a chancel in florid Gothic,.rebuilt in 1855, at a cost of nearly &#163;8,000, in memorial of the Rev. J. Dawson, and containing an altar-tomb to him; has a very fine stained glass E window by Hardman; and contains a richly-sculptured, octagonal, ancient font, and a brass of 1487. There are chapels for Baptists and Primitive Methodists, an endowed school with &#163;17 a year, and charities &#163;40. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martham</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/martham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642959</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10195676</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506542</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MARTHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3294</id>
   <name>REPPS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3911</id>
   <name>POTTER HEIGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3928</id>
   <name>WAXHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
