<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4752</id>
<name>BURSTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4119062807773</lat>
<lon>1.14617335509768</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURSTON, a parish in Depwade district, Norfolk; on an affluent of the river Waveney, adjacent to the Eastern Counties railway, 2&#188; miles NNE of Diss. It has a station on the railway; and its Post Town is Diss. Acres, 1,449. Real property, &#163;2,731. Pop., 419. Houses, 87. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;418. Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is a flint structure, in good condition, with round tower and octagonal turret. There is a Wesleyan chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654222</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/burston/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10161939</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BURSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10501866</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURSTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2312</id>
<name>BRISTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.84667658238</lat>
<lon>1.0774839133185</lon>
<gazetteerText>BRISTON, or Burston, a village and a parish in Erpingham district, Norfolk. The village stands on the river Bure, 4 miles SSW of Holt, and 9 ENE of Ryburgh r. station; and has a post office under Thetford, a fortnightly stock market, and a cattle fair on 26 May. The parish comprises 2,751 acres. Pop., 931. Houses, 232. The property is subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;317. Patron, Lord Hastings. The church is decorated and perpendicular English, and had formerly a round tower. There are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and charities &#163;9. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Briston</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654673</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/briston/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050376</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BRISTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10501404</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BRISTON HALL MELIORS CHOSSELLS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1700</id>
   <name>GUESTWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5741</id>
   <name>THURNING</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
