<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5746</id>
<name>HAPPISBURGH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8174931004758</lat>
<lon>1.52941288249224</lon>
<gazetteerText>HAPPISBURGH, or HASBOROUGH, a village and a parish in Tunstead district, Norfolk. The village lies scattered on the summit and declivities of the seabank, 7 miles E of North Walsham r. station, and 18&#189; NNE of Norwich; and has a post office, of the name of Happisburgh, under Norwich. The parish comprises 1, 953 acres of land, and 210 of water. Real property, &#163;4, 792. Pop., 584. Houses, 144. The property is divided among a number. The manor belongs to the Sielys. Cliffs are on the coast, and have so unstable a character as to menace the safety of the church. An ancient Danish fort was here. Some of the inhabitants are employed in fishing. The living*is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;300. Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is ancient; consists of nave, aisle, and chancel, with S porch, and a tower 112 feet high; and was recently restored, at a cost of about &#163;1, 500. There are a Primitive Methodist chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;44. Parr was vicar. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/happisburgh/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Happisburgh</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647512</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10205487</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HAPPISBURGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10504600</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HAPPISBURGH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1661</id>
   <name>WALCOTT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1662</id>
   <name>EAST RUSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1672</id>
   <name>WITTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1692</id>
   <name>CROSTWIGHT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1703</id>
   <name>LESSINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2645</id>
   <name>HEMPSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4703</id>
   <name>RIDLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
