<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1696</id>
<name>FAKENHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8399379178468</lat>
<lon>0.864657548027278</lon>
<gazetteerText>FAKENHAM, a town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Walsingham district, Norfolk. The town stands on the slope of a hill, at the river Wensum, adjacent to the Wymondham and Wells railway, 9&#189; miles S of Wells; has, of late years, undergone much improvement; is a seat of petty sessions, and a polling-place; and has a head post office, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, two banking offices, two chief inns, an ancient market - cross, a tolerably spacions market-place, a three-arched bridge, a church, four dissenting chapels, and charities &#163;70. The bridge was built in 1833, on the site of a previous one; and consists of white bricks, with stone parapets and iron palisades. The church is fine later English with a handsome tower; was beautifully restored in 1864; and has an octagonal font. A weekly market is held on Thursday; and fairs on Whit-Tuesday and 22 Nov. Pop., 2, 182. Houses, 460. The parish is sometimes called Fakenham-Lancaster. Acres, 2, 208. Real property, &#163;11, 511; of which &#163;70 are in the railway, and &#163;45 in gas-works. Pop., 2, 456. Houses, 521. The manor belongs to the Duchy of Lancaster. Salt was formerly made from salt-pits here. Five fine springs, one of them strongly chalybeate, are near the town. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;862.* Patron, Trinity College, Cambridge.&#151;The sub-district contains twenty-two parishes. Acres, 27, 818. Pop., 7, 325. Houses, 1, 522. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/f/fakenham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fakenham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649730</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015546</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FAKENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10514990</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FAKENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541426</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FAKENHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1107</id>
   <name>WELLS NEXT THE SEA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1691</id>
   <name>SOUTH CREAKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2801</id>
   <name>MELTON CONSTABLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5344</id>
   <name>STIFFKEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5464</id>
   <name>LITTLE WALSINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5957</id>
   <name>SCULTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5978</id>
   <name>CASTLE ACRE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6041</id>
   <name>LANGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6042</id>
   <name>EAST RUDHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6046</id>
   <name>GREAT MASSINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
