<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>21044</id>
<name>OUTWELL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6104926718972</lat>
<lon>0.23627973955648</lon>
<gazetteerText>OUTWELL, a village and a parish in the district of Wisbeach and counties of Cambridge and Norfolk. The village stands on the old river Nen and on the Wisbeach canal, immediately N of Upwell, and 5 miles S S E of Wisbeach r. station; and has a post-office under Wisbeach. The parish comprises 506 acres in Cambridgeshire; and, together with a part of Emneth, 2, 512 in Norfolk. Real property of theportion, &#163;2, 107. Pop. in 1851, 442; in 1861, 381. Houses, 91. Real property of the N portion, &#163;6, 169. Pop. in 1851, 1,006; in 1861, 884. Houses, 197. The property is much sub-divided. The manor belongs to W. Townley, Esq. Beaupr&#233; Hall is the residence of the Rev. W. G. Town-ley. A hermitage or Benedictine house stood ancientlyat Molycourt; and was made a cell to Ely by Henry VI. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Va-lue, &#163;631.* Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is a brick building, covered with cement; was recently repaired, at a cost of &#163;2, 200; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with porch and tower. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists, a mixed school, and charities &#163;163. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/o/outwell/</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/CAM/Outwell/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640781</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=21919</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10048280</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OUTWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10079214</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>OUTWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10178812</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>OUTWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10480619</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>OUTWELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
