<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1323</id>
<name>WYMONDHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5599423083757</lat>
<lon>1.11396392744077</lon>
<gazetteerText>WYMONDHAM, or Windham, a town and a parish in Forehoe district, Norfolk. The town stands on the Norwich and Thetford railway, at the junction of the line to Dereham and Wells, 9&#189; miles WSW of Norwich; grew around a cell to St. Albans abbey, founded in 1107 by W. D&apos;Albini: was devastated by fire in 1615, and by plague in 1631; is a seat of petty sessions and county courts; stands on elevated ground, is irregularly built, and presents a somewhat antique appearance; carries on brewing and the manufacture of paramattas, nets, satins, and crapes; publishes a weekly newspaper; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a r. station with telegraph, a banking office, a hotel, an interesting old market-cross repaired in 1863, a house of correction for females, a church, 6 dissenting chapels, a free grammar-school, national and British schools, charities &#163;204, a weekly market on Friday, and three annual fairs. The church of the ancient monastic cell became partly parochial in 1249; was eventually denuded of its monastic attachments; underwent alterations and reconstructions in decorated and later English architecture; retains Norman portions of the original structure; was interiorly repaired in 1845; and has an E octagonal tower and steeple, and an unfinished W tower. Pop. of the town in 1851, 2,970; in 1861, 2,152. Houses, 546.&#151;The parish is divided into Wattlefield, Sutton, Silfield, Town-Green, Market-Street, and Downham quarters; and comprises 10,613 acres-Real property, &#163;20,267; of which &#163;989 are in railways. Pop. in 1851, 5,177; in 1861, 4,952. Houses, 1,137. Kimberley Hall, Burfield Hall, Stanfield Hall, Cavick House, Wattlefield Hall, and Silfield Lodge are chief residences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;515.* Patron, the Bishop of N. A chapel of ease is in Wattlefield. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/w/wymondham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wymondham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633446</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10123367</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WYMONDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10468980</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WYMONDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10511677</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WYMONDHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541116</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WYMONDHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2272</id>
   <name>SHIPDHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2286</id>
   <name>HEMPNALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2289</id>
   <name>HINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2300</id>
   <name>ATTLEBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2925</id>
   <name>MATTISHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2931</id>
   <name>BRACON ASH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4674</id>
   <name>BUNWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5455</id>
   <name>HETHERSETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5484</id>
   <name>CARBROOKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5698</id>
   <name>OLD BUCKENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
