<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1671</id>
<name>WIGGENHALL ST GERMAN</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6920985337174</lat>
<lon>0.351321589696255</lon>
<gazetteerText>WIGGENHALL-ST. GERMANS, a parish and a village, in Downham district, Norfolk; on the river Ouse, 2&#189; miles NNW of Watlington r. station, and 4 SSW of Lynn. It has a post-office&#8225; under Lynn, and a wooden bridge over the Ouse. Acres, 1,219. Real property, &#163;3,648. Pop. in 1851, 750; in 1861, 633. Houses, 156. The decrease of pop. was caused by absence of labourers on the Eau-Brink drainage works. The property is much subdivided. All the four W. parishes are in Fitton manor; and much of the land is below the high-water level of the Ouse, and protected by strong embankments. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;160.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of N. The church is ancient; and there are three Methodist chapels. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/w/wiggenhall_st_german/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015212</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST GERMAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10033317</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST GERMANS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10189240</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST GERMANS WITH ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10216679</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST GERMANS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10511197</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST GERMAN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>6040</id>
<name>WIGGENHALL ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7064526271855</lat>
<lon>0.350571135240512</lon>
<gazetteerText>WIGGENHALL-ST. MARY-THE-VIRGIN, a parish, with Saddlebow hamlet, in Downham district, Norfolk; on the river Ouse, 3&#189; miles NW by N of Watlington r. station, and 4&#189; SW of Lynn. Post town, Lynn. Acres, 2,807. Real property, &#163;5,332. Pop., 307. Houses, 63. The property is divided chiefly among three. Saddlebow House is the seat of W. H. Allen, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;160.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is ancient. There is a parochial school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/w/wiggenhall_st_maryvir/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10077102</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143044</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST MARY THE VIRGIN WITH ISLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10215791</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10511203</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST MARY THE VIRGIN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3930</id>
<name>WIGGENHALL ST PETER</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6860027586325</lat>
<lon>0.365005628270712</lon>
<gazetteerText>WIGGENHALL-ST. PETER, a parish in Downham district, Norfolk; on the river Ouse, 1&#190; mile N by W of Watlington r. station, and 4&#189; SSW of Lynn. Post town, Lynn. Acres, 944. Real property, &#163;2,327. Pop., 153. Houses, 33. The property is divided chiefly between two. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;120.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is ancient. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/w/wiggenhall_st_peter/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10077114</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10123331</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10514824</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST PETER</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2255</id>
<name>WIGGENHALL ST MARY MAGDALEN</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6549504039197</lat>
<lon>0.339213016392265</lon>
<gazetteerText>WIGGENHALL-ST. MARY-MAGDALENE, a parish, with a village, in Downham district, Norfolk; on the river Ouse, at Watlington r. station, and 6 miles SSW of Lynn. Post town, Lynn. Acres, 4,248. Real property, &#163;8,895. Pop., 825. Houses, 181. The property is subdivided. About three-fourths of the area are fen, drained by a steam-engine of 40 horse-power. An Augustinian nunnery, a cell to Castle-Acre, was founded here in 1181. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;270.* Patron, Rev. W. B. Dalby. The church is ancient. There are Baptist and Primitive Methodist chapels, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/w/wiggenhall_st_marymag/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10049659</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST MARY MAGDALEN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3930</id>
   <name>WIGGENHALL ST PETER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>21247</id>
<name>WIGGENHALL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6508704425813</lat>
<lon>0.377825440673506</lon>
<gazetteerText>WIGGENHALL, a sub-district in Downham district, Norfolk; containing the four W. parishes, eight other parishes, and two parts. Acres, 32,152. Pop., 6,171. Houses, 1,349. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10541098</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WIGGENHALL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
