<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3532</id>
<name>NEWTON BY CASTLE ACRE</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7031960873827</lat>
<lon>0.716186747172735</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWTON-BY-CASTLEACRE, a parish in Swaffham district, Norfolk; on the river Nar, adjacent to the Peddar way, 2&#189; miles N W of Dunham r. station, and 4&#188; N by E of Swaffham. Post-town, Brandon. Acres, 1,058. Real property, &#163;1, 693. Pop., 84. Houses, 15. The property belongs to A. Fountaine, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;103. Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is Saxon orearly Norman; was originally cruciform, but now wants the transepts; and has a low tower. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/n/newton_by_castle_acre/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296648</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10106035</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NEWTON BY CASTLE ACRE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507157</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NEWTON BY CASTLE ACRE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3936</id>
<name>WEST NEWTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8193350162732</lat>
<lon>0.522000278657448</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWTON (West), a village and a parish in Freebridge-Lynn district, Norfolk. The village stands 2 miles E by S of Wolverton r. station, and 7 N E by N of Lynn; was recently rebuilt by the Prince of Wales; and has a postal letter-box under Lynn. The parish comprises 1, 230 acres. Real property, &#163;1, 310. Pop., 268. Houses, 51. The manor and most of the land belong to the Prince of Wales. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;178.* Patron, the Prince of Wales. The church is ancient and tolerable. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/n/newton_west/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Newton,_Norfolk</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10057607</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST NEWTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10094318</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST NEWTON WITH APPLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10123434</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WEST NEWTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507170</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEST NEWTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1680</id>
<name>NEWTON FLOTMAN</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5424136048577</lat>
<lon>1.25977036198372</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWTON-FLOTMAN, a parish, with a village, in Henstead district, Norfolk; on a branch of the river Yare, adjacent to the Great Eastern railway, 1 mile N E of Flordon r. station, and 3&#189; N by E of Long Stratton. It took the latter part of its name from a &quot;flote&quot; or ferry on the river. Post-town, Long Stratton. Acres, 1, 173. Real property, &#163;2, 584. Pop., 328. Houses, 75. The property is subdivided. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Swainsthorpe, in the diocese of Norwich. The church is good; consists of nave and chancel, with S porch and embattled tower; and contains a fine brass monument of the Blondevilles. There are a village school, and charities &#163;12. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/n/newton_flotman/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7291088</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015327</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NEWTON FLOTMAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507169</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NEWTON FLOTMAN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>2930</id>
<name>BIRCHAM NEWTON</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.8775753517626</lat>
<lon>0.632853704213927</lon>
<gazetteerText>BIRCHAM (Newton), a parish in Docking district, Norfolk; 2 miles S of Docking, and 9&#189; W by N of Fakenham r. station. Post Town, Bircham, under Rougham. Acres, 1,128. Real property, &#163;959. Pop., 118. Houses, 20. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Bircham-Tofts, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;434.* Patron, the Marquis of Cholmondeley. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/bircham_newton/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bircham_Newton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655631</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10057759</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BIRCHAM NEWTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10083242</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BIRCHAM NEWTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10500837</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BIRCHAM NEWTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23437</id>
<name>NEWTON ST FAITH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.7056192072749</lat>
<lon>1.28647471633679</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEWTON-ST. FAITH, a parish in St. Faith district, Norfolk; 1 mile N W of Horsham, St. Faith, and 5&#188; N by W of Norwich r. station. Post-town, St. Faith, under Norwich. The acre age is returned with Horsham, St. Faith. Real property, &#163;2, 103. Pop., 273. Houses, 71. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the p. curacy of Horsham, St. Faith, in the diocese of Norwich. There is a Wesleyan chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
</results>
