<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1706</id>
<name>METHWOLD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5242868576475</lat>
<lon>0.492082659907173</lon>
<gazetteerText>METHWOLD, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Thetford district, Norfolk. The village stands 2&#188; Miles SSW of the river Wissey, 2&#188; WNW of the Devil&apos;s dyke, and 5&#190; NW by N of Brandon r. station; was once a market-town; has still a cattle market on Mondays, and a cattle fair on 23 April; and has a post office under Brandon. The parish contains also the hamlet of Methwold-Hithe, situated 1 mile W by N of the village. Acres, 13,192. Real property, &#163;11,438. Pop. in 1851, 1,669; in 1861,1,509. Houses, 332. The property is much subdivided. An extensive tract was formerly heath, famous for rabbits, known as Muel or Methwold rabbits; and is now all under cultivation. The inhabitants a re exempt from serving on juries out of the manor, and from tolls at markets and fairs. A small priory, a cell to Castle-Acre, was once at Slevesholm, and has left some traces. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;340.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with pinnacled tower and octagonal lantern and spire; and is large, good, and beautiful. There are a large Wesleyan chapel, chiefly of flint; a daily school, supported by the duchy of Lancaster; and charities &#163;50.&#151;The sub-district contains also eleven other parishes, and three extra-parochial tracts. Acres, 68,693. Pop., 8,869. Houses, 1,978. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/methwold/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642689</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10015674</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>METHWOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506700</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>METHWOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541270</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>METHWOLD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
