<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5455</id>
<name>HETHERSETT</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5978324578085</lat>
<lon>1.18917341656078</lon>
<gazetteerText>HETHERSETT, a village and a parish in Henstead district, Norfolk. The village stands near the Norwich and Brandon railway, 5&#189; miles SW by W of Norwich; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Wymondham..The parish comprises 2, 674 acres. Real property, &#163;7, 498. Pop., 1, 169. Houses, 268. Thickthorn House and Hethersett Hall are the chief residences. Canteloff or Cantelose manor here was formerly a parish; still ranks ecclesiastically as a rectory; and had a church, the site of which is still called the old churchyard. Kett and his rebel band held their councils in the parish, in 1549, under a large tree called the Old Oak. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Canteloff, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;651.* Patron, Caius College, Cambridge. The church was built about 1350, and has a lofty embattled tower, with small spire. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a slightly endowed national school, and charities &#163;53. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/hethersett/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hethersett</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647023</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10195378</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HETHERSETT</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2295</id>
   <name>GREAT MELTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4676</id>
   <name>KETTERINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4693</id>
   <name>WRAMPLINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6231</id>
   <name>BARFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
