<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2261</id>
<name>FELTWELL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4890721756704</lat>
<lon>0.474626467524388</lon>
<gazetteerText>FELTWELL, a village and a parish in Thetford district, Norfolk. The village stands near Sams Cut in the Fen, 3 miles N by E of Lakenheath r. station, and 5&#189; NW of Brandon; is large and neatly built; and has a post office&#8225; under Brandon, and a fair on 20 Nov. The parish comprises 14, 060 acres. Real property, &#163;11, 556. Pop., 1, 553. Houses, 352. The property is much sub-divided. There are four manors; and they belong to four parties. About 8, 000 acres in the parish are fen; and about 300 under wood. The upland tracts were enclosed in 1815. Feltwell Lodge is a chief residence. The parish comprises two quondam parishes, St. Mary and St. Nicholas; and is sometimes called Feltwell-St. Mary and St. Nicholas. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;1, 207.* Patron, alternately the Lord Chancellor and the Bishop of Norwich. St. Mary&apos;s church consists of nave, chancel, and aisles, with massive square tower; has a brass of 1482; and was altered and enlarged in 1862. St. Nicholas church is ancient, and serves now as a cemetery chapel. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists. Mundeford&apos;s free schools and alms-houses have &#163;300; and other charities, including a fuel allotment of 360 acres, have &#163;83. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/f/feltwell/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649568</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10049740</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>FELTWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10143068</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FELTWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10503656</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FELTWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10573452</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FELTWELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>3956</id>
<name>FELTWELL ANCHOR</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4707199736626</lat>
<lon>0.400491386595111</lon>
<gazetteerText>Feltwell Anchor, par., W. Norfolk, adjacent to St Mary and St Nicholas Feltwell, pop. 47. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10123744</id>
   <status>CP/ExP</status>
   <name>FELTWELL ANCHOR</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
