<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4730</id>
<name>HORSHAM ST FAITH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6845609831903</lat>
<lon>1.28429029575135</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORSHAM-ST. FAITHS, a village and a parish in St. Faith district, Norfolk. The village stands on a branch of the river Bure, 5 miles NNW of Norwich r. station; was once a market town; and has now a postoffice, of the name of St. Faiths, under Norwich, and a prolonged annual cattle fair commencing on 17 Oct. The parish includes also Newton-ST. Faiths, and comprises 1, 750 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 114. Pop., 918. Houses, 180. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to Viscount Ranelagh. A Benedictine priory, a cell to Couches abbey in Normandy, was founded here, in 1105, by Robert Fitzwalter; and was given, at the Reformation, to E. Ebrington and R. Southwell. An hospital of the Knights Templars also was here before 1163; and was given to the Benedictine priory. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;101. Patron, Viscount Ranelagh. The church is ancient, and has an embattled tower. There are two Wessleyan chapels, a national school, and a workhouse, - and the latter serves for the district of St. Faith, and has accommodation for 300 inmates. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/horsham_st_faith/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horsham_St_Faith</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10143196</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORSHAM ST FAITH WITH NEWTON ST FAITH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10161617</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HORSHAM ST FAITH AND NEWTON ST FAITH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505495</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HORSHAM ST FAITH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17328</id>
   <name>BROADLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
