<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2234</id>
<name>BLOFIELD</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.642137934427</lat>
<lon>1.45007989536166</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLOFIELD, a village, a parish, a subdistrict, a district, and a hundred in Norfolk. The village stands near the Yarmouth railway and the river Yare, 1 mile NE of Brundall r. station, and 7 E of Norwich; and it has a post office under Norwich, and is a seat of petty sessions.&#151;The parish comprises 2,334 acres. Real property, &#163;7,548. Pop., 1,155. Houses, 265. The property is subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;896.* Patron, Caius College, Cambridge. The church is good. An endowed school has &#163;10, and other charities &#163;75.-The subdistrict contains the parishes of Blofield, Brundall, Postwick, Great Plumstead, Little Plumstead, Witton, Bradeston, Strumpshaw, Buckenham, Hassingham, Lingwood, Burlingham-St. Edmund, Burlingham-St. Andrew, Hemblington, and Woodbastwick, and part of the parish of Thorpe St. Andrew. Acres, 17,816. Pop., 5,787. Houses, 1,144.&#151;The district comprehends also the subdistrict of South Walsham, containing the parishes of South Walsham-St. Mary, South Walsham-St. Lawrence, Burlingham-St. Peter, Ranworth, Panxworth, Upton, Fishley, Acle, Beighton, Moulton, Halvergate, Tunstall, Wickhampton, Freethorpe, Southwood, Cantley, Limpenhoe, and Reedham. Acres of the district, 44,178. Poor-rates in 1866, &#163;6,904. Pop. in 1861, 11,521. Houses, 2,359. Marriages in 1866, 77; births, 354,-of which 36 were illegitimate; deaths, 238,-of which 72 were at ages under 5 years, and 7 at ages above 85 years. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60,811; births, 3,410; deaths, 2,330. The places of worship in 1851 were 33 of the Church of England, with 5,537 sittings; 2 of Independents, with 350 s.; 3 of Baptists, with 370 s.; 2 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 232 s.; and 8 of Primitive Methodists, with 835 s. The schools were 16 public day schools, with 793 scholars; 27 private day schools, with 484 s.; 23 Sunday schools, with 1,099 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 24 s. The workhouse is in Lingwood.-The hundred comprises twentyfour parishes and part of another. Acres, 19,594. Pop., 6,280. Houses, 1,265. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Blofield</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655335</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/b/blofield/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blofield</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001470</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>BLOFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10049337</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BLOFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10097381</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>BLOFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10139697</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>BLOFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173917</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>BLOFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10198306</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>BLOFIELD AND FLEGG</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541220</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BLOFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10569977</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BLOFIELD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2911</id>
   <name>TUNSTALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2933</id>
   <name>BURLINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3962</id>
   <name>HEMBLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5153</id>
   <name>LINGWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5454</id>
   <name>BURLINGHAM ST PETER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5820</id>
   <name>BEIGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
