<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3171</id>
<name>MARHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6596732383473</lat>
<lon>0.543654851876883</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARHAM, a village and a parish in Downham district, Norfolk. The village stands 1&#189; mile S of the river Nar, 3&#188; SW of Narborough r. station, and 7 W by N of Swaffham; is a long and pleasant place; and has a postal letter-box under Downham. The parish comprises 3,966 acres. Real property, &#163;5,377. Pop., 870. Houses, 179. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Sir Thomas Hare, Bart. Marham House is the seat of H. Villebois, Esq. A Cistertian nunnery was founded here, in 1251, by Isabella de Albini; was given, at the dissolution, to the Hares; and has left some remains at a farm-house, a little W of the church. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;434. * Patron, St. John&apos;s College, Cambridge. The church consists of nave, S aisle, and chancel, with a lofty tower; and is good. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and a fuel allotment of 200 acres. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marham</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/m/marham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643041</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093004</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10506487</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MARHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2304</id>
   <name>BARTON BENDISH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2619</id>
   <name>SHOULDHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3502</id>
   <name>BOUGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4718</id>
   <name>FINCHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
