<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2647</id>
<name>KENNINGHALL</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4279328227786</lat>
<lon>1.01081650543634</lon>
<gazetteerText>KENNINGHALL, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Guiltcross district, Norfolk. The village stands 4 miles ESE of East Harling r. station, and 6 S by W of Attleborough; was the seat of Boadicea and the East Anglian kings; took thence the name of Cheninkhala or Cyninghalla, signifying &quot;king&apos;s house, &quot; and modernized into Kenninghall: retains vestiges of the royal castle in mounds, which are now called Kenning hall Place; and has a post office under Thetford, a hotel, a weekly cattle market on Monday, and sheep and cattle fairs on 18 July and 30 Sept. The parish comprises 3, 600 acres. Real property, &#163;7, 810. Pop. in 1851, 1, 648; in 1861, 1, 405. Houses, 280. The property is much subdivided. The chief landowners are the Duke of Norfolk and the Earl of Albemarle. The manor was held by the De Albinis; passed to the Monaltos, the Mowbrays. and the Howards; and belongs now to the Duke of Norfolk. A palace, on the site of the royal castle, and in the form of the letter H, went to the Crown on the attainder of Thomas, Duke of Norfolk; was, for some time, the residence of Queen Mary; was used by Queen Elizabeth, as a summer seat; and was taken down about 1650. The Guiltcross workhouse stands 1&#189; mile S of the village; and, at the census of 1861, had 194 inmates. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;250.* Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is large and good; has a tower of flint and stone; and bears, on the buttresses of its S side, the crest of the Norfolk family. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, and charities &#163;67.&#151;The sub-district contains also twelve other parishes. Acres, 25, 904. Pop., 6, 025. Houses, 1, 336. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/k/kenninghall/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645805</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10068617</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>KENNINGHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505872</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KENNINGHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10565285</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KENNINGHALL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1733</id>
   <name>FERSFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2802</id>
   <name>BLO NORTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5926</id>
   <name>NORTH LOPHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
