<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2284</id>
<name>HEACHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9109734272574</lat>
<lon>0.493802371375677</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEACHAM, a village and a parish in Docking district, Norfolk. The village stands on the coast, and on the Lynn and Hunstanton railway, 9 miles N by E of Castle-Rising; is a considerable but scattered place; ranks as a sub-port to Lynn; and has a post office under Lynn, a railway station, and a fair on 20 June. There is no harbour; but the beach is such as to serve readily for the lading and unlading of small craft. The parish comprises 3, 353 acres of land, and 1, 500 of water. Real property, &#163;6, 005; of which &#163;50 are in quarries. Pop., 990. Houses, 226. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to H. S. Le Strange, Esq. A Cluniac monastery, a cell to Lewes abbey, was founded here, in the time of William Rufus, by William de Warren, Earl of Surrey; and was given, at the dissolution, to the Duke of Norfolk. Bricks and tiles are made. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;226. Patron,F. Neville Rolfe, Esq. The church is good, has an embattled tower, and contains a brass of an armed knight, and several monuments. There are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, and charities &#163;15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/heacham/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heacham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647242</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10050042</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HEACHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10504818</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEACHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574754</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEACHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574766</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEACHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574778</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HEACHAM AND RISING</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
