<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3501</id>
<name>THORPE NEXT NORWICH</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6345140244828</lat>
<lon>1.34914074666299</lon>
<gazetteerText>THORPE-NEXT-NORWICH, or T.-St. Andrew, a parish in Norwich and Blofield districts, Norfolk; on the river Yare, and on the Norwich and Yarmouth railway, 2 miles E of Norwich. A picturesque village is on the Yare, and a recent railway bridge spans the river. Thorpe-Hamlet is the part within Norwich district, and has a post-office under Norwich. Acres of the parish, 2,525. Real property, &#163;14,414; of which &#163;800 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 3,000; in 1861, 3,841. Houses, 752. The increase of pop. arose from the erection of houses suburban to Norwich. The manor was given by Henry I. to the Bishops of Norwich; had a palace of the Bishops; was exchanged away to Henry VIII.; and belongs now to W. Birkbeck, Esq. The Norfolk lunatic asylum, erected in 1814, is 1 mile SE of the village. A section of the parish, under the name of T.-St. Matthew, was made a separate charge in 1852. The head living is a rectory, and that of St. Matthew is a p. curacy in the diocese of Norwich. Value of the former, &#163;600;* of the latter, &#163;99.* Patron of the former, W. Birkbeck, Esq.; of the latter, the Rector. A new church was built in 1866. There are an Independent chapel, an endowed school with &#163;45 a year, a free school, and charities &#163;77. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10097885</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>THORPE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10104830</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>THORPE ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1682</id>
   <name>PORINGLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1683</id>
   <name>RACKHEATH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1714</id>
   <name>BRUNDALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2234</id>
   <name>BLOFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3512</id>
   <name>SALHOUSE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4692</id>
   <name>WOODBASTWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4717</id>
   <name>STOKE HOLY CROSS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4751</id>
   <name>BROOKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5459</id>
   <name>TROWSE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5958</id>
   <name>SPROWSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
