<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5473</id>
<name>HADDISCOE</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5324269971618</lat>
<lon>1.60781206346719</lon>
<gazetteerText>HADDISCOE, a village and a parish in Loddon district, Norfolk. The village stands near the East Suffolk and the Lowestoft railways, and near the river Waveney and the boundary with Suffolk, 5 miles N by E of Beccles; and has a station on the Lowestoft railway, and a post office under Norwich. The parish comprises 2, 071 acres. Real property, &#163;4, 057. Pop., 355. Houses, 81. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to H. S. Grimmer, Esq.; and the manor house is pleasantly situated, and commands fine views. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of MonksToft, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;500.* Patron, King&apos;s College, Cambridge. The church stands on a rising. ground; is ancient, battlemented, and very good; and has a Norman south door, an apsidal chapel, and a round five storey tower. There are a Primitive Methodist chapel, and town lands &#163;50. A preceptory of Knights Templars was here in the time of Henry III.; and a bridge, called St. Olave&apos;s, was built over the Waveney by Dame Hobart, in the time of Henry VII., and rebuilt in 1770, and in 1848. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647685</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/haddiscoe/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10195652</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HADDISCOE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10504569</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HADDISCOE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3923</id>
   <name>THORPE NEXT HADDISCOE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
