<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3964</id>
<name>HOLT</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9036996628871</lat>
<lon>1.09387134996255</lon>
<gazetteerText>HOLT, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Norfolk. The town stands on an eminence, 3&#189; miles from the coast, and 10 E by N of Walsingham r. station; commands a charming view over the surrounding fertile country; suffered great damage, by fire, in 1708; is now well built, and presents a pleasant appearance; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a postoffice &#8225; under Thetford, a banking office, two good inns, a sessions house, a police station, a corn exchange, a church, three dissenting chapels, a free grammar school, a national school, a British and infant school, a literary institute, and charities &#163;357. The church is decorated and later English; has a square tower, formerly surmounted by a lofty spire, which served as a sea mark; and contains several monuments. The grammar school was founded, in 1654, by Sir Thomas Gresham; was rebuilt, in a handsome and commodious manner, in 1860; has an endowed income of &#163;348, and an excellent library; holds a scholarship in Sidney-Sussex college, Cambridge, and another scholarship at either university; and had as a master, for upwards of 30 years, John Holmes, author of a Greek grammar. A weekly market is held on Friday; and fairs are held on 25 April and 25 Nov. Sir Thomas Gresham, Sir Richard Gresham, Thomas Girdlestone, the physician, and William Withers, the writer on forest trees, were natives.&#151;The parish comprises 2, 991 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 670; of which &#163;13 are in gas works. Pop., 1, 635. Houses, 372. The manor belonged to the family of De Vaux; and is now divided into four. A common around the town was enclosed in 1810. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;563.* Patron, St. John&apos;s College, Cambridge.&#151;The sub-district contains also sixteen other parishes, and is in Erpingham district. Acres, 28, 221. Pop., 6, 787. Houses, 1, 593. - The hundred contains thirty-one parishes. Acres, 43, 908. Pop. in 1851, 10, 764; in 1861, 9, 942. Houses, 2, 351. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/h/holt/</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holt,_Norfolk</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646701</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10044297</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10123823</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10505343</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10507674</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PLUMSTEAD BY HOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575254</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2924</id>
   <name>LETHERINGSETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>148</id>
<name>SHERINGHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.9390963787448</lat>
<lon>1.2089719938901</lon>
<gazetteerText>SHERINGHAM, two villages and a parish in Erpingham district, Norfolk. The villages are Lower S. and Upper S., and have each a post-office under Norfolk. Lower S. stands on cliffs of the coast, 4&#189; miles W by N of Cromer, and 12 NW of North Walsham r. station; is supplied with water from a reservoir formed in 1862; carries on a considerable fishery; and has a harbour excavated out of a cliff, curing-houses, about 173 boats, a coastguard station, a lifeboat, a mariners&apos; chapel, and a reading room. Upper S. stands 1&#189; mile SSW of Lower S., and contains the church. The parish comprises 2,181 acres of land, and 175 of water. Real property, &#163;3,337. Pop., 1,289. Houses, 299. The manor, with S. Hall, belongs to H. R. Upcher, Esq. A black priory, a cell to Nutley abbey, was founded here in the time of Henry II. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;70. Patron, the Bishop of Norwich. The church is early and later English, and was repaired in 1851. There are a school, and charities &#163;21. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheringham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638019</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/s/sheringham/</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10025450</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SHERINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10079226</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SHERINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10508770</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHERINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541335</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SHERINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2293</id>
   <name>KELLING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2641</id>
   <name>EDGEFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3032</id>
   <name>BEESTON REGIS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3266</id>
   <name>WEYBOURNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3420</id>
   <name>GRESHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3474</id>
   <name>BODHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3964</id>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5132</id>
   <name>CLEY NEXT THE SEA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5161</id>
   <name>BLAKENEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5458</id>
   <name>THORNAGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
