<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>3957</id>
<name>FOULSHAM</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.783959608201</lat>
<lon>1.0232810414448</lon>
<gazetteerText>FOULSHAM, a village and a parish in Aylsham district, Norfolk. The village stands on an affluent of the river Wensum, 4&#189; miles NE of Elmham r. station, and 18 NW of Norwich; was almost totally destroyed by fire in 1770; was afterwards rebuilt on a better plan, and with cheerful aspect; was once a market-town, and has still a fair on the first Tuesday of May; has also a post office&#8225; under Thetford, a bridge, a church, a Baptist chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;89; and is a seat of petty sessions. The bridge was built in 1813. The church was rebuilt at the rebuilding of the village, and has a fine tower. The churchyard contains an ancient altar-tomb, bearing a curious broken inscription in Saxon characters. The parish comprises 3, 226 acres. Real property, &#163;7, 112. Pop., 1, 022. Houses, 241. The property is subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;602. Patron, Lord Hastings. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/f/foulsham/</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649139</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10123756</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FOULSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10503840</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FOULSHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2279</id>
   <name>FOXLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5933</id>
   <name>BAWDESWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6002</id>
   <name>THEMELTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
