<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>918</id>
<name>DOWNHAM MARKET</name>
<container>NORFOLK</container>
<lat>52.6036219397873</lat>
<lon>0.378822337826766</lon>
<gazetteerText>DOWNHAM, or Downham-Market, a town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district in Norfolk. The town stands on the side of a hill, at the river Ouse, adjacent to the Lynn and Ely railway, 11 miles S by W of Lynn. It has recently undergone much improvement; contains a spacious ornamental market square; has a head post office, &#8225; a banking office, a railway station, two chief inns, a recently-erected commodious court-house, a church, four dissenting chapels, a cemetery with two mortuary chapels, a mechanics&apos; institute, two public schools, a spacious and handsome workhouse, and charities &#163;149; had anciently a Benedictine priory, belonging to Ramsey abbey; and is a seat of petty sessions and county courts, and a polling-place. Markets are held on Saturdays: and fairs on 3 March, 8 May, and 13 Nov. A great trade in butter, for the London market, was long done; but has in good measure been removed to Swaffham. Pop., 2, 458. Houses, 567.&#151;The parish comprises 2, 490 acres. Real property, &#163;13, 651. Pop., 3, 133. Houses, 657. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to Ramsey abbey. The land is fenny, and much frequented by wild fowl, but includes much good dairy pasture. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;403. Patron, Rev. E. R. Franks.&#151;The sub-district contains the parishes of Downham, Crimplesham, Bexwell, Ryston, Denver, Fordham, Roxham, Hillgay, and Southery, and parts of the parishes of Wimbotsham, Stow-Bardolph, and Upwell,-the last partly in Cambridgeshire. Acres, 28, 686. Pop., 8, 878. Houses, 1,883. The district comprehends also the sub-district of Fincham, containing the parishes of Fincham, Barton-Bendish, Marham, West Dereham, Wereham, Wretton, Stoke-Ferry, Boughton, and Stradsett; and the sub-district of Wiggenhall, containing the parishes of Wiggenhall-St. Mary-the-Virgin, Wiggenhall-St. Mary-Magdalene, Wiggenhall-St. Germans, Wiggenhall-St. Peter, Watlington, Tottenhill, Wormegay, Shouldham, Shouldham-Thorpe, South Runcton, Holme-next-Runcton, Wallington-cum-Thorpland, and parts of Wimbotsham and Stow-Bardolph. Acres, 83, 687. Poor-rates in 1862, 13, 344. Pop. in 1841, 19, 202; in 1861, 20, 264. Houses, 4, 336. Marriages in 1860, 137; births, 657, -of which 70 were illegitimate; deaths, 411, -of which 150 were at ages under 5 years, and 12 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1, 464; births, 7, 207; deaths, 4, 229. The places of worship in 1851 were 34 of the Church of England, with 7, 458 sittings; 6 of Baptists, with 771 s.; 2 of Quakers, with 245 s.; 22 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 3, 109 s.; 22 of Primitive Methodists, with 2, 204 s.; and 4 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 440 s. The schools were 20 public day schools, with 1, 443 scholars; 47 private day schools, with 823 s.; 46 Sunday schools, with 2, 691 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 2 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Downham_Market</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651030</link>
<link>http://www.origins.org.uk/genuki/NFK/places/d/downham_market/</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Downham</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10027925</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>DOWNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10041971</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>DOWNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10083369</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>DOWNHAM WEST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10088677</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>DOWNHAM MARKET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10104853</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>DOWNHAM MARKET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10139843</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>DOWNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10169185</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DOWNHAM MARKET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173152</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>DOWNHAM MARKET</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541074</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DOWNHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1693</id>
   <name>WEST DEREHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2339</id>
   <name>RUNCTON HOLME</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3293</id>
   <name>WRETTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3369</id>
   <name>DENVER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4688</id>
   <name>WIMBOTSHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4706</id>
   <name>RYSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4716</id>
   <name>STOKE FERRY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5144</id>
   <name>CRIMPLESHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5582</id>
   <name>WEREHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5975</id>
   <name>STRADSETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
