<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7646</id>
<name>CASTOR</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5820780716996</lat>
<lon>-0.332971547990778</lon>
<gazetteerText>CASTOR. a village and a parish in Peterborough district, Northampton. The village stands on Ermine-street, adjacent to the river Nen, and to the Peterborough and Northampton railway, 5 miles W of Peterborough; and has a station on the railway and a post office under Peterborough. It occupies part of the site of the Roman station Durobriv&#230;; and was known to the Saxons as Castra or Kyneburgceastre. Numerous Roman relics, including a Jupiter Terminalis, pavements, urns, and coins from Trajan to Valens, have been found around it. A nunnery was founded at it in the 7th century, by a daughter of King Penda; and destroyed, in 1010, by the Danes.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlet of Ailesworth, and the chapelries of Sutton and Upton. Acres, 7,020. Rated property, &#163;8,519. Pop., 1,323. Houses, 272. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;528. Patron, the Bishop of Peterborough. The church is Norman, with early English tower and spire; exhibits curiously the features and decorations of the Norman period; and underwent recently a thorough renovation. The vicarages of Sutton and Upton are separate charges. Bishop Madan was rector. There are an Independent chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653530</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10267171</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CASTOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10267183</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CASTOR</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
