<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8358</id>
<name>WOODFORD</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.168077815603</lat>
<lon>-1.21184416623033</lon>
<gazetteerText>WOODFORD, a parish, with W. village and West Farndon and Hinton hamlets, in Daventry district, Northampton; 7&#189; miles NE of Cropredy r. station, and 7&#189; S by W of Daventry. It has a postal wall-box under Daventry. Acres, 2,655. Real property, &#163;5,641. Pop., 735. Houses, 186. The property is much subdivided. W. manor belongs to the Earl of Ellesmere; West Farndon manor, to A. Cartwright, Esq.; Hinton manor, to Sir R. Knightley, Bart. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;275.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is good; and there are Moravian and Wesleyan chapels, a national school, and charities &#163;12. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299537</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10287108</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WOODFORD CUM MEMBRIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10287110</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WOODFORD CUM MEMBRIS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7519</id>
   <name>APPLETREE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7590</id>
   <name>BODDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7643</id>
   <name>BYFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7651</id>
   <name>CHARWELTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7909</id>
   <name>EDGCOTE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7920</id>
   <name>EYDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7929</id>
   <name>FAWSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7985</id>
   <name>HELLIDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8268</id>
   <name>CHIPPING WARDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9200</id>
   <name>PRIORS MARSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>8357</id>
<name>WOODFORD</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3799947511807</lat>
<lon>-0.585275837118113</lon>
<gazetteerText>WOODFORD, a parish, with a village, in Thrapston district, Northampton; 2&#189; miles SW by W of Thrapston r. station. It has a post-office under Thrapston. Acres, 1,750. Real property, &#163;4,194. Pop. in 1851,726; in 1861,912. Houses, 207. The increase of pop. arose from extension of shoe manufacture. The property is subdivided. W. Lodge is the seat of Lient.-Gen. the Hon.G. Arbuthnot. Ironstone is quarried; and Roman relics have been found. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;497.* Patron, Lord St. John. The church was recently restored, and has a tower and spire. There are a Baptist chapel, national schools, and charities &#163;86. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.kellner.eclipse.co.uk/genuki/NTH/Woodford</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woodford,_Northamptonshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633657</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66299</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10287080</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WOODFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10287091</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WOODFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
