<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8218</id>
<name>THRAPSTON</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3929670360426</lat>
<lon>-0.520272509598073</lon>
<gazetteerText>THRAPSTON, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Northamptonshire. The town stands on the river Nen, and on the Northampton and Peterborough railway, at the intersection of the line from Kettering to Huntingdon, 20 miles NE by N of Northampton; had a ruined hermitage in the time of Henry VIII.; comprises four streets, in the form of a cross; is a seat of petty sessions and county courts; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a r. station with telegraph, three banking offices, a hotel, a court-house, a corn exchange, a bridge, an ancient church partly rebuilt in 1841, a Baptist chapel, national schools, a girls&apos; educational endowment of &#163;21 a year, a workhouse, a weekly market on Saturday, and three annual fairs. The parish comprises 990 acres. Real property, &#163;5,013. Pop., 1,257. Houses, 247. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;430.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor.&#151;The sub-district contains 14 parishes. Acres, 27,387. Pop., 7,459. Houses, 1,624.&#151;The district includes Raunds sub-district, and comprises 51,188 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;7,011. Pop. in 1851, 12,841; in 1861, 14,065. Houses, 3,064. Marriages in 1863, 116; births, 517,-of which 40 were illegitimate; deaths, 368,-of which 170 were at ages under 5 years, and 7 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,071; births, 4,721; deaths, 2,658. The places of worship, in 1851, were 25 of the Church of England, with 6,069 sittings; 1 of Independents, with 450 s.; 10 of Baptists, with 2,353 s.; 8 of Wesleyans, with 1,376 s.; 1 of Primitive Methodists, with 168 s.; 1 undefined, with 12 s.; and 1 of Latter Day Saints, with 60 s. The schools were 21 public day-schools, with 1,220 scholars; 20 private day-schools, with 385 s.; 34 Sunday schools, with 2,479 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 12 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thrapston</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Thrapston</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635937</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66274</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10108901</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>THRAPSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10139065</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>THRAPSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10207125</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>THRAPSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10282070</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>THRAPSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10282081</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>THRAPSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10470213</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>THRAPSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553969</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>THRAPSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581230</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>THRAPSTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7485</id>
   <name>ALDWINCLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7663</id>
   <name>CLOPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8211</id>
   <name>THORPE ACHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8245</id>
   <name>TITCHMARSH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
