<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8010</id>
<name>HELPSTON</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6306242555759</lat>
<lon>-0.3430248882403</lon>
<gazetteerText>HELPSTONE, a village and a parish in Peterborough district, Northamptonshire. The village stands adjacent to the Syston and Peterborough railway, 2&#189; miles from the boundary with Lincolnshire, and 4 SSW of MarketDeeping; and has a station with telegraph on the railway, a post office under Market-Deeping, and a fine early English stone cross. The parish comprises 1,860 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 372; of which &#163;43 are in quarries. Pop., 763. Houses, 148. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Sir John Trollope, Bart. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;108. Patron, the Hon. George W. Fitzwilliam. The church is of various dates, from Norman downward; has an early Norman tower, surmounted by an octagonal decorated English tower and spire; had once a chantry; was partially restored in 1862 and in 1865; and contains three sedilia, an octagonal font, and a piscina. During the restoration of it there were found an ancient stone coffin, many Norman and early English sepulchral slabs, very many early medi&#230;val glazed flooring tiles, and some fragments of Roman flue tiles. There are an Independent chapel, a free Methodist chapel of 1863, and a national school with &#163;40 a year from endowment. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647146</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10276512</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HELPSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10276548</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HELPSTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7913</id>
   <name>ETTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
