<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8115</id>
<name>DEANSHANGER</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0580719291543</lat>
<lon>-0.892645884561474</lon>
<gazetteerText>PASSENHAM, a village and a parish in Potterspury district, Northampton. The village stands on the river Ouse, at the boundary with Bucks, 1 mile W S W of Stony-Stratford, and 3 W S W of Wolverton r. station; was known to the Saxons as Passanham; and was theplace where Edward the Elder halted in his expeditionagainst the Danes, and raised an entrenchment whilefortifying Towcester. The parish contains also the hamlet of Denshanger, and parts of Puxley and Old Stratford; and its post town is Stony-Stratford. Acres, 2, 230. Real property, &#163;5, 386. Pop. in 1851, 969; in 1861, 1, 105. Houses, 233. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to the heiress of the late Viscount Maynard. The parish is traversed by the Buckingham canal, and includes great part of Whittlewood forest. Lace-making is carried on. The living is a rectory, united with the p.curacy of Denshanger, in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;650.* Patrons, the Trustees of the late Viscount Maynard. The church is old and ivy-clad; consists of nave and chancel, with a tower; and contains a finely carved pulpit, twelve richly carved stalls, and a handsome monument to Sir R. Banastre, who died in 1649. A new church was built in 1853; and there are chapels for Baptists and Primitive Methodists, parochial schools, and a boarding school. B. Willis, theantiquary, was a resident. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deanshanger</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651461</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22787</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10279586</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>DEANSHANGER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279598</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PASSENHAM WITH DEANSHANGER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
