<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8114</id>
<name>GREAT OXENDON</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4458134294279</lat>
<lon>-0.920882320013896</lon>
<gazetteerText>OXENDON (Great), a village and a parish in the district of Market-Harborough and county of Northampton. The village stands &#189; a mile W of the Northampton and . Market-Harborough railway, 2&#190; miles S of Market-Harborough; and has a station, jointly with Clipstone, on the railway, and a post-office, of the name of Oxendon, under Northampton. The parish comprises 1, 620 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 173. Pop., 238. Houses, 54. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;410.* Patron, the Rev. E. Parker. The church is ancient, has anembattled tower, contains an effigies of Lady Gorges, and stands &#188; of a mile from the village. There are a dissenting chapel, and a parochial school. Morton, whowrote the &quot; Natural History of Northamptonshire, &quot; wasrector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Oxendon</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648042</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10093284</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>OXENDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279562</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OXENDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279574</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GREAT OXENDON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24864</id>
<name>LITTLE OXENDON</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4487448379899</lat>
<lon>-0.930165211653771</lon>
<gazetteerText>OXENDON (Little), a hamlet in Little Bowden parish, Northampton; 2 miles S W of Market-Harborough. Acres, 510. Real property, &#163;902. Pop., 40. The property belongs to T. T. Paget, Esq. Coins, pottery, and tiles were recently excavated; and are supposed to have been inhumed by devastating fire, at the time of thebattle of Naseby. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
</results>
