<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8194</id>
<name>KINGS SUTTON</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0271307029923</lat>
<lon>-1.26238653147233</lon>
<gazetteerText>KINGS-SUTTON, a village, a parish, and a hundred in Northampton. The village stands near the river Cherwell, the Oxford canal, the Oxford and Wolverhampton railway, and the boundary with Oxfordshire, 3&#189; miles N by E of Aynho r. station, and 4&#190; SSE of Banbury; and has a post office&#8224; under Banbury. The parish includes also the hamlet of Walton, and parts of the hamlets of Astrop, Charlton, and Purston; and is in the district of Brackley. Acres, 3, 850. Real property, &#163;9, 782. Pop., 1, 145. Houses, 270. The manor belongs to Mrs. Willes. The manor house is occupied byT. Willes, Esq.; and Astrop House is the seat of Sir William Brown, Bart. A mineral spring, called St. Rumbald&apos;s well, was formerly much visited, but has lost its reputation. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;140.* Patron, Mrs. Willes. The church is later English; comprises nave, aisles, chancel, and porches; and has a W tower, with lofty crocketted spire. There are chapels for Baptists and Primitive Methodists, a national school, and charities &#163;135.-The hundred contains twenty-one parishes and part of another. Acres, 48, 999. Pop. in 1851, 13, 000; in 1861, 13, 397. Houses, 3, 009. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kings_Sutton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645443</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10210598</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>KINGS SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10281520</id>
   <status>CP/CP/AP</status>
   <name>KINGS SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10281556</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KINGS SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10281570</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>KINGS SUTTON WITH NEWBOTTLE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8096</id>
   <name>NEWBOTTLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
