<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7534</id>
<name>ASHTON</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1421596142715</lat>
<lon>-0.873274248399263</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHTON, a parish in Potterspury district, Northampton; on the Northwestern railway and the Grand Junction canal, near Salcey forest and the Blisworth tunnel, 1&#189; mile SSE of Roade r. station, and 7 S of Northampton. Post Town, Roade under Northampton. Acres, 1,290. Real property, &#163;1,787. Pop., 374. Houses, 84. The property is divided among a few. The inhabitants have a right of common in Salcey forest. The living is a rectory in the dio. of Peterborough. Value, &#163;275. Pa tron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is good; and there are Baptist and Methodist chapels, and charities &#163;20. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.kellner.eclipse.co.uk/genuki/NTH/Ashton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656922</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashton,_South_Northamptonshire</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashton,_East_Northamptonshire</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22780</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10264376</id>
   <status>AP/CP/Ch</status>
   <name>ASHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10264480</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASHTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>7540</id>
<name>ASHTON</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4840511730845</lat>
<lon>-0.429777435569831</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHTON, a hamlet in Oundle parish, Northampton; near the Peterborough railway and the Nen river, 1 mile E of Oundle. Real property, &#163;1,984. Pop., 177. Houses, 39. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656921</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10264492</id>
   <status>Hmlt/CP</status>
   <name>ASHTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>22439</id>
<name>ASHTON</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6383704044287</lat>
<lon>-0.369809993333822</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHTON, a hamlet in Ufford parish, Northampton; 2&#189; miles W of Helpstone r. station, and 5 E by S of Stamford. Acres, 980. Real property, &#163;1,069. Pop., 115. Houses. 21. Ashton Wold is a resort of sportsmen. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10264546</id>
   <status>CP/Hmlt</status>
   <name>ASHTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>7543</id>
<name>ASTON LE WALLS</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1532542976376</lat>
<lon>-1.27741369417582</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASTON-LE-WALLS, a parish in the district of Banbury and county of Northampton; on the verge of the county, on the Roman road to Dorchester, near the Oxford canal, 4&#189; miles NE of Cropredy r. station, and 8 NNE of Banbury. It includes the hamlet of Appletree; and its Post Town is Chipping-Warden under Banbury. Acres, 1,270. Real property, &#163;3,436. Pop., 221. Houses, 42. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;535.* Patron, St. John&apos;s College, Oxford. The church is of the 13th century. The Roman Catholics have a chapel and a school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aston_le_Walls</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301967</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10264571</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ASTON LE WALLS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10264583</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASHTON LE WALLS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
