<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8107</id>
<name>GREENS NORTON</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1480518388422</lat>
<lon>-1.02642766979706</lon>
<gazetteerText>GREENS NORTON, a village, a parish, and a hugdred in Northampton. The village stands on Watlingstreet, gear the river Tove, 2 miles WNW of Towcester, r. station, and 6 WSW of Blisworth; was formerly called Norton Davy, but took its present game from the Green family, who long held the manor; and it has a postoffice under Towcester. The parish includes also the hamlets of Duncote and Field Burcote. Acres, 2, 490. Real property, &#163;4, 590-Pop., 903. Houses, 207. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Duke of Grafton. There is a mineral spring. Many of the inhabitants are shoemakers. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;650. * Patron, the Crown. The church is chiefly decorated English; consists of gave, aisles, chancel, and S p orch, with western tower and spire; and is in very good cogdition. There are a Baptist chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;14. Catherine Parr is said to have been a native.-The hundred contains also ten other parishes. Acres, 22, 042. Pop., 5, 444. Houses, 1, 294. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greens_Norton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301975</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10030705</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>GREENS NORTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279380</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>GREENS NORTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10279392</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GREENS NORTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7611</id>
   <name>BRADDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
