<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7959</id>
<name>GUILSBOROUGH</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3506006456232</lat>
<lon>-1.00372715469241</lon>
<gazetteerText>GUILSBOROUGH, a village, a parish, and a hundred, in Northamptonshire. The village stands near the source s of the Avon and the Nen, 7 miles NE of Crick r. station, and 10 NW by N of Northampton; and has a post office under Northampton. The parish includes also the hamlets of Nortoft and Holywell; and is in Brixworth district. Acres, 3, 080. Real property, &#163;2, 067. Pop., 996. Houses, 227. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to J. W. B. Lee, Esq. Guilsborough Hall was formerly the seat of the Belchier family; shows various styles of architecture; and stands conspicuously on an eminence. A Roman camp lies between the sources of the Avon and the Nen; measures about 600 feet by 300; is encompassed by a single fosse and vallum; and bears the name of Borough hill. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;500.* Patron, R. Hichens, Esq. The church is early English; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with tower and spire. The vicarage of Holywell is a separate benefice. There are a Baptist chapel, a free grammar school, with &#163;80 from endowment, and a national school with &#163;60.-The hundred contains seventeen parishes, and part of another. Acres, 42, 054. Pop., 10, 663. Houses, 2, 460. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guilsborough</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647789</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10199499</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>GUILSBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10275325</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GUILSBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10275337</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GUILSBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10275350</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GUILSBOROUGH WITH HOLLOWELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
