<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7634</id>
<name>BRIXWORTH</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3249904032873</lat>
<lon>-0.895430689103453</lon>
<gazetteerText>BRIXWORTH, a village, a parish, a subdistrict, and a district, in Northamptonshire. The village stands adjacent to the Northampton and Market-Harborough railway, 7 miles N of Northampton; and has a station on the railway, and a post office&#8225; under Northampton. It was formerly a market-town, under the Fitz-Simons; and it still has a fair on Whit-Monday. Here are a workhouse, built at a cost of &#163;5,800, and the kennels of the Pitchley hounds. The parish comprises 3,410 acres. Real property, &#163;7,636. Pop., 1,253. Houses, 269. The property is subdivided. Brixworth Hall belonged formerly to the Nicholses; and passed to the Woods. Some of the inhabitants are lace-makers, and some quarriers. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Peterborough. The church shows fine features of very early Norman, with additions of later character; has a curious staircase leading to the tower; is supposed to have been built on the foundations of a Roman basilica; and was restored in 1865. There are a Wesleyan chapel, an endowed school with &#163;50 a year, and charities &#163;58. The subdistrict contains the parishes of Brixworth, Holcot, Scaldwell, Lamport, Haselbeech, Maidwell, Draughton, Faxton, Old or Wold, Walgrave, and Hannington. Acres, 19,435. Pop., 4,555. Houses, 993.&#151;The district comprehends also the subdistrict of Spratton, containing the parishes of Spratton, Ravensthorpe, Holdenby, East Haddon, Cold Ashby, Naseby, Thornby, Guilsborough, Cottesbrook, and Great Creaton; and the subdistrict of Moulton, containing the parishes of Moulton, Overstone, Boughton, Pitsford, Brington, Harlestone Church-Brampton, and Chapel-Brampton, and the extra-parochial tract of Althorp. Acres, 59,926. Poorrates in 1866, &#163;14,667. Pop. in 1861, 15,359. Houses, 3,360. Marriages in 1866, 73; births, 474,-of which 34 were illegitimate; deaths, 252,-of which 97 were at ages under 5 years, and 7 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,055; births, 4,710; deaths, 3,078. The places of worship in 1851 were 30 of the Church of England, with 6,907 sittings; 6 of Independents, with 1,250 s.; 10 of Baptists, with 2,180 s.; 7 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 1,399 s.; and 2 undefined, with 260 s. The schools were 28 public day schools, with 1,573 scholars; 34 private day schools, with 477 s.; and 42 Sunday schools, with 2,345 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brixworth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654660</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Brixworth</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66338</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10138759</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>BRIXWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186729</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>BRIXWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10199440</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>BRIXWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10266919</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BRIXWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10266944</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BRIXWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553908</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EAST BRIXWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553910</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEST BRIXWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570542</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BRIXWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12751886</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE MID</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
