<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7689</id>
<name>CRICK</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3478496414541</lat>
<lon>-1.13567273399534</lon>
<gazetteerText>CRICK, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in the district of Rugby and county of Northampton. The village stands near Watling-street, adjacent to the Union canal, 2 miles NE of the Kilsby tunnel of the North-western railway, and 6 &#189; miles ESE of Rugby; and has a station, 3 miles distant, on the railway, and a post office under Rugby. The parish comprises 3, 930 acres. Real property, &#163;7, 519. Pop., 999. Houses, 236. The property is much subdivided. The surface is traversed by a ridge of hills, forming the watershed between the basin of the Avon and the basins of the Ouse and the Nen. A tunnel of the canal through this ridge, in the vicinity of the village, is 1, 524 yards long. The parish is a meet for the Pytchley hounds. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;890.* Patron, St. John&apos;s College, Oxford. The church is good; and there are an Independent chapel, and charities &#163;70. Arch-bishop Land-was rector. -The sub-district contains nine parishes, part of another, and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 26, 669. Pop., 4, 962. Houses, 1, 191. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crick,_Northamptonshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651989</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10109280</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>CRICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10268175</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CRICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10268187</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CRICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548159</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CRICK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8369</id>
   <name>YELVERTOFT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
