<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>462</id>
<name>IRTHLINGBOROUGH</name>
<container>NORTHAMPTONSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3239305700521</lat>
<lon>-0.617294780831884</lon>
<gazetteerText>IRTHLINGBOROUGH, a village and a parish in Wellingborough district, Northampton. The village stands near the river Nen, and near Higham-Ferrers r. station, 2 miles N of Higham-Ferrers; is popularly called Artleboro&apos;; consists chiefly of one street, nearly 17hr. mile long; carries on trade in the making of boots and shoes, parchment, and lace; and has a post office&#8225; under Higham-Ferrers. The parish comprises 3, 720 acres. Real property, &#163;8, 370. Pop. in 1851, 1, 577; in 1861, 1,800. Houses, 407. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to the Hon. G. W. Fitzwilliam and the Ecclesiastical Commissioners. Some remains exist of a secular college, founded in the time of Edward III., by Lord Mayor Pyel. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Peterborough. Value, &#163;266. Patron, the Hon. G. W. Fitzwilliam. The church is ancient; presents some interesting features; and has a fine octagonal tower, surmounted by a turret. A stone cross, 13 feet high on steps, is near the church. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, a national school, and charities &#163;87. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.kellner.eclipse.co.uk/genuki/NTH/Irthlingborough</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irthlingborough</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646034</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=66290</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10074540</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>IRTHLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10277176</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>IRTHLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10277188</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>IRTHLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10277190</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>IRTHLINGBOROUGH ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10277220</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>IRTHLINGBOROUGH ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10277243</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>IRTHLINGBOROUGH ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10277267</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>IRTHLINGBOROUGH ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12831791</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>IRTHLINGBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
