<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20067</id>
<name>BULWELL</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0038459128072</lat>
<lon>-1.19968828779488</lon>
<gazetteerText>BULWELL, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Basford district, Notts. The village stands in Sherwood forest, adjacent to the Midland railway, 4 miles NNW of Nottingham; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Nottingham. The parish includes also the hamlet of Hempshill. Acres, 1,210. Real property, &#163;6,732. Pop., 3,660. Houses, 785. The property is subdivided. Bulwell Hall is the seat of the Rev.Padley. Limestone is worked. Calico printing, lacemaking, stocking-making, brick-making, and malting are carried on. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;328.* Patron, the Rev.Padley. The church is new, and has a square tower. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists. A school has &#163;18,-other charities, 13. The subdistrict contains five parishes. Acres, 8,264. Pop., 7,823. Houses, 1,671. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulwell</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654338</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Bulwell/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10258224</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BULWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10258248</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BULWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10258250</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BULWELL ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553763</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BULWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570670</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BULWELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1062</id>
<name>HUCKNALL</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0315718962553</lat>
<lon>-1.21282874266943</lon>
<gazetteerText>HUCKNALL-TORKARD, a village and a parish in Basford district, Notts. The village stands near Hucknall r. station, 1 mile W of the river Trent, and 8 NNW of Nottingham; is a large place; and has a post office &#8225; under Nottingham.&#151;The parish comprises 3, 270 acres. Real property, &#163;6, 599. Pop., 2, 836. Houses, 611. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Duke of Portland. An extensive colliery, employing about 500 men, and yielding coal of excellent quality, was recently opened. Excellent limestone is quarried, and stocking making and lace making are carried on. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;135. Patron, the Duke of Portland. The church is ancient, in tolerable condition; and contains the tomb of Lord Byron the poet, and monuments of several of his ancestors. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, Primitive Methodists, and New Connexion Methodists, a national school, and a charity of about &#163;50 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/HucknallTorkard/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hucknall</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646460</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10004603</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HUCKNALL TORKARD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10220452</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HUCKNALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10262392</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HUCKNALL TORKARD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10262410</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HUCKNALL TORKARD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553623</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HUCKNALL TORKARD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12829231</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HUCKNALL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7422</id>
   <name>GREASLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
