<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7558</id>
<name>MARNHAM</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.2209325980116</lat>
<lon>-0.812746329580376</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARNHAM, a township in East Retford district, and a parish partly also in Southwell district, Notts. The township lies on the river Trent, 3&#190; miles N by E of Carlton-on-Trent r. station, and 5 ESE of Tuxford; and has a fair, for horses, cattle, and merchandise, on 12 Sept. Acres, 2,380. Real property, &#163;4,306. Pop., 273. Houses, 46. The parish contains also the township of Grassthorpe, and the hamlet of Skegby; and its Post town is Carlton-on-Trent, under Newark. Acres, 2,890. Real property, &#163;6,146. Pop., 348. Houses, 67. The property is subdivided. The manor of Marnham belongs to the Hon.H. Cust; and that of Grassthorpe, to the Right Hon. J. E. Denison. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;396. * Patron, the Hon.H. Cust. The church belonged to the Knights Temp1ars; is early perpendicular English; was recently restored; and has a tower. There are an endowed school with &#163;10 a year, and charities &#163;41. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Marnham/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7299021</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10264960</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10264972</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARNHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7398</id>
   <name>FLEDBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7421</id>
   <name>GRASSTHORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7592</id>
   <name>NORMANTON ON TRENT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
