<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7324</id>
<name>CLARBOROUGH</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3439718294825</lat>
<lon>-0.901878020559988</lon>
<gazetteerText>CLARBOROUGH, Clareborough, or Clayborough, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in East Retford district, Notts. The village stands near the Roman road to Lincoln, the Chesterfield canal, and the Retford and Gainsborough and the Great Northern railways, 2 miles NE of East Retford; and has a post office under Retford. The parish contains also the hamlets of Bollom, Gring ley, Little Gringley, Moorgate, and Walham, and the East Retford workhouse. Acres, 3, 870 Real property, &#163;9, 959. Pop., 2, 412. Houses, 529. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of St. Saviour, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;331.* Patrons, Simeon&apos;s Trustees. The parish church was built in 1258 by Archbishop Sewell; and is good. The church of St. Saviour, in Moorgate, was built in 1828. There are a P. Methodist chapel, and charities &#163;10. -The sub-district contains seven parishes and parts of three others. Acres, 19, 560. Pop, 6, 076. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Clarborough/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clarborough</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652942</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10258868</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CLARBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10258881</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CLARBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553830</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CLARBOROUGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12798179</id>
   <status>ExP</status>
   <name>LANDS COMMON TO CLARBOROUGH AND HAYTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7426</id>
   <name>GROVE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7444</id>
   <name>HAYTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
