<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7264</id>
<name>BLIDWORTH</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0940988493304</lat>
<lon>-1.13037842827194</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLIDWORTH, a Village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Mansfield district, Notts. The village stands in Sherwood forest, 4 miles E of Kirkby r. station, and 5 SE of Mansfield; and has a post office under Mansfield. The parish includes also the hamlets of Bottoms, Fishpool, and Rainworth. Acres, together with HaywoodOaks and Lindhurst extra-parochial tracts, 6,610. Real property, &#163;6,694. Pop., 1,166. Houses, 250. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to the Archbishop of York. A hollowed block of rock is regarded by some as a Druidical altar. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;283.* Patron, alternately the Bishop of Manchester and the Prebendary of Oxton. The church is Norman, and was repaired in 1839. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a national school.-The subdistrict includes also two extra-parochial tracts. Acres, 6,610. Pop., 1,188. Houses, 253. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655346</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Blidworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blidworth</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10256940</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BLIDWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10256951</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLIDWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553702</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BLIDWORTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7370</id>
   <name>EDINGLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7386</id>
   <name>FARNSFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7445</id>
   <name>HAYWOOD OAKS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7525</id>
   <name>LINBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7528</id>
   <name>LINDHURST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7587</id>
   <name>NEWSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7724</id>
   <name>OXTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7725</id>
   <name>PAPPLEWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
