<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7715</id>
<name>NUTHALL</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.992827078624</lat>
<lon>-1.24527892981425</lon>
<gazetteerText>NUTHALL, a village and a parish in Basford district, Notts. The village stands 2 miles W of Bulwell r.station, and 4&#189; N W by N of Nottingham; and has a post-office under Nottingham. The parish contains also the hamlets of Awsworth, Hempshill, and Cinder-Hill; and includes the tract of Shilo, formerly extra-parochial. Acres, 1, 644. Real property, &#163;4,066; of which &#163;1,000 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 685; in 1861, 842. Houses, 180. The increase of pop. arose from the opening of a colliery and of iron-stone quarries. The property is subdivided. The manor of Nuthall belongs to R Holden, Esq; and that of Awsworth to the Earl of Stamford. Nuthall Temple, the seat of R. Holden, Esq., is modelled after a celebrated Italian villa, and stands in a fine park. An extensive colliery and a stone quarry are at Cinder-Hill. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;350* Patron, R. Holden, Esq. The church is old, was repaired in 1860, and has a tower. The p. curacy of Awsworth is a separate benefice. A parochial school is in Nuthall; and a Primitive Methodist chapel and a school-charity of &#163;5 are in Awsworth. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Nuthall/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuthall</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7300866</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10268990</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NUTHALL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10269027</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NUTHALL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
