<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>859</id>
<name>KIRKBY IN ASHFIELD</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0949511255948</lat>
<lon>-1.2569614789925</lon>
<gazetteerText>KIRKBY-IN-ASHFIELD, a village and a parish in Basford district, Notts. The village stands 1 mile W of Kirkby r. station, 1&#189; E of the boundary with Derbyshire, and 5 SW of Mansfield; is a large place; and has. a post office, of the name of Kirkby, under Mansfield. The parish includes also the village of Kirkby-Folly and the hamlet of Kirkby-Woodhouse; and contains the sources of the rivers Maun, Leen, and Erewash, and the junction of the Erewash Valley railway with the Nottingham and Mansfield railway. Acres, 5, 590. Real property, &#163;11, 885; of which &#163;5, 654 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 2, 363; in 1861, 2, 886. Houses, 577. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of coal mining. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the.Duke of Portland. Kirkby Old Hall, Langton Hall, and Hardwick are chief residences. Frame work knitting is largely carried on. The living is a rectory, united with the chapelry of Kirkby-Woodhouse, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;730. * Patron, the Duke of Portland. The parish church is partly Norman, and was recently restored. The church of KirkbyWoodhouse was built in 1861. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, and a large parochial school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/KirkbyinAshfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kirkby-in-Ashfield</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645309</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10153694</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>KIRKBY IN ASHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10263116</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>KIRKBY IN ASHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10263128</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KIRKBY IN ASHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10263130</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KIRKBY IN ASHFIELD ST THOMAS</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
