<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7516</id>
<name>EAST LEAKE</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8351194392091</lat>
<lon>-1.17622589834173</lon>
<gazetteerText>LEAKE (EAST), a village and a parish in the district of Loughborough and county of Nottingham. The village stands on an affluent of the river Soar, 2 miles N of the boundary with Leicestershire, 3&#190; ESE of Kegworth r. station and 5 N by E of Loughborough; communicates, by post, with Loughborough; has hiring fairs at Candlemas, and on the first Tuesday and last Friday of November; and is a polling place.&#151;The parish comprises 2, 540 acres. Real property, 4, 899. Pop., 1, 059. Houses, 245. The property is much subdivided. Framework knitting is largely carried on. Theliving is a rectory, united with the rectory of West Leake, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;719.* Patron, the Rev. J. Bateman. The church is later English; consists of nave, aisle, and large chancel, with tower and spire; and was recently in bad condition. There are a large Baptist chapel, a recent Methodist chapel, a large endowed school, with &#163;49 a year, and charities &#163;31. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/EastLeake/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Leake</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650397</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10263967</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EAST LEAKE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10263979</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EAST LEAKE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7281</id>
   <name>UPPER BROUGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7310</id>
   <name>BUNNY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7349</id>
   <name>COSTOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7418</id>
   <name>GOTHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7483</id>
   <name>KEYWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7487</id>
   <name>KINGSTON ON SOAR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7813</id>
   <name>WIDMERPOOL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7817</id>
   <name>WILLOUGHBY ON THE WOLDS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7831</id>
   <name>WYSALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10655</id>
   <name>NETHER BROUGHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
