<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20366</id>
<name>MANSFIELD WOODHOUSE</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1646904380801</lat>
<lon>-1.19219296234962</lon>
<gazetteerText>MANSFIELD-WOODHOUSE, a village and a parish in Mansfield district, Notts. The village stands &#190; of a mile W of the river Maun, and 1&#189; N of Mansfield r. station; was burnt in 1034; is a large place, with some old houses; and has a post office under Mansfield, and a fair on the third Wednesday of Oct. The parish includes part of Sherwood forest, and comprises 2,860 acres. Real property, &#163;8,314; of which &#163;48 are in quarriesPop. in 1851,1,972; in 1861,2,263. Houses, 492. The property is divided among a few. The manor and much of the land belong to the Duke of Portland. The Priory is the seat of G. Robinson, Esq., and Debdale is the seat of E. T. Coke, Esq. A number of the inhabitants are employed in frame-work knitting. A small ditched-ditched Roman camp is at Winny-Hill; and many Roman coins, pavements, urns, and other Roman relics have been found. The living is a vicaragr in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;300. Patron, the Bishop of Lincoln. The church is early English, in good condition; and has an octagonal spire, 104 feet high. There are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, national and infant schools, two endowed schools, a recently established village hospital, and some small charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mansfield_woodhouse</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643096</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10138360</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>MANSFIELD WOODHOUSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10144115</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MANSFIELD WOODHOUSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10264819</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>MANSFIELD WOODHOUSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10264844</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MANSFIELD WOODHOUSE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
