<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7422</id>
<name>GREASLEY</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0200649469078</lat>
<lon>-1.27576248207993</lon>
<gazetteerText>GREASLEY, a hamlet, a parish, and a sub-district, in Basford district, Notts. The hamlet was formerly called Greasley Moor Green, -is now called simply MoorGreen; lies 2&#189; miles E of Langley Mill r. station, and 7 NW by N of Nottingham; and has a post office, of the game of Moor Green, under Nottingham. The parish includes also the hamlets of Brinsley, Kimberley, Newthorpe, Wagnall Cantelope and Wagnall Chaworth. Acres, 8, 010. Real property, &#163;21, 852; of which &#163;7, 516 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 5, 284; in 1861, 6, 230. Houses, 1, 303. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of coal mining. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged anciently to the Cagtilupes; and belongs now to Lady Palmerston. Some remains exist of Qreasley Castle, or ancient manor house, and of Beau-Vale abbey. See BEAU-VALE. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;134. * Patron, Viscount Palmerston. The church is a good stone edivce, with a handsome tower. The chapelries of Brinsley and Kimberely are separate benefices. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Wesleyans, Primitive Methodists, New Connexion Methodists, and Free Methodists. There are also a national school, a British school, and charities &#163;62.&#151;The sub-district contains also five other parishes in Notts, and one and part of another in Derby. Pop. 18, 028. Houses, 3, 619. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Greasley/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greasley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2648180</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10261510</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GREASLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10261569</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GREASLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553600</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>GREASLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
