<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20419</id>
<name>RADFORD</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.956058965319</lat>
<lon>-1.18417634070353</lon>
<gazetteerText>RADFORD, a suburban town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district in Notts. The town is suburban to Nottingham; lies on the river Leen and on the Nottingham and Mansfield railway, 1&#189; mile W N W of the centre of Nottingham; consists of two parts, called Old R. and New R.; increased its population nearly sixfold between 1801 and 1861; shares largely in the manufactures of Nottingham, chiefly lace and stockings; and has a post-office under Nottingham, a railway-station, two churches, six dissenting chapels, a national school, a workhouse, and charities &#163;12. St. Peter&apos;s church was rebuilt in 181 2; and is a neat Gothic edifice, with a tower. Christchurch was built in 1845, and is in New Rad ford. The parish includes Kensington, New Coleorton, and part of Hyson-Green, and comprises 1,000 acres. Real property, &#163;27, 659. Pop. in 1851, 12, 637; in 1861, 13, 495. Houses, 2, 858. The manor belongs to J. S. Gregory, Esq. Gas-works were erected in 1844; and coal ismined. The living of St. Peter is a vicarage, and that of Christchurch is a p. curacy, in the diocese of Lincoln. Value of the former, &#163;293; * of the latter, &#163;300. Patron of the former, the Lord Chancellor; of the latter, alternately the Crown and the Bishop. The sub-district comprises the parts of Rad ford and Lenton parishes N of the road from Nottingham to Ilkeston and S W of the road to Alfreton. Pop. in 1851, 8, 888; in 1861, 10, 192. Houses, 2, 162. The districtcomprehends also the sub-district of Lenton, containing the parts of Rad ford and Lenton parishes S of the Nottingham and Ilkeston road, together with the extra-parochial tract of Brewhouse-Yard; the sub-district of Hyson-Green, containing the rest of Radford and Lenton parishes; and the sub-district of Snenton, conterminate with Snenton parish. Acres of the district, 6, 800. Poor-rates in 1863, &#163;9, 211. Pop. in 1851, 26, 776; in 1861, 30, 479. Houses, 6, 366. Marriages in 1863, 229; births, 1,055, of which 80 were illegitimate; deaths, 686, of which. 355 were at ages under 5 years, and 11 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 2, 802; births, 11, 281; deaths, 7, 241. The places of worship, in 1851, were 4 of the Church of England, with 2, 801sittings; 3 of Independents, with 422 s.; 2 of Baptists, with 410 s.; 5 of Wesleyans, with 1, 400 s.; 3 of New Connexion Methodists, with 802 s.; 2 of Primitive Methodists with 393 s.: 1 of the Wesleyan Association, with 140 s.; and 1 of Latter Day Saints with 300 s. The schools were 6 public day schools, with 831 scholars; 43private day schools, with 1,097 s.; and 17 Sunday schools, with 2, 799 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radford,_Nottingham</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Radford/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Radford</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10138371</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>RADFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10215500</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>RADFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10269430</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RADFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10269453</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RADFORD ST PETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10269477</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RADFORD ALL SOULS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10269489</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RADFORD ST MICHAEL AND ALL ANGELS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553787</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NOTTINGHAM NORTH WEST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12781143</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RADFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
