<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7571</id>
<name>MISTERTON</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.4483342906282</lat>
<lon>-0.863008021233573</lon>
<gazetteerText>MISTERTON, a village, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in the district of Gainsborough and county of Nottingham. The village stands on the Chesterfield canal, 1&#189; mile W of the river Trent, at the boundary with Lincoln, and 5 NW by N of Gainsborough r. station; is a considerable place; and has a post office under Gainsborough.-The township includes the village, and extends into the country. Real property, &#163;7,098. Pop., 1,089. Houses, 250.&#151;The parish contains also the township of West Stockwith, and comprises 5,420 acres. Real property, &#163;9,889. Pop. in 1851,1,743; in 1861, 1,627. Houses, 387. The decrease of pop. was all in West Stockwith, and arose from the migration of watermen and rope-makers, occasioned by the facilities of railway communication. The property is much subdivided. The chief landowners are the Duke of Portland, J. H. Hill, Esq., and Misses Hill. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;120. Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of York. The church was partly rebuilt in 1848; and consists of nave, aisles and chancel, with tower and spire. The p. curacy of West Stockwith is a separate benefice. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists, an endowed school, and charities &#163;10.&#151;The sub-district contains also five other parishes. Acres, 14,763. Pop., 3,151. Houses, 709. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Misterton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misterton,_Nottinghamshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642417</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10186638</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>MISTERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10265265</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MISTERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10265290</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MISTERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548044</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MISTERTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
