<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>538</id>
<name>SUTTON IN ASHFIELD</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1289877965122</lat>
<lon>-1.25577994268379</lon>
<gazetteerText>SUTTON-IN-ASHFIELD, a small town, a township, a parish, and a sub-district, in Mansfield district, Notts. The town stands near the Nottingham and Mansfield railway, 3&#189; miles SW of Mansfield; is irregularly built; carries on cotton and thread-hosiery manufactures; publishes a weekly newspaper; and has a post-office&#8225; under Mansfield, a r. station, a fine church with lofty spire, restored and enlarged in 1868, four dissenting chapels, a large national school, a provision market every Saturday, and stock fairs on Easter Tuesday and on the second Tuesday of Oct. The township contains also Eastfield hamlet. Real property, &#163;8,705; of which &#163;150 are in gasworks. Pop., 6,483. Houses, 1,367. The manor belongs to the Duke of Portland.&#151;The parish includes the township of Hucknall-under-Huthwaite, and comprises 6,040 acres. Pop., 7,643. Houses, 1,611. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;330.* Patron, the Duke of Devonshire.&#151;The sub-district includes also Skegby and Fulwood. Pop., 8,455. Houses, 1,768. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sutton-in-Ashfield</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/SuttoninAshfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636484</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10028840</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SUTTON IN ASHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10102467</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SUTTON IN ASHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270649</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SUTTON IN ASHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270650</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SUTTON IN ASHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270662</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SUTTON IN ASHFIELD ST MICHAEL AND ALL ANGELS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553738</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SUTTON IN ASHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12832023</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SUTTON IN ASHFIELD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>859</id>
   <name>KIRKBY IN ASHFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7220</id>
   <name>ANNESLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7757</id>
   <name>SKEGBY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7784</id>
   <name>TEVERSAL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17195</id>
   <name>ASHFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
