<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7376</id>
<name>ELSTON</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0208674728071</lat>
<lon>-0.865830133801365</lon>
<gazetteerText>ELSTON, or Elveston, a parish and a chapelry in Southwell district, Notts. The parish lies on Car Dyke, near the river Trent, 3z miles SE of Fiskerton r. station, and 5&#189; SW of Newark. Post town, Stoke, under Newark. Acres, with the chapelry, 1, 640. Real property, &#163;3, 812. Pop., 262. Houses, 65. The property is divided among a few. Elston Hall is the seat of Mrs. F. Darwin, and was the birthplace of Dr. Darwin. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;375.* Patron, Mrs. F. Darwin. The church contains monuments of the Darwins, and was renovated in 1859. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists. Darwin&apos;s school and alms-houses have &#163;24 from endowment; and other charities &#163;31. -The chapelry is in East Stoke parish; adjoins Elston parish on the NE; and is included with that parish in poor-rate assessment. Post town, Stoke, under Newark. Rated property, &#163;2, 674. Pop., 210. Houses, 51. The property is sub-divided. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the vicarage of East Stoke, in the diocese of Lincoln. The church is ancient but good: and there is a Wesleyan chapel. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/ElstonChapel/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Elston/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elston</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650049</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10260450</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ELSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10260474</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ELSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10260486</id>
   <status>Ch</status>
   <name>ELSTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7768</id>
   <name>EAST STOKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7783</id>
   <name>SYERSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7788</id>
   <name>THORPE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
