<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7777</id>
<name>SUTTON BONINGTON</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8218271806418</lat>
<lon>-1.24530562035242</lon>
<gazetteerText>SUTTON-BONNINGTON, a village and two parishes in the district of Loughborough and county of Nottingham. The village stands near the river Soar, 1 mile S by E of Kegworth r. station, and 10&#189; SSW of Nottingham; and has a post-office under Loughborough. The parishes are St. Ann and St. Michael. Acres, 1,910. Real property, &#163;6,266. Pop., 381 and 638. Houses, 92 and 154. The manor of St. Ann belongs to W. Paget, Esq.; and that of St. Michael, to G. E. Paget, Esq. The livings are rectories in the diocese of Lincoln. Value of St. A., &#163;270;* of St. M., &#163;700.* Patron of St. A., the Lord Chancellor; of St. M., the Dean and Chapter of Bristol. The church of St. A. is old; and that of St. M. is a fine edifice, with tower and lofty spire. There are two dissenting chapels, an endowed school for boys with &#163;52 a year, a subscription school for girls, and charities &#163;12. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/SuttonBonnington/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/SuttonBonnington/StAnne/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/SuttonBonnington/StMichael/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sutton_Bonington</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636488</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10270558</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>SUTTON BONINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270583</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SUTTON BONINGTON ST ANNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10270595</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SUTTON BONINGTON ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
