<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7265</id>
<name>BLYTH</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.3768964427598</lat>
<lon>-1.05651891346179</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLYTH, a village and a township in Worksop district, Notts; and a parish in Worksop and East Retford district, Notts, and in Doncaster district, W. R. Yorkshire. The village occupies a gentle ascent on the Ryton rivulet, 2&#189; miles W by S of Ranskill r. station, and 7 NNE of Worksop; and has a post office under Worksop. It was formerly a market-town; and it still has fairs on Holy Thursday and 20 Oct. The township includes also the hamlets of Norney and Oldcoates, and part of the hamlet of Ranby. Real property, &#163;4,721. Pop., 698. Houses, 167. The parish includes likewise the lordship of Hodsock, and the townships of Styrrup, Barnby-Moor, Ranskill, Torworth, Austerfield, and Bawtry. Acres, 17,110. Real property, &#163;31,057. Pop., 3,486. Houses, 784. Blyth Hall, in Blyth township, belonged formerly to the Mellishes; and is now the seat of H. H. Walker, Esq. Serlby Hall, 2 miles N of Blyth village, is the seat of Viscount Galway. The country around these seats, as well without the parks as within, is so rich and ornate as to look all like a garden. An hospital for a warden, three chaplains, and a number of leprous persons, was founded at Blyth-Spittal, to the S of Blyth village, by William de Cressy, Lord of Hodesac; but has all disappeared. A Benedictine priory was founded at Blyth village, in 1088, by Roger de Builly; and given, at the dissolution, to Richard Andrews and William Ramsden; and a part of it, called the conventual nave, still stands connected with the nave of the parish church. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;751.* Patron, Trinity College, Cambridge. The church is a noble edifice in successive characters from Norman to later English; has a very ancient tower; and contains an effigies and armorial bearings of the Mellishes. The p. curacy of Bawtry, with the p. curacy of Austerfield, is a separate benefice. There are four dissenting chapels, two public schools, and two alms-houses. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/YKS/WRY/Blythe/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655316</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blyth,_Nottinghamshire</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Blyth/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10042630</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>BLYTH AND CUCKNEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10256963</id>
   <status>AP/Tn/CP</status>
   <name>BLYTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10256975</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLYTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
