<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>88</id>
<name>ARNOLD</name>
<container>NOTTINGHAMSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0199304972943</lat>
<lon>-1.12333080460146</lon>
<gazetteerText>ARNOLD, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Basford, Notts. The village stands near Sherwood forest, 2&#189; miles ENE of Bulwell r. station, and 5&#189; N by E of Nottingham. It has a post office&#8225; under Nottingham. Its inhabitants are employed chiefly in lace and stocking making. The parish includes also part of Daybrook hamlet and the seats of Arnold Grove and Sherwood Lodge. Acres, 4,570. Real property, &#163;12,059. Pop., 4,642. Houses, 971. The property is much sub-divided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lincoln. Value, &#163;310.* Patron, the Duke of Devonshire. The church is later English, and has a tower. There are chapels for Sc. Presbyterians, Baptists, Wesleyans and P. Methodists. A school has &#163;23 from endowment, and other charities &#163;10. R. Bonington the painter, born in 1801, was a native.-The subdistrict comprises six parishes and an extra-parochial liberty. Acres, 18,540. Pop., 8,378. Houses, 1,779. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/NTT/Arnold/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arnold,_Nottinghamshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657030</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10002722</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>ARNOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10062810</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>ARNOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10255879</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ARNOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10255880</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ARNOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10553568</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ARNOLD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12836405</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ARNOLD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7255</id>
   <name>BESTWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7315</id>
   <name>CALVERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7381</id>
   <name>EPPERSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7509</id>
   <name>LAMBLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7824</id>
   <name>WOODBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
