<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>20399</id>
<name>PEMBROKE DOCK</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6947491326039</lat>
<lon>-4.94054511055604</lon>
<gazetteerText>PEMBROKE-DOCK, a sea-port town and a chapelry in Pembroke, St. Mary parish, Pembrokeshire. The town stands on a branch of Milford-haven, at the W terminus of the Pembroke and Tenby railway, opposite New Milford, and 2 miles N W of Pembroke; was formerly called Pater; became a place of government dockyards, in 1814, in lieu of Milford-Haven; includes an area of 88 acres, surrounded by a high wall, with two flanking martellotowers, with a sea frontage of nearly &#189; a mile, and withtwelve building slips for ships of all sizes, under iron-roofed sheds; has also a dry dock for first-rate ships, a fort mounting 24 guns, large barracks defended by bastions and a fosse, and a hut encampment and a jettyat Hobbs-Point; carries on considerable trade with Ireland and America; is the point of regular steam communication with Waterford; and has a head post-office, &#8225;a railway station, a banking office, and two hotels. The chapelry was constituted in 1844. Real property in 1860, &#163;15, 326; of which &#163;35 were in quarries, and &#163;100 in gas-works. Pop. in 1861, 10, 190; of whom 1, 285were military, and 558 were persons on board vessels. Houses, 1, 353. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, alternately the Crown and the Bishop. The church was built in 1848. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640502</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10289014</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PEMBROKE DOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835863</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PEMBROKE DOCK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
