<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9455</id>
<name>WHITCHURCH</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.8839278362839</lat>
<lon>-5.1824721863954</lon>
<gazetteerText>WHITCHURCH, a parish in Haverfordwest district, Pembroke; on St. Brides bay, 3 miles E by S of St. Davids, and 12&#189; WNW of Haverfordwest r. station. It contains Solva village, which has a post-office under Haverfordwest. Acres, 3,138. Real property, &#163;3,159. Pop. in 1851, 1,252; in 1861, 1,085. Houses, 284. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;101.* Patrons, the Bishop and Chapter of St. D. The church was reported in 1859 as bad. There are three dissenting chapels, and charities &#163;6. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/Whitchurch/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10322613</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WHITCHURCH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>9459</id>
<name>WHITECHURCH</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9827239031353</lat>
<lon>-4.68349575442966</lon>
<gazetteerText>WHITECHURCH, or Eglwys-Wen, a parish in the district of Cardigan and county of Pembroke; 6&#189; miles SSW of Cardigan r. station. Post town, Cardigan. Acres, 2,481. Real property, &#163;1,589. Pop., 318. Houses, 70. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;113. Patron, T. Lloyd, Esq. The church is bad. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/Whitechurch/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634110</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10322674</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WHITECHURCH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
