<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2585</id>
<name>CAREW</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6979343276552</lat>
<lon>-4.82264049211935</lon>
<gazetteerText>CAREW, or Carey, a village and a parish in the district and county of Pembroke. The village stands on a creek of Milford haven, near the Pembroke and Tenby railway, 4 miles ENE of Pembroke. Here is a very ancient and beautiful cross, probably Saxon or Danish, of a single shaft, 14 feet high, covered with Runic carvings. The parish comprises 5,256 acres of land, and 380 of water; and its Post Town is Pembroke. Real property, &#163;5,958; of which &#163;458 are in quarries. Pop. 993. Houses, 216. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the princes of South Wales; was given as a dowry with Nesta, daughter of Rhys ap Tewdwr, to Gerald de Windsor; passed to Sir Rhys ap Thomas; gave entertainment to the Earl of Richmond, on his way to Bosworth field; was, soon afterwards, the scene of a great tournament, the first show of its kind in Wales; and belongs now to the Carews of Crocomb. A fortress stood here in the times of the Welsh princes; and a magnificent mansion was added to this in the time of Henry VII. Some part of the ancient fortress seems still to exist in a shattered, ivy-clad barbican; and the shell of the added mansion still stands, and is one of the finest ruins in Wales. The architecture is rich late perpendicular; the windows are large, square, and lanternlike; and the great hall has a lofty porch, and measures 102 feet by 20. Milton House, Freestone Hall, and Wilsdon are fine mansions; and the last occupies ground on which Cromwell had his quarters when besieging Pembroke castle. Extensive limestone quarries were worked, but have been stopped. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;182.* Patron, the Bishop of St. David&apos;s. The church is early English, with good perpendicular tower; and contains monuments of the Carews and others. The vicarage of Redberth is a separate benefice. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653800</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/Carew/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10066621</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CAREW</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
