<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5909</id>
<name>HAROLDSTON ST ISSELL</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7838220772475</lat>
<lon>-4.96079671674022</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARROLDSTON-ST. ISSELLS, a parish in Haverfordwest district, Pembroke; on the river Cleddy, 1 mile SE of Haverfordwest town and r. station. Post town, Haverfordwest. Acres, 1, 150. Real property, &#163;2, 050. Pop., 281. Houses, 59. The old seat of the Harrolds and the Perrots here is now a ruin. Fern Hill is the chief residence. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;56. Patron, James Higgon, Esq. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/HaroldstonStIssells/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10210938</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HAROLDSTON ST ISSELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>8789</id>
<name>ST ISSELLS</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7293425717876</lat>
<lon>-4.71038830931801</lon>
<gazetteerText>ISSELS (ST.), a village and a parish in Narberth district, Pembroke. The village stands on Carmarthen Bay, 3 miles N of Tenby r. station; and is a resort for sea bathing. The parish comprises 3, 740 acres of land, and 90 of water. Post town, Tenby. Real property, &#163;9, 549; of which &#163;4, 743 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 1, 784; in 1861, 2, 022. Houses, 403. The increase of pop. arose from resort for sea bathing, from the opening of a coal mine, and from the establishment of a blast furnace for iron. The property is divided among a few. Kilgetty was a seat of the Pictons, and is now a farmhouse. An export trade, in minerals, is carried on at Saundersfoot Pier. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;114.* Patron, the Chapter of St. Davids. The church is small; has a tall square tower; and was recently in very bad condition. There is an endowed school, with &#163;15 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/StIssells/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10302341</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ST ISSELLS</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2356</id>
   <name>EAST WILLIAMSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2901</id>
   <name>CRUNWEAR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2972</id>
   <name>LOVESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4405</id>
   <name>JEFFRESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5508</id>
   <name>AMROTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8617</id>
   <name>REDBERTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8620</id>
   <name>REYNALTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9515</id>
   <name>YERBESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11052</id>
   <name>LUDCHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
