<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>6733</id>
<name>MAENORBYR</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.6528913931726</lat>
<lon>-4.80067286737371</lon>
<gazetteerText>MANORBIER, or MANORBEAR, a village and a bar ish in the district and county of Pembroke. The village stands on the coast, adjacent to the Pembroke and Tenby railway, 5 miles ESE of Pembroke; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Tenby. The parish contains also the hamlets of Jameston and Newton. Acres, 3,493. Real property, &#163;5,169; of which &#163;125 are in quarries. Pop., 715. Houses, 151. The property is divided among a few. Manorbier Castle was built in the time of Henry I., by William de Barri, ancestor of Giraldus Cambrensis; passed, through the Windsors and others, to Phillips of Picton; belongs now to Lord Milford; appears to have been constructed in the manner more of a convenient mansion than of a feudal fortress; is now an extensive ruin, little altered from its original condition, except by the erosions of time; includes moat, entrance-gateway, parts of surrounding ramparts, and a lofty loop-holed embattled wall; and stands on a commanding site, overlooking a reach of coast. Giraldus Cambrensis was born here; and has left, in his Itinerary, a glowing description of the fish-ponds, the vineyards, the hazel-groves, and other attractions of his native place, all now quite or nearly extinct. The coast, however, is picturesque; and shows, among other features, a cromlech on cliffs at a cave, and two or three curious fissures, about 100 feet deep, in old red sandstone rock. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;125. Patron, Christ&apos;s College, Cambridge. The church is a wildly irregular ancient structure; has a N tower, in the angle of transept and chancel; comprises remarkably formed S aisle, transept, and nave-vaults; shows very curious interior arches, rising from square piers without capital o r impost; contains a monument of the De Barris; and was recently restored. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manorbier</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/Manorbier/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643104</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10240852</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MAENORBYR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2585</id>
   <name>CAREW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5360</id>
   <name>HODGESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8783</id>
   <name>ST FLORENCE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
