<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4436</id>
<name>LLANDEILO</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.9303872383993</lat>
<lon>-4.76608954452609</lon>
<gazetteerText>LLANDILO, a parish in Narberth district, Pembroke; on the upper part of the river Cleddau, under Precelly mountain, 5&#188; miles NNW of Narberth-Road r. station, and 8 N by W of Narberth. Post town, Narberth. Acres, 1,132. Real property, &#163;310. Pop., 126. Houses, 25. The surface is hilly; and the rocks include good slate. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the p. curacy of Llangolman, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. The church is dedicated to St. Teilo. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/Llandilo/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10150176</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>LLANDEILO LLWYDARTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1627</id>
<name>CRINOW</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.798723769323</lat>
<lon>-4.71819396021694</lon>
<gazetteerText>CRINOW, or Croynwydd, a parish in Narberth district, Pembroke; 1&#189;mile E of Narberth, and 2 SSE of Narberth Road r. station. Post town, Narberth. Acres, 352. Real property, &#163;620. Pop., 70. Houses, 15. The manor belongs to the Eatons. The living is a rectory in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;86. Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is very good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/Crinow/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/3345140</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10013719</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CRINOW</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>5508</id>
<name>AMROTH</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.7418579013961</lat>
<lon>-4.66684701302609</lon>
<gazetteerText>AMROTH, or Ambroth, a parish and a subdistrict in the district of Narberth, Pembroke. The parish lies on Carmarthen bay, 6 miles SE of Narberth, and 6&#189; S by W of Whitland r. station; and has a post office under Tenby. Acres, 2,878; of which 230 are water. Real property, &#163;2,754. Pop., 889. Houses, 195. The property is divided among a few. Coal is worked, and fishing is carried on. Amroth Castle, delightfully situated on the coast, was formerly a grand feudal residence, the seat of a follower of Arnulph de Montgomery, called Eare Wear; but passed to the family of Ackland, and is now a splendid modern mansion. The living is a vicar age in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;98. Patron, J. L. P. Lewis, Esq. The church is early English, and has a curiously formed tower. Charities, &#163;20.-The subdistrict comprises eight parishes and part of another Acres, 24,508. Pop., 3,265. Houses, 689. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/Amroth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657336</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amroth,_Pembrokeshire</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10197132</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>AMROTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10564311</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AMROTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
