<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8380</id>
<name>NEVERN</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0025738144919</lat>
<lon>-4.79023523150425</lon>
<gazetteerText>NEVERN, or Nefern, a village and a parish in the district of Cardigan and county of Pembroke. The village stands on the rivulet Nevern, in a picturesque reach of deep wooded vale, 2 miles E N E of Newport, and 8 S W of Cardigan r. station; and was once a borough, governed by a portreeve and burgesses. The parish is divided into the quarters of Cregie, Kilgwyn, Morva, and Trewern; and its post town is Newport, under Haverfordwest. Acres, 14, 637; of which 115 are water orforeshore. Real property of Cregie, &#163;1, 430; of Kilgwyn, &#163;1, 346; of Morva, &#163;3, 1 54; of Trewern, &#163;1, 751. Pop.of the whole in 1851, 1, 642; in 1861, 1, 436. Houses, 315. The decrease of pop. was caused by the migration of agricultural labourers. The property is much subdivided. Llanhyfer Castle stood on an eminence above the village; is said to have been the chief palace of theprinces of Dyfed; was probably the residence of Martinde Tours, before he married the daughter of Rhys ap Grufydd; was a square structure, with a bastion at eachangle; towered aloft, on one side, from the rim of arocky ravine, and was defended, on the other sides, by adeep fosse excavated in the solid rock; and has left sometraces. A mansion of the time of Henry VII. was the seat of Sir James ap Owain, passed to occupants of otherfamilies, and is now a farm-house. Llwyngwair and Henllys are present chief residences. A bridge, called Pont-Baldwyn, crosses the Nevern rivulet; and is said to have been the first or one of the earliest places atwhich Archbishop Baldwin and Giraldus preached thecrusades. Pentre-evan, about 1&#189; mile from the village, is a remarkably large cromlech; has a top-stone measuring 18 feet by 9; is so high that six persons on horse-back can be sheltered under it; and is surrounded by arude Druidical circle. 150 feet in circumference. Anothercromlech, with a furrow in the top-stone, is at Llech-y-Dribedd. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Kilgwyn, in the diocese of St. David&apos;s. Value, &#163;240.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church is Norman, in tolerable condition, with a tower; has anunpaved floor, which has been gradually raised fully 7feet above the original level by frequent interments; and contains a coffin-lid, with an early Greek cross. The churchyard is planted with yew-trees; and contains a very fine cross of the 9th century, 2 feet broad, 1&#189; footthick, 13 feet high, circular at the top, and carved onall sides with knot-work. Charities, &#163;24. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nevern</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/Nevern/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641747</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10287741</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NEVERN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1454</id>
   <name>BAYVIL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1780</id>
   <name>EGLWYSWRW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6785</id>
   <name>MELINE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
