<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1134</id>
<name>TENBY</name>
<container>PEMBROKESHIRE</container>
<lat>51.67528357462</lat>
<lon>-4.70337729741515</lon>
<gazetteerText>Tenby, parl. and mun. bor., seaport town, and watering-place, Pembrokeshire, on W. side of Carmarthen Bay, 9 miles E. of Pembroke and 276 miles W. of London by rail, 640 ac., pop. 4750; P.O., T.O., 2 Banks, 2 newspapers. Market-days, Wednesday and Saturday. Tenby was one of the Flemish settlements planted in Pembrokeshire in the 12th century, and until the time of Elizabeth was a port of much commercial importance. From that period it declined greatly until the present century, when it came into repute as a resort for bathing. It is now a flourishing watering-place. The trade of the port is not extensive - chiefly fish and oysters. The church is interesting, and some portions of the old walls still remain, but the ruins on Castle Hill are inconsiderable. Tenby is one of the Pembroke Boroughs, which return 1 member to Parliament. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/PEM/Tenby/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636104</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10302535</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST MARY IN LIBERTY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10302547</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>TENBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10302560</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ST MARY OUT LIBERTY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10487638</id>
   <status>AP</status>
   <name>ST MARY TENBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549371</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TENBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12783115</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TENBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12796389</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>TENBY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828159</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>TENBY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3166</id>
   <name>GUMFRESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8413</id>
   <name>PENALLY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11068</id>
   <name>CALDY ISLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
