<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8631</id>
<name>RHAEADR</name>
<container>RADNORSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3014800222518</lat>
<lon>-3.50823218688092</lon>
<gazetteerText>RHAYADER, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, a district, and a hundred, in Radnor. The town stands on the river Wye, and on the Mid-Wales railway, 14 miles S of Llanidloes; was originally called Rhaiadr-Gwy, signifying &quot;the cararact of the Wye; &quot; took thatname from a slight river-fall which was almost destroyed in 1780, by operations for building a bridge; had acastle, built in 1178 by Rhys ap Gruffydd, burnt in 1231by Llewelyn, and demolished in the civil wars of Charles I.; had also a cell to Strata-Florida abbey; is a boroughby prescription, governed by a bailiff; unites with Presteigne, New Radnor, Knucklas, Knighton, and Cefnllys in sending a member to parliament; was once a seat of assizes; is now a seat of county courts and a polling-place; occupies a situation of much beauty, amid a tract of barren hills; serves as a centre to tourists forexploring circumjacent scenery; consists chiefly of fourstreets, intersecting at right angles; and has a head post-office, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, a good inn, a town hall built in 1768, a church, three dissenting chapels, an endowed school with &#163;11 a year, and a bequest of &#163;2,000 for a divinity lecture. Markets are heldon Wednesdays and Saturdays; and fairs, on 6 and 27 Aug., 26 Sept., 14 Oct., and 3 Dec. The borough includes all R. parish and part of Dyffryngwy township. Pop. in 1851, 1,007; in 1861, 1,030. Houses, 214. The parish was disjoined from Nantmel in 1735. Acres, 1 88. Real property, &#163;1, 598. Pop., 846. Houses, 183. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of St. Davids. Value, &#163;75.* Patron, the Vicar of Nantmel.&#151;The sub-district contains also the parishes of Cwmtoyddwr, St. Harmon, Abbey-cwm-Hir, and Llanwrthwl, the last electorally in Brecon. Acres, 74,004. Pop., 3, 639. Houses, 679. The district comprehends also the sub-district of Nantmel, containing the parishes of Nantmel, Llanfihangel-Helygen, Llanyre, Cefnllys, and Llan-badarn-fawr. Acres of the district, 105, 532. Poor-rates in 1863, &#163;4,085. Pop. in 1851, 6, 796; in 1861, 6, 816. Houses, 1, 219. Marriages in 1863, 58; births, 231, of which 41 were illegitimate; deaths, 175, of which 69 were at ages under 5 years, and 6 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 410; births, 2, 279; deaths, 1, 213. The places of worship, in 1851, were 11 of the Church of England, with 2, 586 sittings; 5 of Independents, with 1, 390 s.; 8 of Baptists, with1, 538 s.; 5 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 272 s.; and 4of Calvinistic Methodists, with 537 s. The schools were 5 public day-schools, with 267 scholars; 6 private day-schools, with 177 s.; and 20 Sunday schools, with 1,002s. The hundred comprises six of the same parishes as the district. Acres, 67, 935. Pop., 4, 853. Houses, 884. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rhayader</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Rhayader</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/RAD/Rhaeadr/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639470</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10081221</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>RHAEADR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10113131</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>RHAEADR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10220518</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>RHAYADER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10297710</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RHAEADR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10547209</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RHAYADER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828068</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>RHAYADER</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
