<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8392</id>
<name>NEW RADNOR</name>
<container>RADNORSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2433384075653</lat>
<lon>-3.14981803607757</lon>
<gazetteerText>RADNOR (New), a town and a parish in Presteigne district, Radnorshire. The town stands on the river Somergill, under Radnor forest, 6&#189; miles W N W of Kington r. station, and 7 W S W of Presteigne; is known to the Welsh as Maes-Hyved, signifying the &quot;imbibingmeadow, &quot; and alluding to the occasional absorption of the Somergill river in the neighbouring soil; was once aplace of great importance, with a border castle; was theplace where Archbishop Baldwin and Giraldus Cambren-sis commenced their crusade-mission in 1188; continued to be of so much importance in the time of Henry VIII., as then to give its name to the newly constituted countyaround it; was, for some time, a seat of assizes and a market-town; fell so far into decay as to have its chiefbusiness, of every kind, transferred to Presteigne; is aborough by prescription, governed under charter of Elizabeth, by a bailiff, two aldermen, and other officers; uniteswith Presteigne, Rhayader, Knighton, Knuckles, and Cefnllys, in sending a member to parliament; gives the title of Earl to the family of Bouverie; is a seat of sessions and a polling-place; consists now chiefly of one irregularly-built street, with many dilapidated cottages; and has a head post-office, &#8225; an inn, a town hall, a smallborough jail, a memorial cross, a church, a dissentingchapel, an endowed school with &#163;15 a year, charities &#163;12, and fairs on 14 Aug. and 28 Oct. The castle was built by the Mortimers, occupied early by the Welsh, and demolished by King John; was re-built by the English, taken in 1231 by the Welsh, burnt in 1263 by Llewelyn ap Grufydd, and finally destroyed in 1401 by Owen Glendower; and is now represented only by amound. The memorial cross was erected in 1864, to thememory of Sir G.Lewis; has somewhat the form ofan Eleanor cross, but is more solid; and consists of threestages, rising from a stepped base, and crowned by aspire. The church stands on the side of a hill, was re-built by Dean Merewether, and has a tower. The borough includes the parishes of New Radnor and Llan-fihangel-nant-Mellan, and parts of the parishes of Old Radnor, Llandegley, and Cascob. Pop. in 1851, 2, 345; in 1861, 2, 262. Houses, 466. The parish includes part of the township of Upper Harpton, and comprises 3, 342acres. Real property, exclusive of the part of Upper Harpton, &#163;1, 769. Pop., exc. of that part, 463. Houses, 97. Pop. of the whole, 490. Houses, 100. The property is not much divided. Downton House is the seat of Sir E. Cockburn. A picturesque waterfall of 70 feet, called Water-break-its-neck, is about a mile from the town. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Hereford. Value, &#163;304.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Radnor</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/RAD/NewRadnor/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641584</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10220543</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>NEW RADNOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10288071</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NEW RADNOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10491873</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>RADNOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10548664</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RADNOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12783139</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>RADNOR</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
