<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10543</id>
<name>WROXETER</name>
<container>SHROPSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6712959770678</lat>
<lon>-2.61789693733996</lon>
<gazetteerText>WROXETER, a village and a parish in Atcham district, Salop. The village stands on Watling-street and on the river Severn, 2&#190; miles SSE of Upton-Magna r. station, 3&#190; W of the Wrekin, and 5&#190; SE by E of Shrewsbury; was known to the ancient British as Caer-Vrauch, -to the Romans as Uriconium, to the Saxons as Wrecinceastre; has most interesting remains of a Roman town, once 3 miles in circuit, and defended by a rampart 9 feet thick; has yielded great numbers and great variety of interesting Roman relics; is believed to possess rich wealth of other Roman relics underground, and capable of recovery by excavation; was, for a considerable time, the capital of the Cornavii; suffered devastation by the Saxons and the Danes; forms the subject of many learned papers in various periodicals, and of a recent work entitled &quot;A Guide to Uriconium;&apos;&apos; and has a post-office under Shrewsbury. The parish includes five townships, and comprises 4,774 acres. Real property, &#163;5,670. Pop., 616. Houses, 120. The manor belongs to the Duke of Cleveland; and much of the property to Lord Berwick. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;330.* Patron, the Duke of Cleveland. The church is good; and there are an endowed grammar-school with &#163;50 a year, and charities &#163;7. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Wroxeter/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wroxeter</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633473</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10367890</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WROXETER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10367906</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WROXETER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10515</id>
   <name>UPPINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
