<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4451</id>
<name>ALBERBURY</name>
<container>SHROPSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7135660327334</lat>
<lon>-2.93172630567741</lon>
<gazetteerText>ALBERBURY, or Abberbury, a township and a subdistrict in the district of Atcham, Salop: and a parish, partly in the same district and county, and partly in the district and county of Montgomery. The township lies on Watling-street, near the Severn, 4 miles SW of Bas church r. station, and 9 W by N of Shrewsbury; and has a post office under Shrewsbury. Acres, with Wollaston chapelry, 6,471. Pop., exclusive of Wollaston, 632. Houses, 110. The township is called Alberbury Lower Quarter; and the chapelry is called Alberbury Upper Quarter. Loton Hall, the seat of Sir Baldwin Leighton, Bart., is adjacent. A priory for black monks was founded at Alberbury by Fitzwarren, in the time of Henry I., and was given by Henry VI. to All Souls&apos; College, Oxford. The subdistrict of Alberbury comprises two parishes and part of a third. Acres, 12,034. Pop., 2,235. Houses, 446. The parish of Alberbury comprises the two Alberbury Quarters in Salop, and the townships of Banseley, Middletown, and Uppington, and the chapelry of Criggion in Montgomery. Acres, 9,599. Real property, &#163;8,429. Pop., 1,918. Houses, 360. The property is subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Hereford. Value, &#163;187.* Patron, All Souls&apos; College, Oxford. The church is ancient. The vicarages of Wollaston and Criggion are separate benefices. Charities, &#163;17. Glyn, a hamlet in this parish, was the birthplace of old Parr. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alberbury</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Alberbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/wal/MGY/Alberbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657572</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10060308</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>ALBERBURY LOWER QUARTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10064211</id>
   <status>AP/Tn</status>
   <name>ALBERBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10150607</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>ALBERBURY WITH CARDESTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10151340</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ALBERBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10559182</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ALBERBURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
