<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7585</id>
<name>PAKEFIELD</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4464491613411</lat>
<lon>1.72762044944822</lon>
<gazetteerText>PAKEFIELD, a village and a parish in Mutford district, Suffolk. The village stands on the coast, 2 miles S S W of Lowestoft r. station; and has a post-office under Lowestoft. The parish comprises 686 acres of land and 85 of water. Real property, &#163;2,056. Pop., 768. Houses, 182. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to H. Reeve, Esq. The coast is very dangerous, and has suffered considerable encroachment by the sea. A life-boat establishment is here; and a lighthouse was erected in 1832, showing a fixed light 68 feet high, and visible at the distance of 9 miles. Bloodmere hill is said to have been the scene of a battle with the Danes; iscrowned with a barrow; and, in 1780, yielded a number of pieces of ancient armour. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;186.* Patron, the Church Patronage Society. The church is ancient but good; comprises two quondam churches, forming adouble aisle; has a thatched roof and an embattled tower; and contains an octagonal font, a silver chalice of 1337, and two brasses of 1417 and 1451. There are a Quakers&apos;chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;31. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Pakefield/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640675</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10265745</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PAKEFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10265770</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PAKEFIELD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7229</id>
   <name>GISLEHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
