<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7498</id>
<name>MENDLESHAM</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.2407825767199</lat>
<lon>1.07646353580639</lon>
<gazetteerText>MENDLESHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Hartismere district, Suffolk. The village stands on clay soil, 3&#189; miles SE of Finningham r. station, and 5 NW by W of Debenham; consists of two streets, indifferently built; was once a market-town; and has a post office under Stoneham, a police station, and a fair on 2 O ct. The parish contains also the hamlet of Mendlesham-Green, distant about 1&#189; mile from the village. Acres, 3,944. Real property, &#163;7,513. Pop. in 1851, 1,442; in 1861,1,316. Houses, 293. The property is snbdivided. The manor belongs to Tyrell, Esq. A silver crown, weighing 60 ounces, and supposed to have belonged to a king of East Anglia, was exhumed about the end of the 17th century. A runic gold ring also was found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, 1584.* Patron, E. White, Esq. The church was given by William Rufus to Battle abbey; includes some Norman arches; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with lofty tower; and was restored in 1864-6. There are chapels for Independents and Baptists, a national school, an endowed grammar school with &#163;40 a year, and charities &#163;290.&#151;The sub-district contains also ten other parishes. Acres, 20,092. Pop., 5,830. Houses, 1,271. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Mendlesham/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642750</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10263300</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MENDLESHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10263311</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MENDLESHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541773</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MENDLESHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17457</id>
   <name>SUFFOLK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
