<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5118</id>
<name>GORLESTON</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.5812414744712</lat>
<lon>1.72054267151913</lon>
<gazetteerText>GORLESTON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Mutford district, Suffolk. The village stands near the mouth of the river Yare, adjacent to South-Town or Little Yarmouth, 2 miles S of Great Yarmouth town and r. station; is large and handsome; crowns two acclivities, Prospect-hill and Battery-hill, commanding a fine view over the Yare, the Denes, Yarmouth, and the German ocean; and has a post office under Yarmouth. The parish includes also South-Town or Little Yarmouth; and comprises 2, 135 acres of land, and 40 of water. Real property, &#163;16, 630. Pop. in 1851, 3, 999; in 1861, 4, 472. Houses, 973. The increase of pop. arose from proximity to Yarmouth, and from the immigration of many fishermen from Barking. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage, united with the rectories of South-Town and West-Town, in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;381 . Patron, Henry Allnutt, Esq. The church is later English and commodious. St. Mary&apos;s chapel, in South-Town, is a separate charge. There are three dissenting chapels, a working men&apos;s institute, and a large national school. Remains exist of an Augnstinian priory, founded, in the time of Edward I., by W. Wodegrove, and given at the dissolution, to John Eyer. Captain Manby was a resident.&#151;The sub-district contains also five other parishes. Acres, 10, 942. Pop., 6, 339. Houses, 1, 351. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gorleston</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Gorleston/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10102790</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GORLESTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10179944</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GORLESTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10504235</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>GORLESTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541293</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>GORLESTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7052</id>
   <name>BRADWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
