<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9308</id>
<name>HORRINGER</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.2243371969141</lat>
<lon>0.683721183220123</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORNINGSHEATH, or HORRINGER, a village and a parish in Thingoe district, Suffolk. The village stands 2 miles SW of Bury-ST. Edmunds r. station; and has a post office, of the name of Horringer, under Bury-ST. Edmunds, and a fair on 4 Sept.&#151;The parish includes also the hamlet of Horsecroft, and comprises 2, 200 acres. Real property, &#163;4, 103. Pop., 670. Houses, 136. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged formerly to Bury abbey, and belongs now to the Marquis of Bristol. Horringer House was once the seat of the Bury abbots, and is now the seat of W. M. Winch, Esq. Brooke House is the residence of General Sir James Simpson; Hopleys, of J. F. Dove, Esq.; and Horscroft, of W. B. Wigson, Esq. The parish, prior to 1528, formed two parishes, called Great H. and Little H. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Ely; and was united in 1868 with Ickworth. Value, &#163;750.* Patron, the Marquis of Bristol. The church is decorated English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with porch and tower; and was repaired in 1818. There are an endowed school with &#163;9 a year, and other charities with &#163;15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/6620336</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Horningsheath/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10257761</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GREAT AND LITTLE HORNINGSHEATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10257773</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HORRINGER CUM ICKWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10263633</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>GREAT HORNINGSHEATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10263645</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GREAT HORNINGSHEATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10263669</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LITTLE HORNINGSHEATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10263670</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LITTLE HORNINGSHEATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318956</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HORRINGER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318981</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>GREAT AND LITTLE HORNINGSHEATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575308</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HORNINGSHEATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575333</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HORRINGER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7305</id>
   <name>ICKWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
