<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>153</id>
<name>BECCLES</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4577397725807</lat>
<lon>1.57466474246295</lon>
<gazetteerText>BECCLES, a town, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Wangford district, Suffolk. The town stands on the river Waveney, and on the Eastern Counties railway, amid pleasant environs, 8&#189; miles W of Lowestoft. It belonged anciently to Bury Abbey; and suffered severely, in 1586, from fire. It is now well-built; and comprises several streets, which diverge from a spacious market-place. The town hall was built in 1839, and is used as a courthouse. The corn exchange was formerly the theatre. The assembly-room is a handsome building, with a public library attached. The house of correction is a substantial and commodious structure; but is now used only as a police station. The parish church is later English; consists of nave, chancel, and aisles, altogether 148 feet long and 61&#189; feet wide; was renovated in 1859; and has a tower, 92 feet high, built about 1515, detached a short distance from the SE corner, and commanding a fine view of the surrounding country. Another church, or a chapel, connected with an hospital for lepers founded in the time of Edward III., stood at Endgate. A new cemetery has been formed, comprising 5 acres, beautifully laid out, and containing two chapels. The town has chapels for Independents, baptists, and Methodists, a free grammar school with income of &#163;184, another free school with &#163;197, further charities with &#163;290, a head post office,&#8225; a railway station, two banking offices, and two chief inns. A weekly market is held on Friday; and a fair also is held on Whit-Monday. The Waveney is navigable hence to the sea, making Beccles a sub-port to Yarmouth; a good coal, corn, and malt trade is carried on; and a weekly newspaper is published. The town was incorporated by Queen Elizabeth; is governed by a mayor, four aldermen, and twelve councilors; possesses a common of about 900 acres; and has a corporate income of about &#163;2,200; and is a polling-place for East Suffolk. The parish is co-terminate with the borough. Acres, 1,892. Real property, &#163;16,381. Pop., 4,266. Houses, 984. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;370. Patron, the Rev. E. Holland. The subdistrict comprises thirteen parishes. Acres, 18,181. Pop., 7,221. Houses, 1,558. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656067</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Beccles/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beccles</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10025552</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>BECCLES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10028050</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BECCLES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10140377</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>BECCLES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10250316</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BECCLES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10250328</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BECCLES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541712</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BECCLES</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>337</id>
   <name>HALESWORTH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>437</id>
   <name>BUNGAY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>482</id>
   <name>SOUTHWOLD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2639</id>
   <name>DITCHINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3421</id>
   <name>LODDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7041</id>
   <name>BLYTHBURGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7626</id>
   <name>REYDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7859</id>
   <name>WENHASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7978</id>
   <name>WORLINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8133</id>
   <name>WRENTHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
