<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7650</id>
<name>RUSHMERE ST ANDREW</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.0623976459259</lat>
<lon>1.21201634358826</lon>
<gazetteerText>RUSHMERE, a village and a parish in Woodbridge district, Suffolk. The village stands 1&#190; mile E S E of Westerfield r. station, and 2&#189; E by N of Ipswich; and has a post-office under Ipswich. The parish includes part of Ipswich borough, and comprises 2, 142 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 599. Pop., 678. Houses, 141. Pop.of the part in I. borough, 240. Houses, 54. The manor belongs to the Marquis of Bristol. Limes and Pineloftare chief residences. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;180.* Patron, the Marquis of Bristol. The church was rebuilt in 1861, at a cost of &#163;1, 500. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7670891</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10267249</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RUSHMERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10267262</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RUSHMERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10267274</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>RUSHMERE ST ANDREW</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7114</id>
   <name>CULPHO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7607</id>
   <name>PURDIS FARM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7834</id>
   <name>TUDDENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>7648</id>
<name>RUSHMERE</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4297360403722</lat>
<lon>1.67500791450026</lon>
<gazetteerText>RUSHMERE, a parish in Mutford district, Suffolk; 2&#189; miles S S W of Carlton-Colville r. station, and 5 S W of Lowestoft. Post-town, Wangford. Acres, 759. Real property, &#163;1, 602. Pop., 121. Houses, 29. The property is divided among a few. There are sand pits. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;212.* Patrons, Lord Boston and F. W. Irby, Esq. The church is old but good. There is a parochial school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Rushmere/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638944</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10267213</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RUSHMERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10267237</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RUSHMERE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
