<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>910</id>
<name>OULTON BROAD</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4732369372909</lat>
<lon>1.71305046312421</lon>
<gazetteerText>OULTON, a hamlet and a parish in Mutford district, Suffolk. The hamlet lies near Lothing lake, the river Waveney, the Norwich and Lowestoft railway, and the boundary with Norfolk, 1 mile E S E of Mutford-Bridge r. station, and 2&#189; W of Lowestoft; and bears the name of Oulton-Street. The parish contains also the hamlet of Mutford-Bridge, and comprises 1, 997 acres. Post-town, Lowestoft. Real property, &#163;4, 430; of which &#163;65 are in the Lowestoft and Norwich navigation. Pop., 747. Houses, 148. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to Dudley Oliver, Esq. Oulton High House was built in 1550, by the Hobarts; retains a fine mantel-piece and some curious carved work of the 16th century; was long known as the &quot;haunted house; &quot; served for some time as a school-house; and is now the residence of Mrs. Caldecott. G. Borrow, the historian of the gipsies, has considerable property in the parish. The Mutfordworkhouse is here; and, at the census of 1861, had 117inmates. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Norwich. Value, &#163;462.* Patron, Sir S. M. Peto, Bart &apos; The church was originally cruciform; b as a chancel and a Ntransept of the time of Edward I., and a central tower with a base tier resembling Norman work; includes a nave and a S porch; and contains a carved octagonal font, and remains of ancient stained glass; and the chancel was restored in 1862. There is a parochial school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oulton_Broad</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Oulton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640829</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10169392</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>OULTON BROAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10265587</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>OULTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10265605</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OULTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10265617</id>
   <status>CP/ExP</status>
   <name>OULTON BROAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10265680</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OULTON BROAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10541621</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>OULTON BROAD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7079</id>
   <name>CARLTON COLVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
