<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7436</id>
<name>LAKENHEATH</name>
<container>SUFFOLK</container>
<lat>52.4175020895065</lat>
<lon>0.508818938158131</lon>
<gazetteerText>LAKENHEATH, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Mildenhall district, Suffolk. The village stands on a gentle eminence, amid a great extent of rabbit warren, 2 miles S of the Ely and Brandon railway, and of the Little Ouse river at the boundary with Norfolk, and 5&#189; SW of Brandon; commands an extensive view of the surrounding country; was formerly a market-town; and has a post-office,&#8225; under Brandon, a station on the railway, about 3 miles distant, a good inn, and a fair on the Thursday after Midsummer day.&#151;The parish includes also the hamlet of Undley. Acres, 10,550. Real property, &#163;10,514. Pop. in 1851,1,864; in 1861,1,797. Houses, 394. The chief landowners are the executors of W. G. Eagle, Esq. Nearly 3,000 acres, chiefly in the E, are open rabbit warren; and a large tract in the W is fen. There are sand pits and clay pits. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Ely. Value, &#163;136. Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Ely. The church is ancient; has Norman features; was partly repaired in 1863; and comprises nave, aisles, and chancel, with massive tower about 80 feet high. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, and Wesleyans; two free schools for boys, with &#163;40 and &#163;16 a-year; and charities &#163;95.&#151;The sub-district contains also four other parishes, and considerable part of Mildenhall parish. Pop., 5,890. Houses, 1,248. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SFK/Lakenheath/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lakenheath</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645020</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10261820</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LAKENHEATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10261946</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LAKENHEATH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10563173</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LAKENHEATH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1706</id>
   <name>METHWOLD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2261</id>
   <name>FELTWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2914</id>
   <name>NORTHWOLD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3119</id>
   <name>HOCKWOLD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3341</id>
   <name>CALDECOTE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5854</id>
   <name>OXBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7058</id>
   <name>BRANDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7846</id>
   <name>WANGFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
