<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12927</id>
<name>EAST HARPTREE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2883688582743</lat>
<lon>-2.62742287564994</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARPTREE (EAST), a village and a parish in Clutton district, Somerset. The village stands near the source of the river Yeo, under the Mendip hills, 6&#189; miles N of Wells r. station; and has a post-office&#8225; under Bristol. The parish includes also the hamlet of Coley, and comprises 2,770 acres. Real property, &#163;4,305; of which &#163;200 are in mines. Pop., 657. Houses, 154. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Countess Waldegrave. Harptree Court, long the seat of the Waldegraves, is a pleasant mansion. The Lamb cavern is in mountain limestone W of the village; and the source of the Yeo is a copious stream gushing from the rock further W. The rocks include manganese and zinc; and the subsoil consists largely of a kind of breccia. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;106.* Patron, the Bishop of Bath and Wells. The church is ancient but good; consists of nave, aisle, and chancel, with a tower; and contains a figured altar-tomb of Sir John Newton, who died in 1568. There are a Wesleyan chapel, an endowed school with &#163;13, and other charities with &#163;77. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/EastHarptree/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Harptree</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650422</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10433710</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EAST HARPTREE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10433733</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EAST HARPTREE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
