<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13143</id>
<name>NORTH PETHERTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0829601196056</lat>
<lon>-3.0011368620702</lon>
<gazetteerText>PETHERTON (North), a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Somerset. The village stands1&#189; mile W of the Taunton canal, and 2&#189; S by W of Bridgewater r. station; consists of a main street, and a few smaller streets; is a seat of petty sessions; and has a post-office under Bridgewater, and fairs on 1 May and Monday before 13 Nov. The parish includes the chapelry of North Newton, the tythings of Petherton-Limit, Town-Denison, Buckland-Fee, and Woolmersdon, and the hamlets of Huntworth, West Newton, Shearston, Tuckerton, Moorland, and Bankland; extends eastwardbeyond the river Parret; and is in Bridgewater district. Acres, 10, 336. Real property, &#163;20, 506. Pop. in 1851, 3, 845; in 1861, 3, 943. Houses, 825. The property is much subdivided. The manor, with Maunsel Grange, belongs to Sir A. F. A. Slade, Bart. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;900.* Patron, the Rev. J. W. Robinson. The church is fine later English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with two porches and a lofty tower; and has a pulpitresting on the shoulders of a human figure carved instone. The p. curacies of North Newton and North-moor-Green are separate benefices. There are national schools, a British school, a school endowment of &#163;46a year, and charities &#163;9. The sub-district excludesthe small section of the parish beyond the Parret; and includes all the rest of the parish, and five other parishes. Pop., 5, 305. Houses, 1,080. The hundredcontains eight parishes, and part of another. Acres, 31, 533. Pop. in 1851, 7, 302; in 1861, 7, 663. Houses, 1, 563. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/NorthPetherton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Petherton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641284</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18631</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18688</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18689</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18684</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18686</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18687</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18691</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18692</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18685</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18690</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10097710</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>NORTH PETHERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439280</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>NORTH PETHERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439292</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTH PETHERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549917</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NORTH PETHERTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12809</id>
   <name>DURSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12877</id>
   <name>GOATHURST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13170</id>
   <name>ST MICHAELCHURCH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13344</id>
   <name>THURLOXTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
