<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13410</id>
<name>WINCANTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0459869456241</lat>
<lon>-2.39325511602218</lon>
<gazetteerText>WINCANTON, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Somerset. The town stands on the river Cale, and on the Dorset and Somerset railway, 5 miles SSE of Bruton; was known to the Saxons as Wyndcaleton; suffered great devastation by the plague in 1553; was the scene of a skirmish between the troops of the Prince of Orange and some dragoons of James II. in 1688; contains a house in which the Prince of Orange slept after the skirmish; is a seat of petty sessions and county courts, and a polling place; occupies steep ground at the head of the broad vale of Blackmoor; and has a post-office&#8225; under Bath, a r. station with telegraph, two banking offices, two chief inns, a police station, a town hall, a reading room, a good church, Independent and Baptist chapels, a national school, a workhouse, charities &#163;6, a brewery, a weekly market on Wednesday, and fairs on Easter Tuesday and 29th Sept.&#151;The parish comprises 4130 acres. Real property, &#163;15,150. Pop., 2,450. Houses, 476. The manor was given, at the Norman Conquest, to W. de Douay; and passed to the Lovells, the Zouches, the Seymours, and the Daubenys. Marsh Court was the manor house, and is now occupied by a farmer. A priory was founded at Stavordale, by R. Lovell, in 1263; and has left some interesting remains, now incorporated with a farm stead. Mineral springs, similar to those of Cheltenham, are at Horwood. The site of an ancient British fort, called Kennewilkins Castle, is in the middle of a wood. Roman coins have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;130. Patrons, Messrs. G. and J. Messiter.&#151;The sub-district contains 12 parishes. Acres, 19,646. Pop., 6,007. Houses, 1,304.&#151;The district comprehends also Bruton, Milborne-Port, and Castle-Cary sub-districts; and comprises 66,120 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;11,320. Pop. in 1851, 21,311; in 1861, 21,500. Houses, 4,588. Marriages in 1866, 153; births, 629,-of which 43 were illegitimate; deaths, 399,-of which 118 were at ages under 5 years, and 10 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-61, 1,460; births, 6,613; deaths, 4,309. The places of worship, in 1851, were 41 of the Church of England, with 9,498 sittings; 10 of Independents, with 2,406 s.; 3 of Baptists, with 650 s.; 1 of Quakers, with 50 s.; 14 of Wesleyans, with 1.633 s.; 2 of Primitive Methodists, with 285 s.; 1 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 8 s.; 1 of Bible Christians, with 70 s.; and 1 of Latter Day Saints, with 300 s. The schools were 28 public day-schools, with 1,595 scholars; 48 private day-schools, with 852 s.; 46 Sunday schools, with 3,114 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 37 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Wincanton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wincanton</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Wincanton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633861</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18755</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10055702</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>WINCANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10187011</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WINCANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10202474</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WINCANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446533</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WINCANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446545</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WINCANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549851</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WINCANTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12467</id>
   <name>BRATTON SEYMOUR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12557</id>
   <name>NORTH CHERITON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12963</id>
   <name>HOLTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12965</id>
   <name>HORSINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13092</id>
   <name>MAPERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13549</id>
   <name>BUCKHORN WESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13679</id>
   <name>KINGTON MAGNA</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13940</id>
   <name>WEST STOUR</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
