<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13119</id>
<name>NORTON ST PHILIP</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3054556789355</lat>
<lon>-2.31599126818226</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTON-ST. PHILIP, a village and a parish in Frome district, Somerset. The village stands 2&#189; miles W of the boundary with Wilts, 4 S S W of Freshford r.station, and 6 S by E of Bath; contains an old inn, a very curious building of the 15th century; and has a post-office under Bath. The parish comprises 1, 527acres. Real property, &#163;3, 500. Pop. in 1851, 788; in 1861, 672. Houses, 168. The decrease of pop. arose mainly from the removal of coal carriers, consequent upon the opening of the railway . The property is much subdivided. Norton House is the residence of Mrs. Gutch. The skirmish between the army of the Duke of Monmouth and the King&apos;s troops under Feversham, resulting in the repulse which drove Monmouth to the fatal field of Sedgemoor, took place near the village. There are several malting-houses, a brewery, and a corn mill. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;110.* Patron, the Bishop of Bath and Wells. The church is later English; was restored in 1847; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with porch and loftytower. There are Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, an endowed school with &#163;50 a year, and charities &#163;25. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/NortonStPhilip/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norton_St_Philip</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10438652</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NORTON ST PHILIP</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438664</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTON ST PHILIP</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
