<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12674</id>
<name>CONGRESBURY</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3655141663701</lat>
<lon>-2.81320729728327</lon>
<gazetteerText>CONGRESBURY, a village and a parish in Axbridge district, Somerset. The village stands on the river Yeo, 2 miles S by E of Yatton r. station, and 6&#189; N of Axbridge: has a post office, of the name of Congresbury, Somerset; was once a market-town; and still has a fair on 14 Sep. A college is said to have been founded at it, in 711, by St. Congar, an Eastern prince; and an interesting ancient market cross is still here, on five flights of steps. The parish comprises 4, 443 acres. Real property, &#163;12, 203. Pop., 1, 190. Houses, 267. The property is much subdivided. Part of the land is marshy. The living is a vicarage, united with St. Lawrence-Wick, in-the dio. of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;800.* Patron, R. Hunt, Esq. The church is later English. The vicarage of St. Ann is a separate benefice; and the church of it was built in 1865. There are two dissenting chapels, a national school, and charities &#163;14. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Congresbury</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Congresbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652463</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10426935</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CONGRESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10426947</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CONGRESBURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24111</id>
<name>HEWISH</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3740740451296</lat>
<lon>-2.86354812560347</lon>
<gazetteerText>HEWISH, a hamlet in Yatton parish, Somerset; near the river Yeo, 61/2. miles N of Axbridge. Pop., 67. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10426996</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CONGRESBURY ST ANN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10434531</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HEWISH ST ANN AND WICK ST LAWRENCE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
