<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>700</id>
<name>CREWKERNE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.8836357775077</lat>
<lon>-2.79290163195999</lon>
<gazetteerText>CREWKERNE, a town, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred in Somerset. The town stands in the valley of the river Parret, on the Yeovil and Exeter railway, surrounded by a wide amphitheatre of hills, 2&#188; miles N of the boundary with Dorset, and 8&#189; SW by W of Yeovil. It dates from ancient times; was known to the Saxons as Crocern or Cruaern; is now a busy place; publishes a weekly newspaper; and has a head post office, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, a banking office, two chief inns, a market-house, two churches, four dissenting chapels, a free grammar school, another endowed school, two alms-houses, and other charities with a total of &#163;524. One of the churches succeeded a previous edifice, given by the Conqueror to Caen abbey; and is itself a beautiful cruciform structure of the 15th century, in perpendicular English, with richly-carved doors and windows, and with a lofty central tower, surmounted by turrets. The other church was built in 1853; is also in the English perpendicular style; and consists of nave, north aisle, chancel, and bell-turret. The grammar school was founded in 1499; has an endowed income of &#163;320, with four exhibitions; and had for a pupil Mr. Justice Best, afterwards Lord Wyndford. Markets are held on Saturdays; and a fair on 4 Sept. Manufactures of sail-cloth, webbing, and girths are carried on. The father of Tom Paine, author of the &quot;Rights of Man, &quot; was a native. Pop., 3, 566. Houses, 725. -The parish includes also the tythings of Clapton, Coombe, Easthams, Furland, Hewish, Woolminstone, Laymore, Horn, Ash, Greenham, and part of Black Down. Acres, 5, 331. Real property, &#163;22, 025. Pop., 4, 705. Houses, 942. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged, at Domesday, to the Crown; and passed, through the Redvers, the Courtenays, and others, to the Pouletts. Wulfric, the anchorite, who was visited by Henry I. and Stephen, lived in a cell at Hasilborough; and St. Ranns was buried in a chapel on Ranna-hill. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Christ Church, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;300.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Winchester. -The sub-district contains eight parishes; and is in the district of Chard. Acres, 13, 103-Pop., 8, 084. Houses, 1, 659. -The hundred contains six parishes. Acres, 12, 140. Pop., 7, 781. Houses, 1, 580. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Crewkerne/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crewkerne</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652000</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10134080</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>CREWKERNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135280</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CREWKERNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427654</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CREWKERNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427680</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CREWKERNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427691</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WEST CREWKERNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549498</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CREWKERNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10572162</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CREWKERNE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12932</id>
   <name>HASLEBURY PLUCKNETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12959</id>
   <name>HINTON ST GEORGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13100</id>
   <name>MERRIOTT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13105</id>
   <name>MISTERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13142</id>
   <name>NORTH PERROT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13206</id>
   <name>SEABOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13370</id>
   <name>WAYFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13747</id>
   <name>MOSTERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13786</id>
   <name>SOUTH PERROT</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
