<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>277</id>
<name>BURNHAM</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2415462314555</lat>
<lon>-2.99467970130557</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURNHAM, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict in the district of Axbridge, Somerset. The village stands on the coast, at the mouth of the rivers Brue and Parret, at the terminus of a short branch railway, in connection with the central Somerset and the Bristol and Exeter railways, 2 miles NW of the Highbridge Junction, and 9 SW by W of Axbridge. It has a post office&#8225; under Bridgewater, and an hotel; and is frequented as a watering-place. The beach at it is a fine sand; but is left bare, to the breadth of 4 miles, at low water. A project was authorized in August 1860 for constructing a tidal harbour in connection with the branch railway, with the view of traffic by steam-vessels, to the various ports of the Bristol Channel and of South Wales. There is a large monthly market. Two mineral springs, severally saline and sulphurous, are close to the beach; and the two lights, for guiding vessels into the river Parret, 91 and 23 feet high, 1,500 feet asunder, the higher one intermitting, the lower one fixed, are in the neighbourhood. The parish includes also the tything of Huish-juxta-Highbridge, the hamlets of Edithmead and Highbridge, and part of the tything of Aston-Morris. Acres, 4,302; of which 430 are water. Real property, &#163;16,557. Pop., 2,252. Houses, 473. The property is much divided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;559.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Wells. The church is an ancient building, 140 feet in length, with a lofty tower, serving as a landmark; was recently well restored; and contains a magnificent altar piece designed by Inigo Jones. The vicarage of Highbridge is a separate benefice. There are a national school and charities &#163;72. Bishop King was vicar.-The subdistrict contains seven parishes. Acres, 25,256. Pop., 5,707. Houses, 1,233. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burnham-on-Sea</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/BurnhamOnSea/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7290758</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10042010</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10137561</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186274</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BURNHAM ON SEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10422759</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10422760</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BURNHAM ON SEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10422772</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BURNHAM ON SEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10422784</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BURNHAM WITHOUT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549711</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570748</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BURNHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>259</id>
   <name>HIGHBRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12458</id>
   <name>BERROW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12461</id>
   <name>BIDDISHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12469</id>
   <name>EAST BRENT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12470</id>
   <name>BRENT KNOLL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13090</id>
   <name>LYMPSHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13093</id>
   <name>MARK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13135</id>
   <name>OTTERHAMPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13246</id>
   <name>STOGURSEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13371</id>
   <name>WEARE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
