<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12411</id>
<name>BATHEASTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.4156152714476</lat>
<lon>-2.32523664525723</lon>
<gazetteerText>BATHEASTON, a parish and a subdistrict in Bath district, Somerset. The parish lies on the river Avon, near the Foss&amp; way, 1 &#189; mile N by E of Bathampton r. station, and 2 &#189; NE of Bath. It has a ferry to Bathampton, and a post office under Bath. Acres, 1,863. Real property, &#163;11,106. Pop., 1,698. Houses, 353. The property is much subdivided. Lines of houses and numerous villas make the south-western part suburban to Bath. The manor belonged to the Saxon kings, and the church was early appropriated to Bath abbey. Solsbury hill, 600 feet high has traces of a circular camp sup posed to have been used by the Saxons in their siege of Bath. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of St. Catherine, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;298.* Patron, Christ Church college, Oxford. The church is perpendicular English; was partly rebuilt in 1860; and contains a tablet to the Rev. J. Conybeare, the Anglo-Saxon scholar, who was several years vicar. There are a church at St. Catherines, Wesleyan and Moravian chapels, a national school, and charities &#163;35.-The subdistrict comprises Soper&apos;s farm and eight parishes. Acres, exclusive of Soper&apos;s farm, 9,819. Pop., 6,989. Houses, 1,374. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656171</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Batheaston</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Batheaston/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10420283</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BATHEASTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10420313</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BATHEASTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549474</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BATHEASTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13169</id>
   <name>ST CATHERINE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13291</id>
   <name>SWAINSWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13424</id>
   <name>WOOLLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
