<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12831</id>
<name>EVERCREECH</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1515413366024</lat>
<lon>-2.49931653112781</lon>
<gazetteerText>EVERCREECH, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Shepton-Mallet district, Somerset. The village stands adjacent to the Somerset and Dorset railway, near the Fosse way, 3&#190; miles SE by S of Shepton-Mallet; and has a station on the railway, and a post office&#8225; under Bath. The parish includes also the chapelry of Chester-blade, and the hamlets of Bagbury, Southwood, and Stoney-Stratton. Acres, 4, 078. Real property, &#163;9, 760. Pop., 1, 321. Houses, 304. The property is much sub-divided. Silk-weaving is carried on, but has undergone such decline as to cause considerable decrease of the population. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Chesterblade, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;226.* Patron, the Dowager Lady Talbot de Malahide. The church is good, and has a tower which figures finely in the landscape. There are a Methodist chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;60. -The sub-district contains also nine other parishes. Acres, 21, 233. Pop., 5, 141. Houses, 1, 166. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evercreech</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649842</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Evercreech/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10431104</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EVERCREECH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10431165</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EVERCREECH WITH CHESTERBLADE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549991</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>EVERCREECH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
