<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12463</id>
<name>BLACKFORD</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0336049637954</lat>
<lon>-2.48834040793109</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLACKFORD, a parish in Wincanton district, Somerset; 4&#189; miles WS W of Wincanton r. station, and 5 N by W of Milborne-Port. Post Town, North Cadbury, under Bath. Acres, 578. Real property, with Compton and Pauncefoot, &#163;2,839. Pop., 164. Houses, 37. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;177.* Patron, B. H. Hunt, Esq. The church is early English, with a fine Norman entrance-arch. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blackford</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Blackford/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18759</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10421561</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>BLACKFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10421573</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLACKFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24416</id>
<name>BLACKFORD</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2249146306857</lat>
<lon>-2.84643150645256</lon>
<gazetteerText>BLACKFORD, a chapelry in Wedmore parish, Somerset; between the rivers Axe and Brue, 2&#190; miles N by E of Edington Road r. station, and 4&#189; S of Axbridge. It has a post office under Weston-super-Mare. Pop., 677. Houses, 147. The chapelry was constituted in 1844 The manor belonged to H. Saxey, and was given by him to Bruton hospital. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Vicar of Wedmore. The church is modern. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/3345372</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10421585</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BLACKFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
