<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12502</id>
<name>BURRINGTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.324832055879</lat>
<lon>-2.74927380059624</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURRINGTON, a village and a parish in Axbridge district, Somerset. The village stands amid romantic scenery, at the northern skirt of the highest part of the Mendip hills, 5 miles NE by N of Axbridge, and 5&#189; SE of Yatton r. station; and has a post office, of the name of Burrington, Somerset. The parish comprises 2,009 acres. Real property, &#163;2,455. Pop., 477. Houses, 106. The property is divided among a few. A romantic rocky hollow leads from the village up the Mendips; and is flanked by ribbed masses of mountain limestone. A descending cavern, at the side of this, about a &#188; of a mile from the village, was discovered in 1795 to contain about fifty human skeletons, supposed to have been entombed here by the ancient Britons; and discovered afterwards to contain bones of horses, sheep, and other animals, supposed to have taken refuge in it after it ceased to be a place of sepulture. An earthwork, called Burrington Ham, occurs on a hill further up; and is Thought to have been a scene of Druidical rites. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;147.* Patrons, the Inhabitants. The church is later English, and was restored in 1856. There are a national school and charities &#163;18. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burrington,_Somerset</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Burrington/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654234</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10422796</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>BURRINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10422802</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BURRINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
