<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>14540</id>
<name>RODE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2826325107267</lat>
<lon>-2.27151929498522</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROAD, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Frome district, Somerset. The village stands on the river Frome, at the boundary with Wilts, 4 miles N N E of Frome r. station; extends, beyond the boundary, into Wilts; was once a market-town; and has a post-office under Bath, a temperance hall, a mechanics&apos; institute, and a large cheese fair on the Monday after 9 Sept. The parish comprises 928 acres. Rated property, &#163;2, 446. Pop., 663. Houses, 171. The property is much sub-divided. The manor belongs to Mrs. Jones. Merfield House is the seat of H. B. Pooll, Esq. Extensive woollendye-works are at Shawford. The-living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Woolverton, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;650.* Patron, J. B. Starky, Esq. The church was built about the beginning of the15th century; and has a tower, with a railed battlementin one corner, called the King&apos;s Chair, and traditionallysaid to have been mounted by Charles II. for reconnoitering after the battle of Worcester. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, and a national school.&#151;The sub-district contains also ten other parishes and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 11, 348. Pop., 3, 573. Houses, 838. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Rode/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rode</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639240</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10439826</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RODE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439838</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RODE MAJOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10480218</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>RODE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549528</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ROAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
