<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13097</id>
<name>MARTOCK</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.978652266648</lat>
<lon>-2.76992772013799</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARTOCK, a village, a parish, a hundred, and a subdistrict, in Yeovil district, Somerset. The village stands near the river Parret and on the Fosse way, adjacent to the Durston and Yeovil branch of the Bristol and Exeter railway, 6&#189; miles NW by W of Yeovil; was once a market town; and has a station with telegraph on the railway, a head post office&#8225;, two good inns, a market-cross, a church, two dissenting chapels, a national school, a grammar school founded in 1661, and charities &#163;20. The market-cross consists of base and steps of old date, and a surmounting fluted column of newer date, bearing a sun-dial, a gilt ball, and a vane. The church is later English, of fine character; comprises nave, aisles, transepts, and chancel, with a tower; has a roof of open wood-work; and was recently restored. Pinnacled archways, of the year 1627, gave entrance to the churchyard. The manor-house, an edifice of the 14th century, now divided into separate tenements, but still in good preservation, adjoins the churchyard; and the hall of it has an open timber roof, and some richly carved corbels. The dissenting chapels are for Independents and Baptists. A fair is held on 21 Aug. The parish contains also the chapelry of Long-Load, and the hamlets of Ash, Bower-Hinton-with-Hurst, Coat, Milton, Stapleton, and Witcombe. Acres, 7,302. Real property, &#163;20,383. Pop., 3,155. Houses, 619. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to J. Goodden, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;450.* Patron, the Treasurer of Wells Cathedral. The vicarages of Ash and Long Load are separate benefices.-The hundred is conterminate with the parish.&#151;The sub-district contains also three other parishes. Acres, 11,945. Pop., 5,979. Houses, 1,210. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Martock/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martock</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642947</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10056100</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>MARTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438081</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438093</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549607</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MARTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10576933</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MARTOCK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12327</id>
   <name>ASH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12726</id>
   <name>CURRY RIVEL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12775</id>
   <name>DRAYTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12972</id>
   <name>ILCHESTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12990</id>
   <name>KINGSBURY EPISCOPI</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13056</id>
   <name>LONG LOAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13110</id>
   <name>MUCHELNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13350</id>
   <name>TINTINHULL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17233</id>
   <name>SOUTH SOMERSET</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
