<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13227</id>
<name>SOMERTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0553844431011</lat>
<lon>-2.7393783549114</lon>
<gazetteerText>SOMERTON, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Somerset. The town stands on an eminence adjacent to the river Cary, 5 miles ENE of Langport r. station; was a residence of the West Saxon kings, and gave name to Somersetshire; suffered devastation by the Danes in 877; had anciently a castle, in which King John of France was confined; is now a seat of petty-sessions; and has a post-office&#8225; under Taunton, a banking office, two chief inns, a town hall, an ancient market cross, a recent police station, a decorated English church, three dissenting chapels, an endowed school with &#163;30 a year, a national school, alms houses with &#163;50 a year, charities &#163;59, a weekly market on Tuesday, and nine annual fairs.&#151;The parish includes the tythings of S.-Borough, S.-Earl, and Hurcott, and the hamlets of S.-Door, Catsgore, Highbrooks, and Midney. Acres, 6,925. Real property, &#163;11,973. Pop., 2,206. Houses, 480. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;279.* Patron, the Earl of Ilchester. -The sub-district contains nine parishes, and is in Langport district. Acres, 20,744. Pop., 5,797. Houses, 1,266.-The hundred comprises 24,917 acres. Pop., 5,929. Houses, 1,271. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Somerton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Somerton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637527</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10006041</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>SOMERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10185543</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>SOMERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10441584</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SOMERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10441614</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SOMERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549784</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SOMERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12747019</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>SOMERTON AND FROME</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12313</id>
   <name>ALLER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12543</id>
   <name>CHARLTON MACKRELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12666</id>
   <name>COMPTON DUNDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12921</id>
   <name>HIGH HAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12967</id>
   <name>HUISH EPISCOPI</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12977</id>
   <name>KEINTON MANDEVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12997</id>
   <name>KINGSDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13032</id>
   <name>LANGPORT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13133</id>
   <name>OTHERY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13287</id>
   <name>LONG SUTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
