<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13438</id>
<name>YATTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3943798928517</lat>
<lon>-2.8168621862228</lon>
<gazetteerText>YATTON, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Bedminster district, Somerset. The village stands near the Bristol and Exeter railway, 4&#188; miles S by E of Clevedon; and has a head post-office&#8225; designated Yatton, Somerset, and a r. station.&#151;The parish contains also Cleeve village and Claverham hamlet, and comprises 5,374 acres. Real property, &#163;14,543. Pop. in 1851, 2,061; in 1861, 1,851. Houses, 382. The property is much subdivided. The manor, with Cleeve Court, belongs to T. Castle, Esq. The tract around Cleeve presents some picturesque and diversified scenery. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;430.* Patron, the Bishop of B. and W. The church is cruciform and decorated and later English. The vicarages of Cleeve and Kenn are separate benefices. There are national schools and charities &#163;57.&#151;The sub-district contains 8 parishes. Acres, 20,048. Pop., 8,236. Houses, 1,531. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Yatton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yatton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633404</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10447239</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>YATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10447264</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>YATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549966</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>YATTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12674</id>
   <name>CONGRESBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13159</id>
   <name>PUXTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17260</id>
   <name>NORTH SOMERSET</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
