<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13367</id>
<name>WALTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1197032785978</lat>
<lon>-2.77810334749012</lon>
<gazetteerText>WALTON, a parish, with a village, in Wells district, Somerset; 3&#188; miles SW of Glastonbury r. station. It has a post-office under Bath. Acres, 2,502. Real property, &#163;4,259. Pop., 731. Houses, 164. The manor belongs to the Marquis of Bath. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to Street. The church is decorated English. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Walton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walton,_Somerset</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634837</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10445231</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>WALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10445243</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WALTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>13368</id>
<name>WALTON IN GORDANO</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.4545909007191</lat>
<lon>-2.82828955699209</lon>
<gazetteerText>WALTON-IN-GORDANO, a parish in Bedminster district, Somerset; on the coast, 1&#190; mile NE of Clevedon r. station. It has a post-office under Clevedon. Acres, 1,315. Real property, &#163;1,513. Pop., 191. Houses, 43. The manor belongs to Sir W. Miles, Bart. W. Castle belonged to the Mortimers; passed to the Seymours, the Thynnes, and others; and is now an extensive ruin. The living is a rectory, united with Weston-in-Gordano, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;360.* Patron, Sir W. Miles, Bart. The church is modern. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/WaltonInGordano/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walton_in_Gordano</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634831</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10445267</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WALTON IN GORDANO</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10445279</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WALTON IN GORDANO</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
