<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12551</id>
<name>CHEDDAR</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2769815814973</lat>
<lon>-2.77301175719381</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHEDDAR, a village and a parish in Axbridge district, Somerset. The village stands near the Cheddar Cliffs, on the S side of the Mendip hills, 2&#189; miles ESE of Axbridge; and is near a station of the Cheddar Valley and Yatton railway, from Yatton to Wells, opened in 1869. It is an ancient but decayed place, irregularly built; and it has a post office&#8225; under Weston-super-Mare, two inns, and an old market-cross restored in 1834. A considerable market was long held in it; and there still are fairs on 4 May and 29 Oct. The parish includes also part of Draycott hamlet. Acres, 6, 998. Real property, &#163;12, 634. Pop., 2, 032. Houses, 457. The property is much subdivided. The manor was a seat of Alfred the Great; and belong. ed afterwards to the De Cheddars, who long represented the county in parliament. The manor-house stood near Axbridge; and is partly extant in a farm-house. Cheddar Cliffs are a narrow, winding, romantic ravine, nearly a mile long, faced with vertical cliffs, cut by fissures, festooned with shrubs, fashioned naturally into buttresses, towers, and pinnacles, and rising in one part to an altitude of 429 feet. A copious streamlet issues from the chasm; has power enough, after a few hundred yards, to drive paper and corn mills; and passes on to the Axe. A cavern, accidentally discovered at the enlarging of a corn mill in 1839, possesses a singularly rich display of stalagmites and stalactites, in great variety, of beautiful, grotesque, and fantastic forms. This cavern is small and narrow; but others exist of larger size, great gloomy vaults; and one of them can be explored for about 300 feet. Cheddar cheese has been famous from early times; and owes its excellence, in a main degree, to the rich pasture of the grass farms. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;203.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Wells. The church is perpendicular English, with a square tower 100 feet high; and contains a sculptured stone pulpit, a rich oaken screen, and two brasses of 1443. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists. A school has &#163;46 from endowment; and other charities have &#163;152. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Cheddar/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cheddar</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653281</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10423909</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CHEDDAR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10423958</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHEDDAR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12349</id>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12464</id>
   <name>BLAGDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12548</id>
   <name>CHARTERHOUSE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12669</id>
   <name>COMPTON MARTIN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12929</id>
   <name>WEST HARPTREE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13122</id>
   <name>NYLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13166</id>
   <name>ROWBERROW</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13221</id>
   <name>SHIPHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13254</id>
   <name>RODNEY STOKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13361</id>
   <name>UBLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
