<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12971</id>
<name>HUTTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.327123770611</lat>
<lon>-2.9300983769332</lon>
<gazetteerText>HUTTON, a village and a parish in Axbridge district, Somerset. The village stands 1&#189; mile E of Weston-super-Mare Junction r. station, and 7 NW of Axbridge; is a neat place, with several good houses; and has a post office under Weston-super-Mare.&#151;The parish comprises 1,876 acres. Real property, with Locking, &#163;6, 543. Rated property of H. alone, &#163;4, 500. Pop., 359. Houses, 83. The property is subdivided. The principal landowner is Sir G. Smyth. The manor, with Hutton Court, belongs to E. Bisdee, Esq. Hutton Court was formerly an ecclesiastical establishment, supposed to have belonged to Glastonbury abbey; and it contains a fine old hall, with open oak roof; and has an embattled tower, which commands a fine view of the surrounding country. Ochre pits, old mines, and several caverns are in the parish; and quantities of bones of elephants, tigers, hy&#230;nas, boars, wolves, and other animals have been found in the caverns. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;434. * Patron, G. Gibbs, Esq. The church is decorated English; consists of nave, aisle, and chancel, with embattled tower; and contains recent painted W window, a memorial window to a former rector, and several monuments and brasses. Charities, &#163; 4. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Hutton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hutton,_Somerset</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646342</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10434993</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10435018</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HUTTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
