<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12926</id>
<name>HARDINGTON MANDEVILLE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.8921477430943</lat>
<lon>-2.704633936438</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARDINGTON-MANDEVILLE, a village and a parish in Yeovil district, Somerset. The village stands near the Sutton-Bingham station of the Yeovil and Exeter railway, 2 miles from the boundary with Dorset, and 4 SW of Yeovil; and has a post-office, of the name of Hardington, under Yeovil. The parish comprises 2,631 acres. Real property, &#163;2,839. Pop., 668. Houses, 140. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to Lord Portman. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;471. * Patron, Rev. W. Vassall. The church, with the exception of the tower, was re-built in 1864; and is in the decorated English style. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hardington_Mandeville</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/HardingtonMandeville/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7294008</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10433666</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HARDINGTON MANDEVILLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10433680</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARDINGTON MANDEVILLE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13138</id>
   <name>PENDOMER</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>12924</id>
<name>HARDINGTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2709651296824</lat>
<lon>-2.36932742736166</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARDINGTON, a parish in Frome district, Somerset; 3&#190; miles NW by N of Frome r. station. Post-town, Frome. Acres, 831. Real property, &#163;789. Pop., 22. Houses, 3. The manor belonged to Lord Poltimore, and had belonged to his ancestors, the Bampfyldes, for upwards of 450 years. The living is a rectory, annexed to the rectory of Hemington, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. The church was originally a private chapel of the Bampfyldes; consists of nave and chancel with a belfry; and was recently restored. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Hardington/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647496</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10433617</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HARDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10433630</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARDINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
