<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12984</id>
<name>KILMERSDON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.264021073541</lat>
<lon>-2.43922116246289</lon>
<gazetteerText>KILMERSDON, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Somerset. The village stands, amid picturesque scenery, 6 miles NW by W of Frome r. station; is a seat of petty sessions; contains some good streets, well built and paved; has a post office under Bath, a good inn a temperance hall, with lecture room, a church, national schools, and gas works; and publishes a weekly newspaper. The church is later English; and consists of nave, aisle, and chancel, with lofty tower.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlets of Coleford, Charlton, Kilmersdon Common, Luckington, Newberry, and Lypiate. Acres, 3, 460. Real property, &#163;5, 611. Pop., 2, 194. Houses, 486. The manor, Ammerdown House, ans much of the land, belong to the Rev. T. R. Joliffe. Ammerdown House is an edifice in the Grecian style, after designs by Wyatt; stands in a park of 4 miles in circuit; and commands extensive views. A beautiful column, 150 feet high, to the memory of Col. T. S. Joliffe, is in the park. The rocks are varions, and include much coal at a great depth. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath. Value, &#163;244.* Patron, the Rev. T. R. Joliffe. The p. curacy of Coleford is a separate benefice. Charities, to the value of &#163;35, inclusive of &#163;23 to a school, are in Kilmersdon; and chapels for Wesleyans and Primitive Methodists are in Coleford.-The subdistrict contains also six other parishes and part of another; and is in Frome district. Acres, 11, 588. Pop., 3, 999. Houses, 877.-The hundred contains ten parishes. Acres, 14, 573. Pop., 7, 358. Houses, 1, 572. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Kilmersdon/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kilmersdon</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645597</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10031059</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>KILMERSDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10435353</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>KILMERSDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10435389</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KILMERSDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549553</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KILMERSDON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12353</id>
   <name>BABINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12961</id>
   <name>HOLCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13042</id>
   <name>LEIGH UPON MENDIP</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
