<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13372</id>
<name>WEDMORE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2203058579734</lat>
<lon>-2.81488243119185</lon>
<gazetteerText>WEDMORE, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Axbridge district, Somerset. The village stands on a rising-ground, 4 miles NNE of Shapwick r. station, and 4&#190; S of Axbridge; was known to the Saxons as Wetmor; is nominally a borough, governed by a portreeve; is also a polling place; and has a post-office&#8225; under Weston-super-Mare, and two annual fairs. The parish contains five tythings and numerous hamlets. Acres, 9,986. Real property, &#163;23,788. Pop. in 1851, 3,905; in 1861, 3,653. Houses, 804. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged anciently to the Crown, and belongs now to the Barrows. A summer palace of King Alfred stood on Mudgley hill, but has left no vestiges. Much Cheddar cheese is made. A pot of Danish coins was found in the churchyard in 1851. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;360.* Patron, the Bishop of B. and W. The church is ancient, cruciform, and good. The p. curacies of Theale and Blackford are separate benefices. Eleven chapels were anciently in different parts; but remains of only one of them now exist. There are Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, an endowed school, and charities about &#163;60.&#151;The sub-district contains 6 parishes. Acres, 20,044. Pop., 6,265. Houses, 1,367. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Wedmore/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wedmore</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634618</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10445360</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WEDMORE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10445383</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEDMORE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12878</id>
   <name>GODNEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13098</id>
   <name>MEARE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>12349</id>
<name>AXBRIDGE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.288350630703</lat>
<lon>-2.81386855599256</lon>
<gazetteerText>Axbridge, par. and small town with ry. sta., mid. Somerset, 9&#189; miles NW. of Wells, 540 ac., pop. 718; P.O., T.O., 2 Banks. Market-days, Tuesday and Saturday. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656730</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Axbridge</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Axbridge/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Axbridge</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10025515</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10055489</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10097460</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10112011</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418537</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418562</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549723</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10560780</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10569138</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12757992</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>AXBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
