<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>701</id>
<name>ILMINSTER</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.9268146603037</lat>
<lon>-2.91247880866229</lon>
<gazetteerText>ILMINSTER., a town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Chard district, Somerset. The town stands on the river Isle, the Chard canal, and the Chard and Taunton railway, 5 miles N by E of Chard. It takes its name from the river Isle and from its own church or minster. It was a place of some importance in the Saxon times. It was, at one period, more extensive than at present; and it has repeatedly suffered injury by fire. It comprises two long streets, from E to W and from N to S; and contains many good houses. It has a head post office, &#8225; a railway station, a banking office, two chief inns, a fourarched bridge, a market house, a police station, a church, three dissenting chapels, a grammar school, a large national school, and charities &#163;15; and is a seat of petty sessions, and a polling place. The church belonged to Muchelney abbey; is cruciform and decorated English, with chantry chapel and pinnacled central tower; and contains brasses and monuments of the Wadhams, one of whom was the founder of Wadham College, Oxford. The grammar school was founded in 1550, by H. Waldron, a native; includes a secondary school for the lower branches; and has &#163;900 a year from endowment, and two exhibitions at Oxford. Markets are held on Wednesdays and Saturdays; a fair is held on the last Wednesday of Aug.; and brewing, flax working., glove making, cloth making, rope making and brick making are carried on. Samwayes, the theologian, was a native. Pop., 2, 194. Houses, 468.&#151;The parish is divided into the tythings of Town, Horton, Hilcombe, Church, and Winterhay; and contains part of the hamlet of Crock-Street. Acres, 4, 050. Real property, &#163;16, 419; of which &#163;60 are in gas works, and &#163;40 in the canal. Pop., 3, 419. Houses, 685. The manor, with Dillington House, belongs to John L. Lee, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;500. * Patron, Mrs. Scott Gould.&#151;The sub-district contains also fourteen other parishes. Acres, 20, 220. Pop., 7, 448. Houses, 1, 568. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Ilminster/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646265</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ilminster</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10135291</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>ILMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10435055</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ILMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10435080</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ILMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10435092</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>ILMINSTER WITHOUT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549504</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ILMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10575473</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ILMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12339</id>
   <name>ASHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12368</id>
   <name>BARRINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12474</id>
   <name>BROADWAY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12723</id>
   <name>NORTH CURRY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12724</id>
   <name>CURRY MALLET</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12755</id>
   <name>DONYATT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12854</id>
   <name>FIVEHEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12935</id>
   <name>HATCH BEAUCHAMP</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12974</id>
   <name>ILTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12975</id>
   <name>ISLE ABBOTS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
