<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13102</id>
<name>MILBORNE PORT</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.9771985346398</lat>
<lon>-2.46998235387201</lon>
<gazetteerText>MILBORNE-PORT, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Wincanton district, Somerset. The town stands at the foot of a hill, on a small affluent of the river Yeo, &#190; of a mile WNW of the boundary with Dorset, 1 SE of the Salisbury and Yeovil railway, and 2&#190; NE by E of Sherborne; took its name from its situation on a mill-stream, and from the Saxon word Port signifying a borough; was a place of some consequence prior to the Norman conquest; is a borough by prescription, having still nine capital bailiffs; sent two members to parliament in the time of Edward III., and from that of Charles I., till the passing of the reform act, but then was disfranchised; was long a market-town, but has ceased to be so; possesses still the pediment and steps of an ancient market-cross; has also a curious old townhall, half a cottage, with a Norman doorway; has likewise a ball-court, erected by Sir William Medlycott for the use of its inhabitants; was occupied, for some time, by a party of Cromwell&apos;s soldiers, who provoked the town&apos;s people to rise against them, and drive them from the town; consists now chiefly of detached houses; and has a post office under Sherborne, a railway station, a good inn, a church, Independent and Wesleyan chapels, national and British schools, and charities &#163;39. The church is Norman; was recently restored; consists of nave, aisles, transept, and chancel, with a large tower; and contains monuments of the Medlycotts. Fairs are held on 5 June and 28 Oct.; a manufacture of cloth, dowlas, and stockings was formerly considerable; and glove-making, leather-dressing, and shoe-making are now carried on.&#151;The parish contains also the tything of Kingsbury-Regis and the hamlet of Milborne-Wick. Acres, 3,277. Real property, &#163;7,368. Pop., 1,814Houses, 351. Venn House, a red brick mansion of somewhat unique appearance, built by Inigo Jones, is the seat of Sir William Medlycott, Bart. An ancient camp is at Milborne-Wick. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;233.* Patron, Sir W. Medlycott, Bart.&#151;The sub-district contains also six other parishes. Acres, 17,606. Pop., 5,395. Houses, 1,159. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milborne_Port</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/MilbornePort/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642549</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18746</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10202450</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>MILBORNE PORT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438184</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MILBORNE PORT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438196</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MILBORNE PORT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549875</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MILBORNE PORT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10577100</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MILBORNE PORT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758900</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>MILBORNE PORT</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12541</id>
   <name>CHARLTON HORETHORNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12636</id>
   <name>ABBAS COMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12689</id>
   <name>CORTON DENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12875</id>
   <name>GOATHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12953</id>
   <name>HENSTRIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13152</id>
   <name>POYNTINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13276</id>
   <name>STOWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13290</id>
   <name>SUTTON MONTIS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13582</id>
   <name>PURSE CAUNDLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13756</id>
   <name>OBORNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
