<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12558</id>
<name>CHEW MAGNA</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3555346946569</lat>
<lon>-2.60165643626794</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHEW-MAGNA, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Clutton district, Somerset. The village stands on an affluent of the river Avon, 3 miles W by S of Pensford, and 5 SE of Bourton r. station; has a post office&#8225; under Bristol; is a seat of petty sessions; and was once a borough and a market-town. The parish includes the tythings of Bishop-Sutton, North Elm, Stone, Knowle and Knighton-Sutton; and both it and the village are sometimes called Bishops-Chew. Acres, 006. Real property, &#163;1, 230. Pop., 1,855. Houses, 394. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to the Bishop of Bath and Wells. Chew Court is a ruined mansion of the middle ages. A Druidical circle is at Stanton-Drew; and a Roman camp, at Bow-Ditch. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Holy Trinity, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;634.* Patron, alternately the Bishop and others. The church is decorated English; and was restored in 1860. The p. curacy of Dundry is a separate benefice. There is a chapel of ease at Bishops-Sutton. There are also chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, an endowed school, and charities &#163;36. -The sub-district contains seven parishes and a ville. Acres, 13, 009. Pop., 4, 422. Houses, 966. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chew_Magna</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/ChewMagna/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653197</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10134020</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>CHEW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10424069</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CHEW MAGNA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10424070</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHEW MAGNA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549632</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHEW MAGNA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10571492</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHEW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10571509</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHEW MAGNA</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12559</id>
   <name>CHEW STOKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
