<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13406</id>
<name>WILLITON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1654010799875</lat>
<lon>-3.31864198183552</lon>
<gazetteerText>WILLITON, a small town, a chapelry, a sub-district, a district, and a hundred, in Somerset. The town stands near the West Somerset railway, under the Quantock hills, 1&#189; mile from the coast, and 14&#189; NW of Taunton; belonged, in the time of King Stephen, to the Fitzurses: passed to the Demboroughs and the Wyndhams; is a seat of county courts, and a polling place; publishes a weekly newspaper; presents a neat appearance, with cottages embowered in shrubs; comprises two long streets; and has a post-office&#8225; under Taunton, a r. station with telegraph, a banking office, a hotel, remains of two old crosses, an early English church restored in 1858, two dissenting chapels, a national school, a workhouse, and two annual fairs.&#151;The chapelry seems to be identical with the town, and is in St. Decumans parish; but the pop is not separately returned. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;70. Patron, the Vicar of St. Decumans.&#151;The sub-district contains 6 parishes. Acres, 17,709. Pop., 5,679. Houses, 1,000.&#151;The district comprehends also Minehead, Dunster, Stogursey, and Stogumber sub-districts; and it formerly included likewise Dulverton sub-district. Acres, exclusive of Dulverton, 109,202. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;11,826. Pop. in 1851, 19,895; in 1861, 19,918. Houses, 3,836. Marriages in 1866, 81; births, 583,- of which 19 were illegitimate; deaths, 304,-of which 75 were at ages under 5 years, and 14 at ages above 85. Births in the ten years 1851-60, 5,659; deaths, 3,525. The places of worship, in 1851, inclusive of Dulverton sub-district, were 39 of the Church of England, with-8,865 sittings; 3 of Independents, with 270 s.; 6 of Baptists, with 1,388 s.; 8 of Wesleyans, with 1,359. s.; 1 of Primitive Methodists, with 34 s.; and 4 of Bible Christians, with 360 s. The schools were 29 public day-schools, with 1,616 scholars; 39 private day-schools, with 783 s.; and 44 Sunday schools, with 2,514 s.-The hundred contains 31 parishes, and bears the name of Williton and Free manors. Acres, 115,485. Pop. in 1851, 17,068; in 1861, 17,345. Houses, 3,285. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Williton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Williton</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Williton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633894</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10042021</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WILLITON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10042914</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WILLITON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10098520</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>WILLITON AND FREEMANORS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10187588</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>WILLITON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446466</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>WILLITON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446478</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WILLITON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549814</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WILLITON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>568</id>
<name>WELLINGTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.9695707320096</lat>
<lon>-3.23459091151139</lon>
<gazetteerText>WELLINGTON, a town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Somerset. The town stands on a gentle elevation, near the Bristoland Exeter railway, at the foot of the Blackdown hills, 6&#189; miles SW by W of Taunton; gives the titles of Viscount, Earl, and Duke to the family of Wellesley; is a seat of petty-sessions and county courts; is governed by a portreeve and some other officers; publishes two weekly newspapers; carries on woollen manufacture and iron-founding; comprises five streets, containing many respectable residences; and has a head post-office,&#8225; designated Wellington, Somerset, a r. station with telegraph, a banking office, two chief inns, a police station, a market house and town hall, a library and reading room, a fine ancient church with graceful later English tower, a handsome modern church, a neat Independent chapel of 1861, five other dissenting chapels, national and British schools, alms houses with &#163;149 a year, a workhouse, a weekly market on Thursday, and two annual fairs. Pop. in 1861, 3,689. Houses, 793.&#151;The parish includes three hamlets, and comprises 5,195 acres. Real property, &#163;21,088; of which &#163;30 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 6,415; in 1861, 6,006. Houses, 1,261. The manor belonged to Alfred the Great; was given to the see of Wells; passed to the Somersets and the Pophams; and belongs now to the Duke of Wellington. A pillar, monumental of Wellington and Waterloo, stands on a lofty hill, 2&#189; miles S of the town; figures conspicuously over an extensive picturesque landscape; and was designed to be surmounted by a bronze statue of the hero of Waterloo. The living is a vicarage, united with Trinity and West Buckland chapelries, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;1,084.* Patron, Mrs. Pulman.&#151;The sub-district contains six parishes. Acres, 13,563. Pop., 8,305. Houses, 1,745.&#151;The district comprehends also Culmstock, Milverton, and Wiveliscombe sub-districts; and comprises 60,454 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;12,378. Pop. in 1851, 22,121; in 1861, 20,480. Houses, 4,356. Marriages in 1863, 134; births, 577,-of which 31 were illegitimate; deaths, 380, -of which 125 were at ages under 5 years, and 22 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,305; births, 6,147; deaths, 3,919. The places of worship, in 1851, were 27 of the Church of England, with 9,367 sittings; 5 of Independents, with 1,451 s.; 6 of Baptists, with 1,692 s.; 3 of Quakers, with 372 s.; 8 of Wesleyans, with 1,416 s.; 3 of Bible Christians, with 345 s.; and 1 undefined, with 200 s. The schools were 19 public day-schools, with 1,373 scholars; 37 private day-schools, with 933 s.; 37 Sunday schools, with 2,915 s.; and 4 evening schools for adults, with 49 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Wellington/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wellington,_Somerset</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Wellington</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634575</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10003842</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10023956</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10028036</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10107799</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10139107</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10185531</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10445395</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10445449</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10445462</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WELLINGTON WITHOUT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549942</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581989</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12754140</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>SOMERSETSHIRE WESTERN OR WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835668</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WELLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3132</id>
   <name>CHURCHSTANTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4176</id>
   <name>HEMYOCK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5214</id>
   <name>CLAYHIDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12498</id>
   <name>WEST BUCKLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13031</id>
   <name>LANGFORD BUDVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13123</id>
   <name>NYNEHEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13168</id>
   <name>RUNNINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13172</id>
   <name>SAMPFORD ARUNDEL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13463</id>
   <name>THORNE ST MARGARET</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
