<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12726</id>
<name>CURRY RIVEL</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0165291837915</lat>
<lon>-2.8721063863449</lon>
<gazetteerText>CURRY-RIVELL, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in Langport district, Somerset. The village stands near the river Parret and the Durston and Yeovil railway, 2 miles WSW of Langport; and has a post office under Taunton, and fairs on the last Wednesday of Feb., and the Monday after 1 Aug. The parish includes also the tythings of Hambridge and Portfield, part of the tythings of Burton-Pynsent and Week, and part of the hamlet of Westport. Acres, 4, 108. Real property, &#163;9, 550. Pop., 1, 704. Houses, 359. The property is much subdivided The surface is hilly; and the rocks include blue has. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Weston, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;310.* Patron, W. Speke, Esq. The church is early English; consists of nave and chancel, with porch and tower; has beautiful windows; and contains carved oaken seats and screen, and a curious monument of M. and R. Jennings. The vicarage of Hambridge is a separate benefice. Charities, &#163;28.&#151;The sub-district contains twelve parishes and two extra-parochial tracts. Acres, 17, 615. Pop., 5, 189. Houses, 1, 058. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/CurryRivel/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curry_Rivel</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651680</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10428105</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CURRY RIVEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10428129</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CURRY RIVEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10566186</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CURRY RIVELL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
