<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>21589</id>
<name>PENSFORD</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3714810329246</lat>
<lon>-2.54740701090984</lon>
<gazetteerText>PENSFORD, a village and parish in Clutton district, Somerset. The village stands on the river Chew, and the North Somerset railway, 6&#189; miles S S E of Bristol; was once a market-town, and a seat of cloth manufacture; and has a station on the railway, a post-office&#8225; under Bristol, and fairs on 6 May and 8 Nov. The parish iscalled St. Thomas-in-Pensford, and comprises 740 acres. Real property, not separately returned. Pop., 312. Houses, 78. Hill House is a chief residence. A railway viaduct, of 16 arches, and upwards of 90 feet high, herecrosses the Chew river; and was constructed in 1866. The scenery is fine. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the vicarage of Stanton-Drew, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. The church is partly Norman, with an embattled tower; and contains an old carved oak pulpit, acurious old stone font, and monumental tablets to the Guys, the Veales, and the Thompsons. There are British schools and some small charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pensford</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640410</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Pensford/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10439991</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PENSFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10447811</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>ST THOMAS IN PENSFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>13156</id>
<name>PUBLOW</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3747969147587</lat>
<lon>-2.53808135775757</lon>
<gazetteerText>PUBLOW, a parish in Clutton district, Somerset;on an affluent of the river Avon, and on the Radstock railway, 5&#188; miles S S E of Bristol. It includes part of Woolard hamlet, and has a post-office under Bristol. Acres, 1, 335. Real property, &#163;2, 754. Pop. in 1851, 810; in 1861, 643. Houses, 136. The decrease of pop.was caused by the closing of copper-works. The propertybelongs chiefly to E. L. Popham, Esq. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;25. The church was almost wholly rebuilt, at greatcost, in 1860; and was shattered by lightning in thefollowing year. There are chapels for Calvinists and Methodists, a parochial school, an apprenticing charity of &#163;25 a year, and some other charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Publow/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Publow</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639871</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10439255</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PUBLOW WITH PENSFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439565</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>PUBLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439577</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PUBLOW</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12662</id>
   <name>COMPTON DANDO</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13094</id>
   <name>MARKSBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
