<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13104</id>
<name>MILVERTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0202622181508</lat>
<lon>-3.26832343121114</lon>
<gazetteerText>MILVERTON, a small town, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Somerset. The town stands in a beautiful deep small valley, overhung in the W by steep high cultivated hills, 3&#189; miles NNW of Wellington r. station, and 13&#189; SW of Bridgewater; is an ancient place, formerly a borough, and still nominally governed by a portreeve and other officers; consists chiefly of three irregular streets; and has a post office, &#8224; under Wellington, Somerset, a good inn, a picturesque old marketcross, a church, Independent and Wesleyan chapels, an endowed school with &#163;54 a year, and charities &#163;59. The church stands on an eminence, overlooking the town; is later English, of the time of Henry VII., 120 feet by 60; was recently restored; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with porch and tower: and contains old seats with beautifully carved ends. A weekly market is held on Friday; and cattle fairs, on Easter Tuesday, 25 July, and 10 Oct. A considerable woollen trade was formerly carried on, but has almost entirely ceased. John de Milverton, a friar who wrote furiously against Wickliffe, and Dr. Thomas Young, who first deciphered Egyptian hieroglyphics, and established the undulatory theory of light, were natives.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlets of Preston-Bowyer, Houndsmoor, and Screedhay. Acres, 5,475. Real property, &#163;11,481. Pop. in 1851,2,146; in 1861,1,895. Houses, 429. The decrease of pop. was caused partly by the closing of a large tannery. The surface is diversified; and the higher grounds command extensive views. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Langford-Budville, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;600.* Patron, the Archdeacon of Taunton.&#151;The sub-district contains also eight other parishes, and is in Wellington district. Acres, 15,130. Pop., 4,214. Houses, 912.-The hundred excludes two parishes of the sub-district, but includes two which lie beyond it. Acres, 14,812. Pop., 4,002. Houses, 862. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Milverton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milverton,_Somerset</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642457</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10030845</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>MILVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10084489</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>MILVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438238</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MILVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438240</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MILVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549930</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MILVERTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
