<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13095</id>
<name>MARSTON BIGOT</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.191207102603</lat>
<lon>-2.33306739320852</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARSTON-BIGOTT, a village and a parish in Frome district, Somerset. The village stands near the East Somerset railway, 2&#189; miles SW of Frome r. station; and gives the title of Baron to the Earl of Cork. The parish contains also the hamlet of Gaer-Hill; and its Post town is Frome. Acres, 2,238. Real property, &#163;4,010. Pop. in 1851,449; in 1861,379. Houses, 83. The property is subdivided. The manor, with Marston House, belongs to the Earl of Cork; and came into the possession of his ancestors about 1630. A spot called MarstonMoat was the site of a more ancient manor-house. A field called Conqueror&apos;s Mead, near that spct, is said to lhave been the scene of a great battle in ancient times; and it has a barrow, supposed to have been formed by intern ent of the slain. A bastard freestone abounds, and is used for mortar and for manure. Bricks and tiles are made. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;280.* Patron, the Earl of Cork. The church was rebuilt in 1789; is in the Norman style; consists of nave and chancel, with porch and tower; and has beautiful stained glass windows. A chapel of ease is at Gaer-Hill: and national schools are there and at the village. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/MarstonBigot/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10438044</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARSTON BIGOT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438056</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARSTON BIGOT</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
