<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13147</id>
<name>PITMINSTER</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.9659462493631</lat>
<lon>-3.12152803259115</lon>
<gazetteerText>PITMINSTER, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Taunton district, Somerset. The village stands under Black down hills, near the boundary with Devon, 4&#189; miles S by W of Taunton r. station. The parish includes thetythings of Blagdon, Duddlestone, Fulford, Leigh, Pitminster, and Trendle; and its post town is Taunton. Acres, 5, 120. Real property, &#163;10, 832. Pop., 1, 572. Houses, 334. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to Mr. Cox. Barton Grange, Eastbrook House, Maryville, Canons-Grove, Pondisford Park, Pondisford Lodge, Culmhead House, Pitminster Lodge, and Haygrass House are chief residences. There are two maltings and a tannery. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;550.* Patron, the Rev. G. R. Lawson. The church is early English; and consists of nave, aisles, chancel, and porch, with tower and spire. There are an Independent chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;13.&#151;The sub-district contains also9 other parishes. Acres, 21, 702. Pop., 4, 950. Houses, 969. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Pitminster/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pitminster</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640251</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10439371</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>PITMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439383</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PITMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549670</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PITMINSTER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12322</id>
   <name>ANGERSLEIGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12677</id>
   <name>CORFE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13134</id>
   <name>OTTERFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13233</id>
   <name>STAPLE FITZPAINE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
