<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13151</id>
<name>PORTBURY</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.470377830067</lat>
<lon>-2.7284668265037</lon>
<gazetteerText>PORTBURY, a village, a parish, and a hundred, in Somerset. The village stands adjacent to the Bristoland Portishead railway, near Wans dyke, 1&#189; mile W of the river Avon, and 6 W N W of Bristol; occupies the site of a Roman station, where Roman coins, foundations of Roman villas, and other Roman relics have beenfound; and has a post-office under Bristol, and a railway station. The parish includes the tythings of Abbots, Caswell, Claptons-Wick, Court, Cross, Failand, Hamgreen, Happerton, Honor, Peters, Sheepway, Watchouse, and Woolcombe; and is in Bedminster district. Acres, 3, 849; of which 130 are fore-shore water. Real property, &#163;7, 310. Pop., 677. Houses, 135. The manor belongs to Sir W. Abdy, Bart. An Augustiniancell to Bromere priory was here, and has left some vestiges. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;400.* Patron, the Bishop of Worcester. The church is ancient; and consists of nave, aisles, chancel, and chapel, with a fine tower. There are a parochial school, and charities &#163;9. The hundred contains also eleven other parishes. Acres, 26, 369. Pop.in 1851, 10, 765; in 1861, 11, 558. Houses, 2, 242. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Portbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portbury</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640075</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10140742</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>PORTBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439450</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PORTBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439462</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PORTBURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
