<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13117</id>
<name>NORTON FITZWARREN</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0312927878776</lat>
<lon>-3.1594679619009</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTON-FITZWARREN, a village and a parish in Taunton district, Somerset. The village stands near the river Tone, the Bristol and Exeter railway, and the Taunton and Watchet railway, 2&#189; miles W N W of Taunton; is a pleasant place; and has a post-office under Taunton. The parish contains the tythings of Langford and Vanhampton, and comprises 1, 307 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 521. Pop., 634. Houses, 131. The property is divided among a few. The manor, with the Manor-House on a commanding site, belongs to N. Welman, Esq. Montys Court is the residence of Lady Slade; Norton Court, of the Hewetts; and Way House of Major A. Jones. A curious earthwork is on a hill above the church; comprises 13 acres, engirt by ditch and double rampart; is locally fabled to have been the haunt of a prodigious serpent, which long devastated the surrounding country; and was thought by the Rev. Mr. Warre, in an account of it to the Somerset Arch&#230;ological Society, to be the site of an ancient British town. The present village may not improbably be traceable to an ancient British origin; and, at least, has an ancient importance assigned to it by an old local rhyme, which says, When Taunton was a furzy down, Norton was a market town. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;490.* Patron, Mrs. Mary Hewett. The church is early English; comprises nave, aisles, chancel, and chapel with a tower; and has an E memorial window. The nave and the N aisle were rebuilt in 1853; and the chancel was restored, and the chapel built, in 1865. There are an Independent chapel and a parochial school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/NortonFitzwarren/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norton_Fitzwarren</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641189</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10438597</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NORTON FITZWARREN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438603</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTON FITZWARREN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12941</id>
   <name>HEATHFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13124</id>
   <name>OAKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13128</id>
   <name>KINGSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13236</id>
   <name>STAPLEGROVE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
