<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13158</id>
<name>PURITON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1711048676605</lat>
<lon>-2.96897690238862</lon>
<gazetteerText>PURITON, a parish, with a village, in Bridgewater district, Somerset; on the river Parret and on the Bristol and Exeter railway, 3&#189; miles N N E of Bridgewater. Post-town, Bridgewater. Acres, 1, 632; of which 55 are water. Real property, &#163;5, 724; of which &#163;300 are inquarries. Pop. in 1851, 451; in 1861, 604. Houses, 115. The increase of pop. arose mainly from the establishment of three cement mill. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to B.Greenhill, Esq. The living is a vicarage, annexed to the vicarage of Woolavington, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. The church is ancient, has a tower, and was recently restored. There are an Independent chapel, an endowed school with &#163;10 a year, and charities &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Puriton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Puriton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639844</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15114</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10439620</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PURITON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439632</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PURITON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12970</id>
<name>HUNTSPILL</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2073958013549</lat>
<lon>-2.97583017534437</lon>
<gazetteerText>HUNTSPILL, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Somerset. The village stands near the mouth of the river Parret, 1&#189; mile SW of Highbridge r. station, and 5&#189; N of Bridgewater; is a widely scattered place; was once a market town; and has a post office under Bridgewater, and a fair on 29 June. The parish includes also the village of East Huntspill, and the greater part of the tything of Aston-Morris. Acres, 9, 289; of which 3, 345 are water. Real property, &#163;19, 897. Pop. in 1851, 1, 594; in 1861, 1, 695. Houses, 344. The manor belongs to the Rector. The surface is chiefly rich pasturage; and it is bounded, for some way, on one side by the Parret, on the other by the Brue. Brick making is carried on. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;650.* Patron, Baliol College, Oxford. The church is later English, in good condition; and consists of nave, aisles, transept, and chancel, with porch and tower. The vicarage of East Huntspill is a separate benefice. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a national school with about &#163;6 from endowment, and charities &#163;10.&#151;The sub-district contains also five other parishes and part of another; and is in Bridgewater district. Acres, 19,481. Pop., 4,003. Houses, 817.-The hundred contains only Huntspill and Puriton parishes; and bears the name of Huntspill and Puriton. Acres, 10,921. Pop., 2,299. Houses, 359. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Huntspill/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Huntspill</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2646377</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15101</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15110</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075968</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>HUNTSPILL AND PURITON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10434944</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HUNTSPILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10434956</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HUNTSPILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10434981</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>WEST HUNTSPILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549887</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HUNTSPILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
