<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12515</id>
<name>CANNINGTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1557389007167</lat>
<lon>-3.06742417811021</lon>
<gazetteerText>CANNINGTON, a village, a parish, and a hundred, in Somerset. The village stands 2 miles SSW of a bend of the river Parret, and 3&#189; NW by W of Bridgewater r. station; and has a post office&#8225; under Bridgewater. It dates from ancient times; was known to the Saxons as Caninganmaersees; had a Benedictine nunnery, founded in the time of King Stephen, by Robert de Courcy; and is supposed to have been the birth place of the Fair Rosamond, of ballad notoriety. The parish includes also the hamlets of Edstock and Beer; impinges some distance on the Parret; and is in the district of Bridgewater. Acres, 5,015; of which 380 are water. Real property, &#163;4,850. Pop., 1,419. Houses, 320. The manor belongs to Lord Clifford. Cannington Park, the seat of Lord Clifford&apos;s ancestors, is now occupied as a grazing farm. Brymere House is the seat of the Hon. P. Pleydell Bouverie. Kithill, in the vicinity, has an altitude of 1,067 feet. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;371.* Patron, Lord Clifford. The church was part of the Benedictine nunnery; is later English, and fine; and contains tombs of the Cliffords. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a Roman Catholic chapel, a national school, a charity for alms-houses and for the poor amounting to &#163;330 a year, and other charities &#163;34. -The hundred contains ten parishes. Acres, 28,411. Pop., 5,700. Houses, 1,252. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Cannington/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7290761</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18556</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18546</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18562</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18560</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18561</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18557</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18558</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18555</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18559</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18563</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10185701</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>CANNINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10423107</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CANNINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10423144</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CANNINGTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13242</id>
   <name>STOCKLAND BRISTOL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
