<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12978</id>
<name>KELSTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.40168097316</lat>
<lon>-2.42871639069186</lon>
<gazetteerText>KELSTON, or KELWESTON, a village and a parish in Keynsham district, Somerset. The village stands on the river Avon, near Saltford r. station, 4 miles NW of Bath; and has a post office under Bristol. The parish comprises 1, 095 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 714. Pop. in 1851, 259; in 1861, 212. Houses, 43. The decrease of pop. arose partly from the discontinuance of brass mills. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged to Shaftesbury Abbey, went to a natural daughter of Henry VIII.; passed to the Harringtons, the Hawkinses, and the Neelds; and is now held by trustees of Mr. Inigo Jones. A mansion was built on it, for the Harringtons, in 1587, by Barozzi, the Italian architect; gave entertainment to Queen Elizabeth and James I.; was, with the exception of some out-buildings, taken down in 1760; and was succeeded by a picturesque structure, built for Sir C&#230;sar Hawkins, nearer the river. A handsome school-house was erected, in 1860, by Col. Inigo Jones. Kelston Round Hill has an altitude of 730 feet above sea level. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;296. * The church was rebuilt and enlarged in 1860; consists of nave, S aisle, and chancel, with a tower; and contains the graves of Sir John Harrington, the wit and poet, Henry Harrington, the musician, and the Very Rev. Sir William Cockburn, Bart. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Kelston/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelston</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645847</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10435195</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>KELSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10435201</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KELSTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
