<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12841</id>
<name>FARLEIGH HUNGERFORD</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3163460195665</lat>
<lon>-2.28657469577141</lon>
<gazetteerText>FARLEIGH-HUNGERFORD, a village and a parish in Frome district, Somerset. The village stands on the river Frome, adjacent to Wilts, 2&#189; miles S by E of Freshford r. station, and 8 SSE of Bath; occupies a pleasant spot, commanding picturesque views; claims a very remote antiquity; and has a tolerable inn. The parish comprises 904 acres. Post town, Charterhouse-Hinton, under Bath. Real property, &#163;1, 862. Pop., 127. Houses, 32. The property is divided among a few. The manor was given, by William the Conqueror, to Roger de Cour-celle; and passed to the Montforts, the Burghershes, the Hungerfords, and the Bayntons. A castle was built on it, in the times of Richard II. and Henry IV., by the Hungerfords; and was held, in the civil war of Charles I., for the king. This appears to have comprised an oval double court, with towers upon the walls; but it is now an utter ruin, consisting of a strong arched entrance, two ivy-mantled towers, and some fragments of thick walls. The chapel still stands within the enclosure; has later English windows, with traces elsewhere of early English; and contains armour, altar - tombs, and other monuments of the Hungerfords. Farleigh House is the seat of the Houltons. A Roman pavement was found in 1685. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;195.* Patron, J. T. Houlton, Esq. The church was recently enlarged. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/FarleighHungerford/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Farleigh_Hungerford</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10431281</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>FARLEIGH HUNGERFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10431293</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FARLEIGH HUNGERFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
