<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13246</id>
<name>STOGURSEY</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1937624606179</lat>
<lon>-3.12026546839378</lon>
<gazetteerText>STOGURSEY, or StokeCourcy, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Williton district, Somerset. The village stands 8&#189; miles NW of Bridgewater r. station; was once a market-town; sent members to parliament in the time of Edward III.; and has a post-office&#8225; under Bridgewater, and fairs on 24 May and 23 Sept.&#151;The parish contains also five hamlets, extends to the coast, and comprises 5,853 acres of land and 3,040 of water. Rated property, &#163;9,669. Pop., 1,455. Houses, 314. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged anciently to the De Courcys; and, with Fairfield House, belongs now to Sir P. Acland, Bart. A moated castle of the De Courcys was here, and has left some remains. A battle between the Danes and the Saxons was fought here in 845. The living is a vicarage, united with Lilstock, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;467.* Patron, Eton College. The church is Norman and early English; includes part of a priory cell, founded in the time of Henry II.; and was restored in 1865, at a cost of about &#163;6,000. There are chapels for Independents and Baptists, an elegant national school of 1860, alms houses with &#163;208 a year, and other charities &#163;114. -The sub-district contains 8 parishes. Acres, 18,628. Pop., 2,677. Houses, 547. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Stogursey/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stogursey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636870</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18606</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18614</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18605</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18610</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18604</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18607</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18609</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18611</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18612</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18608</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18613</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10106904</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>STOGURSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10442140</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>STOGURSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10442205</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STOGURSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549838</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STOGURSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12759307</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>STOGURSEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12987</id>
   <name>KILTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
