<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1056</id>
<name>PORTISHEAD</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.4833869799631</lat>
<lon>-2.77470960376865</lon>
<gazetteerText>PORTISHEAD, or Portsheadpopularly Posseta village and a parish in Bedminster district, Somerset. The village stands on the Severn&apos;s estuary, under woodedhills, at the end of Wans dyke, and at the terminus of the Bristol and Portishead railway, opposite King&apos;s Road, 3&#188; miles W S W of the mouth of the river Avon, and 9 W by N of Bristol; is supposed to have been anciently the harbour of Portbury; is now a watering-place, with a gay assemblage of villas; commands a charming view over the Severn&apos;s estuary to the coast and mountains of Wales; and has a post-office&#8225; under Clevedon, a railway-station, a handsome hotel, and marine baths. A steamer pliesdaily, in summer, to Bristol: and magnificent plans have been entertained for forming a series of docks, on a scalesuitable for ocean steamers. The parish contains also the hamlet of North-Weston; and comprises 2,093 acres ofland, and 295 of water. Real property, &#163;7, 771. Pop.in 1851, 1,084; in 1861, 1, 201. Houses, 250. A fortwas formerly at P. Point; was taken from the royalists, in 1645, by Fairfax; and has left some remains. ancient camp was in the parish, 1, 200 feet by 600; and alsohas left some remains. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;729.* Patron, the Rev. F. Norman. The church is early English; and consists of nave, aisle, and chancel, with a fine tower. There are chapels for Independents, Quakers, and Wesleyans,, a national school, and charities &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portishead_and_North_Weston</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640037</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Portishead/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10154169</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>PORTISHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10216916</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>PORTISHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439474</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>PORTISHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439486</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PORTISHEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578656</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>PORTISHEAD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12601</id>
   <name>CLAPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13383</id>
   <name>NORTH WESTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13385</id>
   <name>WESTON IN GORDANO</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
