<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12454</id>
<name>BECKINGTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2664162496167</lat>
<lon>-2.27058448945681</lon>
<gazetteerText>BECKINGTON, a village and a parish in Frome district, Somerset. The village stands near the river Frome and the East Somerset railway, 3 miles NE of Frome; and has a post office&#8225; under Bath. It was formerly a place of some importance, carrying on woollen manufactures; but has suffered greatly from the decline of the clothing trade. The parish includes also the hamlet of Rudge. Acres, 1,830. Real property, &#163;5,243. Pop., 1,036. Houses, 229. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory, united with the rectory of Standerwick, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;540.* Patron, S. L. Sainsbury, Esq. The church was restored in 1861, and it contains monuments of the Seymours and the poet Daniel. There are a Baptist chapel, national, British, and boarding schools, and charities &#163;23. Thomas Beckington, Bishop of Bath and Wells, who figured in the legislation against the Wickliffites, was a native; and Huish, one of the editors of the Polyglott Bible, was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656055</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beckington</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Beckington/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10421238</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BECKINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10421240</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BECKINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10421251</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BECKINGTON WITH STANDERWICK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12457</id>
   <name>BERKLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13038</id>
   <name>LAVERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13080</id>
   <name>LULLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13132</id>
   <name>ORCHARDLEIGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13425</id>
   <name>WOOLVERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
