<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13107</id>
<name>WEST MONKTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0435919737627</lat>
<lon>-3.06277656353594</lon>
<gazetteerText>MONKTON (WEST), a village and a parish in Taunton district, Somerset. The village stands on a spur of the Quantock hills, 2 or 2&#189; miles N of the Bridgewater canal, the Bristol and Exeter railway, and the river Tone, and 3&#189; NE by N of# Taunton; and has a post office, of the name of Monkton, under Taunton. The parish con tains also the hamlets of Bathpool and Gotton. Acres, 3,079. Real property, &#163;8,538. Pop., 1,153. Houses, 248. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to Miss Warre. Monkton House is the seat of Capt. Shuldham; Walford House, of R.. K. M. King, Esq.; Court Place, of J. A. Kinglake, Esq.; Sidbrool House, of R. Hedley, Esq.; Springfield House, of Mrs. Sweet; and Creechbarrow, on the Tone, of Captain Beadon. M any spots command splendid views &apos;&apos;T here are several quarries, and considerable flour mills. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;700. * Patron, the Rev. W.Kinglake. The church is later English, simple but very symmetrical; and consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower. There are a national school, alms houses with i45 a year, and other charities &#163;6. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/WestMonkton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Monkton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634339</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10438329</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WEST MONKTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438330</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST MONKTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
