<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12334</id>
<name>ASHBRITTLE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.9894507875158</lat>
<lon>-3.35518961571394</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHBRITTLE, a parish in Wellington district, Somerset; on the verge of the county, and on the river Tone, near the Western canal, 3&#188; miles from the Bristol and Exeter railway, 6 miles W by S of Wellington. It includes the tything of Greenham; and its Post Town is Wellington, Somerset. Acres, 2,489. Real property, &#163;3,715. Pop., 525. Houses, 100. The property is subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;450.* Patron, J. Quicke, Esq. The church is mainly old, partly new. There are a chapel of ease, built in 1860, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Ashbrittle/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashbrittle</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7292428</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10418252</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ASHBRITTLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418288</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASHBRITTLE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12342</id>
<name>LONG ASHTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.4316359739955</lat>
<lon>-2.65692070110781</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHTON (Long), a parish and a subdistrict in Bedminster district, Somerset. The parish lies on the Bristol and Exeter railway, near Wans Dyke and Dundry Beacon, 3 miles SW of Bristol. It contains Bedminster workhouse, and Bower-Ashton, Kingcott, Providence, Yanley, and Rownham hamlets; and has a post office under Bristol. Acres, 4,237. Real property, &#163;10,535. Pop., 2,000. Houses, 297. The centre is a fertile wooded vale; partly disposed in market gardens and orchards, for sending vegetables and fruit to Bristol. The N rises into a range of bleak but picturesque hills, which command a grand view of the surrounding country. The S goes up to Barrow Common, which is sometimes deemed extra-parochial, and has remains of Roman camps at Stokeleigh and Burwalls. The chief residence is Ashton Court: which see. Many Roman coins have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;450.* Patrons, Sir J. Smyth, Bart., and W. G. Langton, Esq. The church dates from 1390; has a carved Gothic screen, dividing the chancel from the nave and aisles; contains figured stained windows and some handsome monuments; and is surmounted by a tower, with the arms of the Lyons family in stone. There are an Independent chapel, an endowed school with &#163;14, and other charities with &#163;142 Collinson, the county historian, was vicar.-The subdistrict comprises seven parishes. Acres, 19,349. Pop., 5,864. Houses, 1,073. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/LongAshton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_Ashton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643726</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075518</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>LONG ASHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10107763</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>LONG ASHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418409</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LONG ASHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418458</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONG ASHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549980</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LONG ASHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12752520</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>SOMERSETSHIRE NORTHERN</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12360</id>
   <name>BACKWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12856</id>
   <name>FLAX BOURTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13041</id>
   <name>ABBOTS LEIGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>12345</id>
<name>ASHWICK</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2289217663374</lat>
<lon>-2.52702211995891</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHWICK, a parish in Shepton-Mallet district, Somerset; on the Fosseway, near Masbury camp, 3&#190; miles NNE of Shepton-Mallet r. station. It includes part of the hamlet of Oakhill, which has a post office under Bath. Acres, 1,525. Real property, &#163;4,179. Pop., 778. Houses, 201. The property is divided among ten. Ashwick Grove is the seat of the Stracheys. Coal is worked. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;113. Patron, the Vicar of Kilmersdon. The church is good; and there are three dis senting chapels, and charities &#163;13. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Ashwick/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashwick</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301177</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10418460</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>ASHWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418525</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASHWICK</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12327</id>
<name>ASH</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.9917754291786</lat>
<lon>-2.74285875329103</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASH, a hamlet and a chapelry in Martock parish, Somerset. The hamlet stands near the Durston and Yeovil railway, 3 miles Sw of Ilchester. Pop., 322. The chapelry includes the hamlet, and was constituted in 1845. Post Town, Martock under Ilminster. Pop., 580. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;62. Patron, the Vicar of Martock. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ash_(near_Taunton)</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Ash/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ash_(near_Yeovil)</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7292405</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10418057</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>ASH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418136</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12339</id>
<name>ASHILL</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.9523205745189</lat>
<lon>-2.96391062124897</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHILL, a village and a parish in Chard district, Somerset. The village stands near Chard canal, and near the Chard and Taunton railway, 4 miles NW of Ilminster, and 8 SSE of Taunton. It has a post office under Ilminster, and fairs on Easter-Wednesday, and on 12 Sept. or the following Wednesday. The parish comprises 1,790 acres. Real property, &#163;3,324. Pop., 445. Houses, 92. The property is much subdivided. A spring which ebbs and flows is near the village. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Bath and Wells. The church is ancient, and was recently restored. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Ashill/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashill,_Somerset</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301207</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10418320</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ASHILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418343</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASHILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12340</id>
<name>ASHINGTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.9899932726474</lat>
<lon>-2.62742686272464</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHINGTON, a parish in Yeovil district, Somerset; on the river Yeo, and on the Durston and Yeovil railway, 3&#189; miles N of Yeovil. Post Town, Ilchester under Taunton. Acres, 554. Real property, with Draycott, &#163;1,957. Pop., 57. Houses, 10. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;162.* Patron, not reported. The church is good. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Ashington/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10418355</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ASHINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10418392</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASHINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12303</id>
<name>AISHOLT</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.113108030077</lat>
<lon>-3.14546953693607</lon>
<gazetteerText>AISHOLT, or Asholt, a parish in Bridgewater district, Somerset; 4&#189; miles E of Crowcombe-Heathfield r. station, and 7&#189; W by S of Bridgewater. It has a post office under Bridgewater. Acres, 1,252. Real property, &#163;2,643. Pop., 181. Houses, 41. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;280. Patron, Rev. Josh. West. The church is good. Charities, &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2657589</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Aisholt/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aisholt</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18547</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18549</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18554</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18548</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18550</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18551</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18553</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18552</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10417340</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>AISHOLT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10417491</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>AISHOLT</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>12336</id>
<name>ASHCOTT</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1264311309799</lat>
<lon>-2.80865870915405</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHCOTT, a parish in Bridgewater district, Somerset; near the Glastonbury railway, 5 miles WSW of Glastonbury. It has a station on the railway, and a post office under Bath; and includes the hamlet of Pedwell. Acres, 2,272. Real property, &#163;4,328. Pop., 817. Houses, 183 The manor belonged to Glastonbury Abbey. The living is a vicarage, annexed to Shapwick, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. The church was restored in 1860. There are a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;70. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656965</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Ashcott/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashcott</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15103</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10418290</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>ASHCOTT</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24096</id>
<name>ASHTON GATE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.4412772046007</lat>
<lon>-2.61731131048252</lon>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashton_Gate</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7645435</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10421317</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BEDMINSTER ST FRANCIS ASHTON GATE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
