<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12826</id>
<name>ENMORE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1109758606518</lat>
<lon>-3.08873851420658</lon>
<gazetteerText>ENMORE, a parish in Bridgewater district, Somerset; under the Quantock hills, on an affluent of the river Parret, 4 miles WSW of Bridgewater town and r. station. It has a post office under Bridgewater. Acres, 1, 112. Real property, &#163;3, 095. Pop., 314. Houses, 63. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged, at the Conquest, to the Courcelles; passed to the Mallets, the Bayntuns and others; came to the Percevals, Earls of Egmont; and belongs now to the Trevelyans. The mansion on it, Enmore Castle, was built by the first Earl of Egmont; and is a large quadrangular embattled pile, constructed of a dark reddish-coloured stone, flanked at each angle by a low square machicolated tower, with a bastion and two circular towers at the principal entrance. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;183.* Patron, the Rev. J. Levien. The church adjoins the castle; has an Anglo-Norman doorway; and is good. The churchyard contains old yew trees, and the steps and shaft of an ancient cross. Charities, &#163;13. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Enmore/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649986</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18526</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18523</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18528</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18527</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18522</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18524</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18525</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=18529</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10430987</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>ENMORE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10431098</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ENMORE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
