<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1049</id>
<name>RADSTOCK</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2921344204435</lat>
<lon>-2.4473537585562</lon>
<gazetteerText>RADSTOCK, a village and a parish in Clutton district, Somerset. The village stands on the Fosse way, on a small affluent of the river Avon, at a meeting-point of railways forming in 1868 from Frome, Bath, and Keynsham, 7 miles N W of Frome; takes its name from redsandstone lying below and around it; is the centre of anextensive coal-field; was connected, by mineral railway, with the canal near Mitford, and with the Great Western railway at Frome; and has a post-office&#8225; under Bath. The parish comprises 1,005 acres. Real property, &#163;14, 548; of which &#163;9, 202 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 1, 792; in 1861, 2, 227. Houses, 413. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Countess of Waldegrave. Round Hill barrow is near the village. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;270.* Patron, the Countess of Waldegrave. The church consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, withporch and tower. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, Primitive Methodists, United Free Methodists, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Radstock/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radstock</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639715</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10028024</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>RADSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10215470</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>RADSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439735</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RADSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439747</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RADSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439759</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RADSTOCK WITH WRITHLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12462</id>
   <name>BINEGAR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12561</id>
   <name>CHILCOMPTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12825</id>
   <name>EMBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13284</id>
   <name>STRATTON ON THE FOSSE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13433</id>
   <name>WRITHLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13457</id>
   <name>STON EASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
