<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>888</id>
<name>CLEVEDON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.4311112344672</lat>
<lon>-2.84964420572825</lon>
<gazetteerText>CLEVEDON, a village and a parish in Bedminster district, Somerset. The village stands on the coast, under a rocky height called Dial-Hill, at the terminus of a branch railway, 12&#189; miles by road WSW of Bristol. It dates from remote times; but now consists chiefly of a collection of villas built since 1828. It enjoys a moist mild air; is a favourite summer resort for sea-bathing; and has a head post office, &#8225; a railway station with telegraph, two chief inns, marine baths, and a pier 800 feet long, constructed at a cost of &#163;12, 000, and completed in 1869. Dial-Hill commands a magnificent view; and fine walks and rides are in the neighbourhood. Myrtle Cottage here was for some time the residence of the poet S. T. Coleridge; and Clevedon Court, in the vicinity, a noble Tudor mansion amid beautiful grounds, now the seat of Sir Arthur H. Elton, Bart., is associated with the memory of the historian Hallam, whose wife was a daughter of Sir Abraham Elton. Coleridge sang the praises of his cottage in his &quot;Sibylline Leaves;&quot; and the poet Tennyson, in his &quot;In Memoriam&quot; on Arthur Henry Hallam, sings as follows the praises of the village, - There twice a-day the Severn fills; The salt sea-water passes by, And brushes half the babbling Wye, And makes a silence in the hills. The parish comprises 2, 987 acres of land and 1, 080 of water. Real property, &#163;16, 674. Pop., 2, 941. Houses, 463. The property is subdivided. Much of the surface is picturesque. Lead ore was formerly mined. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells; and there are also the p. curacy of Christchurch and the vicarage of East Clevedon. Value of Clevedon, &#163;420; * of Christchurch, not reported; of East Clevedon, &#163;127. Patron of Clevedon, the Bishop of Worcester; of Christchurch, Trustees; of East Clevedon, Sir A. H. Elton, Bart. The old church belonged to St. Augustine abbey in Bristol; is partly Norman, and partly decorated and perpendicular English; and contains the ancient burying-place of the Clevedons, once lords of the manor, and monuments of the Wakes and the Hallams. Christ-church church is a modern edifice in the early English style; and East Clevedon church is in the decorated English style. There are a handsome Independent chapel, Quakers&apos; and Brethren&apos;s chapels, national and British schools, and charities &#163;21. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clevedon</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Clevedon/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652861</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10081646</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>CLEVEDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10166676</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CLEVEDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10425372</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CLEVEDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10425384</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CLEVEDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10425402</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CLEVEDON CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10425414</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CLEVEDON ST JOHN THE EVANGELIST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12829048</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CLEVEDON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12979</id>
   <name>KENN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13002</id>
   <name>KINGSTON SEYMOUR</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13368</id>
   <name>WALTON IN GORDANO</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>24428</id>
<name>EAST CLEVEDON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.438981319063</lat>
<lon>-2.84174905117515</lon>
<gazetteerText>East Clevedon, eccl. dist., Clevedon par., Somerset, pop. 886. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10425426</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EAST CLEVEDON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
