<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12366</id>
<name>BANWELL</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3422135221413</lat>
<lon>-2.87609566380439</lon>
<gazetteerText>BANWELL, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Axbridge, Somerset. The village stands under Banwell Hill, at the NW extremity of the Mendip range, 3 miles SE of the Bristol and Exeter railway, and 4 NNW of Axbridge. It has a station on the railway, a post office&#8225; under Weston-super-Mare, and two inns; and was formerly a seat of petty sessions. A fair is held at it on 18 January, or on the following Monday. A monastery was founded here by some early Saxon king; had for one of its abbots. Asserins or Asser, the biographer of King Alfred; was destroyed by the Danes, and afterwards restored; but seems to have given place to an Episcopal palace; and ceased to be monastic long before the dissolution of monasteries A mineral well in the vicinity expands into a lakelet, drives two mills, and sends off a rivulet to the Bristol Channel near Woodspring priory. The parish contains also the hamlets of Knightcot, East and West Rolston, towerhead, West wick and Waywick, Woolfordshill, and Yarborough. Acres, 4,829. Real property, &#163;15,880. Pop., 1,853. Houses, 362. The property is much subdivided. Ban well-hill belongs chiefly to Captain Law, grandson of the late Bishop of Bath and Wells; and has an obelisk, erected by that prelate. The manor has belonged, since the time of Edward the Confessor, to the Bishops of Bath and Wells. A palace was built on it by Bishop Beckington, but went into neglect, and now is represented only by a large farmhouse and offices, called Banwell Court, and by a cottage orn&#233;e. Two remark able caverns, discovered in 1824, and now so famous as to draw many visitors, occur on the skirts of Banwell Hill; the one, called the Stalactite cavern, presenting many beautiful specimens of translucent stalactites; the other, called the Bone cavern, found to have contained many bones of bears, buffalos, deer, wolves, foxes, and other animals, mingled with diluvium. Bowles depicts a geological crisis, at which he fancies the bones to have been deposited, in his poem of &quot;Banwell Hill or Days Departed.&quot; The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;702.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Bristol. The church is later English; and has a richly-carved screen, a finely sculptured stone pulpit, a circular font, and three brasses. There are a-Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;17.-The subdistrict comprises eight parishes. Acres, 19,906. Pop., 12,649. Houses, 2,043. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Banwell</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Banwell/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656378</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10418951</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BANWELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10419001</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BANWELL</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12592</id>
   <name>CHRISTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>703</id>
<name>WESTON SUPER MARE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3466449613714</lat>
<lon>-2.96970229299557</lon>
<gazetteerText>WESTON-SUPER-MARE, a town and a parish in Axbridge district, Somerset. The town stands on the coast, at the terminus of a short branch of the Bristol and Exeter railway, under the rocky fir-covered Worle hill, 3 miles NE of Brean-Down point, and 20 SW by W of Bristol; was, so late as 1810, a poor small fishing hamlet; suffered then, and for years afterwards, such extensive depositions of ooze from the tide as to be nick-named Weston-super-Mud; underwent great and rapid change, in result of becoming a watering-place; rose to a population of nearly 4,000 in 1851, and doubled that population before the end of 1861: acquired, onward to 1869, such increasingly great improvements as to become a very handsome town and a first-rate sea-bathing resort; comprises many fine streets, terraces, and crescents, together with numerous detached elegant residences; includes a fine open space, called Ellenborough Park lined along the sides with ornamental villas; enjoys a salubrious climate, a good bathing beach, and charming environs; is a seat of petty-sessions and county courts; publishes two weekly newspapers; carries on fine pottery manufacture in two establishments, and a very extensive sprat fishery; and has a new and handsome head post-office,&#8225; a very fine r. station with telegraph, two new and handsome banking offices, three hotels, a town hall in the Venetian style, built at a cost of &#163;3,000, a handsome suite of assembly-rooms, a gentlemen&apos;s club-house of 1869, a market-hall built in 1854 and enlarged in 1859, a promenade-pier 1,100 feet long and 20 feet wide, completed in 1867 at a cost of &#163;20,000, a steam-boat landing-stage beyond the pier, new harbour works at Brean-Down, a parochial church rebuilt in 1824 and enlarged in 1837, another church in the later English style built in 1847, two other churches built in 1855 and 1861, each with a tower and spire, an Independent chapel of 1858, with very fine front steeple, a Baptist chapel of 1866, cruciform and second-pointed, three other dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a tasteful cemetery of 7&#189; acres, with two fine mortuary chapels, a mechanics&apos; institute, subscription reading rooms, a school of art, national and British schools, and some charities. The parish includes Ashcombe and Milton hamlets, and comprises 1,590 acres of land and 1,180 of water-Real property, &#163;36,639; of which &#163;384 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 4,034; in 1861, 8,038. Houses, 1,127. Pop. in 1869, about 12,000. Traces of ancient camps are on Worle hill; and various objects interesting to antiquaries, geologists, and tourists, are in the near vicinity. The head living or St. John&apos;s is a rectory, and the livings of Emmanuel, Christchurch, and Trinity are p. curacies, in the diocese of Bath and Wells Value of St. J., &#163;264;* of E., &#163;148; of C., &#163;138; of T., not reported. Patron of St. J., the Bishop of B and. W.; of E., C., and T., Trustees. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/WestonSuperMare/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weston-super-Mare</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10135310</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10174004</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446016</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446053</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446089</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446119</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446132</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE EMMANUEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446144</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE HOLY TRINITY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446168</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE ST ANDREW BOURNEVILLE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446193</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446200</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE ST SAVIOUR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549735</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741110</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12751400</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>SOMERSETSHIRE WESTON SUPER MARE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835991</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WESTON SUPER MARE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12366</id>
   <name>BANWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12465</id>
   <name>BLEADON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12468</id>
   <name>BREAN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12658</id>
   <name>COMPTON BISHOP</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12980</id>
   <name>KEWSTOKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13052</id>
   <name>LOCKING</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13362</id>
   <name>UPHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13404</id>
   <name>WICK ST LAWRENCE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13412</id>
   <name>WINSCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13428</id>
   <name>WORLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
