<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13086</id>
<name>BISHOPS LYDEARD</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0652425432074</lat>
<lon>-3.179631005477</lon>
<gazetteerText>BISHOPS-LYDEARD, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Taunton, Somerset. The village stands near the Quantock hills, adjacent to the Taunton and Watchet railway, 5 miles NNW of Taunton; and has a station on the railway, a post office&#8225; under Taunton, and a fair on 5 April. The parish includes the tythings of Lydeard-Punchardon, Town, Church, East Bagborough, Quantock-Hill, East Coombe, CamesAsh, Ash-Week, and Free, and the hamlet of Kenley-Bottom. Acres, 4,686. Real property, &#163;9,086. Pop., 1,459. Houses, 292. The property is divided among a few. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;120.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Wells. The church has a very beautiful tower, in perpendicular English, of the time of Henry VII.; and was repaired in 1860. There are two sculptured crosses in the churchyard, an Independent chapel, a parochial school, a petty sessions courthouse, ten alms-houses with &#163;126 a year, and other charities &#163;40. The Rev. F. Warre, who became vicar in 1836, is known for learned local researches.-The subdistrict contains nine parishes. Pop., 4,030. Houses, 811. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/BishopsLydeard/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655564</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bishops_Lydeard</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10437817</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BISHOPS LYDEARD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10437829</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BISHOPS LYDEARD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549693</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BISHOPS LYDEARD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12331</id>
   <name>ASH PRIORS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12644</id>
   <name>COMBE FLOREY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12919</id>
   <name>HALSE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13087</id>
   <name>LYDEARD ST LAWRENCE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
