<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13093</id>
<name>MARK</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2190535017615</lat>
<lon>-2.89520270727497</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARK, a village and a parish in Axbridge district, Somerset. The village stands near the source of the river Brue, 2&#189; miles ENE of Bason-Bridge r. station, and 6&#189; SW by S of Axbridge; and has a post office under Bridgewater, and fairs on the Tuesday before Whitsunday, the Monday before 20 Aug., and the Monday before 20 Sept. The parish contains also the hamlets of Northwick, Southwick, Perry, Yarrow, Vole, Pilbrow, KingsRoad, Harp-Road, Dutch-Road, Yard-Wall, and RiverBridge; and is cut into two sections, E and W. Acres, 4,354. Real property, &#163;14,462. Pop., 1,217. Houses, 269. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to John F. Frazer, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Earl of Chichester. The church is of the 14th century: consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and was restored in 1864. A Wesleyan chapel, in lieu of an old one, was built in 1870. There are a Baptist chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;30. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643035</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Mark/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10438007</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>MARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438019</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARK</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>13094</id>
<name>MARKSBURY</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3585235497468</lat>
<lon>-2.4823771694912</lon>
<gazetteerText>MARKSBURY, a village and a parish in Keynsham district, Somerset. The village stands 3&#189; miles S of Keynsham r. station, and 5&#189; WSW of Bath; and has a post office under Bristol. The parish contains also the hamlet of Houndstreet. Acres, 1,277. Real property, &#163;2,590. Pop., 307. Houses, 65. The property is divided among a few. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;240.* Patron, F. L. Polpham, Esq. The church is ancient but good; and consists of nave and chancel, with porch and tower. There are a Wesleyan chapel and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marksbury</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Marksbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643015</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10438020</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MARKSBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438032</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MARKSBURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
