<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13422</id>
<name>WOOKEY</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.211365658139</lat>
<lon>-2.70987630987097</lon>
<gazetteerText>WOOKEY, or Wokey, a parish, with W. village, and W.-Hole and Henton hamlets, in Wells district, Somerset; 2 miles W by N of Wells r. station. It has a post-office under Wells, Somerset. Acres, 3,420. Rated property, &#163;5,037. Pop., 1,129. Houses, 253. The property is much subdivided. An ancient Episcopal palace stood on a site now occupied by a modern residence, called Mellefont Abbey. W.-Hole cavern penetrates a limestone rock to the extent of 120 feet; was noticed by some very early writers, and described by Dr. Harring-ton of Bath; was the legendary haunt of the &quot;Witch of Wookey,&apos;&apos; who figures in a ballad in Percy&apos;s &quot;Reliques;&apos;&apos; is much visited by tourists; and emits a rapid streamlet which, within a short distance, drives several paper and flour mills. Interesting fossils and Roman relics have been found in and near the cave. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;309.* Patron, the Bishop of B. and W. The church is good. The vicarage of Henton is a separate benefice. There are a national school and charities &#163;46. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Wookey/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wookey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633610</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10446843</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WOOKEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10446867</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WOOKEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23955</id>
<name>WOOKEY HOLE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2260560023509</lat>
<lon>-2.67028526253153</lon>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wookey_Hole</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10446879</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WOOKEY HOLE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
