<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12959</id>
<name>HINTON ST GEORGE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>50.9078696955112</lat>
<lon>-2.82901012759454</lon>
<gazetteerText>HINTON-ST. GEORGE, a village and a parish in Chard district, Somerset. The village stands 4 miles NW of Crewkerne r. station, and 4 ESE of Ilminster; is well built; has a post office under Taunton, and a fair on 23 April; and gives the title of Viscount to Earl Poulett. The parish comprises 1, 500 acres, and is the property of Earl Poulett. Real property, &#163;4, 123. Pop., 761. Houses, 167. The manor belonged to the Powtnels and the Denebands, and passed to the Pouletts. Hinton House is the seat of Earl Poulett; dates from the time of Henry VII.; has a garden front designed by Inigo Jones; and stands in a fine park of about 600 acres. Family pictures in it were given to the great Lord Clarendon, and are now at the Grove in Herts and at Bothwell castle in Scotland. Vantage grounds in the parish command extensive and beautiful views; and one of them has glimpses of both Bristol channel and the English channel. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;200.* Patron, Earl Poulett. The church is early English; comprises nave, S aisle, and chancel, with S porch and lofty tower; and has a fine memorial window, of recent erection, to the children of Earl Poulett. There are a national school and charities &#163;68. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/HintonStGeorge/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hinton_St_George</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10434660</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HINTON ST GEORGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10434671</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HINTON ST GEORGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10434695</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HINTON ST GEORGE WITH DINNINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
