<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12778</id>
<name>DULVERTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0502226876182</lat>
<lon>-3.56843846834373</lon>
<gazetteerText>DULVERTON, a small town, a parish, and a sub-district in the district of Tiverton and county of Somerset. The town stands on the river Barle, amid an amphitheatre of wooded hills, adjacent to Exmoor, 10 miles W of Wiveliscombe, and 12 NNW of Tiverton r. station. It consists chiefly of two neat streets; has a post office&#8225; under Tiverton, three good inns, a five-arched bridge, a parish church, a dissenting chapel, a school with &#163;29 from endowment, and other charities with &#163;28; carries on manufactures in silks and woollens; has markets on Saturdays, and fairs on 10 July and 8 Nov.; and is a seat of sessions, and a polling place. The church is early English, with an embattled tower and a corner turret; was restored in 1853; and contains monuments of the Svdenhams. The parish comprises 8, 337 acres. Real property, &#163;7, 653. Pop., 1, 552. Houses, 301. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the West Saxon kings; was given, by Edward I., to the Pynes; and passed to the Babbingtons and the Sydenhams. The scenery is highly picturesque; and an open spot, called Mount Sydenham, in a wood above the town, commands a very magnificent view. The hills and heaths are much frequented by sportsmen; and serve as meets for the Dulverton harriers, the Tiverton hounds, and the Devon and Somerset hounds. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;322.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Wells.&#151;The sub-district contains eleven parishes and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 73, 727. Pop., 6, 051. Houses, 1, 158. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dulverton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Dulverton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Dulverton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650804</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001547</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>DULVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10112140</id>
   <status>PLU/RegD</status>
   <name>DULVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10193989</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>DULVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429602</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>DULVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10429626</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DULVERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549840</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>DULVERTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2404</id>
   <name>MOLLAND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4872</id>
   <name>OAKFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5775</id>
   <name>EAST ANSTEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12490</id>
   <name>BROMPTON REGIS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12493</id>
   <name>BRUSHFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12834</id>
   <name>EXFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12840</id>
   <name>EXTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13413</id>
   <name>WINSFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13416</id>
   <name>WITHIEL FLOREY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13420</id>
   <name>WITHYPOOL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
