<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13109</id>
<name>MOORLINCH</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1439798696076</lat>
<lon>-2.8730494447878</lon>
<gazetteerText>MOORLINCH, a village, a township, and a parish in Bridgewater district, Somerset. The village stands 3&#190; miles ESE of Shapwick r. station, and 6&#188; E of Bridgewater; and has a fair on 20 Aug. The township comprises 1,122 acres. Real property, &#163;2,454. Pop. in 1851,378; in 1861,334. Houses, 81. The parish contains also the chapelries of Catcott, Edington, Sutton-Mallett, Stawell, and Chilton-upon-Polden; and its Post town is Ashcott, under Bath. Acres, 9,252. Real property, &#163;19,368. Pop. in 1851,2,439; in 1861,2,329. Houses, 534. The property is subdivided. The manor belongs to B.Greenhill, Esq. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelries of Stawell and Sutton-Mallett, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;500.* Patron, the Rev. R. J. Luscombe. The church is partly early English; and consist of nave and chancel, with a tower. The p. curacies of Catcott, Burtle, and Edington-with-Chilton-upon-Polden, are separate benefices. There are independent chapels in Moorlinch and Chilton-upon-Polden, a Wesleyan chapel in Catcott, a Primitive Methodist chapel in Bur.le, and national schools in Moorlinch and Catcott. The charities amount to &#163;152. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/SuttonMallet/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Moorlinch/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7301202</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15117</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=15112</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10438366</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MOORLINCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438380</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MOORLINCH WITH STAWELL AND SUTTON MALLET</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
