<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13099</id>
<name>MELLS</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.2419391791425</lat>
<lon>-2.40141768859883</lon>
<gazetteerText>MELLS, a village and a parish in Frome district, Somerset. The village stands in a valley 3&#189; miles WNW of Frome r. station; is a large place; and has a postoffice under Frome, and fairs on the second Monday after Whit-Monday and on 29 Sept. The parish contains also the hamlet of Vobster. Acres, 3,611. Real property, &#163;7,184; of which &quot;960 are in mines, and &#163;120 in iron-works. Pop. in 1851,1,186; in 1861,972. Houses, 222. The decrease of pop. was caused by a regulation which does not allow more than one family to occupy a cottage. The property is divided among a few. The manor, Mells Park, and much of the land belong to the Rev. J. S. H. Horner. The rocks include coal, pipe-clay, fuller&apos;s-earth, lead ore, and manganese. Coal is worked; brick-making and lime-burning are carried on; and the manufacture of agricultural edge tools, long famous for their superior quality, is conducted in two factories. There are remains of several ancient camps. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;630.* Patron, the Rev. J. S. H. Horner. The church is later English; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with pinnacled tower; and has very fine painted w indows. The vicarage of Vobster, with Leigh-upon-Mendip, is a separate benefice. There are a Wesleyan chapel, a Church school, and parish lands &#163;75. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mells,_Somerset</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Mells/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642776</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10438123</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MELLS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438135</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MELLS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12845571</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>MELLS AND LEIGH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12499</id>
   <name>BUCKLAND DINHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12770</id>
   <name>DOWNHEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12820</id>
   <name>ELM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12924</id>
   <name>HARDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13394</id>
   <name>WHATLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
