<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13112</id>
<name>NAILSEA</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.4239875410057</lat>
<lon>-2.77904864419565</lon>
<gazetteerText>NAILSEA, a village and a parish in Bedminster district, Somerset. The village stands adjacent to the Bristol and Exeter railway, 8 miles W S W of Bristol; isconsiderable place; and has a station on the railway and a head post-office, &#8225; designated Nailsea, Somersetshire. The parish is divided into the tythings of East N., Middle N., and West N. Acres, 2, 771. Real property, &#163;11, 660; of which &#163;1, 600 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 2, 543; in 1861, 2, 278. Houses, 475. The decrease of pop. arose from depression in the glass manufacture, and from emigration. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to Sir J. H. Greville Smyth, Bart. There are collieries, stone quarries, glass-works, corn mills, saw mills, a tannery, and a smallbrewery. A large tract of moorland was enclosed under an act of 1813. A section of the parish, which had a pop. of 955 in 1861, was constituted a separate charge, under the name of Christchurch, in 1844. The headliving is a rectory, and that of Christchurch is a p.curacy, in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value of therectory, &#163;300; * of the p. curacy, &#163;120. Patron of theformer, the Rev. F. Brown; of the latter, the Rector. The parish church, or church of the Holy Trinity, is later English; was thoroughly repaired in 1861; consists of nave, aisles, and chancel, with a tower; and contains a remarkable stone pulpit. Christchurch was built in 1844; is in the early English style; and consists of nave and chancel. There are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and United Free Methodists, and two national schools. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Nailsea/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nailsea</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641913</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10438433</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>NAILSEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438445</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NAILSEA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10438457</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NAILSEA CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12475</id>
   <name>BROCKLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13345</id>
   <name>TICKENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
