<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12522</id>
<name>CASTLE CARY</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.0777628952256</lat>
<lon>-2.53390680992193</lon>
<gazetteerText>CASTLE-CARY, a small town, a parish, and a subdistrict in Wincanton district, Somerset. The town stands on valley and on slopes, amid charming environs, adjacent to the East Somerset railway, 12 miles NNE of Yeovil. A castle at it was built by the Lovells, and made a figure in the civil wars of the time of Stephen; but has disappeared. A manor house adjacent, gave shelter to Charles II. after the battle of Worcester; but has been almost demolished. A beautifully broken hillside, called Castle-Cary Park, was probably the chase of the lords of the manor; and commands a very splendid and extensive view. The principal street of the town runs up a hollow between two hills. The market house is an elegant edifice, built in 1855, at a cost of &#163;2,300; and contains an assembly room upwards of 50 feet long. The parish church surmounts a hillock; has a tower and spire, erected in 1855; is itself partly decorated English of the time of Henry I., partly recent reconstruction; and contains an old font and a richly carved pulpit. There are Independent and Wesleyan chapels, a national school, a post office&#8225; under Bath, a railway station, a banking office, and three chief inns. Markets are held on Mondays; and fairs on the Tuesday before Palm-Sunday, 1 May, Whit-Tuesday, and the Tuesday after 19 Sept. Some trade is carried on in flax-spinning and hair-cloth-weaving.&#151;The parish includes also the hamlets of Clanville, Dimmer, and Cockhill, and the manor of Foxcombe. Acres, 2,625. Real property, with Almsford, &#163;11,977. Pop., 2,060. Houses, 433. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;312.* Patron, the Bishop of Bath and Wells.-The subdistrict contains fifteen parishes. Acres, 16,906. Pop., 6,129. Houses, 1,303. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Cary</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/CastleCary/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653601</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10423235</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CASTLE CARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10423272</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CASTLE CARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549863</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CASTLE CARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10571170</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CARY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12324</id>
   <name>ANSFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12351</id>
   <name>BABCARY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12507</id>
   <name>NORTH CADBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12511</id>
   <name>QUEEN CAMEL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12513</id>
   <name>WEST CAMEL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12733</id>
   <name>DITCHEAT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13089</id>
   <name>WEST LYDFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13126</id>
   <name>WEST BRADLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13146</id>
   <name>PITCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13229</id>
   <name>SPARKFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
