<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12723</id>
<name>NORTH CURRY</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.018316983333</lat>
<lon>-2.97539141298633</lon>
<gazetteerText>CURRY (North), a village, a tything, a parish, a sub-district, and a hundred, in Somerset. The village stands near the river Tone and the Bridgewater and Taunton canal, 3 miles ESE of Durston r. station, and 6 ENE of Taunton; has a post office&#8225; under Taunton, and a fair on the first Tuesday of Sept.; and was formerly a market-town. The tything includes also the hamlet of Broadlane. The parish contains likewise the tythings of Knapp, Lillesdon and Wrantage. Acres, 5, 556. Real property, &#163;13, 231. Pop., 1,839. Houses, 426. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged anciently to the Saxon kings; and belongs now to the Dean and Chapter of Wells. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;325.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Wells. The church is later English and in good condition. The vicarages of West Hatch and Stoke-St. Gregory are separate benefices. There are Baptist and Wesleyan chapels, and a national school. -The sub-district contains eight parishes; and is in Taunton district. Acres, 17, 064. Pop., 5, 999. Houses, 1, 330. The hundred contains five parishes. Acres, 12, 790. Pop., 4, 276. Houses, 937. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/NorthCurry/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Curry</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641379</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10031140</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>NORTH CURRY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10428040</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>NORTH CURRY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10428063</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTH CURRY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549681</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>NORTH CURRY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
