<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>13145</id>
<name>PILTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1669682518914</lat>
<lon>-2.58483283513159</lon>
<gazetteerText>PILTON, a village and a parish in Shepton-Mallet district, Somerset. The village stands 2&#190; miles S W of Shepton-Mallet r. station, and has a post-office under Shepton-Mallet, and a fair on the Monday after 10 Sept. The parish contains also the hamlet of Ham, East Compton, West Compton, Lower Westholme and Upper Westholme. Acres, 5, 593. Real property, &#163;11, 453. Pop., 1, 202. Houses, 261. The property anciently belonged to Glastonbury abbey, and now is much subdivided. Westholme House, Burford, Springfield House, and Perridge House are chief residences. An ancientbarn, which belonged to Glastonbury abbey, is near thechurch, and has an elegantly constructed roof. There is an extensive brewery, with malt-houses attached. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Bath and Wells. The church is ancient, of different periods; consists of nave, N aisle, and chancel, with porch and tower; contains a piscina and several ancient brasses and monuments; and the chancel was recently repaired, and has a large and fine E window. There are chapels for Wesleyans and Bible Christians, a national school, and charities &#163;9. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pilton,_Somerset</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640282</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Pilton/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10439334</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PILTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10439346</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PILTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
