<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12610</id>
<name>OLD CLEEVE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.1462302557569</lat>
<lon>-3.37746747608871</lon>
<gazetteerText>CLEEVE (Old), a parish in Williton district, Somerset; on the coast, adjacent to the Brendon-Hills and the Taunton and Watchet railway, 2 miles SW of Watchet r. station. It includes the chapelry of Leighland, and the hamlets of Warren, London, Binham, Chapel-Cleeve, Blue Anchor, Bilbrook, Pittaker, Hungerford, Stouts, Roughmore, Pancras, Roadwater, Croydon, Goldoncott, Traphole, Pitt, Chidgley, Stacklepath, Hookhill, Old-house, Prettys, Stanborough, and part of Washford; and its post town is Williton, under Taunton. Acres, 5, 413; of which 440 are water. Real property, &#163;7, 491. Pop., 1, 529. Houses, 308. The property is divided among a few. High craggy cliffs are on the coast, commanding fine views across the Bristol channel; and alabaster abounds near Blue Anchor, and is collected and ground for cement in a mill at Williton. A Cistertian abbey was founded in the Vallis Florida, or flowery vale, in the time of Henry II., by William de Romana, Earl of Lincoln; and endowed with the property of the entire parish. A gatehouse of it, bearing an inscription, and some dilapidated walls and arches, partly incorporated with farm-buildings, are still standing. A Lady&apos;s chapel, long a resort of devotees, and still represented by some fragments, stood between the church and Blue Anchor. A fragment of a cross, for guidance to the chapel, stands between the church and Washford; and another ancient cross, in tolerable preservation, stands in the churchyard. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;520.* Patron, Rev. J. B. Webb. The church is ancient, with floor slanting upward from the tower to the chancel; but is in good condition. The vicarage of Leighland is a separate benefice. Charities, &#163;18. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/OldCleeve/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7297232</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10425359</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>OLD CLEEVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10425360</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLD CLEEVE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>13114</id>
   <name>NETTLECOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
