<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12615</id>
<name>CLUTTON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.33030963925</lat>
<lon>-2.53467091025665</lon>
<gazetteerText>CLUTTON, a village, a parish, a sub-district, and a district in Somerset. The village stands near Highbury camp, 3 miles S of Pensford, and 6 &#189; SW of Saltford r. station; and has a post office under Bristol. A railway in course of formation in 1869, from Frome to Bristol, passes near the village. The parish comprises 1, 636 acres. Real property, &#163;5, 735; of which &#163;1, 015 are in mines, and &#163;152 in quarries. Pop., 1, 149. Houses, 252. The property is all in one estate. There are extensive collieries. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;340.* Patron, the Earl of Warwick. The church is Norman, with a modern tower; and there are chapels for Independents, Wesleyans, and Primitive Methodists. A school has &#163;20 from endowment; and other charities &#163;29. -The sub-district contains the parishes of Clutton, Chelwood, Farnborough, Timsbury, Paulton, and High Littleton. Acres, 7, 684. Pop., 6, 663. Houses, 1, 459. -The district comprehends also the sub-district of Midsomer-Norton, containing the parishes of Midsomer-Norton, Farrington, Gurney, Stone-Easton, Chilcompton, Radstock, and Camerton; the sub-district of Chew-Magna, containing the parishes of Chew-Magna, Chew-Stoke, Stowey, Norton-Malreward, Stanton-Drew, Publow, and St. Thomas-in-Pensford, and the ville of Norton-Hawkfield; and the sub-district of Harptree, containing the parishes of East Harptree, West Harptree, Nempnett-Thrubwell, Ubley, Litton, Compton-Martin, Cameley, Hinton-Blewett, and part of Chewton-Mendip. Acres, 47, 026. Poor-rates in 1862, &#163;12, 847. Pop. in 1841, 25, 190; in 1861, 23, 721. Houses, 5, 017. Marriages in 1860, 113: births, 753, -of which 36 were illegitimate; deaths, 443, -of which 130 were at ages under 5 years, and 26 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1, 098; births, 7, 671; deaths, 4, 551. The places of worship in 1851 were 31 of the Church of England, with 9, 768 sittings; 4 of Independents, with 665 s.; 4 of Baptists, with 584 s.; 1 of Quakers, with 100 s.; 26 of Wesleyan Methodists, with 6, 195 s.; 6 of Primitive Methodists, with 530 s.; 6 of Wesleyan Reformers, with 840 s.; 1 of Brethren, with 100 s.; and 1 of Roman Catholics, with 31 attendants. The schools were 33 public day schools, with 2, 480 scholars; 52 private day schools, with 1, 020 s.; 53 Sunday schools, with 4, 299 s.; and 1 evening school for adults, with 6 s. The workhouse is in Clutton. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clutton,_Somerset</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Clutton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652739</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Clutton</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10030274</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>CLUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10107775</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>CLUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10137573</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>CLUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10425530</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CLUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10425566</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CLUTTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>13048</id>
<name>HIGH LITTLETON</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.3156747329845</lat>
<lon>-2.5144254201144</lon>
<gazetteerText>LITTLETON (HIGH), a village and a parish in Clutton district, Somerset. The village stands 8&#189; miles SW by W of Bath r. station, and is considerable.&#151;The parish contains also the hamlet of Hallatrow, which has a postoffice under Bristol. Acres, 1,273. Real property, &#163;4,223. Pop., 860. Houses, 179. High Littleton House is the seat of John R. Mogg, Esq.; Kingwell House, of Capt. Scobell; and Mountvale, of John E. Scobell, Esq. Coal is largely worked. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, &#163;120.* Patron, the Rev. H. Mogg. The church was restored and enlarged in 1824, and again in 1842; comprises nave, aisles, and chancel, with a fine tower; and contains monuments of the 15th century to the Hodges family. There are national schools, and charities &amp;.15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High_Littleton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/HighLittleton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652739</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10437076</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HIGH LITTLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10437088</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HIGH LITTLETON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10549644</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HIGH LITTLETON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
