<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12715</id>
<name>CROWCOMBE</name>
<container>SOMERSET</container>
<lat>51.118957032103</lat>
<lon>-3.23474175144977</lon>
<gazetteerText>CROWCOMBE, a village and a parish in Williton district, Somerset. The village stands under the Quantock hills, near the Taunton and Watchet railway, 7 miles NNE of Wiveliscombe; and has a station on the railway, a post office under Taunton, and an inn. It was formerly a market-town and borough; and it still has fairs on the first Friday of May, the Monday after 1 Aug., and 31 Oct. It is a neat and romantic place; and commands a fine view to the west. The parish includes also the hamlet of Flaxpool. Acres, 3, 176. Real property, &#163;4, 163. Pop., 573. Houses, 116. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged formerly to the Biccombes; and belongs now to the Carews. Crowcombe Court, the seat of the Carews, is a red brick mansion, with portico and wings; stands amid highly picturesque grounds; and contains a fine collection of paintings and curiosities. The church is later English and good; has an embattled tower, which was formerly surmounted by a spire; and contains monuments of the Carews. Crowcombe-Heathfield is a meet for the West Somerset hounds. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Bath and Wells. Value, not reported.* Patron, R. Harvey, Esq. A sculptured cross is in the churchyard; and another is in the neighbourhood. Charities, &#163;66. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SOM/Crowcombe/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651851</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10427903</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CROWCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10427939</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CROWCOMBE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
