<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4821</id>
<name>WEST HORSLEY</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.2642589296876</lat>
<lon>-0.449143503275311</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORSLEY (WEST), a village and a parish in Guildford district, Surrey. The village stands 3&#188; miles N by E of Gomshall r. station, and 6 ENE of Guildford; and has a post office under Ripley.&#151;The parish comprises 2, 993 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 135; of which &#163;10 are in chalk pits. Pop., 706. Houses, 145. The property is divided among a few. The manor, with West Horsley Place, belonged to Lord Berners, the translator of Froissart; passed to the Raleighs; was the favourite residence of Carew Raleigh, son of Sir Walter; passed to the family of Nicholas; and belongs now to H. M. Weston, Esq. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;317.* Patron, H. M. Weston, Esq. The church is partly early English, partly perpendicular; was well restored in 1849; comprises nave, aisles, and chancel, with tower and shingled spire; has, at the W end of the nave, a curious carving of the Nativity, found under the flooring in 1810; and contains monuments of a Berners and a Fullerton. A mortuary chapel belonging to the manor house is traditionally said to contain the head of Sir Walter Raleigh, in the same grave as the remains of his son. There are a national school, and charities &#163;151. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Horsley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634388</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42983</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10102078</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163950</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WEST HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
