<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5608</id>
<name>OCKLEY</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.144710516324</lat>
<lon>-0.362273455640286</lon>
<gazetteerText>OCKLEY, a village and a parish in Dorking district, Surrey. The village stands near the Dorking and Horsham railway, 7 miles S by W of Dorking; has a station on the railway; is supposed to be the Aclea of the Saxon chronicle, where Ethelwulf defeated the Danes ina great battle in 851; and has an old-fashioned green, a post-office&#8225; under Dorking, and two small inns. The parish includes parts of the chapelries of Cold Harbour and Oakwood, and comprises 4, 286 acres. Real property, &#163;3, 570. Pop., 683. Houses, 104. The property is divided among a few. Ockley Court is the seat of MajorW. Calvert; Joldwynds, ofC. Wetton, Esq.; Leith Hill Place, of J. Wedgwood, Esq.; and Elderslie, of G. Arbuthnot, Esq. The parish abounds with traditions of the Danes; and Aubrey saw traces of an ancient castle near the church, and says that the Danes destroyed it with battering engines, placed on Berry Hill, 2 milesdistant. Vestiges of a Roman camp, with double ditch and vallum, are at Holmbury Hill. A magnificent view, over parts of fourteen counties, and to London and these a, is got from Leith Hill. The parish is a meet for the Horsham hounds. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;539.* Patron, Clare College, Cambridge. The church, in 1867, was in bad condition. There are a parochial school, and charities about &#163;90. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ockley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641090</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42947</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10191129</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OCKLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10200829</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>OCKLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
