<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5230</id>
<name>CHOBHAM</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.3524183720068</lat>
<lon>-0.618877942197795</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHOBHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Chertsey district, Surrey. The village stands on Bourn brook, near Bagshot heath and the Basingstoke canal, 3&#189; miles WNW of Woking r. station, and 5&#190; SW of Chertsey; and has a post office&#8225; under Farnborough Station. The parish comprises 11, 536 acres. Real property, &#163;9, 659. Pop., 2, 098. Houses, 416. The property is subdivided. Chobham Place is the seat of Sir Denis le Marchant. Chobham Park belonged to Chertsey abbey; and was the death-place of Archbishop Heath. The Chobham ridges were the site of a great military encampment from April to August 1853; precurrent to the more . permanent encampment of Aldershot. Field works and redoubts, formed at the time of this encampment, may look, not long hence, to be ancient works; the more so that some real antiquities, of the class of Roman camps and roads, are in the vicinity. The surface generally has a bleak appearance; and belongs to the Bagshot sand formation. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Holy Trinity, in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;148.* Patron, J. Thornton, Esq. The church contains some Norman features. A chapelry at Valley-end was formed in 1867; and is served by a p. curate, with salary of &#163;50. There are a Baptist chapel, and charities &#163;25. -The sub-d. contains four parishes. Pop., 5, 289. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chobham,_Surrey</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653109</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42998</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10019620</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHOBHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10103976</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHOBHAM HOLY TRINITY WEST END</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10183212</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CHOBHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10187734</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHOBHAM ST SAVIOUR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10204100</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHOBHAM WITH VALLEY END</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10540290</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CHOBHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
