<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2720</id>
<name>BETCHWORTH</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.2299735929785</lat>
<lon>-0.26928887200999</lon>
<gazetteerText>BETCHWORTH, a village and a parish in Reigate district, Surrey. The village stands on the river Mole, &#190; of a mile S of the Reigate and Reading railway, and 2&#189; miles W by S of Reigate; and it has a station on the railway, and a post office under Reigate. The parish includes also the village of Brockham. Acres, 3,726. Real property, &#163;7,196. Pop., 1,389. Houses, 264. The property is divided among a few. Betchworth Park, with the manor of West Betchworth, belonged to Lord Maltravers, who was made Earl Marshal by Richard II.; passed by marriage, in 1437, to Sir Thomas Brown; went by purchase, in 1690, to Abraham Tucker, author of &quot;the Light of Nature,&quot; who lived and died here: and is now united to Deepdene Park, the property of the family of Hope. It contains a noble avenue of chestnuts and limes, nearly 1,000 feet long; contains also some shapeless ruins of Betchworth Castle, which was fortified and embattled by Sir Thomas Brown. Broome House, adjacent to the railway station, is the seat of Sir Benjamin Brodie. Brockham Lodge, in the neighbourhood of Brockham, is the seat of Mr. W. Bennet; and was the residence of Captain Morris, the song-writer, who preferred the &quot;sweet shady side of Pall Mall&quot; to the woods of Betchworth. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;200.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Windsor. The church was renovated and much altered in 1850; retains some interesting ancient parts, Norman and perpendicular; and has on the chancel floor a fine brass of W. Wardysworth, vicar, 1533. Brockham-Green vicarage is a separate benefice. There are an Independent chapel, and &#163;75 of charities. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655807</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Betchworth</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42950</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10019795</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BETCHWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10071150</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BETCHWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10540276</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BETCHWORTH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
