<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1314</id>
<name>BANSTEAD</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.30268723923</lat>
<lon>-0.181133624705873</lon>
<gazetteerText>BANSTEAD, a village and a parish in Epsom district, Surrey. The village stands under the SW side of Ban stead Downs, 4 miles E of Epsom; and has a post office under Epsom, a r. station, and a police station. The parish comprises 5,518 acres. Real property, &#163;7,214. Pop., 1,461. Houses, 275. The property is subdivided. Banstead Park is a seat belonging to Mr. Yong; and Burgh House, in the neighbourhood, is the seat of the Earl of Egmont. Banstead downs rise to the height of 576 feet; command extensive views; and are famous for coursing, for hunting, and for fine sheep pasturage. Here, said Pope, To Hounslow-Heath I point, and Banstead Down, Thence comes your mutton, and these chicks my own. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Earl of Egmont. The church is chiefly perpendicular English; has a good tower, surmounted by a tall spire; stands on high ground, and serves well, for miles round, as a landmark. Charities, &#163;39. The Banstead and Epsom Downs railway, from the Sutton station of the Croydon and Epsom, was authorised in 1862 and opened in 1865. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Banstead</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656379</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42963</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10019692</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BANSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10128961</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BANSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10221122</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BANSTEAD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2431</id>
   <name>MERSTHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2440</id>
   <name>WOODMANSTERNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4091</id>
   <name>CHIPSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
