<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>157</id>
<name>CATERHAM</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.2829490157887</lat>
<lon>-0.0859521585561543</lon>
<gazetteerText>CATERHAM, a village and a parish in Godstone district, Surrey. The village stands at the terminus of a branch of the South-eastern railway, 7 miles S by E of Croydon; and has a r. station with telegraph, and a post office under Red-Hill. The branch railway deflects from the Brighton line, at Caterham Junction station, 2&#189; miles S of Croydon; is 4&#189; miles long; was opened in 1856; and has stations at Kenley and Warlingham. An omnibus runs from Caterham station to Westerham. The parish comprises 2,460 acres. Real property, &#163;2,997. Pop., 815. Houses, 146. The property is much subdivided. The Roman vicinal way, called Stane-street, went through the parish; and ancient works, indicative of warlike operations, are in it, near a place called War coppice. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;255. Patron, the Rev. J. L. Hesse. The church is mainly early English. The p. curacy of Caterham Valley is a separate charge, and was constituted in 1866. The Warehousemen and Clerks&apos; Orphan asylum, reported to be in Caterham, but really in Beddington, was built in 1865 at a cost of about &#163;20,000; is in the Venetian Gothic style; and has accommodation for 150 boys and girls. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caterham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653520</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43062</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001626</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CATERHAM AND WARLINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10019606</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CATERHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10025620</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CATERHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10052464</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CATERHAM VALLEY ST JOHN THE EVANGELIST</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10091196</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>CATERHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10571200</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CATERHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835000</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CATERHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2439</id>
   <name>WOLDINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5229</id>
   <name>CHALDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>23699</id>
<name>WHYTELEAFE</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.3075867147994</lat>
<lon>-0.0816440314548182</lon>
<gazetteerText>Whyteleaf, 1 mile NW. of Warlingham sta., Surrey; P.O. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whyteleafe</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633993</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075580</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WHYTELEAFE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
