<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1238</id>
<name>HASLEMERE</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.0976347781764</lat>
<lon>-0.718547145830854</lon>
<gazetteerText>HASLEMERE, a decayed town and a parish in Hambledon district, Surrey. The town stands on the Guildford and New Portsmouth railway, amid pleasant environs of hill and vale, 9 miles SSW of Godalming; is said to have succeeded an older and largcr town, situated on the side of an adjacent hill, and destroyed by the Danes; was a borough by prescription, and chartered by Queen Elizabeth; sent two members to parliament, till disfranchised by the act of 1832; was the scene of many expensive and violeiit election coiitests, till its interests became united in the Ear.l of Lonsdale; has now a post office&#8225; under Liphook, a railway station, two inns, a handsome church, an Independent chapel, a literary and scientific institution, and a national school; and is a good centre for tourists to explore the romantic region in the triangle between it, Midhurst, and Petersfield. A weekly market is held on Tuesday; fairs for cattle are held on 13 May and 26 Sept.; articles of turnery are manufactured; and paper mills are in the neighbourhood. An enormous beech tree, about 18 feet in girth at 5 feet from the ground, is 1 &#189; mile to the N; and the remarkable depression in the sand, called the Devil&apos;s Punchbowl, and emitting an afflnent of the Wey, is 2&#188; iniles to the NNW. -The parish coinprises 1,877 acres. Real property, &#163;2, 990. Pop., 952. Houses, 187. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged to the Mores, and passed to the Lowthers. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the rectory of Chiddingfold, in the diocese of Winchester. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haslemere</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647365</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42926</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10019114</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>HASLEMERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10084260</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>HASLEMERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10107866</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HASLEMERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10163924</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HASLEMERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12758637</id>
   <status>PBCon</status>
   <name>HASLEMERE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835309</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HASLEMERE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>180</id>
   <name>PETERSFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1989</id>
   <name>SHOTTERMILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2232</id>
   <name>BRAMSHOTT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5117</id>
   <name>GREATHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5489</id>
   <name>LISS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5648</id>
   <name>SELBORNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6068</id>
   <name>CHIDDINGFOLD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8336</id>
   <name>EASEBOURNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8366</id>
   <name>FERNHURST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8849</id>
   <name>MIDHURST</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
