<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>2431</id>
<name>MERSTHAM</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.2716512897281</lat>
<lon>-0.146966027014112</lon>
<gazetteerText>MERSTHAM, a village and a parish in Reigate district, Surrey. The village stands on the London and Brighton railway, 3 miles NE of Reigate; contains some curious old cottages; and has a station with telegraph on the railway, and a post office under Red Hill. The parish comprises 2,535 acres. Real property, &#163;3,771. Pop., 846. Houses, 173. The property is divided among a few. The manor was given in 1018, by Ethelstan, son of Ethelred II., to Christchurch, Canterbury; and remained with it till the dissolution. Merstham House is the seat of Lord Hytton, made a peer in 1866. A peculiar kind of stone has been quarried in the parish from a very early period; was once esteemed of so much importance as to be kept under the control of the Crown; was used in the erection of Henry VIII. &apos;s chapel at Westminster, and of some parts of Windsor Castle; is a greyish green arenaceous limestone, lying under a grey calcareous marl; is soft at removal from the quarry, but acquires hardness by exposure; resists heat so remarkably as to be characterized as fire-stone; and is now used chiefly for hearths and furnaces. Chalk rock abounds; is calcined to be used as lime; and was formerly worked on a large scale. A tram railway, for the conveyance of the chalk, was constructed so early as 1805; belongs now to the London and Brigh ton company; and is still, in some parts, in working order. A tunnel of the London and Brighton railway, 1,82o yards long, occurs imdiately N of the village. The parish was traversed by the ancient Pilgrim&apos;s road to Canter net. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Valne, &#163;615.* Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church stands on a knoll, among fine old trees, at the E end of the village; includes some early English portions, but is mainly later English; shows the palm-leaf, the mark of the early crusade, among the decorations of its chancelarch; and contains a curious double piscina of decorated character, a square Norman font, four brasses from 1 472, and some handsome monuments to the Jolliffe family. A spring, similar to the Kentish nailbournes, breaks out in wet seasons in a pool at the foot of the church-knoll; and very deep wells, one of them 210 feet deep, occur in varions parts. The parish shares in the charities of Reigate. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merstham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642711</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42958</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10058752</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MERSTHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10146549</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MERSTHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
