<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5225</id>
<name>EAST HORSLEY</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.2668579778384</lat>
<lon>-0.425821466530104</lon>
<gazetteerText>HORSLEY (EAST), a village and a parish in Guildford district, Surrey. The village stands 3&#189; miles NNE of Gomshall r. station, and 5&#189; SW of Leatherhead; is a pleasant place; and has a post office under Woking Station, and a good inn.-Acres of the parish, 1,824. Real property, &#163;1, 880. Pop., 228. Houses, 50. Most of the property belongs to the Earl of Lovelace. East Horsley Towers, the Earl&apos;s seat, includes an ancient tower; was recently extended by the addition of two stately towers, and of a hall 56 feet long, with open timbered roof, of original construction; contains the books and manuscripts bequeathed by John Locke to Lord Chancellor King; contains also many valuable pictures and marbles; and stands in a finely undulating and well wooded park. A manor here was given, in 1036, by the Danish jarl Thored to Christ&apos;s Church, Canterbury; and continued with it till the dissolution. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;257.* Patron, the Archbishop of Canterbury. The church is partly early English, partly perpendicular; consists of nave, N aisle, and chancel, with low embattled tower; has been entirely and tastelessly remodelled; and contains a brass of Bishop Booth of Exeter. There are a free school, and charities &#163;5. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Horsley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2650411</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42982</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10019138</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>EAST HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10182918</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>EAST HORSLEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1966</id>
   <name>OCKHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2948</id>
   <name>EFFINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4092</id>
   <name>EAST CLANDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4821</id>
   <name>WEST HORSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5333</id>
   <name>SEND</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
