<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4094</id>
<name>ASHTEAD</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.3091368023594</lat>
<lon>-0.298259438984821</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHTEAD, a parish in Epsom district, Surrey; on the Croydon and Leatherhead railway, 2&#189; miles SW of Epsom. It has a station on the railway, and a post office under Epsom. Acres, 2,522. Real property, &#163;3,519. Pop., 729. Houses, 124. The property is divided among a few. Ashtead House, the seat of the Howard family, is a splendid mansion, and contains some good pictures. The park has some venerable old oaks and elms, and a long avenue of limes; and is well stocked with deer. Ashtead Common, above the park, commands picturesque views; and contains, among wood, an ancient entrenchment. The Roman Stone-street passed through the parish; and has left relics in the materials of the church. There is a mineral spring, similar to that of Epsom. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;499.* Patrons, the Heirs of the late Hon. Col. Howard. The church is an ancient structure, with a tower; and embodies Roman bricks and tiles in its walls; but has undergone numerous alterations. Sir Robert Howard used to entertain Charles II. in a mansion which occupied the site of the present Ashtead House. an alms house for six poor widows has &#163;32 from endowment, and other charities &#163;16. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656924</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashtead,_Surrey</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42962</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10071070</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ASHTEAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10128948</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ASHTEAD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
