<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1258</id>
<name>BEDDINGTON</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.3686635439926</lat>
<lon>-0.13225526495078</lon>
<gazetteerText>BEDDINGTON, a Village and a parish in Croydon district, Surrey. The village stands on the river Wandle, near the Southeastern and the Wimbledon and Croydon railways, 2&#188;. miles W of Croydon; and it has a station on the latter railway, and a post office under Croydon, London S. The parish includes also the place called Beddington Corner, and the hamlet of Wallington. Acres, 3,909. Real property, &#163;12,060. Pop., 1,556. Houses, 311. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged to the Carews from 1360 till 1860. Beddington House, on the manor, now the seat of the Rev. A. H. Bridges, is chiefly a brick edifice of 1709; but includes a great hall, with very rich open roof, visited by Queen Elizabeth; and contained interesting family portraits, a curious trophy of arms, and an elaborately-formed door-lock. An orangery here, destroyed in 1739, sprang from pips imported by Sir Francis Carew, the brother-in-law of Sir walter Raleigh, the first pips planted in England. At Woodcote, in the southern part of the parish, many Roman remains have been found. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;1,212.* Patron, the Rev. A. H. Bridges. The church shows Norman traces; was founded before the Con quest, and rebuilt of flint in the time of Richard I.; was renovated and extended, at a cost of &#163;3,000, in 1850; and was again repaired in 1869. The p. curacy of Wallington is a separate charge, formed in 1867. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beddington</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43048</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10092644</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BEDDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135370</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>BEDDINGTON AND WALLINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10206870</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BEDDINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10569436</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BEDDINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
