<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>29</id>
<name>FRIMLEY</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.3229153284516</lat>
<lon>-0.727173232770291</lon>
<gazetteerText>FRIMLEY, a village, a chapelry, a township, and a sub-district in Farnham district, Surrey. The village stands on the river Blackwater, near the Southwestern railway, under the Chobham ridges, 1&#190; mile NNW of Farnborough r. station, and 4 SW by S of Bagshot; presents a somewhat picturesque appearance; and has a bridge over the Blackwater, and a post office under Farnborough Station. The chapelry includes the village, and about one-half of the township. Pop., 1, 276. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;70.* Patron, the Rector of Ash. The church is modern; and there are a Baptist chapel, and a national school. The township includes also York-Town chapelry; and is in the parish of Ash. Acres, 7, 505. Real property, &#163;7, 389. Pop. in 1851, 1, 792; in 1861, 2, 683. Houses, 470. The property is much subdivided. Frimley Park is the seat of John Tekell, Esq. The increase of pop. arose partly from the proximity of Aldershot camp, and partly from the erection of the neighbouring structures of Wellington college, Royal Staff college, and Broadmoor asylum.&#151;The sub-district includes also Aldershot parish and camp, politically in Hants. Acres, 11, 649. Pop., 19, 403; of whom 8, 965 were military-Houses, 1, 233. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frimley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2649052</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001638</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>FRIMLEY AND CAMBERLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10019011</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FRIMLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10070697</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>FRIMLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10540227</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>FRIMLEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>825</id>
   <name>WINDLESHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>896</id>
   <name>WOKINGHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1464</id>
   <name>SUNNINGHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3059</id>
   <name>EASTHAMPSTEAD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>3641</id>
   <name>SANDHURST</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5230</id>
   <name>CHOBHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5329</id>
   <name>PIRBRIGHT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>5503</id>
   <name>BISLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6033</id>
   <name>WINKFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>17347</id>
   <name>BRACKNELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>23545</id>
<name>FRIMLEY GREEN</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.3028809913527</lat>
<lon>-0.726038025600457</lon>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frimley_Green</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10128092</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>FRIMLEY GREEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
