<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1960</id>
<name>MORDEN</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.3922570273974</lat>
<lon>-0.203173011661371</lon>
<gazetteerText>MORDON, a village and a parish in Croydon district, Surrey. The village stands 1&#188; mile SW of the river Wandle, 1&#189; SS W of a station of its own name on the Wimbledon and Croydon railway, and 5&#188; WNW of Croydon; and has a post office, under Mitcham, London S. The parish comprises 1,422 acres. Real property, &#163;5,039. Pop., 654. Houses, 125. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged once to Merton abbey, and belongs now to R. Garth, Esq. Mordon Hall was formerly the manor-house, and is now a school. Mordon Park, Mordon Hill, Mordon Lodge, and the Rectory are chief residences. Snuff-mills are on the river; and a large brickfield was lately opened on Mordon Common. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Valne, &#163;353.* Patron, R. Garth, Esq. The church was rebuilt of brick in 1636; has stone decorated windows, which probably belonged to the previous church; has also an embattled tower; and contains some brasses and monuments. There are an endowed school with &#163;36 a year, an endowed Sunday school with &#163;30, and charities &#163;29. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morden</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642233</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43056</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10036574</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MORDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10104385</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MORDEN</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>824</id>
<name>MERTON</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.414727601079</lat>
<lon>-0.202291947485318</lon>
<gazetteerText>Merton, par. and vil. (ry. sta. Wimbledon and Merton), Surrey, on river Wandle, 3&#189; miles SW. of Clapham Junction and 7&#188; miles SW. of Waterloo sta., London, 1765 ac., pop. 2480; has remains of a priory (1115). which became a factory for calico printing; Merton Place, where Lord Nelson lived from October 1801 to May 1803, has been pulled down. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merton_(historic_parish)</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642233</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43032</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10036495</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10056408</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10058764</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MERTON ST JAMES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10136192</id>
   <status>LB</status>
   <name>MERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10146550</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10152975</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MERTON AND MORDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10190940</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MERTON ST JOHN THE DIVINE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10576994</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MERTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740244</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>MERTON AND MORDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12834202</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MERTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>1168</id>
<name>MITCHAM</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.4051152284251</lat>
<lon>-0.162405752835939</lon>
<gazetteerText>MITCHAM, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Croydon district, Surrey. The village stands on the river Wandle, near the Wimbledon and Croydon railway, 4&#189; miles NW by W of Croydon; was known, at Domesday, as Michelham; and has a post office under London S, a railway station with telegraph, a police station, and a fair on 12,13, and 14 Aug.&#151;The parish comprises 2,893 acres. Real property, &#163;22,439; of which &#163;500 are in gas-works. Pop. in 1851,4,641; in 1861,5,078. Houses, 926. The property is much divided. The manor belongs to W. Simpson, Esq. There are numerous mansions and villas. Mitcham Grove mansion belonged to Lord Clive, the conqueror of India; and was given by him to Lord Loughborough, as a thank offering for his defence of Clives policy. Mitcham Manor House, now the seat of W. Simpson, Esq., belonged once to a descendant of Cranmer. Another mansion was the seat of Waldo who wrote on the Liturgy; and others were residences of Sir Walter Raleigh, Dr. Donne, Moses Mendez, and Sir Julins C&#230;sar. A curious ancient house, including remains of a chapel, is in the village. Some hundreds of acres in the parish are covered with plantations of lavander, rosemary, peppermint, camomile, and other aromatic plants for the use of the London perfumers and distillers. A considerable tract also is occupied with roses for making rose-water. The parish has been famous, during about a century, for its plantations of aromatic and medicinal herbs; and the air, over much of it, is strongly perfumed by them. Industry is carried on in corn mills, tobacco works, bleaching-grounds, and calico printing establishments. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;456.* Patron, W. Simpson, Esq. The church was rebuilt in 1821; is an edifice of brick and compo, in the later English style; and has an embattled tower. There are chapels for Independents and Wesleyans, national and infant schools, an endowment of &#163;63 a year for a Sunday school, alms houses for 12 aged females, and other charities &#163;110. The industrial school of St. George-in-the-East, in London, and the Eagle House lunatic asylum also are here; and, at the census of 1861, had respectively 225 and 51 inmates.&#151;The sub-district contains also four other parishes. Acres, 11,594. Pop., 9,381. Houses, 1,764. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mitcham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642414</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43055</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001249</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>MITCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10058788</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MITCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10058790</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MITCHAM CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10146616</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MITCHAM ST MARK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10170266</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MITCHAM ST BARNABAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10190964</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MITCHAM THE ASCENSION POLLARDS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10210902</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MITCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10217131</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MITCHAM ST OLAVE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10540148</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MITCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12740037</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>MITCHAM AND MORDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741716</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>MERTON MITCHAM AND MORDEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12751011</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>SURREY MITCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12755004</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>MITCHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12834834</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MITCHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>824</id>
   <name>MERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>913</id>
   <name>WIMBLEDON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
