<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>4083</id>
<name>HASCOMBE</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.1369378694414</lat>
<lon>-0.553539734439412</lon>
<gazetteerText>HASCOMBE, a village and a parish in Hambledon district, Surrey. The village stands 2&#189; miles ENE of Hambledon, and 4 SE of Godalming r. station; is a picturesque place in an amphitheatre of wooded hills; and has an inn. The parish comprises 1,539 acres. Posttown, Godalming. Real property, &#163;1,969. Pop., 396. Houses, 74. The property is divided among a few. Park Hatch is the seat of J. Godman, Esq. A high ridge, to the S of the village, bears the name of Telegraphhill, from an old disused telegraph on it; commands extensive fine views; and is covered with beech trees, one of which, called the Hascombe beech, is a great landmark. Part of this ridge is named Castle-hill; and has remains of a small Roman camp, with single ditch and vallum. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;171.* Patron,B. Musgrave, Esq. The church was rebuilt in 1864; is in the early English style, ornate and hagiological; consists of nave, aisle, and apsidal chancel, with oak shingled spire; and has a W memorial window, put up in 1865, to the memory of Dr. Conyers Middleton, author of the &quot;Life of Cicero,&quot; and some time rector of Hascombe. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hascombe</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647375</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42938</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10052191</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HASCOMBE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10128213</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HASCOMBE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
