<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1042</id>
<name>SUTTON</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.3651376890246</lat>
<lon>-0.194177817144903</lon>
<gazetteerText>SUTTON, a village and a parish in Epsom district, Surrey. The village stands adjacent to the Epsom railway, 4&#189; miles WSW of Croydon; consists chiefly of one street; is the head polling place for Mid-Surrey; and has a post-office&#8225; under London S, a r. station with telegraph, and two hotels.&#151;The parish includes Ben-hilton group of new villas at Been Hill, numerous other new villas and cottages, and the South Metropolitan District school. Acres, 1,803. Real property, &#163;12,061; of which &#163;30 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 1,387; in 1861, 3,186,-of whom 900 were in the S. M. D. school. Houses, 452. The property is much subdivided. A section with a pop. of about 1,100, was formed, in 1863, into the chapelry of Benhilton. The head living is a rectory, and that of B. is a vicarage, in the diocese of Winchester. Value of the former, &#163;660.* of the latter, &#163;200.* Patron of the former, H. Padwick, Esq.; of the latter, the Representatives of the late T. Alcock Esq. The parochial church was rebuilt in 1863, at a cost of &#163;6,000; and is in late first-pointed style. B. church was built in 1864, and is in the decorated English style. There are several dissenting chapels, a slightly endowed school, and charities &#163;51. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sutton,_London</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636503</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43058</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10001407</id>
   <status>LB</status>
   <name>SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10037244</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10090076</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SUTTON AND CHEAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10142556</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10147517</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10147529</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SUTTON NEW TOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173840</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10204938</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SUTTON CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10213502</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>SUTTON AND CHEAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10595332</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12747287</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>SUTTON AND CHEAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12748127</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>SUTTON SUTTON AND CHEAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12757141</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>SUTTON AND CHEAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12834329</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SUTTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>833</id>
   <name>CARSHALTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>889</id>
   <name>MALDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1235</id>
   <name>NEW MALDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1960</id>
   <name>MORDEN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2438</id>
   <name>WALLINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>2718</id>
   <name>CHEAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4086</id>
   <name>CUDDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>24196</id>
<name>SUTTON</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.2711442148203</lat>
<lon>-0.549135250137304</lon>
<gazetteerText>SUTTON, a tything in Woking parish, Surrey; on the river Wey, 4&#188; miles NNE of Guildford. S. Place was a quadrangular mansion built, in the time of Henry VIII., by Sir R. Weston; was visited by Queen Elizabeth; suffered from fire immediately after her visit; underwent removal of its entrance-gateway side towards the end of last century; includes an ancient Roman Catholic chapel; and belongs now to the Salvins. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sutton_Place,_Surrey</link>
</links>
</place>
<place>
<id>833</id>
<name>CARSHALTON</name>
<container>SURREY</container>
<lat>51.3665340134631</lat>
<lon>-0.168261142634743</lon>
<gazetteerText>CARSHALTON-pronounced Casehorton or Cayshorton-a village, a parish, and a subdistrict in Epsom district,. Surrey. The village stands near the river Wandle and the Epsom railway, 3 miles W by S of Croydon; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under London, S. It was known at Domesday as Aulton; and was once a market-town. The parish comprises 2,904 acres. Real property, &#163;14,178. Pop., 2,538. Houses, 492. The property is subdivided. Carshalton Park was formerly the seat of Sir N. Throckmorton, Dr. Radcliffe and the Scawens; and is now occupied by James Aitken, Esq. The parish is watered by the Wandle and its head streams; and has flour, paper, oil, and snuff mills. A spring, overarched with stone, close to the churchyard, is traditionally associated with Queen Anne Boleyn, and bears her name. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Winchester. Value, &#163;875.* Patron, Albert Cator, Esq. The church is early English, much altered, but in good condition; and contains a remarkable brass of Sheriff Gaynesford, who died in 1490, and three elaborate monuments of last century. There are gas works, a police station, a British school, a national school, an infant school, and charities &#163;58. The subdistrict contains four parishes. Acres, 12,119. Pop., 8,341. Houses, 1,451. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carshalton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653646</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43049</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10083771</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CARSHALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10137652</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>CARSHALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10153141</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>CARSHALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10183194</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>CARSHALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10205610</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CARSHALTON BEECHES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10556557</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CARSHALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12737075</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>SURREY CARSHALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741637</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>CARSHALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741649</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>SUTTON CARSHALTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12747913</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>CARSHALTON AND WALLINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
