<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8292</id>
<name>BURWASH</name>
<container>SUSSEX</container>
<lat>50.9928215585852</lat>
<lon>0.370344255241757</lon>
<gazetteerText>BURWASH, or Burghersh, a village and a parish in Ticehurst district, Sussex The village stands on an affluent of the river Rother, 2&#189; miles WSW of Etchingham r. station, and 8 NW of Battle; and has a post office,&#8225; of the name of Burwash, under Hurst Green. It was formerly a market town, and still has fairs on 12 May and 4 Oct.; and it is a seat of petty sessions. The parish comprises 7,321 acres. Real property, &#163;8,817. Pop., 2,143. Houses, 422. The property is much subdivided. There is a chalybeate spring. The living is a rectory and vicarage in the diocese of Chichester. Value, &#163;699.* Patron, the Rev. J. Gould. The church is early and later English, and was restored in 1856. A chapel of ease, in the early English style, was built at Burwash-Common in 1867. There are an Independent chapel, a Wesleyan chapel, a national school, and charities &#163;40. Burwash gives the title of Viscount to the Earl of Westmoreland. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://homepages.gold.ac.uk/genuki/SSX/Burwash/index.php</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burwash,_East_Sussex</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654196</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10284715</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BURWASH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10284727</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BURWASH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8288</id>
   <name>BRIGHTLING</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>23712</id>
<name>BURWASH WEALD</name>
<container>SUSSEX</container>
<lat>50.9839843577083</lat>
<lon>0.350998870478509</lon>
<unit>
   <id>10284740</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BURWASH WEALD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
