<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>220</id>
<name>WEDNESBURY</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5578409834959</lat>
<lon>-2.01133523348848</lon>
<gazetteerText>WEDNESBURY, a town and a parish in West Bromwich district, Stafford. The town stands on the South Staffordshire and Great Western railways, near the Birmingham canal, 8 miles NW of Birmingham; was called by the Saxons Wodensbury, after the god Woden; is now popularly called Wedgebury; had a castle, built in 916, by the princess Ethelfleda; was made a parliamentary borough, with one representative, by the reform act of 1867; includes, as a borough, West Bromwich and Tipton; was proposed, in the Boundary Commissioners&apos; report of 1868, to include also Darlaston; is a polling place for South Staffordshire; publishes a weekly newspaper; carries on manufactures of railway ironwork, railway-carriages, patent axle-trees, gas tubes, steam and water pipes, and gun-locks, coach springs, hinges, screws, nails, and every kind of wrought iron-work; is managed by a local board of health, who have offices in the Italian style, built in 1867; and has a head post-office,&#8225; two r. stations with telegraph, two banking offices, several good inns, a police station, a later English church, restored in 1827 and 1866, two modern churches in the early English style, ten dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a mechanics&apos; institute, a working man&apos;s club, with library and reading room, eight public schools, charities &#163;250, a weekly market on Saturday, and fairs on 6 May and 3 Aug. Pop. in 1861, within the town limits proper, 15,298. Houses, 2,793. Pop. within the borough limits, as constituted in 1867, about 92,623.&#151;The parish comprises 2,175 acres. Real property, &#163;59,557; of which &#163;8,312 are in mines, &#163;80 in quarries, and &#163;11,987 in ironworks. Pop. in 1851, 14,281; in 1861, 21,968. Houses, 4,057. The manor belonged anciently to the Crown; passed to the Heronviles and the Beaumonts; and belongs now to Sir F. Scott, Bart. and Lady Emily Foley. Coal, iron ore, limestone, potters&apos; clay, and brick clay abound. The head living or St. Bartholomew s is a vicarage, and the livings of St. John and St. James are rectories, in the diocese of Lichfield. Value of St. B., &#163;310;* of St. John, &#163;267; of St. James, &#163;300.* Patron of St. B., the Lord Chancellor; of St. John, Lady E. Foley; of St. James, J. N. Bagnall, Esq. The p. curacy of Moxley is a separate benefice. Lord W. Paget, who died in 1564, was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Wednesbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wednesbury</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634617</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10026891</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10055570</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10296213</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Ch</status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10296237</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10296262</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY ST JAMES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10296274</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10296298</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY ST PAUL WOOD GREEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550348</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581904</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12747470</id>
   <status>PBCon/BCon</status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12830944</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WEDNESBURY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
