<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7857</id>
<name>ALSTONFIELD</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1459593241484</lat>
<lon>-1.88504516079568</lon>
<gazetteerText>ALLSTONEFIELD, or Allstonfield, a village, a township, and a parish on the NE border of Staffordshire, contiguous to Derbyshire. The village stands on the river Dove, 8 miles NNW of Ashborne r. station; and has a post office under Ashborne. The township contains also the hamlet of Stanshope and a workhouse; and is in the district of Ashborne. Acres, 2,700. Real property, &#163;4,488. Pop., 651. Houses, 140. The parish contains also the townships of Heathylee, Quarnford, Hollinsclough, Longnor, Fairfieldhead, Warslow, and Elkstone, in the district of Leek. Acres, 21,860. Real property, &#163;19,824. Pop., 4,117. Houses, 917. The property is divided among a few. Coal, lead ore, and copper are worked. Isaac Walton indulged his angling propensities here, with his friend Cotton of Beresford Hall. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, Sir John Crewe, Bart. The church is a beautiful structure in early English style, with a pinnacled tower. The p. curacies of Quarnford, Longnor, Warslow, and Elkstone are separate benefices. Charities, &#163;54. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Alstonfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alstonefield</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Alstonefield</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22903</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22901</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22902</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22905</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22906</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22908</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22904</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22907</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10197030</id>
   <status>GilU</status>
   <name>ALSTONFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272385</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ALSTONFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10272439</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ALSTONFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10568663</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ALSTONFIELD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
