<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8383</id>
<name>LAPLEY</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.7111937776022</lat>
<lon>-2.21235550238492</lon>
<gazetteerText>LAPLEY, a township and a parish in Penkridge district, Stafford. The township lies 1 mile E of the Liverpool and Birmingham canal, 1&#189; N of Watling-street, and 3&#189; WSW of Penkridge r. station. Pop. in 1851,251. Houses, 47. The parish contains also the township of Wheaton-Aston, which has a post-office under Stafford. Acres, 3,450. Real property, &#163;10,189. Pop. in 1851, 962; in 1861,828. Houses, 181. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to Major Swinfen. A Black priory was founded here, in the time of Edward the Confessor, by Algar, Earl of Mercia, as a cell to St. Remigins abbey at Rheims: was transferred, by Henry V., to Tong college, in Salop; and went, at the Reformation, to Sir Richard Manners. The living is a vicarage, united with the chapelry of Wheaton-Aston, in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;220.* Patron, Major Swinfen. The church has a tower, and was recently restored. The church of Wheaton-Aston was rebuilt in 1857. There are a national school, and charities &#163;26. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Lapley/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lapley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2644870</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10287820</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LAPLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10287856</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LAPLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10576064</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LAPLEY AND TRYSULL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
