<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8489</id>
<name>ROCESTER</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9508136416902</lat>
<lon>-1.84664383539525</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROCESTER, a village and a parish in Uttoxeter district, Stafford. The village stands near the confluence of the rivers Dove and Churnet, adjacent to the junction of the North Staffordshire railway with the branch lineto Ashborne, and at the boundary with Derbyshire, 4 miles N by E of Uttoxeter; and has a station with te1egraph at the railway junction, and a post-office&#8225; under Ashborne. The parish contains also the hamlets of Rocester-Green, Combridge, Denstone, Quixhill, and Stub-wood. Acres, 2, 105. Real property, &#163;6, 866. Pop., 1, 175. Houses, 237. The property is divided among a few. Dove-Leys, Barrow-Hill, and Woodseat are chief residences. A black abbey was founded here in 1146, by R. Bacun; but has left no remains. A one-arched-bridge, of 60 feet in span, was erected over the Dove in 1839-40. A large cotton-mill was built by the late. Sir R. Arkwright. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, T. P. Bainbrigge, Esq. The church is ancient but good; was recently enlarged; and contains monuments of the Staffords. Asection with a pop. of 147 is within the chapelry of Denstone. There are chapels for Baptists and Wesleyans, British schools, and charities &#163;15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Rocester/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rocester</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639275</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10292128</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>ROCESTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10292153</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROCESTER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8025</id>
   <name>DENSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8481</id>
   <name>PRESTWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
