<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8400</id>
<name>LONGNOR</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1850060812006</lat>
<lon>-1.86794096377733</lon>
<gazetteerText>LONGNOR, a village, a township, a chapelry, and a sub-district in Leek district, Stafford. The village stands on the river Manifold, near the river Dove at the boundary with Derby, 6 miles SSE of Buxton r. station; and has a post office under Buxton, and fairs on the second Tuesday of Feb., Easter Tuesday, 4 and 17 May, 5 Aug.., the first Tuesday of Oct., and 12 Nov. The township includes the village, and is in Allstonefield parish. Real property, &#163;1,919. Pop., 514. Houses, 118. The manor belongs to Sir John H. Crewe, Bart. The chapelry is much more extensive than the township. Rated property, &#163;9,230. Pop., 2,228. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;150. Patron, the Vicar of Allstonefield. The church was built about the end of last century; was enlarged with galleries in 1812; and is a plain edifice. There are a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;11.&#151;The sub-district contains six townships of Allstonefield parish, one of Mayfield parish, and three entire parishes. Acres, 29,719. Pop., 5,041. Houses, 1,115. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Longnor/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Longnor,_Staffordshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643650</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=22906</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10288368</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>LONGNOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10288381</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONGNOR</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550038</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LONGNOR</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>4031</id>
   <name>CHELMORTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8181</id>
   <name>HOLLINSCLOUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
