<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>222</id>
<name>WEDNESFIELD</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6070555921691</lat>
<lon>-2.07408194527841</lon>
<gazetteerText>WEDNESFIELD, a township and two chapelries in Wolverhampton parish, Stafford. The township lies on the Wyrley canal, near the South Staffordshire railway, 2 miles NE of Wolverhampton; and has a post-office under Wolverhampton, and a r. station. Real property, &#163;16,486; of which &#163;852 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 4,858; in 1861, 8,553. Houses, 1,708. The increase of pop. arose mainly from the erection of houses for the accommodation of coal-miners. The property is not much divided. Perry Hall is a chief residence. The manufacture of locks, keys, and traps is very largely carried on. Edward the Elder beat the Danes here in 910.-The chapelries are W. and W.-Heath; and are jointly conterminate with the township. The living of W. is a vicarage, and that of W.-Heath is a p. curacy, in the diocese of Lichfield. Value of W., &#163;280;* of W.-Heath, &#163;120. Patron of W., the Bishop of Lichfield; of W.-Heath, H. Rogers, Esq. W. church was built in 1760, and recently enlarged. W.-Heath church was built in 1853. There are three dissenting chapels, several public schools, and charities &#163;20. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Wednesfield/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wednesfield</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634616</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10026957</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WEDNESFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10101074</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>WEDNESFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10296304</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>WEDNESFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10296341</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEDNESFIELD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10296353</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEDNESFIELD ST GREGORY THE GREAT</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>983</id>
<name>HEATHTOWN</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5939966500485</lat>
<lon>-2.09906234949063</lon>
<gazetteerText>Heath Town, dist. with ry. sta., in par. and NE. suburbs of Wolverhampton, W. Staffordshire, pop. 6245; P.O. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heath_Town</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10062858</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HEATH TOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186651</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>HEATHTOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280813</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HEATHTOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280849</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEDNESFIELD HEATH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
