<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8474</id>
<name>PATTINGHAM</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5851148443755</lat>
<lon>-2.25880332723317</lon>
<gazetteerText>PATTINGHAM, a village and a township in Staffordshire, and a parish partly also in Salop, but all in Wolverhampton district. The village stands &#189; a mile from the boundary with Salop, 4&#188; S W of Codsall r. station, and 6 W of Wolverhampton; and has a post-office under Wolverhampton, and a fair on the last Tuesday of April. The township contains also the hamlet of Nurton; is the Staffordshire portion of the parish; and comprises 2, 500 acres. Pop., 959. Houses, 210. The Salop portion of the parish consists of Rudge township, and comprises 1, 542 acres. Pop., 167. Houses, 27. Real property of the whole, with Patshull, &#163;13, 136. Rated property of Pattingham alone, &#163;8, 377. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Earl of Dartmouth. A gold torque, 4 feet long, was found in 1700. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;342.* Patron, the Earl of Dartmouth. The church is ancient, was recently restored, and contains some old monuments. There are an endowed school with &#163;15 a year, and charities &#163;71. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Pattingham/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattingham</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640566</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Pattingham/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10291288</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>PATTINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10291290</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>PATTINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8473</id>
   <name>PATSHULL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
