<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>401</id>
<name>BIDDULPH</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1216826755829</lat>
<lon>-2.16192687254721</lon>
<gazetteerText>BIDDULPH, a parish in the district of Congleton and county of Stafford; on the Stoke and Congleton railway, around Gillow-Heath station, 3 miles SSE of Congleton. It consists of the four hamlets of Over-Biddulph or Overton, Nether-Biddulph, Middle-Biddulph, and Knypersley; and its Post Town is Congleton. Acres, 5,635. Real property, &#163;14,544; of which &#163;4,622 are in mines. Pop., 3,468. Houses, 692. The property is much subdivided. Biddulph Hall, a picturesque Tudor edifice, was anciently the seat of the Biddulph family; but is now mainly a ruin, and partly a farmhouse. Knypersley Hall is the seat of J. Bateman, Esq. The land is largely moorish and hilly; and a peak of it, called Mow Cop, 1,091 feet high, commands fine prospects, even to the Mersey. A tract, called Biddulph Moor, is inhabited by a sort of gipsey tribe, a people of peculiar habits, said to have descended from a Saracen, who came to England in the train of a Crusader. Coal, ironstone, and limestone are extensively worked; and several kinds of manufacture are carried on. Remains of a Druidical temple, known as the Bride Stones, and of three curious artificial caves, are on the N border. The living is a vicarage, united with the p. curacy of Knypersley, in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;122. Patron, J. Bateman, Esq. The parish church is a substantial edifice, with a tower; and Knypersley church is a structure of 1849, in the early English style. Another church, in the Norman style, was built, in 1863, at Biddulph Moor; and forms a separate charge. There are a Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;22. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655708</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Biddulph/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biddulph</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10004652</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BIDDULPH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10062032</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BIDDULPH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10273134</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BIDDULPH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10273146</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BIDDULPH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550040</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BIDDULPH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828962</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BIDDULPH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>6187</id>
   <name>MORETON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8190</id>
   <name>HORTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>24430</id>
<name>BIDDULPH MOOR</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.1206021405159</lat>
<lon>-2.13748429023227</lon>
<gazetteerText>Biddulph Moor, eccl. dist., N. Staffordshire, near Congleton, pop. 1291. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biddulph_Moor</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10273160</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BIDDULPH MOOR</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
