<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8402</id>
<name>MADELEY</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9943410006278</lat>
<lon>-2.33605046145625</lon>
<gazetteerText>MADELEY, a village, a township, and a parish in Newcastle-under-Lyne district, Stafford. The village stands adjacent to the Northwestern railway, 1&#190; mile E of the meeting-point with Salop and Cheshire, and 4&#189; W by S of Newcastle-under-Lyne; and has a station on the railway, and a post office &#8225; under Newcastle, Staffordshire.-The township contains also the hamlet of Little Madeley. Real property, &#163;7,782; of which &#163;400 are in mines. Pop. in 1851,1,423; in 1861,1,725. Houses, 350.&#151;The parish contains also the township of Onnely, and comprises 5,734 acres. Real property, &#163;8,730. Pop. in 1851,1,655; in 1861,1,940. Houses, 392. The property is divided among a few. Madeley House is a chief residence. The land is hilly and well wooded. Coal is worked, brick-making is carried on, and nails are made. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Valne, &#163;266.* Patron, the Hon. Mrs.Offley. The church is ancient but good; and contains monuments of the Egertons and others. There are a chapel of ease, a Wesleyan chapel, a free school and alms houses with jointly &#163;95 a year from endowment, and other charities &#163;60. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Madeley/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madeley,_Staffordshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643234</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10288447</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MADELEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10288460</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MADELEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7869</id>
   <name>ASHLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7991</id>
   <name>CHAPEL CHORLTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8403</id>
   <name>MAER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8419</id>
   <name>MUCKLESTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8612</id>
   <name>WHITMORE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
