<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8147</id>
<name>HARBORNE</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4715886830476</lat>
<lon>-1.96590483369515</lon>
<gazetteerText>HARBORNE, a village, a parish, and a sub-district in the district of Kings-Norton and county of Stafford. The village stands near the boundaries with Worcestershire, Warwickshire, and Birmingham borough, 3 miles SW of Birmingham; was to have a railway, after 1866, to Birmingham r. station; forms a pleasant suburban residence; is connected with Birmingham by a continuous series of villas and other genteel residences along Harborne road; and has a post office&#8225; under Birmingham, a police station, a public library, a steel mill, tin ware works, and a spectacles manufactory. The parish includes also the hamlet of Smethwick. Acres, 3, 296. Real property, exclusive of Smethwick, &#163;13, 286; inc. of S., &#163;60, 418. Pop. in 1851, exc. of S., 2, 350; in 1861, 3, 617. Houses, 704. Pop. inc. of S. in 1851, 10, 729; in 1861, 16, 996. Houses, 3, 292. The increase of pop. arose from participation in the prosperity of Birmingham. The manor belongs to the Marquis of Anglesey. Metchley Abbey is the seat of Lord Calthorpe. Much of the area is occupied by suburban outskirts of Birmingham; and a good deal is disposed in market and strawberry gardens. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;600.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Lichfield. The church is ancient, with a later English tower; and has been extremely disfigured by modern alterations. The churchyard commands a fine view, over parts of Worcestershire, to the Clent Hills and the Bromsgrove Lickey. The chapelries of North Harborne, HarborneHeath, Smethwick, Smethwick-St. Matthew, and West Smethwick, are separate charges. North Harborne was constituted in 1842, Harborne Heath in 1859; and the other three will be noticed in the article SMETHWICK. Pop. of North Harborne in 1861, 5, 550; of HarborneHeath, 2, 289. Houses, 1, 090 and 473. North Harborne is a vicarage. Value, &#163;300.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Lichfield. Harborne Heath is a vicarage. Value, &#163;100. Patron, the Rev. T. Smith. H. H. church was built in 1859, at a cost of upwards of &#163;3, 000; is in the geometric decorated style; and consists of nave, aisles, transept, and chancel, With lofty octagonal turret terminating in a spirelet. There are national schools, with &#163;28 from endowment; four almshouses for families, and one for aged individuals; and other charities, amounting with these, to about &#163;200. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harborne</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Harborne/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647508</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10028929</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>HARBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280461</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>HARBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280515</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280590</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARBORNE ST FAITH AND ST LAWRENCE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10574468</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>HARBORNE</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24150</id>
<name>HARBORNE HEATH</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4607621190257</lat>
<lon>-1.94259381502082</lon>
<unit>
   <id>10280576</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HARBORNE HEATH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>512</id>
<name>SMETHWICK</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4911742716681</lat>
<lon>-1.97088706305413</lon>
<gazetteerText>SMETHWICK, a parochial division and three chapelries in Harborne parish, Stafford. The division is suburban to Birmingham; lies on the Birmingham canal, and on the Birmingham and Stour Valley and the Birmingham and Stourbridge railways, 3 miles W of the centre of Birmingham; is governed by a local board of health; carries on extensive manufactures, of the same kinds as those in Birmingham; enjoys great facilities of communication, with use of the canaland of four railway stations; and has post-offices,&#8225; of the name of S. and West S. under Birmingham, a r. station with telegraph, of the name of S., on the Stour Valley railway, a r. station, of the name of S.-Junction, at the junction of the Stourbridge railway, a &apos;&apos;summit-bridge,&quot; 265 feet long and 68 feet high, over the new canaland railway, a literary institution, with library and news-room, four churches, numerous dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, and several public schools. Real property in 1860, &#163;47,132. Pop. in 1851, 8,379; in 1861, 13,379. Houses, 2,588.-The three chapelries are S.-Trinity, S.-St. Matthew, and West S. or S.-St. Paul; and were constituted in 1842, 1856, and 1860. Pop., 1,058,3,935, and 2,817. Houses, 188,762, and 548. The livings are p. curacies in the diocese of Lichfield. Values, &#163;300,* &#163;191, and &#163;146.* Patrons, Trustees, the Incumbent of S.-Trinity, and Five Trustees. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smethwick</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2637607</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Smethwick/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36178</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36175</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36185</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36180</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36183</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36173</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36174</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36177</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36179</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36181</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36182</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36184</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36187</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36186</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36172</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=36176</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10075166</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10094136</id>
   <status>CB/MB/UD</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10280552</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTH HARBORNE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293121</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293182</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293194</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK ST ALBAN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293200</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK ST CHAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293212</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK ST MARY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293248</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK ST MATTHEW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293261</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK ST MATTHEW WITH ST CHAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293273</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK ST MICHAEL AND ALL ANGELS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293297</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK ST STEPHEN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552266</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SMETHWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10579892</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SMETHWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12749892</id>
   <status>PBCon/BCon</status>
   <name>SMETHWICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12830178</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SMETHWICK</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
