<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8485</id>
<name>RANTON</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8109917499127</lat>
<lon>-2.21779076900542</lon>
<gazetteerText>RANTON, or Ronton, a parish in the district and county of Stafford; on an affluent of the river Sow, 2&#188; miles N by W of Haughton r. station, and 4&#188; W by N of Stafford. It contains the hamlets of Hextells, Brough-Hill, Long Compton, Parknook, and Woodside; and its post town is Stafford. Acres, 1, 970. Real property, with Coton, &#163;3, 494. Pop., 280. Houses, 58. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to the Earl of Lichfield. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;93. Patron, the Earl of Lichfield. The church is tolerable; and there is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranton,_Staffordshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639637</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Ranton/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10291859</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>RANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10291884</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>RANTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>22653</id>
<name>RANTON ABBEY</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8156710006086</lat>
<lon>-2.23891040694405</lon>
<gazetteerText>RANTON-ABBEY, or Ronton-Abbey, an extra-parochial tract in the district and county of Stafford; adjacent to Ranton parish. Acres, 700. Real property, &#163;1,007. Pop., 13. Houses, 3. An Augustinian priory, a cell to Haughmond abbey in Salop, was founded here, in the time of Henry II., by Robert Fitz-Noel; and is now represented by only a tower and a small portion of the cloisters. A shooting-box of the Earl of Lichfield isnear the ruins. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranton_Abbey</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10291896</id>
   <status>CP/ExP</status>
   <name>RANTON ABBEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10291926</id>
   <status>EExP</status>
   <name>RANTON ABBEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
