<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8430</id>
<name>NORTON CANES</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6602231916854</lat>
<lon>-1.96568124743218</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTON-UNDER-CANNOCK, or Norton-Canes, a village and a parish in Penkridge district, Stafford. The village stands adjacent to Watling-street, near the S side of Cannock Chase, 1&#190; mile E by S of Wyrley r. station, 2&#188; N W of the Wyrley and Essington canal, 2&#190; W N W of Brownhills r. station, and 5&#190; N of Walsall, and has a post-office under Stafford. The parish contains also the hamlets of Little Wyrley and Brownhills. Acres, 4,077. Real property, &#163;17, 599; of which &#163;10,000 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 968; in 1861, 1, 628. Houses, 290. The increase of pop. rose from the extension of mining operations. The property is divided among a few. The manor belongs to W. Hanbury and P. F. Hussey, Esqs. Norton Hall and Wyrley Grove arechief residences; and the former belonged to the Bishops of Chester, and passed to the Aston family. Coal and ironstone abound; and the coal is extensively worked around Brownhills. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;330.* Patron, the Bishop of Lichfield. The church was rebuilt and enlarged in 1832, at a cost of &#163;1, 220; has a pinnacled tower; and contains an ancient font. A section of the parish, containing a pop. of 783 in 1861, is within the chapelry of Ogley-Hay, constituted in 1854. There are a Primitive Methodist chapel, an endowed school with &#163;39 a year, and charities &#163;16. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/NortonunderCannock/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norton_Canes</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641193</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10289609</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NORTON CANES</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10289660</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTON CANES</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
