<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7883</id>
<name>BETLEY</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0303056113241</lat>
<lon>-2.35659864084694</lon>
<gazetteerText>BETLEY, a village and a parish in Newcastle-underLyne district, Stafford. The village stands on the verge of the county, near the Northwestern railway, 3&#189; miles N of Madeley station, and 6&#189; NW by W of Newcastleunder-Lyne.-It has a post office&#8225; under Crewe, and fairs on 30 April, 31 July, and 29 Oct.; and was once a market-town. It consists of one wide street; and is a pleasant, healthy place. The parish comprises 1,435 acres, Real property, &#163;3,994. Pop., 850. Houses, 184. Betley Mere, a fine lake near the village, belongs to the Earl of Wilton; Betley Court, an elegant mansion, is the seat of Francis twemlow, Esq.; and Betley Hall, a fine old residence, is the seat of George Tollett, Esq. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, G. Tollett, Esq. The church consists of nave, chancel, and tower,-the nave ancient, the chancel built in 1610, the tower in 1713; and contains neat mural monuments of the Egertons and the Tolletts. There are Wesleyan chapel, and charities &#163;15. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Betley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655802</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Betley</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10095360</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>BETLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10273080</id>
   <status>CP/Tn</status>
   <name>BETLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10273092</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BETLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
