<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>402</id>
<name>ROWLEY REGIS</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4885339910026</lat>
<lon>-2.05341592622891</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROWLEY-REGIS, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Dudley district, Stafford. The village stands adjacent to the Birmingham and Stourbridge railway, near the Birmingham canal, 2&#190; miles S E of Dudley; and has a station on the railway, a post-office&#8225; under Dudley, and a police station. The parish contains also the villages or hamlets of Cradley-Heath, Old Hill, Reddall-Hill, and Tividale. Acres, 3, 503. Real property, &#163;98, 550; of which &#163;44, 234 are in mines, &#163;320 in quarries, &#163;32, 699 in iron-works, and &#163;356 in gas-works. Pop. in 1851, 14, 249; in 1861, 19, 785. Houses, 3, 685. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of miningoperations, and of iron-manufacture. There are severalgood residences. The Rowley hills diversify the surface; rise to an altitude of nearly 900 feet; and send off streamsin opposite directions, towards the Trent and the Severn. Coal, ironstone, building-stone, and excellent clay abound. Iron-works at Corngreaves and Cradley are of great extent; and steel-works, hardware manufactories, agricultural implement works, tile-kilns, and malting establishments, in various parts, employ very many hands. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church comprises nave, aisles, and chancel; and has a tower, rebuilt in 1858. The p. curacy of Reddall-Hill is a separate benefice. Value, &#163;300. There are chapels for Baptists, Wesleyans, Primitive Methodists, and New Connexion Methodists, two endowed schools with &#163;73 a year, a largeschool erected by the New British Iron company, a national school, and charities &#163;60 A Wesleyan chapel at Rowley village was erected in 1863. The sub-districtis conterminate with the parish. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rowley_Regis</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2639040</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/RowleyRegis/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10027860</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>ROWLEY REGIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10062044</id>
   <status>UD/MB</status>
   <name>ROWLEY REGIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10292219</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>ROWLEY REGIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10292220</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROWLEY REGIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550117</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>ROWLEY REGIS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12753081</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>ROWLEY REGIS AND TIPTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
