<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8586</id>
<name>TUTBURY</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.8401722889549</lat>
<lon>-1.71006373228672</lon>
<gazetteerText>TUTBURY, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Burton-upon-Trent district, Stafford. The village stands on the river Dove, near the North Staffordshire railway, 4&#189; miles NW by N of Burton-upon-Trent; was once a market-town; and has a post-office&#8225; under Burton-upon-Trent, a r. station, and fairs on 14 Feb., 15 Aug., and 1 Dec. The parish comprises 4,001 acres. Real property, &#163;11,232. Pop. in 1851, 1,798; in 1861, 1,982. Houses, 407. The manor belongs to the Queen. Berkeley Lodge, Needwood House, and East Lodge are chief residences. T. Castle was a Mercian fort; went, after the Norman conquest, to H. de Ferrars, and was then rebuilt; passed to the Crown in the time of Henry III.; was again rebuilt by John of Gaunt; became the prison of Mary Queen of Scots in 1568-9; was visited by James I. in 1619, 1621, and 1624, and by Charles I. in 1636; was garrisoned for the Crown at the commencement of Charles&apos; civil wars, and visited by him both before and after the battle of Naseby; was taken by Brereton in 1645, and dismantled in the following year; seems to have occupied an area of about three acres; and is now represented by considerable ruins, including gateway and part of walls and towers, surrounded by a deep dry moat. A Benedictine priory was founded in 1080, and made a cell to Peter-super-Divam in Normandy. Upwards of 100,000 ancient coins, supposed to have been lost in 1321, were found in the Dove in 1831; and some of them are now in the British museum. There are cotton and corn mills, and a large glass manufactory. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;286.* Patron, Sir D. Mosley, Bart. The church belonged to the priory, is chiefly Norman, and was restored in 1867. There are three dissenting chapels, an endowed school with &#163;47 a year, and charities &#163;624. The impostor Anne Moor, who pretended to live without food or drink, was a native.&#151;The sub-district contains 7 parishes, 2 parts, and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 27,211. Pop., 6,797. Houses, 1,439. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Tutbury/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tutbury</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635323</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10054618</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>TUTBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173619</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>TUTBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10295592</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>TUTBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10295671</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TUTBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550518</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TUTBURY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10581497</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TUTBURY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7862</id>
   <name>ANSLOW</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
