<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>984</id>
<name>STONE</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.902373528517</lat>
<lon>-2.13794106054053</lon>
<gazetteerText>STONE, a town, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Staffordshire. The town stands on the river Trent, the Grand Junction canal, and the North Staffordshire railway, at the junction of the lines from Colwich and Stafford, 7 miles NNW of Stafford; dates from very ancient times; had a canonry, founded in 670 by King Wulfhere, and made a cell in 1260 to Kenilworth; adjoins a tract on which the Duke of Cumberland drew up his army, in 1745, when pursuing Prince Charles; was the birth-place of Earl St. Vincent; is a seat of petty-sessions and a polling place; consists chiefly of one long street, with smaller diverging streets; carries on shoemaking, brewing, and transit-traffic; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a r. station with telegraph, commodious wharves, two banking offices, a good hotel, two churches, two dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a free grammar-school, an endowed school with &#163;100 a year, a mechanics&apos; institute, a workhouse, charities &#163;144, a weekly market on Saturday, a great market on every alternate Tuesday, and fairs on Shrove-Tuesday, the Tuesday after Mid-Lent, Whit-Tuesday, 5 Aug., and 30 Sept. Pop. in 1851, 3,443; in 1861, 4,509. Houses, 889.&#151;The parish contains 6 townships and a part, 5 liberties, and a hamlet; and comprises 20,030 acres. Real property, &#163;14,960; of which &#163;80 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 8,736; in 1861, 9,382. Houses, 1,867. S. Park is the property of Earl Granville; and Meaford Hall, of General Forester. The head living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;240.* Patron, the Bishop of L. The living of Christchurch is a p. curacy, united with Tittensor chapelry. Value, &#163;300.* Patrons, Simeon&apos;s Trustees. The parish includes also Aston and Hilderstone chapelries, and parts of Blurton, Normacot, and Formbook chapelries.&#151;The sub-district includes all Stone parish, except Normacot township, and all Sandon and Milwich parishes. Pop., 9,528. Houses, 1,908. -The district includes also Ecclesalland Trentham districts-districts, and comprises 68,524 acres. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;6,642. Pop. in 1851, 19,344; in 1861, 21,926. Houses, 4,456. Marriages in 1863, 164; births, 795,- of which 58 were illegitimate; deaths, 477,-of which 186 were at ages under 5 years, and 9 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 1,541; births, 6,353; deaths, 4,176. The places of worship, in 1851, were 25 of the Church of England, with 8,990 sittings; 2 of Independents, with 920 s.; 4 of Wesleyans, with 338 s.; 4 of New Connexion Methodists, with 520 s.; 2 of Primitive Methodists, with 55 s.; and 2 of Roman Catholics, with 440 s. The schools were 23 public day-schools, with 1,979 scholars; 40 private day-schools, with 929 s.; 25 Sunday schools, with 2,530 s.; and 4 evening schools for adults, with 49 s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stone,_Staffordshire</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Stone</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Stone/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636822</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10002837</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10099158</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10111031</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10185567</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186663</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10206303</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10293960</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10294009</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10294046</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONE CHRIST CHURCH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10294058</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>STONE RURAL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550063</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741420</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>STAFFORDSHIRE STONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12741455</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>STONE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7994</id>
   <name>CHEBSEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8041</id>
   <name>ECCLESHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8428</id>
   <name>COLD NORTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8551</id>
   <name>SWYNNERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8611</id>
   <name>WHITGREAVE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8635</id>
   <name>WORSTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8639</id>
   <name>YARLET</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
