<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>458</id>
<name>BRIERLEY HILL</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4877723519309</lat>
<lon>-2.1413399728319</lon>
<gazetteerText>BRIERLEY HILL, a town and a chapelry in Kingswinford parish, Stafford. The town stands on the river Stour, the Dudley and Stourbridge canal, and the West Midland railway, 2&#188; miles NNE of Stourbridge; and has a station on the railway and a head post office.&#8225; It lies in a hilly tract of great mineral wealth; forms a street about a mile long; carries on industry in coal mines, clay fields, brick-works, potteries, glass-works, iron-rolling-mills, boiler-works, chain and spade factories, and malting establishments; and publishes a weekly newspaper. The church at it is a cruciform structure, built in 1765, and enlarged in 1823 and 1837, with a tower which commands an extensive view; and there are chapels for Independents, Baptists, Wesleyan Methodists, and Primitive Methodists. The chapelry includes the town; and was constituted in 1842. Pop., 10,755. Houses, 2,060. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacy of Hart&apos;s Hill, in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Rector of Kingswinford. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/BrierleyHill/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brierley_Hill</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654724</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10074460</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BRIERLEY HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10110993</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>BRIERLEY HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10273924</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>BRIERLEY HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10273948</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BRIERLEY HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12748504</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>BRIERLEY HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12835838</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BRIERLEY HILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
