<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>7911</id>
<name>BREWOOD</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6656659865482</lat>
<lon>-2.17704982622952</lon>
<gazetteerText>BREWOOD, a small town, a parish, and a subdistrict, in Penkridge district, Stafford. The town stands near Watling-street, the river Penk, and the Birmingham and Liverpool canal, 2 miles WNW of Four Ashes r. station, and 4&#189; SW by S of Penkridge; and has a post office&#8225; under Stafford. It formerly had a weekly market; and still has fairs on the third Thursday of March, May, and Nov., and on 19 Sept. Some trade is carried on in malting and lock-making. The parish includes also the liberties of Chillington, Somerford, Engleton, Horsebrook, Coven, Kiddermore-Green, and Huttons and Gunston. Acres, 11,839. Real property, &#163;21,634. Pop., 3,399. Houses, 723. The property is divided among a few. Chillington Hall, a fine mansion, is the seat of the Cliffords. Two nunneries, Cistertian and Benedictine, were founded in the parish, the former in the reign of Richard I., or of John; and came to be known as the White Ladies and the Black Ladies; and they figure under these names in the narrative of Charles II. &apos;s concealment in the neighbouring locality of Boscobel, after the battle of Worcester. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;670.* Patron, the Bishop of Lichfield. The church is later English, with a handsome spire; and was renovated in 1833. The vicarages of Bishopswood and Coven are separate benefices. There are chapels for Independents, Methodists, and Roman Catholics. A grammar school, founded by Dr. Knightley in the time of Queen Elizabeth, and at which Bishop Hurd and Sir E. Littleton were educated, has &#163;412 a year from endowment; and other charities have &#163;47.-The subdistrict contains two parishes and parts of three others. Acres, 20,782. Pop., 5,629. Houses, 1,177. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Brewood/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brewood</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654767</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53395</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53396</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10061258</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>BREWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10273882</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>BREWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10273912</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BREWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550129</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BREWOOD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570396</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BREWOOD</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
