<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8419</id>
<name>MUCKLESTONE</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9408962880468</lat>
<lon>-2.40272802473352</lon>
<gazetteerText>MUCKLESTONE, or Muxton, a township in Stafford, and a parish partly also in Salop; all in the district of Market-Drayton. The township lies near the river Tern at the boundary with Salop, 4&#189; miles N E of Market-Drayton r. station. Real property, &#163;1, 876. Pop., 177. Houses, 35. The parish contains also the townships of Aston, Knighton, Oakley, and Winnington in Stafford, and the chapelry of Woore in Salop; and its post town is Market-Drayton. Acres of the Stafford portion, 3, 240; of the Salop portion, 5, 291. Real property of the Stafford portion, &#163;5, 949; of the Salop portion, &#163;6, 693. Pop. of the whole in 1851, 1, 736; in 1861, 1, 610. Houses, 340. Pop. of the Salop portion in 1851, 860; in 1861, 783. Houses, 169. The property is notmuch divided. The manor belonged anciently to the Morgans, and belongs now to Lord Crewe. Oakley Hallis a chief residence, and stands in an extensive park. Good building stone is quarried. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;1,072.* Patron, Lord Crewe. The church was rebuilt in 1790; but retains a previous tower, from which Margaret of Anjou, in 1459, witnessed the defeat of the royalists on Bloreheath. The p. curacy of Woore is a separate benefice. There are schools with &#163;46 a year from endowment, and charities &#163;126. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/SAL/Mucklestone/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Mucklestone/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mucklestone</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642030</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10289245</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>MUCKLESTONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10289257</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MUCKLESTONE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
