<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>635</id>
<name>TIPTON</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5320495150806</lat>
<lon>-2.05391037902841</lon>
<gazetteerText>TIPTON, or Tibbington, a parish in Dudley district, Stafford; on the Birmingham canal, and on the Stour Valley, the South Staffordshire, the Great Western, and the Oxford, Worcester, and Wolverhampton railways, 1&#189; mile NNE of Dudley. It contains Horseley-Heath, Dudley-Port, Tipton-Green, Princes-End, Toll-End, and part of Greatbridge villages; and it has seven r. stations, wharves, a head post-office&#8225; of Tipton at Horseley-Heath, receiving post-offices&#8225; at Princes-End, Tipton-Green, and Greatbridge, four police stations, a police and petty-sessions court-house, a board of health, and a plentiful supply of good water. Acres, 3,020. Real property, &#163;130,225; of which &#163;32 are in quarries, &#163;38,875 in mines, and &#163;43,549 in ironworks. Pop. in 1851, 24,872; in 1861, 28,870. Houses, 5,695. The property is much subdivided. Iron-stone and coal abound; fire-bricks, cement, soap, grease, malt, files, and nails are made; and heavy iron goods, including anchors, cables, pit-chains, iron-fenders, fire-irons, and all kinds of steam-engine machinery are largely manufactured. The parish is ecclesiastically cut into the four sections of St. Martin, St. Paul, St John, and St. Mark. The livings are all p. curacies in the diocese of Lichfield. Value of St. Martin, &#163;750;* of St. P., &#163;300; of St. J. &#163;50; of St. Mark, &#163;150.* Patron of St. Martin, S. S. Lloyd, Esq.; of St. P., the Incumbent of St. Martin; of St. J., the Incumbent of St. Martin; of St. Mark, alternately the Crown and the Bishop. Three of the churches are recent; and the fourth, excepting the tower, was recently rebuilt. There are 15 dissenting chapels, several national schools, a British school, and charities &#163;69. One of the dissenting chapels, Wesleyan, was built in 1866, at a cost of &#163;5,000. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Tipton/StMartin/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tipton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Tipton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635785</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10098490</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>TIPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10109085</id>
   <status>MB/UD</status>
   <name>TIPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10294927</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>TIPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10294964</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TIPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10295014</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TIPTON ST JOHN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10295040</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TIPTON ST MATTHEW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550099</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TIPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12781362</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TIPTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12833362</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TIPTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24174</id>
<name>TIPTON GREEN</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5263916822644</lat>
<lon>-2.06633659053302</lon>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tipton_Green</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10295117</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TIPTON ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>21674</id>
<name>OCKER HILL</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5398894640914</lat>
<lon>-2.04128875736872</lon>
<gazetteerText>OCKER-HILL, a hamlet and a chapelry in Tipton parish, Stafford. The hamlet lies on the Walsall and Wolverhampton railway, near the Birmingham canal, 1&#189;mile S W of Wednesbury; and has a station on the railway . The chapelry was constituted in 1845; and its post town is Tipton. Rated property, &#163;8, 500. Pop. in 1861, 3, 787. Houses, 726. The property is subdivided. The inhabitants share in the iron manufactories and other industry of Tipton and Wednesbury. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;150.* Patron, alternately the Crown and the Bishop. The church was built in 1850, at a cost of about &#163;2, 500; and is an edifice of blue brick, in the later English style. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641093</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10289828</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TIPTON ST MARK</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>24175</id>
<name>TIVIDALE</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5138167394629</lat>
<lon>-2.03831686450522</lon>
<gazetteerText>TIVIDALE, a village in Rowley-Regis parish, Stafford; on the Birmingham canal, and at an intersection of railways, 1 mile N of Tipton. It has a post-office&#8225; under Tipton, two Methodist chapels, and extensive ironworks, foundries, chain-works, brick-works, collieries, and quarries; and it exports great quantities of the stone popularly called Rowley rag Pop., 1,860. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tividale</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10295075</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TIVIDALE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
