<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>772</id>
<name>WOLSTANTON</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0340444399148</lat>
<lon>-2.24314162737203</lon>
<gazetteerText>WOLSTANTON, a village, a township, a parish, a sub-district, and a district, in Stafford. The village stands adjacent to the North Staffordshire railway, between Etruria and Burslem r. stations, 2 miles NNW of Stoke-upon-Trent; and has a post-office under Stoke-upon-Trent, a church almost entirely rebuilt in 1860 at a cost of &#163;4,500, a Wesleyan chapel built in 1866, and charities &#163;16. The township includes the village, and extends beyond it. Real property, &#163;6,577. Pop. in 1851, 1,317; in 1861, 1,842. Houses, 395. The increase of pop. arose from the extension of the earthen-ware trade. The manor belongs to the Duchy of Lancaster. The parish contains 12 townships, and comprises 10,739 acres. Pop. in 1851 ,22,191; in 1861, 32,029. Houses, 6,237. The property is much subdivided. Most of the area lies within the tract called the Potteries; and there are numerous porcelain and earthenware factories, many brick and tile yards, and several iron and steel works, engine works, and silk and cotton mills. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;350.* Patron, R. Sneyd, Esq. The vicarages of New Chapel, Chesterton, Mowcop, Silverdale, Tunstall, Kidsgrove, and Golden-Hill, are separate benefices.&#151;The sub-district includes only four townships. Pop., 9,653. Houses, 1,985.&#151;The district includes Tunstall sub-district, comprising all the rest of W. parish, and Burslem sub-district conterminate with Burslem parish. Acres of the district, 13,679. Poor rates in 1863, &#163;13,938. Pop. in 1851, 42,916; in 1861, 54,356. Houses, 10,627. Marriages in 1866, 717; births, 2,853,-of which 203 were illegitimate; deaths, 1,960,-of which 1,079 were at ages under 5 years, and 14 at ages above 85. Marriages in the ten years 1851-60, 5,466; births, 20,906; deaths, 12,595. The places of worship, in 1851, were 10 of the Church of England , with 6,183 sittings; 1 of Independents, with 350 s.; 1 of Baptists, with 120 s.; 1 of -Unitarians, the s. not reported; 14 of Wesleyans, with 5,261 s.; 6 of New Connexion Methodists, with 1,708 s.; 11 of Primitive Methodists, with 2,582 s.; 2 of the Wesleyan Association, with 1,556 s.; and 1 of Roman Catholics, with 500 s. The schools were 18 public day-schools, with 2,266 scholars; 59 private day-schools, with 1,750 s.; 40 Sunday schools, with 9,301 s.; and 4 evening schools for adults, with 46 s. The workhouse is in Chell township. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolstanton</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Wolstanton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Wolstanton</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633693</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10043517</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>WOLSTANTON AND BURSLEM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10055714</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>WOLSTANTON AND BURSLEM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10081567</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>WOLSTANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10136611</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>WOLSTANTON UNITED</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10297400</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>WOLSTANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10297461</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WOLSTANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550312</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WOLSTANTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12781398</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>WOLSTANTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>8423</id>
<name>NEWCHAPEL</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>53.0972498999738</lat>
<lon>-2.20929308765277</lon>
<gazetteerText>THURSFIELD, or Newchapel, a chapelry in Wolstanton parish, Stafford; 1&#189; mile E by N of Kidsgrove-Junction r. station, and 3 N of Burslem. It was constituted in 1846; it extends much beyond T. proper, or T. township; and it has a post-office, of the name of Newchapel, under Stoke-upon-Trent. Pop., 3,440. Houses, 630. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;110.* Patrons, R. Sneyd, Esq., and others. The church was built in 1767, and repaired in 1827. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Newchapel/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newchapel</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10289397</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEWCHAPEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10289403</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>NEWCHAPEL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
