<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1319</id>
<name>LONGTON</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.9833035232462</lat>
<lon>-2.13423553390084</lon>
<gazetteerText>Longton.-- mun. bor. and market town, Stoke upon Trent par., Staffordshire, at S. extremity of the Potteries, 2&#189; miles SE. and within the parl. limits of Stoke upon Trent, and 152 miles NW. of London by rail, 786 ac., pop. 18,620; P.O., T.O., 2 Banks. Market-day, Saturday. Before the rise of the industrial activity of the &quot;Potteries,&quot; Longton was an inconsiderable hamlet; it is now a large and prosperous town. During the years 1883-84, Acts of Parliament were obtained, which greatly extended the municipal area by embracing the districts of Dresden, East Vale, and Florence. The people are mostly engaged in the mfr. of china and earthenware, but not a few work in the neighbouring collieries and ironstone mines. Malting, brewing, and brickmaking are the other employments. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/STS/Longton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Longton,_Staffordshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643620</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=53377</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10004688</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>LONGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10278417</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>LONGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10288010</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>LONGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10288058</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10288435</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONGTON ST MARY AND ST CHAD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10550464</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>LONGTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1283</id>
   <name>FENTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>7990</id>
   <name>CAVERSWALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8582</id>
   <name>TRENTHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>21504</id>
<name>LANE END</name>
<container>STAFFORDSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.989344795702</lat>
<lon>-2.13855699740272</lon>
<gazetteerText>LANE-END and LONGTON, a township in Stoke-upon-Trent parish, and within Stoke-upon-Trent borough, Staffordshire; on the North Staffordshire railway, at the junction of the Hanley and the Silverdale branches, 2&#190; miles SE of Stoke-upon-Trent. It contains the post, market, polling, and railway town of Longton. Real property, &#163;38,371; of which &#163;400 are in mines, and &#163;220 in iron-works. Pop. In 1851, 15,149; in 1861,16,690. Houses, 3,277. This township is part of the Potteries; it contained, toward the end of last century, no greater a seat of population than an obscure village; it acquired importance and wealth from vigorous working of the earthenware and porcelain manufacture; it possesses much coal, ironstone, brown limestone, with coloured marl, porcelain clay, and manganese; it presents a large aggregate of edificed area, with the features characteristic of the Potteries; and it has three churches, five dissenting chapels, several public schools, and other institutions. One of the churches is at Edensor; another is called St. James, Longton; and the third is called St. John, Lane-End. The last was rebuilt in 1792, and enlarged in 1827; and has a tower of about 1760. The living of it is a p. curacy in the diocese of Lichfield. Value, &#163;280.* Patrons, Trustees. See Edensor and Longton. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10282147</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LANE END</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
