<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>1248</id>
<name>BEDWORTH</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4734058398838</lat>
<lon>-1.47880164698637</lon>
<gazetteerText>BEDWORTH, a town and a parish in Foleshill district, Warwick. The town stands adjacent to the Coventry canal and the Coventry and Nuneaton railway, 3&#189; miles S of Nuneaton; and has a station on the railway, a post office&#8225; under Nuneaton, and two chief inns. It carries on a manufacture of gauze ribbons, and a large trade in coals, lime, and bricks; and has a fair on Whit wednesday. Pop., 3,968. Houses, 888.&#151;The parish comprises 2,157 acres. Real property, &#163;15,345; of which &#163;2,700 are in mines. Pop., 5,656. Houses, 1,239. The property is much subdivided. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;562.* Patron, the Lord of the Manor. The church is a modern edifice with square embattled tower; and was enlarged in 1850. There are three dissenting chapels, two free schools, and very extensive alms-houses; the last in the form of three sides of a cloistered quadrangle, in later Gothic, built in 1840, at a cost of &#163;8,500. The almshouses have &#163;1,176 of income, and other charities &#163;20. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/Bedworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2656031</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bedworth</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=57088</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10108706</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>BEDWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10294903</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BEDWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10294940</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BEDWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10569503</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BEDWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828949</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BEDWORTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8976</id>
   <name>EXHALL</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
