<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9191</id>
<name>MANCETTER</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.5589091738374</lat>
<lon>-1.53157004299468</lon>
<gazetteerText>MANCETTER, or MANCHESTER, a village and a parish in Atherstone district, Warwick. The village stands adjacent to Watling-street, the river Anker, the boundary with Leicestershire, the Trent Valley railway, and the Coventry canal, 1 mile SE of Atherstone; occupies part of the site of the Roman station Mandnessedum; and, together with the neighbourhood, has finished a considerable number and variety of Roman relics. Pop., 355. Houses, 97. The parish contains also the township of Atherstone, and the hamlets of Oldbury and Hartshill; and its Post town is Atherstone. Acres, 4,120. Real property, &#163;21,637: of which &#163;398 are in quarries. Pop., 5,408. Houses, 1,239. The property is much subdivided. The Manor House is the residence of Viscount Curzon; Mancetter House, of J. R. Harper, Esq.; Mancetter Lodge, ofAlliston, Esq.; and Oldbury Hall, ofH. Okeover, Esq. Robert Glover, who lived in the manor house, and Mrs. Lewis, who was also a resident in the parish, were martyred for religion in respectively 1555 and 1577. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;230. * Patrons, the church Patronage Society. The church stands on an eminence, within the limits of the ancient Roman station; dates from the middle of the 14th century; consists of nave and chancel, with a tower; and contains monuments to RObert Glover and Mrs. Lewis. The vicarages of Atherstone and Hartshill are separate benefices. There are three dissenting chapels, a Roman Catholic chapel, a Benedictine nunnery, a free school, and a girls&apos; national school, in Atherstone; two dissenting chapels, two endowed schools, and a national school, in Hartshill; and eleven alms houses, from a bequest of &#163;2,000, in Mancetter village. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mancetter</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/Mancetter/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643124</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42666</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10316534</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MANCETTER</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10316558</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MANCETTER</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9115</id>
   <name>HARTSHILL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9247</id>
   <name>OLDBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
