<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9364</id>
<name>STONELEIGH</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.3640725549757</lat>
<lon>-1.53805905986113</lon>
<gazetteerText>STONELEIGH, a parish, with a village and seven hamlets, in the district and county of Warwick; on the river Avon, 2&#189; miles E by N of Kenilworth r. station. It has a post-office under Kenilworth. Acres, 9,907. Real property, &#163;15,743. Pop., 1,283. Houses, 283. The manor, from before the Norman conquest till the time of Edward II., belonged to the Crown. A Cistertian monastery was founded here by Henry II.; went, at the dissolution, to the Brandons; and passed to the Leighs. S. Abbey, now a magnificent mansion, the seat of Lord Leigh, retains restored portions of the monastic buildings; consists chiefly of parts erected about the end of the 17th century; stands in an extensive, well-wooded, undulating park; and was visited, in 1858, by Queen Victoria and the Prince Consort. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;510.* Patron, Lord Leigh. The church is ancient, partly Norman, and good. The vicarage of Westwood is a separate benefice. There are a reading room and library, a national school, alms houses with &#163;139 a year, and other charities &#163;21. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/Stoneleigh/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoneleigh,_Warwickshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636809</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=57135</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10320525</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>STONELEIGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10320537</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STONELEIGH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580675</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>STONLEIGH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
