<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9147</id>
<name>LONG ITCHINGTON</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2794893737123</lat>
<lon>-1.40805130618003</lon>
<gazetteerText>ITCHINGTON (LONG), a village and a parish in Southam district, Warwick. The village stands on the river Ichene or Watergall, near the Warwick and Napton canal, 2 miles NNW of Southam and 2 S of Marton r. station; and has a post office under Rugby. The parish contains also the hamlets of Stoney-Thorpe and Bascote. Acres, 4, 510. Real property, &#163;8, 636. Pop. in 1851, 1, 216; in 1861, 1, 150. Houses, 271. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged to the Odingsells; passed through several hands to Dudley Earl of Leicester, who here entertained Queen Elizabeth on her way to Kenilworth; and belongs now to Lord Leigh and the Earl of Aylesford. The parish is a meet for the Warwickshire hounds. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;210. Patron, J. D. Ellis, Esq., three turns, and Lord Leigh, one turn. The church is very an]cient; consists of nave, S aisle, and chancel, with a tower; and was restored in 1866. There are chapels for Independents and Primitive Methodists, a neat national school of 1855, and charities &#163;31. St. Wulfstan was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_Itchington</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/LongItchington/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2643674</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=57112</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10315300</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LONG ITCHINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10315335</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LONG ITCHINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
