<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>8672</id>
<name>CHARLECOTE</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2068864064163</lat>
<lon>-1.61050466133842</lon>
<gazetteerText>CHARLCOTE, a village and a parish in Stratford-on-Avon district, Warwick. The village stands on the river Avon, 3&#190; miles W of the Fosse way, and 4&#189; ENE of Stratford-on-Avon r. station. The parish includes also the hamlets of Thelsford and Hunscote; and its Post Town is Hampton-Lucy, under Warwick. Acres, 2,190. Real property, &#163;4,025. Pop., 245. Houses, 54. The manor, with all the property, belongs to Henry Lucy, Esq. The Lucys have been in possession since the time of Richard I. The manor-house, Charlcote House, was built in 1558, by Sir Thomas Lucy, believed to be the Justice Shallow of Shakspeare. It forms three sides of a quadrangle; shows all the characteristics of the Tudor architecture; has been altered and renovated in strict keeping with its original character; has a gatehouse with an oriel window, flanked by octagon towers, and stands in an extensive well-wooded park. The great hall is believed to have been the scene of Shakpeare&apos;s examination, consequent on his deer stealing exploit; and retains many of the features which it originally possessed. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;183. Patron, Henry Lucy, Esq. The church was rebuilt in 1853, in the decorated style of the 14th century; and the Lucy chapel, separated from the chancel by a richly carved oaken screen, contains the monument of Sir Thomas Lucy and his lady by Bernini, and two other interesting monuments. Charities, &#163;10. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/Charlecote/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlecote</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2653338</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=57034</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10299068</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Ch</status>
   <name>CHARLECOTE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10299093</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CHARLECOTE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
