<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9119</id>
<name>HATTON</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.307730232726</lat>
<lon>-1.65055890120643</lon>
<gazetteerText>HATTON, a village and a parish in the district and county of Warwick. The village stands near the Birmingham and Warwick canal, and the Oxford and Birmingham railway, 3 iniles NW by W of Warwick; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Warwick. The parish contains also the hamlets of Beausall and Shrewley. Acres, 4, 099. Real property, &#163;8, 798. Pop. in 1851, 961; in 1861, 1, 259. Houses, 205. The property is subdivided. The manor belonged to Hugh de Hatton, Earl of Warwick; and was given by him to Wroxhall abbey. The county lnnatic asylum was recently built here, at a cost of &#163;50, 000; is an elegant structnre, in a modified Tudor style, with a frontage of 700 feet; stands on a plot of 40 acres, handsomely laid out; possesses accommodation for about 350 patients;.and, at the census of 1861, had 299 inmates. Hatton Hill commands a fine view of the surrounding country. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;250.* Patrons, Trustees. The church is in good order; has some striking modern painted glass; and contains a tablet to Dr. Samuel Parr, and many monumental inscriptions from his pen. Parr was long the incumbent of the parish; and a noble room in the parsonage was built by him for a library. An endowed school has &#163;20 a year, and other charities have &#163;100. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/Hatton/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hatton,_Warwickshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647335</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=56993</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10314562</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>HATTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10314598</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HATTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9185</id>
   <name>LEEK WOOTTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
