<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9273</id>
<name>POLESWORTH</name>
<container>WARWICKSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.6184513970268</lat>
<lon>-1.60675023870611</lon>
<gazetteerText>POLESWORTH, a village and a parish in Atherstone district, Warwick. The village stands on the river Anker, near the Coventry canal and the Trent Valley railway, 1&#189; mile N of Watling-street, and 4 E S E of Tamworth; is an ancient place; was once a market-town; and has a station on the railway, a post-office&#8225; under Tamworth, and a fair on the Monday after 19 Sept. The parish contains also the hamlets of Warton, Dordon, and Hallend-with-Freazley, and the manors of Pooley and Bramcote. Acres, 6, 310. Real property, &#163;8, 914. Pop.in 1851, 2, 104; in 1861, 2, 451. Houses, 500. The manor and much of the land belong to Sir George Chet-wynd, Bart. Pooley Hall belonged anciently to the Marmions; passed, in 1399, to the Cokains; was rebuilt, in 1509, by Sir T. Cokain; and belongs now toW. G. Wynne Finch, Esq. A nunnery was founded at Poles-worth by King Egbert, or his son; was refounded, after the Norman conquest, by Robert Marmion; and has leftsome remains. There are collieries, quarries, and clay-works. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;502.* Patron, the Lord Chancellor. The church belonged to the ancient nunnery; and consists of nave and aisle, with a very fine tower. The p.curacy of Warton is a separate benefice. There are an Independent chapel, two Baptist chapels, and Church of England endowed schools with &#163;401 a year. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WAR/Polesworth/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polesworth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2640173</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=42679</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10318245</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>POLESWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10318282</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>POLESWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10578590</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>POLESWORTH</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8003</id>
   <name>CLIFTON CAMPVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8151</id>
   <name>HARLASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8525</id>
   <name>STATFOLD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8548</id>
   <name>AUSTREY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8614</id>
   <name>WIGGINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>8642</id>
   <name>GLASCOTE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9236</id>
   <name>NEWTON REGIS</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9353</id>
   <name>SHUTTINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10618</id>
   <name>BILSTONE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11349</id>
   <name>TWYCROSS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
