<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>5343</id>
<name>BARTON</name>
<container>WESTMORLAND</container>
<lat>54.5570235865427</lat>
<lon>-2.88139486000667</lon>
<gazetteerText>BARTON, a parish in West Ward district, Westmoreland; on the river Eamont, 3&#189; miles W by S of Clifton r. station, and 4 SW of Penrith. It extends along Ulles water to its head at Patterdale; includes the townships of High Barton, Low Winder, Stockbridge and Tirril, Yanwath and Eamont-Bridge, and the chapelries of Martindale and Patterdale-with-Hartsop; and contains the post offices of Pooley-Bridge and Patterdale under Penrith. Acres, 35,312; of which 1,622 are water. Real property, &#163;19,825. Pop., 1,808. Houses, 345. The property throughout the townships is not much divided; and the greater part of it belonged to the Lancasters, and ha descended from them to the Earl of Lonsdale; while that of the two chapelries is subdivided. The scenery includes many of the most admired features of the Lake country; and will be noticed in our article on Ulleswater, and in other articles. Various minerals are found in the hills; particularly a variety of spars and petrifactions, on Bartonfell. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Carlisle. Value, &#163;170.* Patron, the Earl of Lonsdale. The church is a low large building, with a heavy tower between the nave and the chancel; was recently repaired and improved; and contains the tomb of one of the Lancasters, and monumental memorials of several other families. The chapelries of Martindale and Patterdale are separate benefices. A grammar school has an endowed income of &#163;91; and other charities &#163;23. Dr. Langbaine, the historian and antiquary, who died in 1657, was a native. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WES/Barton/index.htm</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10092103</id>
   <status>PA</status>
   <name>BARTON FELL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10148431</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>HIGH BARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10171088</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BARTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10191890</id>
   <status>CP/AP/CP</status>
   <name>BARTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
