<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11853</id>
<name>WEST KINGTON</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.4922005541496</lat>
<lon>-2.29156609483028</lon>
<gazetteerText>KINGTON (WEST), a parish, with a village, in Chippenham district, Wilts; near Akeman street and the boundary with Gloucester, 8 miles NW by W of Chippenham r. station. Post town, Marshfield, under Chippenham. Acres, 2, 444. Real property, &#163;4, 115. Pop., 405. Houses, 79. The manor belongs to W. Codrington, Esq. Building stone is quarried. Vestiges exist of a Roman camp. The parish is a meet for the Beaufort hounds. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;417.* Patron, the Bishop of Gloucester and Bristol. The church is ancient, and has a tower. Bishop Latimer was rector. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/WestKington/index.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2634377</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10405970</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>WEST KINGTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10406018</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WEST KINGTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>11857</id>
<name>KINGTON ST MICHAEL</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.4962054497028</lat>
<lon>-2.14163448412794</lon>
<gazetteerText>KINGTON-ST. MICHAEL, -formerly Kington-Monachorum, -a village, a tything, and a parish in Chippenham district, Wilts. The village stands near the Chippenham and Stroud railway, 3 miles NW by N of Chippenham; was once a market town; and has still a fair on 6 Oct. The tything includes the village, and extends into the country. Real property, &#163;3, 745; of which &#163;17 are in quarries. Pop., 530. Houses, 121. The parish contains also the tythings of Kington-Langley and Easton-Piercy; the former of which has a postoffice under Chippenham. Acres, 4, 136. Real property, &#163;8, 705. Pop. in 1851, 1, 219; in 1861, 1, 089. Houses, 245. The property is much subdivided. The manor belonged to the Saxon kings; was given to Glastonbury abbey; and passed to the Snells and the Longs. A Benedictine nunnery, a cell to the abbey, was founded here before the time of Henry II.; and has left some remains at a farm. Aubrey, the antiquary, a native of Easton-Piercy, says that &quot;forty or fifty nuns might be seen in a morning spinning with their wheels and bobbins.&quot; Britton, the antiquary, was a native of the village. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristols Value, &#163;450.* Patron, Ear. Cowley. The church is chiefly early English, with Norman chancel arch, and with a tower of 1726; was restored in 1857; and contains a memorial window to Aubrey and Britton, erected in 1857, two brasses, and some monuments to the Colemans, the Aubreys, and others. The p. curacy of Kington-Langley is a separate benefice. A school has &#163;5 from endowment, all houses &#163;20, and other charities &#163;8 10s. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/KingtonStMichael/index.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kington_St_Michael</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10406080</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>KINGTON ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10406110</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KINGTON ST MICHAEL</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>11855</id>
<name>KINGTON LANGLEY</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.4956463561657</lat>
<lon>-2.11410786035058</lon>
<gazetteerText>KINGTON-LANGLEY, a tything and a chapelry in Kington-St. Michael parish, Wilts. The tything lies 1 mile NE of Kington-St. Michael village, and 2&#189; N of Chippenham r. station; and has a post office under Chippenham. Acres, 1, 642. Real property, &#163;3, 277. Pop., 530. Houses, 121. The chapelry is conterminate with the tything; and bears the alternative name of Langley-Fitzurse. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;100. Patron, the Vicar of Kington-St. Michael. The church was built in 1855. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kington_Langley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/3345436</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10406020</id>
   <status>Ch/CP/Tg</status>
   <name>KINGTON LANGLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10406067</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LANGLEY FITZURSE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10406444</id>
   <status>Ch</status>
   <name>LANGLEY FITZURSE</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
