<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11719</id>
<name>DILTON MARSH</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.2510709526346</lat>
<lon>-2.22546322272357</lon>
<gazetteerText>DILTON-MARSH, a chapelry in Westbury parish, Wilts; on the Westbury and Yeovil railway, adjacent to the boundary with Somerset, 2&#189; miles WSW of Westbury. It was constituted in 1845; is partly identical with Dilton chapelry; and has a post office under Westbury. Rated property, &#163;5, 271. Pop., 1, 561. Houses, 380. The property is much subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;300.* Patron, the Bishop of Salisbury. The church is recent; and there are charities &#163;93. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/Dilton/index.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dilton_Marsh</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2651257</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10402487</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>DILTON MARSH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10402499</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>DILTONS MARSH</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>25557</id>
<name>DILTON</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.2394918198755</lat>
<lon>-2.2020028416278</lon>
<gazetteerText>DILTON, a chapelry in Westbury parish, Wilts; on the Westbury and Yeovil and the Somerset and Wey-mouth railways, 2 miles SW of Westbury. Post town, Dilton-Marsh, under Westbury. Pop. returned with the parish. Dilton Court is the seat of Col. Phipps. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the vicarage of Westbury, in the diocese of Salisbury. The church is old and small. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
</place>
</results>
