<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11494</id>
<name>STEEPLE ASHTON</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.3117286847376</lat>
<lon>-2.14645247716212</lon>
<gazetteerText>ASHTON (Steeple), a village and a tything in Westbury district, and a parish in Westbury and Melksham districts, Wilts. The village stands 2&#189; miles S of the Kennet and Avon canal, and 3&#190; E of the Great Western railway at Trowbridge. It takes its distinctive name from a tall steeple which was destroyed by lightning in 1670. It formerly was a market-town, and still has a fair on 19 Sept.; and it is a seat of petty sessions, and has a post office under Trowbridge.-The tything comprises 2,808 acres. Real property, &#163;5,846. Pop., 776. Houses, 177.&#151;The parish includes also the tythings of Great Hinton, West Ashton, and Littleton, and the chapelry of Semington. Acres, 6,789. Real property, &#163;14,474. Pop., 1,767. Houses, 359. A considerable extent of the land was formerly com mon and recently enclosed. Rood-Ashton House, the seat of the Long family, is about a mile SW of the village. Very numerous fossils have been found; and an ancient pavement, thought to have been Roman, but of different character from other Roman pavements, has been dug up. The living is a vicarage, united with the curacy of Semington, in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;852. Patron, the Master of Magdalene college, Cambridge. The church is large and later English, with a four-spired tower; and was built, toward the end of the 15th century, chiefly by Robert Long, a clothier. The vicarage of West Ashton is a separate charge. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/SteepleAshton/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636970</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=16110</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10396219</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>STEEPLE ASHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10396220</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>STEEPLE ASHTON WITH SEMINGTON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11495</id>
   <name>WEST ASHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11826</id>
   <name>GREAT HINTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
