<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11880</id>
<name>LAVERSTOCK</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.0890526107703</lat>
<lon>-1.77473002205459</lon>
<gazetteerText>LAVERSTOCK, a village and a parish in Alderbury district, Wilts. The village stands on the Bourn river, near the Southwestern railway, 1&#189; mile NE of Salisbury; and has a post office under Salisbury. Its name signifies &quot;the village of the lark.&quot; The parish includes part of Ford tything, and comprises 1, 675 acres. Real property, with the rest of Ford, and with Milford tything, &#163;9, 789. Rated property, exclusive of Milford, &#163;3, 130. Pop., 470. Houses, 83. The property is divided among a few. The manor belonged once to the Good Duke Humphrey, and belongs now to John H.Wyndham, Esq. Laverstock House was formerly the seat of the Dyke family; and is now a private lunatic asylum, with accommodation for upwards of 100 patients. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Salisbury, and is annexed to the commonalty of the Vicars Choral of Salisbury. The church is modern; was built at a cost of &#163;2, 350; has a bell turret; and consists of flint, with stone dressings. Part of the previous church still stands, and contains monuments of the Bathursts. There is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/Laverstock/index.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/7296282</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10406602</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>LAVERSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10406699</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>LAVERSTOCK</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12161</id>
   <name>WINTERBOURNE EARLS</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
