<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11583</id>
<name>BISHOPSTONE</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.0313583578788</lat>
<lon>-1.89339478136523</lon>
<gazetteerText>BISHOPSTONE, a village, a parish, and a subdistrict, in the district of Wilton, Wilts. The village stands on an affluent of the river Avon, 3&#189; miles SSW of Wilton r. station, and 4&#189; SW of Salisbury.&#151;The parish includes also the hamlets of Throope, Croncheston, Faulston, Hamston, Netton, and Pitts; and its Post Town is Bishopstone, under Salisbury. Acres, 4,452Real property, with Stratford-Toney, &#163;6,047. Pop., 685. Houses, 136. The property is subdivided. The living is a rectory and a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;806.* Patron, the Earl of Pembroke The church is cruciform; shows features of many styles and periods, but is mainly of the time of Henry VI.; belonged to the priory of Monkton-Farleigh; and contains two stone coffins, which are supposed to hold the remains of bishops. Charities, &#163;10.-The subdistrict contains eleven parishes and an extra-parochial tract. Acres, 31,459. Pop., 4,904. Houses, 1,036. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655554</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bishopstone,_Salisbury</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/BishopstoneS/index.htm</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10398708</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BISHOPSTONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10398745</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BISHOPSTONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544026</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BISHOPSTONE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11518</id>
   <name>BARFORD ST MARTIN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11648</id>
   <name>BURCOMBE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11703</id>
   <name>COOMBE BISSETT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11778</id>
   <name>GROVELEY WOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11834</id>
   <name>HOMINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12112</id>
   <name>STRATFORD TONY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>11586</id>
<name>BISHOPSTONE</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.543858340472</lat>
<lon>-1.64815055728161</lon>
<gazetteerText>BISHOPSTONE, a parish in Highworth district, Wilts; on the verge of the county, 2&#190; miles S of Shrivenham r. station, and 6 E of Swindon. It has a post office under Shrivenham. Acres, 4,452. Real property, &#163;4,513. Pop., 716. Houses, 147. The property is subdivided. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;208.* Patron, the Bishop of Gloucester and Bristol. The church is tolerable. A school has an endowed income of &#163;59, and other charities &#163;69. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/BishopstoneN/index.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2655553</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10398757</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BISHOPSTONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10398769</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BISHOPSTONE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10398770</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BISHOPSTONE WITH HINTON PARVA</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
