<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>528</id>
<name>TROWBRIDGE</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.3194271910451</lat>
<lon>-2.20917967363927</lon>
<gazetteerText>TROWBRIDGE, a town, a parish, and a sub-district, in Melksham district, Wilts. The town stands on the river Biss, and on the Bath and Salisbury railway, 11&#190; miles SSW of Chippenham; was known to the Saxons as Truthhabrig; came afterwards to be called Tribridge, Trolbridge, and Thoroughbridge; acquired early a castle, which was taken by Stephen from Maud, rebuilt by John of Gaunt, and is now represented only by a moat; became, in the time of Henry VIII., a notable place of cloth manufacture; is now a seat of petty-sessions and county courts; occupies a rocky declivity, sloping to the Biss; presents an irregularly constructed appearance, with nearly all its streets, except the main one, narrow and ill-built; and has a head post-office,&#8225; a r. station with telegraph, two banking offices, several inns, a recent market house erected at a cost of nearly &#163;5,000, a court-hall, a police station, a three-arched bridge, a church of the 14th century restored at a cost of about &#163;8,000, two other churches built in 1836 and 1868, another church purchased from the Baptists in 1860, five dissenting chapels, two schools endowed with jointly &#163;60 a year, two alms houses with &#163;130, and other charities &#163;95 Markets are held thrice a-week; a fair is held on 5, 6, and 7 Aug.; two weekly newspapers are published; and the manufacture of kerseymeres, tweeds, and woollen cloths, is carried on. Pop. in 1861, 9,626. Houses, 2,119.&#151;The parish contains three tythings, and comprises 2,442 acres. Real property, &#163;32,830; of which &#163;250 are in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 11,148; in 1861, 10,487. Houses, 2,322. The manor was given, by Henry VIII., to the Seymours; passed to the Mannerses and the Timbrels; and belongs now to W. Stancomb, Esq. The living of St. James is a rectory, and that of Trinity is a vicarage, in the diocese of Salisbury. Value of St. J., &#163;900; of T., &#163;230.* Patron of St. James, the Church Patronage Society; of Trinity, the Rector of Trowbridge. St. Stephen&apos;s is a chapel of ease; and the vicarages of Staverton and Studley are separate benefices. The poet Crabbe was rector-The sub-district includes Hilperton parish, and comprises 3,520 acres. Pop., 11,367. Houses, 2,531. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/Trowbridge/index.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trowbridge</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2635427</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10043037</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10098440</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10133725</id>
   <status>Borough</status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10413000</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10413011</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10413047</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE HOLY TRINITY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10413059</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE ST THOMAS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544142</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12781635</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12830890</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>434</id>
   <name>BRADFORD ON AVON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1007</id>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11494</id>
   <name>STEEPLE ASHTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11820</id>
   <name>HILPERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11831</id>
   <name>HOLT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12063</id>
   <name>POTTERNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12088</id>
   <name>SEEND</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12101</id>
   <name>SOUTHWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12138</id>
   <name>WESTWOOD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12156</id>
   <name>WINSLEY</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>1007</id>
<name>MELKSHAM</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.3744626899092</lat>
<lon>-2.13681556787072</lon>
<gazetteerText>Melksham.-- market town, par., and township, Wilts, on river Avon, 6&#188; miles S. of Chippenham and 96 miles W. of London by rail - par., 12,572 ac., pop. 5331; township, pop. 4412; town, 413 ac., pop. 2178; P.O., T.O., 2 Banks. Market-day, Tuesday. In Saxon times this place had some importance, and at the Domesday survey it was held as a royal demesne. The Wilts and Berks Canal passes E. of the town. Saline and chalybeate springs are in the vicinity, but although much has been done to give it attraction the town has never gained special note as a watering-place. Woollen goods, cordage, cocoa fibre, and haircloths form its mfrs.; malting also is carried on to some extent. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melksham</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/Melksham/index.htm</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2642786</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10027688</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10154080</id>
   <status>RSD</status>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10155344</id>
   <status>Hundred</status>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10173103</id>
   <status>RD</status>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10178897</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>TROWBRIDGE AND MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10196899</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10408805</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10408817</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10408829</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>MELKSHAM WITHIN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10408830</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>MELKSHAM WITHOUT</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10480905</id>
   <status>ExP</status>
   <name>LAND COMMON TO MELKSHAM WITHOUT AND BROUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544130</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10590243</id>
   <status>EExP</status>
   <name>LAND COMMON TO MELKSHAM WITHOUT AND BROUGHTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12829292</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>MELKSHAM</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11644</id>
   <name>BROUGHTON GIFFORD</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
