<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>11635</id>
<name>NORTH BRADLEY</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.2893825928276</lat>
<lon>-2.22001866476689</lon>
<gazetteerText>BRADLEY (North), a tything, a parish, and a subdistrict in Westbury district, Wilts. The tything lies on an affluent of the river Avon, adjacent to the Great Western railway, 2 miles S of Trowbridge; and has a post office under Trowbridge. Real property, &#163;3,917. Pop., 955. Houses, 231.&#151;The parish includes also the tything of Southwick. Acres, 4,036. Real property, &#163;8,628. Pop., 2,196. Houses, 510. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Salisbury, Value, &#163;398.* Patron, Winchester College. The church was built in the 12th century, and went recently into decay; and a new one, to be in the early transition style, with chapel and tower in the perpendicular style, was founded in 1862. Road-Hill vicarage is a separate charge. There is a Baptist chapel. An asylum for poor, founded by Archdeacon Daubeny, and a school have &#163;159.-The subdistrict includes also part of Steeple-Ashton parish. Acres, 6,076. Pop., 2,510. Houses, 577. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/NorthBradley/index.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Bradley</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641413</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=16111</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10400144</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>NORTH BRADLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10400284</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NORTH BRADLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544154</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BRADLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>23867</id>
<name>RODE HILL</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.2852094269167</lat>
<lon>-2.27390674559149</lon>
<gazetteerText>ROAD-HILL, a chapelry in North Bradley parish, Wilts; adjacent to Road in Somerset, and 3 miles N Wby W of Westbury r. station. It was constituted in 1852; and its post town is Road, under Bath. Pop, 408. Houses, 97. The living is a p. curacy in the diocese of Salisbury. Value, &#163;159.* Patron, the Vicar of North Bradley. The church is good; and there is a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10411210</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>ROAD HILL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
