<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>12094</id>
<name>SHERSTON</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5756597107547</lat>
<lon>-2.20696407288714</lon>
<gazetteerText>SHERSTON-MAGNA, a village and a parish in Ma1msbury district, Wilts. The village stands on the river Avon, 5&#189; miles WSW of Malmsbury, and 8&#189; E by S of Wickwar r. station; was known to the Saxons as Sceorstan; witnessed an obstinate battle, in 1 016, between Edmund Ironside and Canute; was long a place of considerable consequence; and has a post-office, of the name of Sherston, under Ma1msbury, and fairs on 12 May and 2 Oct. The parish comprises 4,280 acres. Real property, with S.-Parva, &#163;8,637. Pop. of S.-M. alone, 1,503. Houses, 325. The property is subdivided. The manors of S.-M and S.-P., with Pinkney Park, belong to W. H. Creswell, Esq. Roman coins have been found; a deep well, supposed to have been of Roman origin, is behind the village; and an entrenched camp, probably Saxon, is a little to the NE. The living is a vicarage, united with S.-Parva, in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value, &#163;150.* Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Gloucester. The church is Norman and cruciform, and has a central tower. There are chapels for Independents, Baptists, and Primitive Methodists, national and British schools, and charities &#163;13. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/SherstonMagna/index.htm</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sherston,_Wiltshire</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2638013</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10411816</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SHERSTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10411828</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SHERSTON MAGNA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10411841</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHERSTON MAGNA</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10411865</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SHERSTON MAGNA WITH SHERSTON PARVA</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10309</id>
   <name>ACTON TURVILLE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10351</id>
   <name>GREAT BADMINTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10406</id>
   <name>BOXWELL</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10592</id>
   <name>DIDMARTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10934</id>
   <name>KINGSCOTE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11012</id>
   <name>NEWINGTON BAGPATH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11038</id>
   <name>NYMPSFIELD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11459</id>
   <name>WESTONBIRT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11486</id>
   <name>ALDERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11907</id>
   <name>LUCKINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
