<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>377</id>
<name>SWINDON</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5595064002</lat>
<lon>-1.77721726845184</lon>
<gazetteerText>SWINDON, two towns, a parish, and a sub-district, in Highworth district, Wilts. The towns are Old S. and New S. Old S. stands on an eminence, near the Wilts and Berks canal, 1 mile SSE of S.-Junction r. station, and 17 NE by E of Chippenham; was known, at Domesday, as Svindune; commands extensive views into Berks and Gloucestershire; presents a picturesque appearance, with old house s of red brick and stone; is a seat of petty-sessions and a polling place; and has a head post-office,&#8225; two banking offices, and two chief inns. New S. stands around S.-Junction r. station, on the Great Western railway, at the forking of the lines toward respectively Chippenham and Gloucester; originated in the removal hither, in 1841, of the entire locomotive department of the railway from Wootton-Bassett; occupies ground which previously was all waste; contains erections of the railway company, constructed at a cost of nearly &#163;500,000, including a great r. station, refreshment-rooms and hotel, a shed 490 feet by 72, an engine-house 290 feet by 140, and extensive workshops; and includes great ranges of neat dwelling-houses, a mechanics&apos; institute, a library and reading room, and a public park. The two towns, for all ordinary business purposes, are practically one. A weekly market is held, and a weekly newspaper published, on Monday; and fairs are held on 21 March, 3 April, 23 May, 25 Sept., and 11 Dec. A spacious corn exchange, with a conventional classic front, was erected in 1866. St. Mark&apos;s church, in New S., was built at a cost of &#163;8,000; and is in the decorated English style, with tower and spire 140 feet high. The Independent chapel in Victoria-street was built in 1866, at a cost of &#163;3,000; and is in the Lombardic style, with a tower 60 feet high. There are also a church in Old S., three dissenting chapels, an endowed school with &#163;54 a year, and charities &#163;108. Pop. of New S. in 1861, 4,167. houses, 716.&#151;The parish comprises 3,136 acres; and is ecclesiastically cut into Old S. and New S. Real property, &#163;37,769; of which &#163;14 are in quarries, &#163;1,559 in canals, and &#163;172 in gasworks. Pop. in 1851, 4,876; in 1861, 6,856. houses, 1,204. The Lawn, contiguous to Old S. town, is the seat of the God dards. A Druidical stone is at Brome. The living of Old S. is a vicarage, and that of New S. is a p. curacy, in the diocese of Gloucester and Bristol. Value of Old S., &#163;302;* of New S., &#163;120.* Patron of Old S., the Lord Chancellor; of New S., the Bishop of G. and B.&#151;The sub-district contains 8 parishes. Acres, 26,608. Pop., 12,224. Houses, 2,346 (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WIL/Swindon/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swindon</link>
<link>http://www.workhouses.org.uk/Highworth</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2636389</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10061490</id>
   <status>MB</status>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10104178</id>
   <status>UA</status>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10135096</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>OLD SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10137275</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>OLD SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10194118</id>
   <status>RegD/PLU</status>
   <name>SWINDON AND HIGHWORTH</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10410861</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWINDON ST PETER PENHILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412675</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412687</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412699</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWINDON ALL SAINTS</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412717</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWINDON ST AUGUSTINE</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412729</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWINDON ST BARNABAS GORSE HILL</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412742</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWINDON ST PAUL COVINGHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10544051</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10567270</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12414687</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12742678</id>
   <status>BCon</status>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12742680</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>SOUTH SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12742691</id>
   <status>CCon</status>
   <name>NORTH SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12755727</id>
   <status>PDivCon</status>
   <name>WILTSHIRE SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>12828792</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWINDON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>49</id>
   <name>STROUD</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>72</id>
   <name>CHELTENHAM</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>344</id>
   <name>WANTAGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>390</id>
   <name>GLOUCESTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>590</id>
   <name>CIRENCESTER</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>827</id>
   <name>MARLBOROUGH</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>1057</id>
   <name>CALNE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10519</id>
   <name>CHURCHDOWN</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>11726</id>
   <name>DURRINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>12113</id>
   <name>STRATTON ST MARGARET</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>23865</id>
<name>NEW SWINDON</name>
<container>WILTSHIRE</container>
<lat>51.5622950710206</lat>
<lon>-1.77925695143412</lon>
<gazetteerText>New Swindon, local government dist., Rodborne Cheney, Stratton St Margaret, and Swindon pars., Wilts, forming the chief part of the town of Swindon, 1310 ac., pop. 17,768; P.O., T.O. See SWINDON. (In 1887, John Bartholomew&apos;s Gazetteer of the British Isles)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10107570</id>
   <status>UD</status>
   <name>SWINDON NEW TOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10186882</id>
   <status>USD</status>
   <name>SWINDON NEW TOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412705</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>SWINDON NEW TOWN</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10412754</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>NEW SWINDON ST PAUL</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
