<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9891</id>
<name>HALLOW</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.2230419971061</lat>
<lon>-2.2717996301689</lon>
<gazetteerText>HALLOW, a village and a parish in Martley district, Worcestershire. The village stands near the river Severn, and near the Worcester and Malvern railway, 3 miles NNW of Worcester; and has a post office under Worcester. The parish includes also the hamlets of Broadheath and Shoulton. Acres, 3, 556. Real property, &#163;9, 121. Pop. in 185, , 308; in 186, , 507. Houses, 320. The property is subdivided. Hallow Park, situated on a height commanding a fine view of the Severn, is the seat of Captain J. P. Lord. There are nurseries, marketgardens, and several neat villas. The living is a p. curacy, annexed, with Christ&apos;s Chapel, to the vicarage of Grimley, in the diocese of Worcester. The old church was rebuilt in 1830, and is now a mortuary chapel. The new church was built in 1869, at a cost of about &#163;4, 000. Christ&apos;s chapel is in Broadheath. There are a Lady Huntingdon&apos;s chapel, an endowed school with &#163;100 ayear, and a free school in Broadheath. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/Hallow/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2647612</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43138</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10334147</id>
   <status>CP/Ch</status>
   <name>HALLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10334159</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>HALLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10334160</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>HALLOW</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10334172</id>
   <status>CP</status>
   <name>SOUTH HALLOW</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9776</id>
   <name>COTHERIDGE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9923</id>
   <name>KENSWICK</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
