<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10102</id>
<name>OLD SWINFORD</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4476238277798</lat>
<lon>-2.14935939910298</lon>
<gazetteerText>SWINFORD (Old), a parish in Stourbridge district; comprising Stourbridge, Lye, Wollaston, Wollescott, and Upper Swinford townships in Worcestershire, and Amblecoat hamlet in Staffordshire. Old S. proper adjoins the Oxford, Worcester, and Wolverhampton railway, 1 mile SSE of Stourbridge; and has a post-office under Stourbridge. Acres of the parish, 3,315. Real property, &#163;48,270; of which &#163;550 are in mines. Pop. in 1851, 20,238; in 1861, 22,958. houses, 4,676. Useful minerals abound; manufactures of iron, glass, and fire-clay utensils are carried on; and ample communications, by the river Stour, by canals, and by railways, exist. The living is a rectory in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;781.* Patron, the Earl of Dudley. The church is good. The p. curacies of Stourbridge-St. John, Stourbridge-St. Thomas, Lye, Wollaston, and Amble-coat are separate benefices. There are numerous dissenting chapels, several endowed schools with aggregately &#163;3,029 a year, and charities &#163;130. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43112</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10290120</id>
   <status>CP/AP/Tn</status>
   <name>OLDSWINFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10290223</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLD SWINFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347312</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OLD SWINFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10347324</id>
   <status>Tn/CP</status>
   <name>UPPER SWINFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580961</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWINFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10580973</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>SWINFORD</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>632</id>
   <name>AMBLECOTE</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10153</id>
   <name>WOLLASTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
