<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>10141</id>
<name>WICK</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1077623251848</lat>
<lon>-2.05156188521874</lon>
<gazetteerText>WICK-NEAR-PERSHORE, a chapelry in Pershore parish, Worcester; 2 miles SE by S of Pershore r. station. It has a post-office under Pershore. Acres, 1,600. Real property, &#163;3,886. Pop., 318. Houses, 65. The manor, with W. House, belongs to A. R. Hudson, Esq.; Upper W. House is the seat ofS. Hudson, Esq.; and Avon Bank, of Mrs. General Marriott. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;105. Patron, the Vicar of Pershore. The church is old. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/Wick/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2633983</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10348602</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>WICK</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10348614</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WICK</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>10142</id>
<name>WICKHAMFORD</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0709512324392</lat>
<lon>-1.90784532388312</lon>
<gazetteerText>WICKHAMFORD, a parish in Evesham district, Worcester; 2&#189; miles SE of Evesham r. station. Post town, Evesham. Acres, 1,242. Real property, &#163;1,304. Pop., 124. Houses, 27. The property belongs chiefly to Lord Sandys. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;41. Patron, Christchurch, Oxford. The church was recently restored. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/Wickhamford/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/8224212</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10348626</id>
   <status>AP/CP/Ch</status>
   <name>WICKHAMFORD</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10348638</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>WICKHAMFORD</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>20495</id>
<name>WICK EPISCOPI</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1719187587368</lat>
<lon>-2.2369092638424</lon>
<gazetteerText>WICK-EPISCOPI, or Lower and Upper Wick, a village in Bedwardine-St. John parish, Worcestershire; 2 miles SW of Worcester. It has a post-office, of the name of Lower Wick, under Worcester. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<unit>
   <id>10348870</id>
   <status>AP/Ch</status>
   <name>WICK EPISCOPI</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
