<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9991</id>
<name>OFFENHAM</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1109969778196</lat>
<lon>-1.91217729184449</lon>
<gazetteerText>OFFENHAM, a village and a parish in Evesham district, Worcester. The village stands on the river Avon, 1&#188; mile S of the boundary with Warwick, and 2 N N E of Evesham r. station: took its name from King Offa, who had a house at it; and is a very retired place, untraversed by any carriage-road. The parish comprises 1, 215 acres. Post-town, Evesham. Real property, &#163;3, 380; of which &#163;12 are in quarries. Pop. in 1851, 400; in 1861, 461. Houses, 95. The increase of pop.arose from the temporary presence of workmen employed in rebuilding the-church. The property is much sub-divided. The manor belonged anciently to the abbots of Evesham; and f ments and extensive foundations of a mansion of the abbots were discovered, a few yearsago, in diggings near the present manor farm-house. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;130.* Patron, Christ Church, Oxford. The church was rebuilt in 1861, at a cost of about &#163;1, 800; is in the early decorated English style; comprises nave, N aisle, and chancel, with a vestry; and retains thetower of the previous edifice, of late perpendicular date and embattled. There are an endowed school with &#163;12 a year, and charities &#163;7. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/Offenham/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2641071</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10342521</id>
   <status>Ch/CP/AP</status>
   <name>OFFENHAM</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10342557</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>OFFENHAM</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
