<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9778</id>
<name>CRADLEY</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4587327885725</lat>
<lon>-2.08838907603656</lon>
<gazetteerText>CRADLEY, a town and a township-chapelry in Hales-owen parish, Worcester. The town stands on the river Stour, at the boundary with Stafford. near the Dudley canal, 2&#189; miles ENE of Stourbridge; is connected by a branch railway with the West Midland at Stourbridge; has a post office under Brierley Hill; and carries on extensive manufactures in iron and hardware. The chapelry includes the town, some manufacturing dependencies, and some rural tracts. Acres, 732. Real property, &#163;8, 471; of which &#163;1, 100 are in mines. Pop., 4, 075. Houses, 779. The property is not much divided. The manor belongs to Lord Lyttleton. A saline spring, called the Lady well, in much medicinal repute, is in a picturesque wooded vale. Coal and ironstone abound on the lands of Netherend. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;116. Patron, the Vicar. of Halesowen. The church is tolerable; and there are chapels for Baptists, Unitarians, Wesleyans, and New Connexion Methodists, and a national school. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/Cradley/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2652170</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10330300</id>
   <status>Ch/CP</status>
   <name>CRADLEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10330336</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>CRADLEY</name>
</unit>
</place>
<place>
<id>20236</id>
<name>CRADLEY HEATH</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.4742368550196</lat>
<lon>-2.07803736290093</lon>
<gazetteerText>CRADLEY HEATH, a place 2&#190; miles from Cradley, in Worcester; with a post office&#8225; under Brierley Hill. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/8224780</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>12831456</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>CRADLEY HEATH</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
