<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9732</id>
<name>BREDON</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0206817142941</lat>
<lon>-2.08392292739384</lon>
<gazetteerText>BREDON, a village in the district of Tewkesbury, and a parish in the districts of Tewkesbury and Winchcombe, and county of Worcester. The village stands on the river Avon, adjacent to the Birmingham and Gloucester railway, 3&#189; miles NE of Tewkesbury; and has a station on the railway, and a post office under Tewkesbury. Eanulf, grandfather of King Offa, got a grant of it from Ethelbald, King of Mercia; and founded at it a monastery, which was transferred, before the Conquest, to the see of Worcester. The parish includes also the hamlets of Norton-by-Bredon, Hardwick-with-Mitton, Kinsham, and Westmancote, and the chapelry of Cutsdean. Acres, 5,818. Real property, &#163;11,608. Pop., 1,555. Houses, 366. Bredon hill separates the vales of Cotswold and Evesham; has an altitude of 900 feet; commands an extensive prospect; has traces of a Roman camp with a double trench; and is a meet for the Worcester hounds. Wollashill Hall is the ancient seat of the Hanfords. The living is a rectory, united with the p. curacies of Norton and Cutsdean, in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;2,300.* Patron, the Duke of Portland. The church occupies the site of the ancient monastery; is an old and interesting edifice of different periods, chiefly early English; has a central tower, surmounted by a graceful spire; and was restored in 1845. The remains of Dr. Prideaux, bishop of Worcester in the time of Charles I., lie in the chancel; a rich monument of Giles Reed, of date 1611, is in a south chapel; and several ancient monastic tombs are in the churchyard. There are a Baptist chapel, a free school with &#163;130 a year, and charities &#163;350. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/Bredon/index.html</link>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bredon</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2654807</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43123</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10329231</id>
   <status>AP/CP</status>
   <name>BREDON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10329243</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>BREDON WITH BREDONS NORTON</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10570372</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>BREDON</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9775</id>
   <name>CONDERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9998</id>
   <name>OVERBURY</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10103</id>
   <name>TEDDINGTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10929</id>
   <name>KEMERTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
<place>
<id>9733</id>
<name>BREDONS NORTON</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.0506529968119</lat>
<lon>-2.10008858673464</lon>
<gazetteerText>NORTON-BY-BREDON, or Bredons-Norton, a hamlet-chapelry in Bredon parish, Worcester; under Bredon hill, near the boundary with Gloucester, 1 mile S E of Bredon r. station, and 3&#189; N E by E of Tewkesbury. Post-town, Bredon, under Tewkesbury. Acres, 1, 100. Pop., 243. Houses, 55. The living is a p. curacy, annexed to the rectory of Bredon, in the diocese of Worcester. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/BredonsNorton/index.html</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10329255</id>
   <status>CP/Ch/CP</status>
   <name>BREDONS NORTON</name>
</unit>
</place>
</results>
