<results>
<copyright>(c) 2012, Great Britain Historical GIS, University of Portsmouth, UK. Published under the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK: England &amp; Wales License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/).</copyright>
<place>
<id>9922</id>
<name>KEMPSEY</name>
<container>WORCESTERSHIRE</container>
<lat>52.1392558738606</lat>
<lon>-2.20342453551671</lon>
<gazetteerText>KEMPSEY, a village, a parish, and a sub-district, in Upton-on-Severn district, Worcester. The village stands on the river Severn, amid charming scenery, 2 miles NW of Wadborough r. station, and 4 S of Worcester city; and has a post office&#8224; under Worcester. The parish comprises 3, 105 acres. Real property, &#163;10, 449. Pop., 1, 433. Houses, 335. The property is much subdivided. The manor belongs to the Bishop of Worcester. A monastery was founded here in 799; and was given, at an early period, to the Bishops of Worcester. A palace of the bishops succeeded the monastery; Henry II. and Edward I. kept court at the palace; and Simon de Montfort, with his prisoner, Henry III., slept in it before the battle of Evesham. The parish contains many genteel residences. Traces exist of a Roman camp of 1 5 acres; and many coins, urns, cups, and other Roman relics have been found. The living is a vicarage in the diocese of Worcester. Value, &#163;248. Patrons, the Dean and Chapter of Worcester. The church was almost wholly rebuilt in 1799; was restored, at a cost of &#163;4, 000, in 1865; is a cruciform structure, with deep chancel and large tower; and contains the effigies of an armed knight. There are a national school, and charities &#163;61.&#151;The sub-district contains also four other parishes, and part of another. Acres, 12, 405. Pop., 3, 511. Houses, 821. (In 1870-72, John Marius Wilson&apos;s Imperial Gazetteer of England and Wales)</gazetteerText>
<links>
<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kempsey</link>
<link>http://www.genuki.org.uk/big/eng/WOR/Kempsey/index.html</link>
<link>http://www.geonames.org/2645833</link>
<link>http://www.british-history.ac.uk/report.asp?compid=43148</link>
</links>
<unit>
   <id>10334895</id>
   <status>CP/AP</status>
   <name>KEMPSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10334901</id>
   <status>EP</status>
   <name>KEMPSEY</name>
</unit>
<unit>
   <id>10552345</id>
   <status></status>
   <name>KEMPSEY</name>
</unit>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>9787</id>
   <name>CROOME DABITOT</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10007</id>
   <name>PIRTON</name>
</nearByPlace>
<nearByPlace>
   <id>10084</id>
   <name>SEVERN STOKE</name>
</nearByPlace>
</place>
</results>
